<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12l22_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works are still topics in school and inspiration to many creative renewals in form of movies or plays.</s>
        <s>But is his work still relevant today or rather outdated?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One could argue taht those problems presented dont occur in modern days.</s>
        <s>Prearranged marriage is a thing of the past and nowadays women can decide for themselves whom to marry.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The counter side might argue that nowadays people struggle with their individual situations and their love more than ever.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nowadays people have more personal goals and are trying to accomplish them by any means in the modern <choice><orig>self-fixiated</orig><reg>self-fixated</reg></choice> world.</s>
        <s>And to combine personal life with new love can be challenging, as it is also portrayed in the play by <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the counter side his work <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> is not so different than other love stories and thus due to the old language outdated.</s>
        <s>The only difference, one might say, is the language compared to newer romantic dramas and the plot mostly stays the same.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Critiques</orig><reg>Critics</reg></choice> may respond that the language is the key aspect, when reading old literature.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> poetic and lyrical writing style described the storyboard in a way that modern language is not capable of.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the stated facts lead me to my opinion, which is that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> still influences modern literature and can be interpreted on the world today regarding timeless themes such as love being connected to irrationality or boundaries like different families / religion / <choice><orig>hirarchy</orig><reg>hierarchy</reg></choice> being in the way of love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
