<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l26_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this given extract from the drama <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref>, published by <name type="misc">Oxford school Shakespeare</name> in <date>2008</date>, <name type="person">Romeo</name> meets <name type="person">Juliet</name> again at her balcony, after their first meeting at the ball.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first, <name type="person">Juliet</name> is very concerned about <name type="person">Romeo</name>, while also wondering how he found her.</s>
        <s>So she questions <name type="person">Romeo</name>, how he got over the walls, that are <choice><orig>surronding</orig><reg>surrounding</reg></choice> her <choice><orig>House</orig><reg>house</reg></choice> and warns him, that he will be killed if anyone sees him, considering what family he stems from.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> just responds that stone walls are not enough to stop love and that it can overcome anything that stands in its way, including <name type="person"><choice><orig>Juliets</orig><reg>Juliet's</reg></choice></name> relatives.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> then again warns him that if seen he will be killed by the <name type="person">Capulets</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> answers by saying that in <name type="person">Juliet's</name> eyes lies more danger than in twenty <choice><orig>enemys</orig><reg>enemies</reg></choice> and that her appreciation is enough to guard him from <choice><orig>enemys</orig><reg>enemies</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> then again underlines her concerns of <name type="person">Romeo</name> being seen.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo's</name><choice><orig>respond</orig><reg>reponse</reg></choice> to this is, that the darkness of the night hides him from others and if <name type="person">Juliet</name> didn't love him, he would be better off dead anyways.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Juliet</name> asks him, how he found her, <name type="person">Romeo</name> says that love guided him and that he would go anywhere to find her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly, <name type="person">Juliet</name> questions whether <name type="person">Romeo</name> really loves her, while also admitting to her love for him.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> then tries reinforce his love swearing to the moon, which is not enough for <name type="person">Juliet</name>, so she stells him to swear by himself.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
