<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12l27_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote>Oh no - please not <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> again!</quote>I imagine that since all of us have been highschool students, at some point we heard this from one of our classmates when it was announced that we would be reading <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> in class.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As we know, the playwright's works are over 400 years old, so why even bother?</s>
        <s>Why do we torture students with the <choice><orig>elisabethan</orig><reg>Elizabethan</reg></choice> language that isn't even spoken anymore?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The answer is quite simple: <choice><orig>Because</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works still matter because we can still learn from them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The playwright's themes connected to his works like love, revenge, guilt, fate and hate are undoubtedly a part of our everyday lives.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Let me present an example to you: I assume that ayou have been at least in love once in your life and experienced all that comes with it: pain, when it comes to an end, passion and doubts.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> characters <add>like <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name></add> help to understand these feelings better, illustrate them and provide a philosophical approach we can always come back to.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another example for the impact his themes have on our society is also hate.</s>
        <s>We often do not even rememeber why we hate this particular person.</s>
        <s>Does this remind you of someone, doesn't it?</s>
        <s>Drawing from <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>, the <name type="person">Montagues</name> and <name type="person">Capulets</name> have been in the same situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Especially the end of the play <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> serves as a lecture or rather warning: this violent and useless hate, just for the sake and habit of hating brings nothing but pain and misery to the families.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Apart from the themes in <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays, his language and rhetoric <choice><orig>is</orig><reg>are</reg></choice> quite unique and exceptional.</s>
        <s>Did you know that he invented over 1700 words?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another point to consider that shows us his relevance even more is the mystery that surrounds him.</s>
        <s>His works have led to a lot of controversy regarding the long-lasting debate if he had actually written the plays by himself - or as we'd say in nowaday's words - <quote>pressed copy-paste</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is obviously still debated about today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Yet, it is also understandable why some might say that he is outdated.</s>
        <s>For instance, the language used by him is extraordinary difficult to understand, especially if English is your foreign language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that, it is very often the case that we can't understand his relevance because the plays seem way too boring and complex to follow.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You might even wonder: <quote>What do I care about an ancient family feud I barely understand?</quote> Don't worry: it is not important to understand each word of the play.</s>
        <s>It is rather crucial to understand the lecture behind the story.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To see, that in a world full of hate, love can overcome everything - starting from as simple as an orchard's wall as to even an ancient family feud.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Especially <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> tragedies ahve had an impact on the theatres around the world and have been of many great examples for the playwrights that came after him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand one might also disagree and say that it should be at least modernized to help appeal to audiences of the 21st century.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, I maintain the view that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is of major importance still in our time.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Eventhough</orig><reg>Even though</reg></choice> his works are more than 400 years old, they have been and still are serving as an inspiration to other playwrights and their audiences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Touching on timeless themes like love and hate, the plays as well as their immense literary value regarding language, <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has undoubtedly impacted your English class and make you either love it or hate it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is now up to teachers and actors as well as writers to help preserve his plays and make them appeal to modern audiences.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
