<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12l31_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>At this time <name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></name> works are famous in the whole world <choice><orig>eventhough</orig><reg>even though</reg></choice> they are more than 400 years old.</s>
        <s>Very famous for <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is his use of langauge that, at this time sometimes is <choice><orig>quiet</orig><reg>quite</reg></choice> difficult to udnerstand.</s>
        <s>This leads to the question if his works are still relevant or are they outdated?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thinking about this question there are many aspects that his works are still relevant.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One is, that while reading <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works you can get to know a part of a historical background from those years.</s>
        <s>When you read the text from <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> you get to know the Elizabethan language he used.</s>
        <s>This might be very interesting for people who like to get to know history.</s>
        <s>Another aspect that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is not outdated is that you get to know the style of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> writing that he is famous for.</s>
        <s>If <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> was <choice><orig>outdatet</orig><reg>outdated</reg></choice> and we would for example read a more modern version of his text we would not be able to get to know the type of language he is famous for.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some can say that it would be more easily to understand but if we want to know how <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> made use of his language and for what he got famous it is not <choice><orig>enoug</orig><reg>enough</reg></choice> to read his text in a more modern and <choice><orig>easyer</orig><reg>easier</reg></choice> way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An argument to say that it is <choice><orig>outdatet</orig><reg>outdated</reg></choice> especially if we must send <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works at school is taht it is too difficult to understand.</s>
        <s>If at this point a student does not want to know much about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> and his use of language it would be <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> argument to say that <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works are not relevant anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But if we concerned with his works and try to read them we will understand his way of language and how he used it better with time which makes it not <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> difficult anymore.</s>
        <s>On top of that you can get extra knowledge of the language at those days and archive more background knowledge.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all one can say that even though <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works are sometimes difficult to understand it is not outdated because you will learn something about the language and the history of those years and there is nothing to say against archiving extra knowledge while reading <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works.</s>
        <s>So in my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works are not outdated and still relevant to read.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
