<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12l28_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>About four centuries ago, one of the greatest playwrights and poets to ever live has written famous plays and sonnets and impressed graced audiences even back then.</s>
        <s>That playwright was <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>.</s>
        <s>However, nowadays we still read <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works in school, play them in theatres and even made stories about them, but do the people still get their meaning?</s>
        <s>Are those plays even still relevant or are we just keeping up the pretense?</s>
        <s>Are Shakespearen plays not outdated?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In our modern society we often like to preach to culture and values and impress others with knowledge, but is taht really a reason to read centuries old plays and poetry that a lot of the children who read it in school don't even understand properly?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However, <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works are classics and historically meaningful.</s>
        <s>If we do not know our history well, can we even still deal with the present properly?</s>
        <s>By not teaching and knowing the past, we increase the danger of letting ourselves make the same mistakes over and over again or - in case of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> - of letting important art that helped shape the Elizabethan age and the following centuries disappear and be forgotten.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some might say that the problem is taht <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works do not deal with <choice><orig>nowadays'</orig><reg>nowaday's</reg></choice> topics and room needs to be made for newer, more fitting artists.</s>
        <s>Why are we dealing with <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> and an ancient tale of two lovers while new artists are trying hard to get our attention with topics that are meaningful to society and culture today?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But the works of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> also dealth with topics that are important now and have lessons in them that are much more valuable than anything new might be.</s>
        <s>Love is still an important thing for us and we have always wondered at fate.</s>
        <s>And in regards to nowadays, in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> there is a war between <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>two</reg></choice> families that can only be resolved with their children's deaths.</s>
        <s>Is that not an important lesson for us nowadays?</s>
        <s>If we keep fighting <choice><orig>usless</orig><reg>useless</reg></choice> wars out of hate or tradition, people will get hurtand it is far more relevant to find compromise than to hurt the other one more and lose everything in the process.</s>
        <s>On top of that, artists like <name type="person">Vincent Van Gogh</name> were not appreciated in their time but finally found their palce among the greats long after their deaths.</s>
        <s>So if a really great artist were among us, they would find their place eventually and <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> would not stand in their way because great art is always recognized eventually.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Still, the children nowadays who are taught about Shakespearen works hardly understand him anymore and would probably prefer a more modern, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">antright</gap> artist to teach them these lessons.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While this is true, children have a lot of other choices Shakespearen works are already being modernized and re-interpreted or summarized and the teachers are doing their best to help the students understand without naming the classics by <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">Geusing</gap> and any important parts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up, Shakespearen works are very much still relevant as they show us how things were but also thematise important and philosophical questions that we still have not found <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">muy</gap> answers to today.</s>
        <s>We need to keep teaching and playing and discussing these works to not let them fade and get lost eventually as their meaning touched a lot of people and influenced our society even nowadays.</s>
        <s>After all, we still talk about love at first sight, don't we?</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
