<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l26_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="factorial_explanation">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Penpal,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I've read ur question about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> in <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> theatre and I found an interesting <choice><orig>newspaperarticle</orig><reg>newspaper article</reg></choice> regarding the topic.</s>
        <s>In this article multiple <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">theatarists</gap>, who still play <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> talk about why they're doing it.</s>
        <s>The first one, called <name type="person">Mario Holetzeck</name>, thinks that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> stays relevant, because he still isn't understood completely.</s>
        <s>He states that we're still discovering new things about him.</s>
        <s>He also says that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> makes you reflect on yourself and makes you discover new things about yourself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another one, called <name type="person">Tobias Wellemeyer</name> <choice><orig>justifys</orig><reg>justifies</reg></choice> it in the impact <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has on modern texts.</s>
        <s>He says that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is the guideline for almost every other important author that came after him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A theatrist called <name type="person">Reinhard Simon</name> sees <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> strength in his ability to appeal to almost everyone.</s>
        <s>He says that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is interesting and exciting for everyone and that at the same time he still is relatable in our current time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last one, called <name type="person">Igor Holland-Moritz</name> states, that just because the amount of literature <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has created, there is no way he cana be ignored.</s>
        <s>His other point is that many modern theatre plays are just reintepretations of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> and that makes him unavoidable.</s>
        <s>Concluding, they basically just like his texts and appreciate his influence.</s>
        <s>In my opinion, this is not enough to justify this gigantic hype around him, but it still has to be taken into consideration.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed><choice><orig>greetings</orig><reg>Greetings</reg></choice>, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
