<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l21_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The tragedy <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> written by <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> and published in <date>1597</date> tells the love story of two young people from rival families that ends with the <choice><orig>dead</orig><reg>death</reg></choice> of both lovers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given extract from Act II scene 2 is about <name type="person">Romeo's</name> and <name type="person">Juliet's</name> secret conversation in the <name type="person">Capulet's</name> garden.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> came to see his beloved one, but as he comes out of hiding <name type="person">Juliet</name> shares her worries with him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> tells <name type="person">Romeo</name> her relatives may find and therefore kill him, but <name type="person">Romeo</name> is not bothered by this danger and tries to calm <name type="person">Juliet</name> down by opening up and charming her with his feelings.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> assures anxious <name type="person">Juliet</name> he will not be seen, but she resists on continuing to ask why he came to her garden and has brought himself in such a miserable and dangerous situation.</s>
        <s>After <name type="person">Romeo</name> answers her questions lovingly again <name type="person">Juliet</name> seems to slowly feel comfortable and starts to respond to <name type="person">Romeo</name> in the same loving way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At this point the scene takes a turn as until here <name type="person">Juliet</name> mostly asks short questions or states her worries and <name type="person">Romeo</name> talks about his feelings a lot more.</s>
        <s>From this moment on though <name type="person">Juliet</name> says a long paragraph about her feelings for <name type="person">Romeo</name> and how she cannot resist him and <name type="person">Romeo</name> only seems to answer <name type="person">Juliet</name> in this part of the scene.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Both <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> state their love to each other as the scene comes to an end.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
