<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l20_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text extract from Act II, scene 2 from <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>William Shakespear's</orig><reg>William Shakespeare's</reg></choice></ref> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> is about <name type="person">Juliet</name> being alone on her balcony at night, secretly talking about her concerns with reference to <name type="person">Romeo</name>, who hides secretly in the dark, listening and then reacting to these concerns.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene begins with <name type="person">Juliet</name> just thinking out loud the whole situation of <name type="person">Romeo</name> being a <name type="person">Montague</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> is then showing his presence by talking, but still hidden in the darkness.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> is surprised how he found her and asks for the reason of his visit, then she worries about her relatives, the <name type="person">Capulets</name>, seeing <name type="person">Romeo</name> here because they would probably murder him.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> however does not care and tells <name type="person">Juliet</name> that he is not <choice><orig>scarred</orig><reg>scared</reg></choice> to die and that the risk is worth it seeing her.</s>
        <s>Besides that he says that he is well hidden in the darkness.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Juliet</name> asks <name type="person">Romeo</name> how he found her, he tells her by love.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> then expresses her feelings for <name type="person">Romeo</name> in a monologue.</s>
        <s>He reacts with a promise, which is taken with a critical view by <name type="person">Juliet</name>.</s>
        <s>The scene ends with <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> knowing now about their love for eachother with a more clearer view.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
