<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12l29_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>No student in a western high school gets around it, at some point there will be talk of him in English class: <name type="person">William Shakespeare</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The playwright and poet of the Elizabethan era is still read and performed in classrooms and on stages all over the world, so who can deny their <choice><orig>reaccuring</orig><reg>reoccuring</reg></choice> confrontation with him.</s>
        <s>But does that also mean that he is still relevant?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>My answer to that would be: <choice><orig>Yes</orig><reg>yes</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work is still relevant today because we make it relevant; stories that are so often newly interpreted, contextualized differently, read in class, analysed, quoted - those are stories you need to know about.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> or not is still relevant today is quite an easy question to answer since how we treat his works can be derived from nothing but facts, but it automatically leads to another one, being: <choice><orig>Should</orig><reg>should</reg></choice> he?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Should <name type="person">William Shakespeare's</name> work still be so relevant today?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Once again, I would agree.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There are many reasons why we keep <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works relevant and one of the most important ones, if not the most important one, no matter how plain is that it brings us joy and entertainment to this day: <choice><orig>His</orig><reg>his</reg></choice> plays are still performed because people still come and watch it.</s>
        <s>There are so many new interpretations, such as movies, that are conventionalised in a way we can understand and relate to it better, especially <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name>, one of the most famous love stories of all time, is still the root of love stories we may not even recognize as <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> fruits.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name>, in his time, wrote of topics and emotions that were so true and universal to humankind back then, that we can still relate to it.</s>
        <s>The guild and lust for power of <name type="person">MacBeth</name> may be the same as of a manager or CEO today, the longing for love, the misunderstandings of a <name type="misc">Summernight's Dream</name> just as nervewrecking  today as in the 17th century.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Not only his plays but also in his sonnets meet emotion and poetry eachother and one could not be conveyed as beautifully without the other present.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even everything that was made in spite of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> would not have seen the light of day without it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One cannot deny the flood of contemporary authors who are also worth being read in class, taken in on stage, takling of the same topics as <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work does, but even better even more fitting, but the spell <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> had on people then lasts until now and if not, so is his work an important historical resource and an inspiration to many.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I would even argue <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is relevant now not in spite of contemporary art but because of it: <choice><orig>So</orig><reg>so</reg></choice> are we still a society after the Enlightenment, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">af</gap> the Realism, or great tragedy, war, a climate crisis, hard facts and a boring sobriety, while <name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></name> works has all the drama and the <choice><orig>flaire</orig><reg>flair</reg></choice> we could ever ask for.</s>
        <s>The research around his person plays a part as well, so have we still not figured out <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> he was one or many and what it was that inspired him, not definitely.</s>
        <s>It is also us looking up to a genius and not understanding it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And even if we wouldn't care about all that, would step away from him and let his story fade into the background, we couldn't flee the words he integrated in our languages, taht we find so normal and still can trace back to <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> or the blueprint for every drama we still care about today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is quite disheartening to be left to believe that we may have peaked so early on in the course of literature and maybe we have not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But I think we can not get away from him, not surpass him while functionary, thinking or writing in his order and since I believe him to talk so very true to the human soul I think in all that will ever truly touch us will have parallels to him, not just because he was so great, but because truth and truth are so alike.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion I owuld say, and this may sound confusing, that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is still relevant for the reasons he is still relevant and those are still being relevant.</s>
        <s>A society that works in similar cultural and political systems to <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> that does not break out but just evolves from it, can always relate to his work.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is relevant to our past, which built our present which builds our past and therefore we make it relevant to all by engraving it in culture, trying to understand it, trying to be understood by it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
