<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l29_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given extract one can find many means of language used to show how <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> think about their love and express it, and how they deal with their love's difficult <choice><orig>circumstance</orig><reg>circumstance's</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> is much more worried and timid than <name type="person">Romeo</name>; she asks him questions or asks him to confess her love as well to know that what she does is worth it, as shown in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 90)</ref> <quote>Dost thou love me?</quote> and continued in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 92-93)</ref> <quote>Thou mayst prove false; at lovers' perjuries They say, love laughs</quote>, which shows much better how worried she is, that her love isn't reciprocated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She is also scared that <name type="person">Romeo</name> is found by her family in their orchard; she warns him several times, such as in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 64f)</ref> <quote>And the place death, considering who thou art, if any of my kinsmen find thee here</quote> and already expresses her love through wanting him safe <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 74)</ref> <quote>I would not for the world they saw thee here</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <name type="person">Juliet</name> refers back to a monologue she held earlier in the scene, she is apologetic about it yet cannot deny it.</s>
        <s>She takes a risk by saying that she gives up the convention and therefore their family feud as well <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 85)</ref> <quote>but farewell compliment</quote> if <name type="person">Romeo</name> was to love her as well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> on the other hand is bold and foolish.</s>
        <s>Not just his action, coming to the orchard, shows this, but also the hyperboles he uses when <name type="person">Juliet</name> tries to warn him, such as <quote>with love's light wings did I o'er-perch these walls</quote> in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 66)</ref>, which also includes a metaphor and an alliteration, giving his expressiosn a feeling of lovesickness or <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">toverunkeness</gap> that makes everything appear to be dramatic and poetic, just as alliterations and metaphors do, and <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 72-73)</ref> <quote>look thou but sweet, and I am proof against their enmity</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> does not take the danger he is in seriously or doesn't care about it since he is so infatuated by his love for <name type="person">Juliet</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also allures to their <choice><orig>families</orig><reg>families'</reg></choice> rivalry and how their love is stronger by denying his family and himself if <name type="person">Juliet</name> was not fond of either or both <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 61)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> both speak openly about their love for eachother.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> more than <name type="person">Juliet</name> as though they can't deny it.</s>
        <s>The word <quote>love</quote> itself is often found such as in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 66,77,80,94,111)</ref> and more.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That their love is under unusual circumstances like knowing eachother for such a short time or coming from rivaling families is also shown by the contrasts used in the extract: <name type="person">Juliet</name> starts by saying <quote>My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words of that tongue's utterance, yet I know the sound</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 58-59)</ref> showing that even after only such a short time <name type="person">Romeo</name> is so dear to <name type="person">Juliet</name>.</s>
        <s>This adds legitemacy to their love for the viewer, who takes this play in even more quickly than  time goes by within the play and needs to believe in their love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That <name type="person">Romeo</name> is aware of the conflicting situation they are in yet does not care about it is shown in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 77-78)</ref>.</s>
        <s><quote>My life were better ended by their hate, than death prorogued, wanting of thy love</quote>.</s>
        <s>This contrast shows how the love between them, despite the circumstances of hate, is stronger than it.</s>
        <s>This also makes their love more believable but also more dramatic, both engaging the viewer.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That both of them are infatuated with eachother is also shown to the audience by their register: <choice><orig>They</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> compliment eachother <quote>fair saint</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 61)</ref> <quote>gentle Romeo</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 93)</ref> and speak in an endearing way of eachother.</s>
        <s>The tone of romance in the scene also lies in the metaphors, alliterations, rhymes and <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">siliber</gap> in their speech; all of these stylistic devices work with imagery or sound building an atmosphere for the reader to undersand and feel the love displayed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Repeatedly the night is <choice><orig>refered</orig><reg>referred</reg></choice> to in metaphors <quote>night's cloak</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 75)</ref>, <quote>mask of night</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 85)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Both times the night is hiding <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name>, keeping them of getting caught by <name type="person">Juliet's</name> relatives or eachother.</s>
        <s>These metaphors don't just have the previous mentioned effect but also allure to their ongoing romance that only allows them to meet at night.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The moon, which is mentioned first in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 107)</ref> is a <choice><orig>reaccuring</orig><reg>reoccuring</reg></choice> motive throughout the play as well.</s>
        <s>Rhymes can be found in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 61)</ref> or <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 86-87)</ref>.</s>
        <s>A strong <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">silibe</gap> can be found in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 82-84)</ref> <quote>I am not a pilot; yet, wert thou as far as that vast shore wash'd with the farthest sea, I would adventure for such merchandise</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Not just does it say that <name type="person">Romeo</name> would've taken a great distance onto him in order to <choice><orig>sea</orig><reg>see</reg></choice> <name type="person">Juliet</name>, but the sea also represents danger, especially after <name type="person">Romeo</name> declares that he is not a sailor.</s>
        <s>It also compliments <name type="person">Juliet</name> again, her being metaphorically the treasure in this comparison.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This also proves to the audience how strong <name type="person">Romeo's</name> love for <name type="person">Juliet</name> is and makes love as a motive for his future actions believable to the viewer.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
