<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l24_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="comparative report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Matthew,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>how</orig><reg>How</reg></choice> are you doing?</s>
        <s>I heard about the essay you're working on and I'm keen on helping you with it to give you the German perspective.</s>
        <s>I found an interesting article in the <name type="misc">Märkische Allgemeine</name> from <date>April 2016</date> which is a German newspaper, explaining why producers in <name type="geo">Brandenburg</name> still put on <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays which could really help you to illustrate the global appeal of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first argument which the director of a theater in <name type="geo">Cottbus</name> states is that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> deals with timeless and human topics such as revenge, love, hate or anger so even though it is history it still relates to our life and society.</s>
        <s>Therefore, he explains that his plays have to many different aspects that the recipient often gets surprised by new perspectives.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, another producer is convinced that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> was an essential figure in theater and poetry and that he shaped all the following poets.</s>
        <s>Additionally, he not only compliment his way of illustrating human conflicts in a poetic way but also his versatile characters.</s>
        <s>The director goes so far and declares <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> as the poet who illustrates feelings the most beautiful and the most drastic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Other arguments for <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays from the third producer are that they address a broad audience, create discussions and are relevant for every generation because they represent all aspects of life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, the producer states that the amount of work that was handed down to us and all the translations that exist represent the relevance of his works.</s>
        <s>Therefore, he believes that <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> literatur is timeless and gives the love story of <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> as an example.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could help you with your essay and that the arguments of the producers were interesting for you.</s>
        <s>If you have any further quetsions or want my opinion regarding <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> feel free to ask.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best regards, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
