<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l28_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given extract of Act 2 scene 2 of <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>'s work <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref>, first published in <date>1579</date>, is about the second meeting of the two lovers in the <name type="person">Capulet's</name> orchard, when <name type="person">Romeo</name> overhears <name type="person">Juliet</name> talking about him and then comes out of hiding to respond.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> is rather concerned regarding this meeting with <name type="person">Romeo</name>.</s>
        <s>She questions how he managed to climb the high walls to her family's orchard and warns him of the consquences that will follow if he is found.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> replies to this that love has helped him overcome the walls and that he is not scared of being found.</s>
        <s>However, <name type="person">Juliet</name> still attempts to reason with him by saying that they might even kill him if he is found, to which <name type="person">Romeo</name> only says taht he fears her contempt more than anything the <name type="person">Capulets</name> might do to him and that her kindness would arm him against her family.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Since <name type="person">Juliet</name> is not convinced, <name type="person">Romeo</name> tells her that the darkness outside can hide him well enough but that he wold rather die than live without her love anyway.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <name type="person">Juliet</name> seems to calm down at taht she voices further concerns regarding the meeting.</s>
        <s>She fears that <name type="person">Romeo's</name> promise of love might prove to be false or taht he thinks that she is easily charmed.</s>
        <s>Therefore she asks him to not swear his love lightly and offers to make it harder for him to win her over.</s>
        <s>Her wish is that he does not take her love lightly because of how fast she fell for him.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> wants to swear by the moon but <name type="person">Juliet</name> finds it  too <choice><orig>changeable</orig><reg>changable</reg></choice> and unpredictable, so when <name type="person">Romeo</name> asks her what to swear on instead, she tells him not to swear at all or on himself instead, because he is godlike to her.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
