<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12g19_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given text is a speech delivered by <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> at the <name type="misc">COP26 World Leaders Summit Opening Ceremony</name>, on the <date>1st of November in 2021</date>.</s>
        <s>The topic of the speech is climate change and global warming.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> starts his speech by welcoming the audience, then he compares the audience, including himself, to <name type="person">James Bond</name> who has to switch off a bomb.</s>
        <s>He draws a connection from the comparison to the reality and <choice><orig>specifys</orig><reg>specifies</reg></choice> that the global warming is the metaphorical bomb.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore he describes his experience in <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> <add>in 2010</add> and <name type="geo">Paris</name> <add>in 2015</add> where itw as decided that the point of no return was set at 1.5 degrees.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> underlines the importance of keeping this promise by drawing out the anger and impatience of the world, if this <name type="misc">COP26</name> will not actually change something, concerning the climate change.</s>
        <s>Additionally the appeal that the technology and possibility truly exists is emphasized by <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref>.</s>
        <s>After that he repeats history that the industralized <choice><orig>countrys</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice> created this problem 200 years ago.</s>
        <s>Then he claims that they would have to solve this problem today with funds.</s>
        <s>He emphasizes that those funds will help the rest of the world to use green technology.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>According to <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> this will only happen if the countries, especially the key countries, work together.</s>
        <s>He explains that this will be necessary to make progress and attract private sectors, which <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> thinks are very important.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> repeats that the technology exists to perform a change, but he questions if the leaders have the necessary will to perform this change.</s>
        <s>Further he <choice><orig>critisizes</orig><reg>criticizes</reg></choice> that all plans are made for a far future and says, that he plans for himself to experience this future, in order to emphasize.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>the</orig><reg>The</reg></choice> importance of the change, because it will not only impact the new generations, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">lout</gap> also the leaders themselves.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then he pressures the leaders by emphasizing that it will be their own children and grandchildren who will judge them, if they fail to stop climate change.</s>
        <s>Further he agrees with his prediction of the <choice><orig>posteritys</orig><reg>posterity's</reg></choice> reaction to state that the leaders are not allowed to fail.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally he <choice><orig>appealls</orig><reg>appeals</reg></choice> to the leaders and makes them hope by claiming that they would have the ideas, technology, bankers etc., basically every tool to <choice><orig>succed</orig><reg>succeed</reg></choice> at stopping global warming in the end he underlines once more that they would have the duty to stop climate change and that it will be possible to stop it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
