<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12g20_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this part we are going to analyse the scene regarding the relationship between <name type="person">Macbeth</name> and his wish and the methods she uses to convince him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We start with the relationship in general.</s>
        <s>I think it is clear that <name type="person">Lady Macbeth</name> is the more dominant of the two.</s>
        <s>This can be observed through her having a higher share in her conversation with her husband.</s>
        <s>Sometehing that also indicates this is her openly calling him a coward and stating that she in his place would go through with his plan.</s>
        <s>She also seems to be the more <choice><orig>ambigious</orig><reg>ambitious</reg></choice> of the two, due to her trying to persuade her husband him in the end being persuaded also shows that he is the weaker minded one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now to the methods she uses to <choice><orig>pussvay</orig><reg>pursuade</reg></choice> her husband.</s>
        <s>Therefore we have to look at her statements in the first one <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">cardly</gap> basically calls him a coward and a lazy man therefore she uses rhetorical questions like <quote>Was the hope drunk, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">wuruw</gap> you dressed yourself</quote>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second time speaking she basically further questions his <choice><orig>curage</orig><reg>courage</reg></choice> also using rhetorical questions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last part she explains to him, they won't get caught also using rhetorical questions.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
