<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g38_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, I will analyse <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra's</ref> intention in her blog post on environmental pollution by focusing on communicative strategies and stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>On the one hand, the author indirectly quotes scientists to add validity to her line of arguments <quote>(Many scientists ... pollution)</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 26-27)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Thus, she expresses the importance of a quick reaction for pollution and emphasizes the human responsibility for the current situation.</s>
        <s>On the other hand, she names an example <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 28-32)</ref> of a murderous accident with 2000 victims to highlight its <quote>hazardous effect [...] on the activities of living beings</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 2-3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She wants to express the accumulation of incidents caused by environmental pollution of incidents caused by environmental pollution and to emphasize the cruel effects, for example by directly saying that also women and children <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 31)</ref> had been killed.</s>
        <s>In addition, she uses a variety of words from the same word field, like <quote>toxic</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 30)</ref>, <quote>poisonous</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 31)</ref>, <quote>hazardous</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>, <quote>contaminated</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 25)</ref> to underline the numerous negative effects of pollution.</s>
        <s>Thus, she shows that all pollutants harm us in some way and we have to re-think industry.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, she implements stylistic devices: The enumeration <quote>the automobiles ... insecticides</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 22-23)</ref> is to underline the multiple causes of pollution.</s>
        <s>The author wants to express the many things we need to change and focus on to <quote>restore the ecological balance</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She employs the comparison <quote>like Hiroshima 1945</quote> to point out the predicted fall-out by environmental harming.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then, she enhances the necessity of a quick reaction and <quote>measures to meet</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The metaphorical language <quote>blind alleys of adversity</quote> shall highlight the negative effects of industrial civilization we therefore, need to tackle on.</s>
        <s>She finishes her post by an appeal <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref> to make the reader remember the current situation and need of measures.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Mitra</ref> makes use of several stylistic devices and communicative strategies to drive her message home.</s>
        <s>She <choice><orig>intents</orig><reg>intends</reg></choice> to warn of environmental pollution and convince the reader to react by promoting a change industry and measures.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
