<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a10g41_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="title">Globalised Environmental Pollution - Causes and Effects</ref>, written by <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> and published in her <name type="misc">Blog on Environment</name> on <date>5th February 2014</date>, is about the global issue of environmental pollution and shows the problems and effects it has on our life and future.</s>
        <s>She states that the environmental pollution has a negative effect on our world and our life.</s>
        <s>Besides, she points out that our bisphere is in a balance of many substances to allow (human) life, but with the development of human potentials and the age of technology, the pollution of the environment has increased due to urbanisation and industrialization.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, according to the author that this has an effect on life in a destructive way and from the author's point of view there are so many other causes that many natural <q>things</q> are contaminated today.</s>
        <s>Lastly, <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> is of the opinion of that we need a change in our growing and developing humany to restore the ecological balance, because otherwise it could be too late.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
