<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g38_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution report">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Science has shown that pollution derives mainly from human activity.</s>
        <s>In my opinion, we are as humans responsible for the global problem of environmental pollution, as I will argue in the following.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Most relevantly, human driven urbanization and industrialization cause the most pollution, as not only research has shown but we can daily see: Automobiles and synthetic <choice><orig>detergants</orig><reg>detergents</reg></choice> have a major effect on environmental harming.</s>
        <s>Sure one could argue, that companies produce this equipment and thus are responsible for the hazardous effect, but they take their cues from the consumers, so that we decide in the end.</s>
        <s>Therefore, it is important for everyone to realize the current situation, re-think his or her own effect on the environment and then change the lifestyle in the aspects most harming our planet.</s>
        <s>For example, one could eat less meat and buy organic food and reduce one's own ecological footprint.</s>
        <s>In addition, politics need to pass rules for companies to reduce their toxic effect, and start-ups as well as good ideas to solve the problem should be promoted by the government to quickly develop new technology not being as harmful as the current one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, human beings primarily drive environmental pollution and are therefore responsible for it.</s>
        <s>Thus, we have to stop it by meeting measures and everyone re-thinking his or her lifestyle.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
