<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>c12l10_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote>That in black ink my love may shine bright</quote> This quote comes from <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">65th Sonnet</ref> that discusses the aspect of love, death, time and youth.</s>
        <s>In order to convince his readers, he uses persuasive techniques.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly, he begins his sonnet with a strong imagery of nature <quote>nor stone, nor earth, nor boundless sea</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>, in which the reader feels invited to imagine nature's <choice><orig>phenomens</orig><reg>phenomenons</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He does also draw strong comparisons between beautiful aspects of nature and the morality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> mentions the summer's honey breath <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 5)</ref> the reader Connect a positive atmosphere and imagine his words vividly.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> also known for his dramatic contrast, which I think have a huge impact on the persuasive power of his sonnets.</s>
        <s>As mentioned, he draws a positive imagery of nature and summer.</s>
        <s>But in the next moment, he dramatically contrasts it with other, rather negative visualizations, such as <quote>rocks or gates</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 7, 8)</ref>, which leave a rather oppressive tone to the poem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Having analyzed others sonnets of <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, it's striking that he follows the same techniques to persuade his readers.</s>
        <s>The first quatrain supposed to introduce the reader into the theme of his sonnets, which in this case is the power of nature and beauty, compared to the impact our mortality has on us as human beings.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Secondly, he draws in his second quatrain a vivid imagery of his themes and as a consequence, his words become alive.</s>
        <s>The reader being invited to imagine the given themes and to connect them with own interpretations and experiences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third quatrain is known as the extract, where a turning point or a dramatic point is being added to the sonnet.</s>
        <s>In this case, it's the aspect of time that can't be impacted by any influences.</s>
        <s>Time passes, not even a <quote>strong hand can hold his swift foot back</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The extract, where <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> puts all his conviction to is his couplet.</s>
        <s>In these two lines the reader gets persuaded the most, that's why I have chose the quote <quote>That in black ink my love may still shine bright</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> at the beginning of my text: it conveys his message and at the same ime it leaves a strong, convincing note to the overall sonnet, which is in this case his never ending, unconditional love towards his addressee, the young man named youth.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my point of view, it's a strong and convincing sonnet, especially in the lights of Shakespearean poetry and his time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> lived in England udring the Elizabethan Age, where they were struggling with political, social, religious and economic developements.</s>
        <s>Considering these aspects, his society had to deal with, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnet is a great <choice><orig>potencial</orig><reg>potential</reg></choice> to escape from these conflicts and to identify with someone, who knows how it is to be a human.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> poetry gives your fundamental life lessons, such as experiencing love, facing death or for instance like in <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> changes in beauty and youth throughout time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally, his works are ultimative educational tools, that <choice><orig>guides</orig><reg>guide</reg></choice> you through your life.</s>
        <s>You get to know how humans function and you can easily relate to the position the writer is in, thanks to his timeless themes of love, friendship and in this case altering beauty.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Dealing with <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> poetry implies understanding changes in society, it helps you learning about history, due to the fact that he writes about experiences he made during his life in the Elizabethan age.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This respective summit makes clear, the beauty and youth had a very high value during his time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up, one can say that the sonnet is convincing, especially taking into account that he demonstrates timeless themes, everyone - no matter in which time one lives in - can identify and sympathize with <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, due to the fact that he describes how it feels to be a human in the world, where nothing has an impact on the changement of time, youth and beauty.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Therefore certain to say that <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnet is not of an age, but for all time, he made it possible to persuade everyone in his time, but also in our time of his work.</s>
        <s>Not for nothing he was named <quote>The Bard</quote>, his sonnets and especially <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> make it clear, why he was named a great poet: because of his talent to persuade his readers by discussing themes, everyone can relate to.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
