<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l11_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Taking a closer look, the sonnet reveals many stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>What is very striking is the anaphora that occurs in line five, nine as well as <choice><orig>thirdteen</orig><reg>thirteen</reg></choice> <quote>O, how, O fearful, O, none</quote>.</s>
        <s>Not only does the anaphora structure of the poem and guide the reader throughout the poem, but it also sounds like a helpless scream.</s>
        <s>This allows the reader to feel the emotions this speaker has and it gives it dimension.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line one the reader finds an enumeration <quote>nor stone, nor earth, nor boundless sea</quote>.</s>
        <s>In context with the contents of the summit, the enumeration tries to describe how <choice><orig>powerfull</orig><reg>powerful</reg></choice> the time and its mortality towards the human kind is, by comparing it to natural phenomena that seem indestructible.</s>
        <s>It affects the reader to have respect and maybe even fear.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Typically for a Shakespearean poem he uses many contrasts like <quote>rage</quote> and <quote>beauty</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> to make his poems more interesting for the <choice><orig>audiance</orig><reg>audience</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>In line three and four he <choice><orig>personificates</orig><reg>personifies</reg></choice> beauty by saying that <quote>beauty is no stronger than a flower</quote>.</s>
        <s>By that, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> tries to explain the fragility of love and compares it to a flower.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Line five is a great example for <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> use of imagery <quote>summer's honey breath</quote>.</s>
        <s>Imagery creates a vivid image in the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>reader's</reg></choice> mind and leads them to feel, smell or taste what is written.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The rhetorical question <quote>shall times best jewel from time's chest lie hid?</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> has the effect on the <choice><orig>audiance</orig><reg>audience</reg></choice> to not only read the sonnet but also think about what is mentioned, questioning <choice><orig>themself</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice> and trying to find a solution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The solution is found in the couplet.</s>
        <s>The speaker knows, that nothing can stop <choice><orig>times</orig><reg>time's</reg></choice> curse but the love can be put down in writing <quote>black ink</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>As long as it is written down, love and its beauty will not die but <quote>still shine bright</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The intention of dishonored is to respect time itself and feared, but not to hide from <choice><orig>times</orig><reg>time's</reg></choice> effect that it has in every part of our <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> always used to write about meaningful and important themes which people could relate to.</s>
        <s>That's what him and his sonnets are so unique.</s>
        <s>His sonnets had a structural construct, for example his first sonnets from 1 - 126 were <choice><orig>adressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> to a young man and the others are <choice><orig>adressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> to the <name type="misc">dark lady</name>.</s>
        <s>What is important to mention, also in context with the sonnet, is that his sonnets grew with Shakespeare, and love grows as well.</s>
        <s>It has a beginning and also an end.</s>
        <s>That means that love eventually dies.</s>
        <s>His first sonnets were about the beauty and bright side of love.</s>
        <s>As he wrote more sonnets, the themes and meanings got darker as well as more realistic.</s>
        <s>That is a great way of expressing the experiences in life as an artist.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
