<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l01_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the first quatrain the unknown speaker describes how strict one's love can be.</s>
        <s>There we see a pattern about the strong <choice><orig>wil</orig><reg>will</reg></choice> of nature which he compares with the power of love.</s>
        <s>Even <choice><orig>powerfull</orig><reg>powerful</reg></choice> <choice><orig>phenomenoms</orig><reg>phenomenons</reg></choice> given on our planet such as <quote>brass</quote>, <quote>stone</quote>, <quote>earth</quote> and a <quote>boundless sea</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 1)</ref>, cannot destroy the power of two humans in love.</s>
        <s>But the reality of <quote>mortality</quote> with this <quote>rage</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 3)</ref> will infect their beauty.</s>
        <s>He symbolizes <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> action as a flower, what can be interpreted as lovely, quiet and beautifully graceful.</s>
        <s>In <choice><orig>vers</orig><reg>verse</reg></choice> 1, we also find an <choice><orig>innumaration</orig><reg>enumeration</reg></choice>, while the speaker lists different word fields.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second quatrain <choice><orig>specifys</orig><reg>specifies</reg></choice> on the <quote>summer's honey breath</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 5)</ref>, what stands for sweetness and the <choice><orig>hayday</orig><reg>heyday</reg></choice> of pure love, that has to hold out against times in life that are not easy and passionate, the <quote>wrackful siege of batt'ning days</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 6)</ref> there he points out the contrast between <quote>summer honey's breath</quote> and <quote>batt'ring days</quote> to underline the quick reconstruction of human emotions dependent of radical changes, given situations, accomplishments or tests in life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In verse 7 the speaker uses a <choice><orig>methapor</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> of a <quote>rock</quote> to explain the hardness of the feeling love  which is <quote>impreganable</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 7)</ref> but at the same time <quote>not so stout</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This can be <choice><orig>interpretated</orig><reg>interpreted</reg></choice> as the strong relationship in one's love, which seems to be undestroyable but have no sound basis.</s>
        <s>Therefore the author uses the climax in v. 8 to underline this point of view.</s>
        <s>Because neither <quote>gates of steel</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 8)</ref> that are stronger than rocks, can bear the complicated part of love.</s>
        <s>Inverse nine he concludes the statement: <quote>O fearful meditation, where, alack</quote>, which follows three rhetoric questions <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 10-12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>They ask <choice><orig>themselve</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice> if one should forget the good old times of this love which describes as <quote>time's best jewel</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 10)</ref> in <quote>time's chest</quote>, where he uses the personification of time or <choice><orig>whos</orig><reg>who's</reg></choice> <quote>strong hand</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 11)</ref> can bring back these carefree times.</s>
        <s>This can implify higher powers such as <choice><orig>god</orig><reg>God</reg></choice> and the heavenly graces.</s>
        <s>He also wishes someone had forbid to spoil the beatuy of love, so that the fair youth had a chance to overthink one's trust in the durabiliy of love: <quote>or who his spoil of beauty can forbid</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Here we also find <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> assonance of the letter <quote>o</quote> which can also be found in v. 5 <quote>O how shall (...)</quote>, v. 9 <quote>O fearful meditation!</quote>, v. 11 <quote>Or what strong hand (...)</quote> and v. 13 <quote>O, none (...)</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last couplet, they compare this feeling as a <quote>miracle</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 13)</ref> irrespective of what the speaker mentioned before.</s>
        <s>And makes clear, that <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">h</gap> is love, in <quote>black ink</quote> still <quote>shines bright</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The colour black stands for deep mysterious thoughts and feelings, that can be associated with negativity.</s>
        <s>Here <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> placed a typical moral which are included in most of his sonnets.</s>
        <s>Even if there are negative aspect in love that may be <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">strining</gap>, one's love has to be stronger and harder than them.</s>
        <s>Because <quote>time best jewel</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 10)</ref> will always be there.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
