<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12l16_t3</author>
        <name>letter_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Shakespeare,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you very much for writing back to me, after I told you about my problems.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With this sonnet you animated me to react fast and finally tell <name type="person">Jane</name> about my infinity love to her until it is too late.</s>
        <s>You have opened my eyes.</s>
        <s>Without you I still would not have told her the truth about my feelings for her.</s>
        <s>Especially your aspects of the running time convinced me to confess her my love at the same evening.</s>
        <s>But to be honest, as I wrote you <choice><orig>detailled</orig><reg>detailed</reg></choice>about my problem, I was pretty sure, that you will open my eyes and solve the problem for me.</s>
        <s>I was sure about this, because I have read several sonnets from you.</s>
        <s>In your sonnets and especially in the sonnet, which you sent to me, I pretty like, that you give impulses to take actions, without <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> too precise.</s>
        <s>With this the reader knows exactly what to do but on his way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I know this has not directly to do with my problem, but I wanted to say that I love your plays in the globe theater.</s>
        <s>I met there are many different people and the globe theater is the only place, where it is not important from where I come, after drinking beer with the others.</s>
        <s>Because of this I forget every time, when I am there my problems.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With this letter, I wanted to thank you for your reply and the fantastic plays in the globe theatre.</s>
        <s>You inspire me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best wishes and big thanks, John Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
