<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12l12_t1</author>
        <name>present</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given sonnet <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> was written by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>The sonnet has 14 lines which can be <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> in three verses of four and a couplet at the end.</s>
        <s>The metre of the sonnet is an iambic pentameter, which means that every line has ten syllables and there is always every seonc line emphasized.</s>
        <s>The rhyme of the sonnet can be divided in <name type="misc">ABAB, CDCD, EFEF, GG</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The addressee of the sonnet could be every reader and the intention of <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is to convince the reader from his opinion.</s>
        <s>The mainly theme is that nothing can beat the time.</s>
        <s>In first, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> tells the reader that even things that are supposed to be not mortal loses his power with the time.</s>
        <s>Also beauty <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> resist mortality.</s>
        <s>After that he gets deeper into the theme and asks himself how can summer be forever when there is time.</s>
        <s>He also tells about rocks and steel which both loses his impregnability with the time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Afterwards, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> writes that even jewels, power and beauty cannot resist the effects of the time.</s>
        <s>In the last couplet, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> explains that even if nothing can resist the time, he still loves to write.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
