<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12l08_t3</author>
        <name>letter_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Shakespeare,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I'm glad about being the addressee of your sonnet.</s>
        <s>When reading that very sonnet I feel very honored!</s>
        <s>Especially when you compared <choice><orig>my</orig><reg>me</reg></choice> to <quote>time's best jewel</quote>.</s>
        <s>On top of that, yur imaginary is impressive.</s>
        <s>The way you described a summerday in just three words <quote>summer's honey breath</quote> is fabulous.</s>
        <s>Reading those words is like something nature, tasting sweetness and feeling a windy breeze on my <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> body.</s>
        <s>You really know the human soul well.</s>
        <s>You have the talend of saying what very one feels and thinks, no matter how paradox it sometimes seems <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(cf. v. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>That's what sets you apart from all the other writers.</s>
        <s>Most of them tell stories about their life, their wishes and their thoughts but you, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, you are inspired with the talent to write about fundamental things.</s>
        <s>Your writing changes withing the time and the exes of the reader.</s>
        <s>Your topics are timeles.</s>
        <s>I bet, they will be read today, tomorrow nd in the future!</s>
        <s>And for sure, they will be read by boys and girld, young men and young women and lastly by people of old age.</s>
        <s>Everyone will feel attached by your work and not only me, because you wrote about me, but also others because they can embody themselves into the sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Above that all, there is no doubt that throughout this special sonnet, my horizon widened extremely.</s>
        <s>Reading the lines in which you compare me to <quote>swift feet</quote> that <quote>need a strong hand to be hold back</quote>, explains how you felt about our friendship.</s>
        <s>Thus, the amount of emotions that are captured in those 113 words is so <choice><orig>entiredly</orig><reg>entirely</reg></choice> massive that it helps me to <choice><orig>empathise</orig><reg>emphasize</reg></choice> with others knowing what they are going through.</s>
        <s>Short: Your words have a pastoral effect.</s>
        <s>May your words shine bright!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Your beloved Fair Youth</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
