<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>c12l12_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear William,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have received your letter with the sonnet and I am how responding to you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The message of the sonnet is very deep and I have never thought like this over this quesstion.</s>
        <s>I like your sonnet and I think it shows the effects and the unstoppability of time very pictoral.</s>
        <s>I can agree with you and I think that everything gets destroyed by the time someday.</s>
        <s>But even if the imagination of that is not comfortable, I think that this is a thing of nature.</s>
        <s>Everything that lives dies and nothing is really endless.</s>
        <s>I also like the message of the last two lines that you still love writing, even if time could destroy your texts someday.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion, you are one of the most important and <choice><orig>influental</orig><reg>influential</reg></choice> writer in history, even 500 years later!</s>
        <s>You hae invented over 1700 words and people still use those words.</s>
        <s>People also use popular phrases from your plays and sonnets without even knowing.</s>
        <s><quote>To be or not to be; that is the question</quote> is a famous example for that.</s>
        <s>Also your themes are still relevant today.</s>
        <s>Love, death, time and beauty are themes with no matter of time which makes your plays or sonnets almost timeless.</s>
        <s>These themes will not lose their matter because they are part of the life of a human.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you very much for your letter,</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
