<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12l15_t1</author>
        <name>present</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">present</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following lines, the poem <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> written by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> in the 16th century, is going to be analyzed.</s>
        <s>The sonnet was published during the <choice><orig>elizabethan</orig><reg>Elizabethan</reg></choice> time in <name type="geo">England</name> and deals with the transitoriness of youth, love and beauty because of the immortality of time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet consists of, as well as every sonnet of <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, 14 lines which are divided into three quatrains with four lines each and a last <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">doptain</gap> with two lines.</s>
        <s>In addition to that, the rhyme scheme is also similar to <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> other sonnets.</s>
        <s>The rhyme is <name type="misc">ABAB CDCD EFEF GG</name> and is paired with iambic parameter as the meter.</s>
        <s>The last two lines bring up an explanation for the first 12 lines.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first lines of the sonnet, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> right about the nature's mortality which destroys its beauty and power.</s>
        <s>After that the poet asks how beauty could resist the power of time.</s>
        <s>Later he recognizes that nothing, no matter how strong something might be, could resist the decay of time.</s>
        <s>The last quatrain <choice><orig>consist</orig><reg>consists</reg></choice> of the question, if there is something that can hold back the time from killing the beauty of the earth.</s>
        <s>The last two lines bring up a solution which consists of the poet saying that even if nothing can beat the mortality of time his love will never end because he expressed it through his writings.</s>
        <s>As sad in the introduction, the main topic of <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is the mortality of time which leaves no chance for mortal aspects like love, beauty or youth.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
