<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12l07_t1</author>
        <name>present</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">present</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is written by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>The date of publishment is unknown.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The main theme is that summer is over and winter is arriving slowly.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is written in three quatrains and a final couplet.</s>
        <s>So in total there are fouteen lines.</s>
        <s>All the three quatrains are written with crossrhymes, the final couplet has a pairrhyme.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metre of all fourteen lines is the iambic pentameter, so in one foot, there is always an unstressed and a stressed syllable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first two quatrains are just a long question asked over four verses.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first quatrain, the question is how the beautiful summer, which is capable of growing flowers, shall resist the aggressive winter which is powerful enough to destroy strong rocks.</s>
        <s>The second quatrain is pretty similar to the first one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Here the question is how the nice warm days, that <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> describes as <quote>summer's honey breath</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> shall be able to hold on against the winter with its cold breezes and frosts when even massive gates of steel can get destroyed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last quatrain is different than the first two.</s>
        <s>Here are three questions asked.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first question is, where the summer could hide, until winter will be gone and it can show itself again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The other two questions are, if there is somebody who can defeat the winter or who can hold it back.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The final couplet says, that this would be a <quote>miracle</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>, but even if it would not happen, the love that is connected to summer will live further on in <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnets.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
