<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>c12l03_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello William,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I I'm really happy that you sent me such a great sonnet, thank you for that.</s>
        <s>I hope you are doing well.</s>
        <s>Well, I really like the topic of the sonnet.</s>
        <s>We, as young people living in the <name type="person"><choice><orig>Elizabeathan</orig><reg>Elizabethan</reg></choice></name> time, always have to worry about our outer appearance.</s>
        <s>Beauty and youth is such a big topic in our society and how you look and what you wear is more important <choice><orig>that</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> what you think and what you say.</s>
        <s>So this topic will catch many young people.</s>
        <s>I think even in the future it can still matter because young people will always care a lot about their outer appearance.</s>
        <s>I love the way you have written this poem.</s>
        <s>The high number of rhetorical questions really makes people think about what you have written.</s>
        <s>I really like the nature theme the comparison between flowers and stones is a catching symbol that everyone can easily get.</s>
        <s>It is not hard to understand but it is still written in such a good way.</s>
        <s>The contrast you give brings irony in your writing which brings joy at the same time.</s>
        <s>I enjoy the structure at the end.</s>
        <s>You give some last questions to really make the readers think about the issue and <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> you give a solution.</s>
        <s>Very often your sonnets do not <choice><orig>include</orig><reg>inclued</reg></choice> a solution and this is the reason why they often give a depressing atmosphere.</s>
        <s>But this sonnet spends hope because you come up with a solution and show that mortality is something totally normal everyone has to deal with.</s>
        <s>The fact that you included the hierarchy of our society and your sonnet is very cool.</s>
        <s>Everything gets ranked even though flowers and stones and you included the higher position of the stones.</s>
        <s>I also love that you kind of criticize the society by saying that youth is not just about beauty but it can also be defined by words, so the intelligence of people becomes important and not just their appearance.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>William, you are such a great writer, you really deserve your big role in the history of literature.</s>
        <s>You're right about the most fundamental things in life, like youth, beauty and love and you have the power to focus <choice><orig>intensly</orig><reg>intensely</reg></choice> on one aspect without getting stucked to it.</s>
        <s>Your wordplays bring life to your writings and it is just fasxinating how you already invented so many new words.</s>
        <s>Your topics are just timeless and you connect brutality to irony in an incredible way.</s>
        <s>You can include different topics in one writing and write about murder with humor.</s>
        <s>Nobody can do this as you can.</s>
        <s>I hope you will never stop writing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
