<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>c12l14_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Above all I think that the imagery used by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is very important and good for explaining the topic of <choice><orig>natures</orig><reg>nature's</reg></choice> destruction by human.</s>
        <s>And I do think that <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> persuasive power is also shown in the sonnet.</s>
        <s>The Elizabethan time was a quite reserved time.</s>
        <s>Everyone had his place in society.</s>
        <s>In that perspect critique was not that common and <choice><orig>critizing</orig><reg>criticizing</reg></choice> the whole of humanity neither.</s>
        <s>And given those aspects <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> could be seen as quote revolutionary.</s>
        <s>The protection of nature was not a big deal at all and <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> trying to change that by using his enormous influence is quite impressive.</s>
        <s>But it's not that this is the only sonnet kind of criticizing the Elizabethan society.</s>
        <s>Killing a king or showing an image of love which failed due to actual <choice><orig>boundries</orig><reg>boundaries</reg></choice> in that time, he is revolutionary when it comes to his writings.</s>
        <s>So I think that this <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> fits very well with his others.</s>
        <s>And I think that you can, in the <choice><orig>end</orig><reg>End</reg></choice>, see that he really adores poetry and writing.</s>
        <s>He implies that his writings have the power to <choice><orig>safe</orig><reg>save</reg></choice> and embody the beauty of nature, which is declining day by day.</s>
        <s>So I think that, <choice><orig>allthough</orig><reg>although</reg></choice> many people did not share his thoughts of his time, his sonnet is very persuasive.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the way he writes, compares and personificates and takes <choice><orig>untypical</orig><reg>atypical</reg></choice> seems to write, he delivers a persuasive image of how he thinks about the topic.</s>
        <s>And with that he delivers the message which really fits the circumstances given.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
