<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l14_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In order to understand the message of <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> and to get an overview of the way<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> creates such a strong message within just a brief piece of poetry a further analysis of the formal and poetic devices is necessary to be done.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Like every<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> sonnets the <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> contains 14 verses and is structured into three quatrains with four lines each and a heroic couplet at the end.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> makes especial use of a sonnet's structure by adding an argumentative flow with succesive <choice><orig>thesises</orig><reg>theses</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>antithesises</orig><reg>antitheses</reg></choice> through his poetry.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sonnet 138 starts off with the introduction of the topic and gives a first indicator for the conflict by expressing the perspective of the lyrical I knowing that the beloved one is lying get still believing her that she speaks the truth and expecting the lie to be a consequence of the <quote>the world's false subtitles</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This works as the first thesis the author gives and creates a first vision of the theme upon the reader or listener of the sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second quatrain the argumentative structure continues.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The person of the poem puts the untrue behavior of the beloved one, about the age of the lyrical I, into perspective, by making a concession to him or herself saying <quote>my days are past the best</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The person of the poem returns the lie by not responding to it truthfully but crediting the beloved one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This can be seen as an additional thesis or the ongoing argument of the first quatrain, but it further supports the argumentative structure.</s>
        <s>The third quatrain then is directed by the Volta.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Two rhetorical questions refer to the <choice><orig>thesises</orig><reg>theses</reg></choice> of the first and second quatrain and introduce the antithesis.</s>
        <s>The rhetorical questions extend the message of the poem as they examine the before said and are followed by the <choice><orig>explaination</orig><reg>explanation</reg></choice> of the lyrical I, who relativates the behavior of him or herself and the beloved one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The lines 11 and 12 go together with the heroic couplet and form the synthesis of the sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The lyrical I concludes that they can lie together and therefore also create truth together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But the main message of the poem comes along with the antithesis of the third quatrain, stating trust as love's most important habit and pointing out that a loving relationship alters in a different way than in biological matter.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With a better understanding of the structure<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses not arbitrary but to convey his message onto the listener and reader, it is also of great importance to learn how the poetic devices he includes go along with it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From line 1 the author <choice><orig>personificates</orig><reg>personifies</reg></choice> love, giving it a female character and using it as a term for the beloved one the poem is about.</s>
        <s>This convinces the reader or listener that the conflict of the poem is of great importance not only to a single person but love and relationships in general.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second line portrays an antithesis within itself <quote>I do believe her, though I know she lies</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> representing the conflict of a lover.</s>
        <s>For the reader this line is striking to get an idea of what the sonnet is about and what it is going to tell.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By the personification <quote>the world's false subtleties</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> the author gives the world a humane attribute to blame it for the beloved <choice><orig>ones</orig><reg>one's</reg></choice> acting.</s>
        <s>Therefore the reader or listener follows his ideal of not blaming the other person but the outward circumstances of the world influencing their behavior.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>my days are past the best</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref> lets the lyrical I find a fluttering way of concession in order to understand the intention that lead the beloved one to speaking the untrue.</s>
        <s>The reader or listener can understand and tolerate the process of finding reason.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author uses another personification <quote>her false speaking tongue</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> yet again to not blame the aspect of lying on the beloved one but directing the attention on another circumstance.</s>
        <s>One of the most important poetic devices then follows in the Volta, that consists of two rhetorical questions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>But wherefore says she not she is unjust?</quote><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> refers to the starting thesis and questions the background of the beloved one, which <quote>And wherefore say not I that I am old?</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> refers to the thesis of the second quatrain and <choice><orig>let's</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> the person of the poem question itself.</s>
        <s>This sustainably convinces the reader that the conflict of the sonnet is conveyable onto both sides of the relationship and also prepares the conclusion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Unlike other Shakespearean sonnets the conclusion of <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> is not just found in the heroic couplet at the end but extends over the last quatrain as well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The anaphora of the word <quote>And</quote> at the beginning of lines 10, 12 and 14 gives evidence that the lyrical I builds up his or her synthesis over several verses and through <choice><orig>enjambements</orig><reg>enjambments</reg></choice> creates an ongoing conclusion.</s>
        <s>In the end one can say that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> not only manages to illustrate the topic of truthfulness in loving relationships throughout <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> but also makes use of the argumentative structure of a sonnet and links it with poetic devices in order to convey his subsequent messages onto the reader or listener.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
