<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>a12l10_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="NA" genre_family="NA">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Ladies and Gentlemen,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am a student at a grammar school in <name type="geo">Cologne</name>, <name type="geo">Germany</name>, and I am writing to you today, because I am very much in disbelief of your choice on taking<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> off the school curriculum.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Dealing with<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> in school has many advantages.</s>
        <s>The students get an even wider inside into modern drama and poetry by having the background on Shakespeare.</s>
        <s>He inspired a lot of modern artists with his work.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now you might say that the old <choice><orig>elizabethan</orig><reg>Elizabethan</reg></choice> language<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> uses, can cause confusion among the students, but I am in belief that after examining three to four sonnets, the students will understand and benefit from those.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition the language of the poet uses, is in many ways beneficial for an <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> class.</s>
        <s>For example will learn the students not only to analyze the massive amount of devices that are used in every sonnet but also learn some thing for their own lives.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> delivered topics which are still relevant in <date>2021</date>, being loved or topics that evolve around <choice><orig>human kind</orig><reg>humankind</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Many students do also enjoy presenting the work of<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> as it is meant to present.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the basis of the given aspects I would kindly ask to reconsider your choice.</s>
        <s>I am certain if there would be a way to determine also the opinion of others, a school wide survey would be a good democratic way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
