<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g05_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical_exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>subject: <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> should not be banned</s>
        <date>08.12.2021</date>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear <name type="person">Mr. Rump</name>,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am and I live in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>I know that you do not know me, but you are the headmaster of my American friend <name type="person">Gabriella</name>.</s>
        <s>As you already saw in the subject, I am writing to you, because I think that the novel <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> should not be banned from any shcool library worldwide.</s>
        <s>I read the book and we talked about it in school so I can have an opinion on that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> understand why I should be banned.</s>
        <s>Because it contains offensive language?</s>
        <s>But then why is it fine to read <name type="misc">To kill a Mockingbird</name>, which contains the N-word?</s>
        <s>It is written from a black woman and the protagonist is also a 16 year old black girl.</s>
        <s>What should be offensive?</s>
        <s>And it is normal that teenagers use vulgar language.</s>
        <s>They use it in their freetime and when speaking to their friends.</s>
        <s>Why should it be a problem in a book?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To say that the book encourages teenagers to use drugs is in my opinion wrong.</s>
        <s>I think especially in the end the novel underlines that drug dealing and being a gang member puts you in danger.</s>
        <s>A good example is <name type="person">DeVante</name> who wants to stop dealing drugs and who wants to leave the gang and achieves his goals with the help of <name type="person">Maverick</name>, who did the same.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also the argument that it shows <choice><orig>negativ</orig><reg>negative</reg></choice> light on the police is in my opinion weak.</s>
        <s>On the one hand the novel just shows the reality of police violence in the USA.</s>
        <s>On the other hand in the novel it is also a cop, who does a great job.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Uncle Carlos</name> is also a cop, but does not shoot black people.</s>
        <s>He is a cop because he wants to protect his family.</s>
        <s>That is why not all cops are <choice><orig>showed</orig><reg>shown</reg></choice> in negative light.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Racial injustice is a very important topic worldwide.</s>
        <s>This book helps to enlighten students and make them more aware of their behaviour.</s>
        <s>When we ban it everywhere <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> I do not know how we should learn about discrimination.</s>
        <s>When we do not learn about it the big difference between black and white whill not get smaller but bigger.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I was able to convince you on my opinion and that you think about my questions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Kind regards, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
