<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11g08_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>To: <name type="person">Lee</name> From: <name type="person">Jane</name></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Leo,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you are doing well during this difficult time.</s>
        <s>I learned a lot about racism, especially in the <name type="geo">US</name> and found this <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> newspaper article from the <name type="misc">Zeit Online</name> which is about racism in the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
        <s>The newspaper article is written in <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> so I'm going to sum it up for <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">genn</gap>.</s>
        <s>The newspaper article <ref target="a11gk1_2" type="title"> Schwarze in der USA: Der Rassismus ist messbar"</ref> is about differences between white and black people in the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
        <s>At first the author writes about <name type="person">Michael Brown</name>, a teenager who was shot by a police officer.</s>
        <s>The author says that this event shows that there is still segregation between balck and white people.</s>
        <s>He says that police officers stop <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> search vehicles of black persons way more often than they would stop white people.</s>
        <s>In addition to that people of color have worse chances to <choice><orig>gratuade</orig><reg>graduate</reg></choice> than white people, even 50 years after the <name type="misc">Civil Rights Act</name> formally ended discrimination.</s>
        <s>Furthermore around one fourth of black people live in poverty, way more than white people with about <choice><orig>one-tenth</orig><reg>one tenth</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Equally important it is much harder to find a job for a black person than it is for a white person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all it is shocking <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">thiecl</gap> people will get discriminated because of their race, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">espessily</gap> in the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope that I could give you an understanding about how much we know about racism in the <name type="geo">US</name> even in <name type="geo">Germany</name> and I hope to hear from you soon.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Bye, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
