<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11g03_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>how are you doing in <name type="geo">Texas</name>.</s>
        <s>Is the weather still that hot as it was, when I <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">insited</gap> you the last time?</s>
        <s>And what about <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">Dexoson</gap> and <name type="person">Nina</name>, are they good?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I heard <name type="misc">THUG</name> or <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> was banned in a school district in <name type="geo">Texas</name>.</s>
        <s>I personally think that this shouldn't be the case.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example I read this novel this year in my English class and of course the plot is pretty hard, the language could be offensive, drugs could be shown more critical, the sexual references could be left out and the police wasn't as good as it should be, but in my eyes - this is life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If you aren't ready for the truth you have lost anyway.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think especially how the book is written made it unique and the topic with which it <choice><orig>dealed</orig><reg>dealt</reg></choice> is more important than ever.</s>
        <s>It is a very well-discussed topic today and through social media and the news the <name type="misc">Black Lives Matter</name> movement plays a bigger role than it ever did.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You do live in <name type="geo">America</name>, in the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
        <s>Racism and discrimination is a part of your every day life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><add>Maybe not of yours, but people with a black skin have to face such problems every day</add>.</s>
        <s>If one takes some time and searches for some statistics, that people, because of their skin color, aren't treated and seem equal.</s>
        <s>It is a problem, which is still a part of our <choice><orig>every-day</orig><reg>everyday</reg></choice> life and I think that should be terrifying and disturbing, not the language of the novel.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am even of the opinion that we should be make this novel available for students worldwide, not only students in the <name type="geo">USA</name>, because this racism and discrimination are international.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope that you will read the novel once again - or just read the novel for the first time - then you will be able to gain an own opinion and maybe we even share the same opinion, because I think the situation, especially the poor neighborhood <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">ftoos</gap>, which is controlled through a gang, is shown so good, that it could not be better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope to hear from you seen and greetings,</s>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
