<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Throughout the whole novel conflict of identity is thematized.</s>
        <s>In this excerpt it is <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">mimaday</gap> shown through narrative techniques and perspectives, which are for example first person narrator, flashback and tensed atmosphere.</s>
        <s>
          <add>The effect of them will be analysed in the following.</add>
        </s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Mainly the whole novel is written in a first person narrator perspective, the reader has a limited point of view.</s>
        <s>In this perspective the author makes use of the personal pronoun <quote>I</quote>, which underlines the point of view.</s>
        <s>As a combination of this points the reader is very attached <add>emotionally connected / attached</add> to the plot and to the character, which is in this case <name type="person">Starr</name> the protagonist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Typically for the first person anrrator as the protagonist is also that the readers get to know about thoughts, feelings and motivations of the narrator, through which he get first-hand information and impressions towards the plot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One also has to keep in mind that through the limited point of view important information could get left out <add>e.g. motivations, feelings, etc. of other characters</add>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In terms of narrative techniques one has to mention that the author made use of many direct speeches.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Direct speeches like <quote>a hairbrush is not a gun</quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>, <quote><s>'<name type="person">Starr</name>', she says, making her way over.</s><s>'What are you doing out here'</s></quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 26)</ref> bring the plot closer to the reader, because it creates a feeling, as <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">onesoflt</gap> would be in this scene.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The interior monologue in line 5 to line 7, which is a part <choice><orig>stream-of-consciousness</orig><reg>stream of consciousness</reg></choice>, which is a part of the means of presentation <add>term for a specific style of narration</add>, allows the reader to know thoughts of <name type="person">Starr</name>, which is supportive to understand <name type="person">Starr</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One can find another thought in line 48, in which <name type="person">Starr</name> convinces and forces herself to speak in front of the crowd, her friends and the police.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This scene is also supportive for the understanding of <name type="person">Starr</name>, because there, in this scene, one could see that she puts her fears under the public welfare, even though she has to overcome herself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another narrative technique is the flashback between line 19 and line 22.</s>
        <s>Here the author switches between past and presence, as one hsould in a flashback <add>normally used to bring <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> event from the past closer to the reader</add>, to underline how deep the effect of <name type="person">Khalil's</name> murder for <name type="person">Starr</name> is - she has to think about it again and again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <add>
          <s>So one could say that through this scene, one can understand <name type="person">Starr</name> more - and the effect <name type="person">Khalil's</name> murder has.</s>
        </add>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If one refers to mode of presentation panoramic <add>many events described in a short way</add> and scenic <add>many details, short amount of time</add>, one has to classify this one as a scenic description.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Especially the first three lines are pretty much detailed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 29 the author also makes use of another technique - the <choice><orig>fore-shadowing</orig><reg>foreshadowing</reg></choice>, in which events, which take a place in the future, are teased.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Here <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> brings up the point of <name type="person">Starr's</name> biggest voice and thought the fact that <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> herself yelled through the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">hellhorn</gap> one automatically is teased and thrilled if <name type="person">Starr</name> will do this too.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">Tensel</gap> is also the whole atmosphere in this excerpt, which is probably created through many direct speeches and the situation, in which protestors are facing cops.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, one could say that the state of mind <name type="person">Starr</name> is presented through many <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> narrative techniques and the whole way of narration.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The biggest impact on this <choice><orig>discription</orig><reg>description</reg></choice> is probably created through the interior monologue and the flashbacks.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
