<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11g09_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have heard that the book <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> which we have finished reading in our English class recently was banned from school libraries in your school district some time ago.</s>
        <s>This is a real shame in my opinion because the book is trying to spread a very important and relevant message.</s>
        <s>It's pointing out issues that we currently have with racism all over the world and especially in the <name type="geo">US</name> and that people need to stand up for equality and their freedom.</s>
        <s>I can understand that the offensive language, the sexual references, the depicted drug use and the vulgar content are not <choice><orig>apropriated</orig><reg>appropriate</reg></choice> for especially younger people, so I would suggest you to rather make this a 16+ book rather than banning it all together.</s>
        <s>The negative depiction of the police is not a good reason to ban this book in my opinion because the things adressed in this book are realities and things we cannot close our eyes on by banning a piece of literature, especially because we really need to adress these <choice><orig>isues</orig><reg>issues</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>chang</orig><reg>change</reg></choice> something about that.</s>
        <s>I hope I was able ot change your mind of the ban and see the book from a different perspective.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
