<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g01_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical_exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am a friend of one of your students and I am writing to you because I heard that your school banned the novel <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> from school libraries.</s>
        <s>In <name type="geo">Germany</name>, where I live, we read the novel in our English class and I think that it is very important that people read books with topics like <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref>.</s>
        <s>Especially in countries or states like <name type="geo">Texas</name> where racism is <choice><orig>stil</orig><reg>still</reg></choice> a huge problem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The book talks about very important topics like racism but also about speaking up for yourself, your family and minorities in general.</s>
        <s>These are things that young people should learn about.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The novel <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> is a really good book to teach people about racism because it is from the perspective of a black girl.</s>
        <s>It shows the events from <choice><orig>first hand</orig><reg>first-hand</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Thats</orig><reg>That's</reg></choice> a perspective that most of the white teenagers do not get to <choice><orig>now</orig><reg>know</reg></choice> vey often.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Despite the main character being a black girl she is also very relatable because she is a teenager in high school just like your students.</s>
        <s>My friend told me that you banned the book because of vulgar and offensive language, sexual references and depicted drug use.</s>
        <s>I think that it is really important to talk about topics like these because some of your students will probably have to deal with them one day.</s>
        <s>And by reading the novel <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> that shows druge use as something bad they get to know why they should never do something like that.</s>
        <s>The novel sets an example for your students.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I agree that the novel showed some police officers in a negative light but the book also shows the reader that there are many officers that also want justice just like <name type="person">Starr</name> and her family.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All these topics are topics that are not only relevant in the <name type="geo">USA</name> but also worldwide.</s>
        <s>That is why I think that the novel should be read by students worldwide.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope that I could make you think with my letter and that you <choice><orig>concider</orig><reg>consider</reg></choice> to add <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> to your school library or even as an obligatory read in your school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
