<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b12l14_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David's</ref> speech consisted of suitable references and an interesting way of presenting it, which all added to the impact the speech might has made on the audience attending as well as a broader public audience.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While I'm not sure if the illustration with stunning, cinematic pictures in the background was necessary or a bit over the top, I am certain that it has left an impact on a visual level on especially the broader public watching.</s>
        <s>By choosing to stick with easy references, such as the <quote>new industrial revolution</quote> and leaving out statistics completely, the speech is easily understandable and suitable for audience without the scientific knowledge about climate change.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough's</ref> non-political approach and humane plead for action, leaves an impact on all audiences.</s>
        <s>Considering his position I also believe it to be very appropriate, because it makes it clear that it's on the politicians to act.</s>
        <s>The fact that he urges them to act, without attacking them or sharply criticizing them, makes it easier for him to reach them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Looking back at <date>2016</date>, <name type="person">Leonardo DiCaprio's</name> speech functions in a similar way it was generally well received, so I do not think that <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David</ref> can go any wrong with his approach.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
