<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l24_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given extract from Act II scene 2 from <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>'s <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> <name type="person">Romeo</name> surprises <name type="person">Juliet</name> at her place in the middle of the night.</s>
        <s>It is the famous balcony scene where they confess their love for each other.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless, <name type="person">Juliet</name> is concerned about <name type="person">Romeo</name> showing up.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <name type="person">Romeo</name> comeso ut of hiding <name type="person">Juliet</name> immediately recognizes his voice but is concerned about the danger that any of the <name type="person">Capulet</name> kinsmen might find and kill him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> on the other hand is not scared of them and insists that his love is so strong that no one can stop him.</s>
        <s>If only she likes him too, her love will protect him.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, he takes her worries and explains that the darkness of the night covers him.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless, he states that he wants the kinsmen to find and kill him if <name type="person">Juliet</name> does not love him back.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Further in the scene, <name type="person">Juliet</name> is concerned about <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> or not <name type="person">Romeo</name> truly loves her or if their love is evolving <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> quickly.</s>
        <s>Questioning his love and her behavior she wants <name type="person">Romeo</name> to give her his honest word and promise that his love is truthful.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Overall, <name type="person">Juliet</name> is concerned about <name type="person">Romeo's</name> life that is in danger whereas he tries to take her fear away and states that the danger of her not loving him back is greater than his death.</s>
        <s>Therefore, both want the validation of the other concerning their love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
