<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l15_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the play <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 3</ref> by <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="author">Ayad Akhtar</ref> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir Kapoor</ref> (<add><name type="misc">Abdullah</name></add>) is the protagonist.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is a lawyer, about 40 years old and lives in an <choice><orig>appartement</orig><reg>apartment</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">New York</name> together with his wife <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In Scene 3 <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is presented as a really emotional and rude person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the beginning of the scene he's full of anger and also a bit desperate because of <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> and not getting promoted in his job.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His language and way of expressing himself is always rude and not nice <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 71)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He often uses the word <quote>fucking</quote> in his sentences <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 71, 72)</ref> which shows that he's not really kind and nice towards other people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of not getting promoted in his job that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> gets, he acts really emotional and yells most of the time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He furthermore explodes and can't believe that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> got promoted even though <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is twice as long as <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> in the company.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He nearly gets physical when <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and him get in a heated conversation which ends up <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> spitting in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face which shows his disgusting behaviour and racist side about jews probably because of experiences as a little kid when his mom spits in his face because he had a <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> girlfriend which let him spit in his girlfriend's face just because she was <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> acts really emotional and doesn't think before doing something which really affects his interactions in the play like when he hit <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 74)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After realizing what he has done he instantly regrets it and is in shock because of himself which shows he acts <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> fast before thinking of the consequences of his acting.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is the perfect example of how hard it is to live undercover and what a massive impact Islamophobia and hiding his real identity can have especially after <name type="misc">9/11</name> as a Muslim.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
