<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l12_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is an around thirty year old man and lives in <name type="geo">Manhattan</name> with his wife <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
        <s>He is from <name type="geo">Pakistan</name> and his ethnicity has a <choice><orig>muslimic</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice> background.</s>
        <s>He grew up with strict <choice><orig>muslimic</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice> parents, but now doesn't <choice><orig>believes</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> in this religion anymore and <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to distance himself from his heritage.</s>
        <s>Because he wants to be accepted in American society without being discriminated he changed his name and pretends to be from <name type="geo">India</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this scene <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is described as aggressive and not thinking much about his actions and what he does.</s>
        <s>He handles the situation by offending others and doesn't try to talk about things that make him mad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This behaviour especially gets clear when he beats his wife but also already before, when he spits into <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face.</s>
        <s>He does all that because he feels treated unfair and discriminated but that's of course not an excuse for beating someone.</s>
        <s>He thinks that he worked harder for the job that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> got and gives her the fault for ruining his career (<quote>First you steal my job and now you try to destroy my marriage?</quote>, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">l. 18-19</ref>).</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref><choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> everything to be successful in job, be accepted by everybody and just have a good life with his wife.</s>
        <s>But now he understands that this is not that easy even if he changed his name.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless he feels discriminated and just doesn't get what he wants and works hard for like for the job.</s>
        <s>That makes him mad and depressed, so he <choice><orig>looses</orig><reg>loses</reg></choice> the control about his feelings and lets out his rage in this aggressive way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also the fact that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> has an affair with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> of course makes him mad.</s>
        <s>He trusted her and this makes him maybe also wonder if he's not enough for his wife and creates feelings of inferior for himself, even if he doesn't <choice><orig>shows</orig><reg>show</reg></choice> that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all he acts very aggressive, not really caring about others and not aware of his actions.</s>
        <s>He rather gets <choice><orig>controled</orig><reg>controlled</reg></choice> by his feelings than thinking <choice><orig>alot</orig><reg>a lot</reg></choice> about things that happen.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But in some way his behaviour is explainable because he <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> hard to fit in society and do things correctly but even if he does everything for this like changing his name, he gets disappointed by others but also by himself.</s>
        <s>He doesn't find a way to be <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> accepted and reach his goals in life what makes him mad in this situation.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
