<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l21_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this given extract of <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 3</ref> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, the main protagonist, plays a main and influential role in the scene.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir <choice><orig>Khapoor</orig><reg>Kapoor</reg></choice></ref> is a <choice><orig>pakistani</orig><reg>Pakistani</reg></choice> man who has been angried to <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> for a long time, and has been having some trouble with his religious and foreign background.</s>
        <s>These factors play a major role in the extract and have a lot of connections with his character.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The conflict situation where <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> has been brought into revealed a strong anger that build itself up in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 71, ll. 26-31)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His anger is partially seen in his <choice><orig>languag</orig><reg>language</reg></choice> and tone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is an unconscious and insecure character and is oftenly not sure how to respond to different situations.</s>
        <s>His unconsciousness and insecurity is seen when he blames the rather not guilty character <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> and connects his work and foreign background with his confrontation <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, ll. 22-28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His religious and foreign background connected with his work life had been bothering <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> since his early days and resulted in him having an inner conflict.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is also presented as a stressed and violent character who cannot handle himself in this state of emotion <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 17 <quote>vicious</quote>, p. 71, l. 22 <quote>inflamed</quote>)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His struggle of handling negative emotions is also seen in his actions <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 40)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Him spitting in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Issacs</orig><reg>Isaac's</reg></choice></ref> face reveals the bad connection between his emotions and his background <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> overcomes him in <choice><orig>unpleasent</orig><reg>unpleasant</reg></choice> situations.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>A</orig><reg>An</reg></choice> anger factor for this is his childhood and his more or less <q>trauma</q> he experienced where his mother spat in his face when bringing <choice><orig>unpleasent</orig><reg>unpleasant</reg></choice> news.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The beating of his wife proves that he shows his vulnerability rather through violence than through words <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 26, p. 74, l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref><choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> find words and him being fueled by anger <choice><orig>deliveres</orig><reg>delivers</reg></choice> actions that he rather regrets <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 74, l. 15)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The detailed analysis shows that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir <choice><orig>Khapoor</orig><reg>Kapoor</reg></choice></ref> is emotionally unstable and in <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> major inner conflict which bothers him daily.</s>
        <s>He hasn't found his identity and place in his life and is escaping from facing his truth.</s>
        <s>It shows that he <choice><orig>continiously</orig><reg>continuously</reg></choice> lies to himself which results in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> having a big gap in his life and that is why regretful actions follow.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
