<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l22_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>To analyze <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> behaviour and attitudes in this scene one must first take a closer look at the general information we have on him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir Kapoor</ref> is the main character of <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 3</ref>.</s>
        <s>He is of South Asian origin and grew up in a traditional <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice> family.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is revealed in the play that his family was deeply <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>antisemitic</reg></choice> as he wasn't allowed to see his crush who was <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> when he was 10.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> could not identify himself with the Islam he turned his back in Islam and now talks derogatory about it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of his job as a lawyer at the Jewish law firm <name type="misc">Bernstein, Leibowitz (...)</name> he changed his name so that he would not sound <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is very invested in his work and determined to become a partner of the law firm he is working for.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That feeling of always being an outsider and having to achieve everything on his own combined with the feeling of superiority reflects in his behaviour.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His enormous rage when <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> told him that she would be made partner at the law firm is displayed in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">l. 23f. p. 71</ref>: <quote><qs>You wait a week to tell me this?</qs><qs>And the second I say something you don't even like hearing you walk away from me in the mid fucking sentence.</qs><qs>Who are you?</qs></quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> character is expressed excellently through that sequence.</s>
        <s>It becomes evident by the swear words that he fells superior to <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another characteristic aspect is that he will become aggressive in order to not show his true feelings which are disappointment and sadness over not getting the job.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The writer also conveys the impression that the relationship between <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is characterised by constant competition that intensified over the course of the past months and that is now finally exploding.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is portrayed as a very ambitious character.</s>
        <s>An example for that is his confidence.</s>
        <s>On one hand he seems <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> confident in himself which becomes evident as it is impossible for him to imagine an affair between <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> <quote>what</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 29 p. 71)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through his unwillingness to believe that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> might have been unfaithful her significance to him is expressed.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> would rather accuse <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> of making the accusation up: <quote>(...) now you try to destroy my marriage</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 18 p. 72)</ref>, than believing <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> could have cheated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That his wife could have cheated would have been too much for his already damaged ego.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Therefore he is in denial and centers all his rage/hurt on <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> who he describes as: <quote>You're fucking evil.</quote></s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By stating: <quote>First you try to steal my job (...) After everything that I have done for you?</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 18 p. 72)</ref>, it is made clear that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> does not think <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> deserves the job and that he feels let down by her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The feeling of being unjustly treated and being more deserving of the job than <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is further exploited when <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> describes: <quote><qs>You have no idea how much of myself I've poured into the place?</qs><qs> (...) I still leave the office after you do</qs></quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 22-25)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He contrasts his effort with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory's</ref> and according to him, his is obviously more.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> character is ieniant to use vulgar language and does not shred away from insults such as <quote>You're the asshole</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 33 p. 72)</ref>, <quote>You think you are the nigger</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 29)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These outbursts support him being an aggressive character.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another fact that adds to taht impression are the director's note on <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> such as <quote>vicious</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> and <quote>exploding</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When he spits in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face their relationship is symbolized.</s>
        <s>They both despise each other and when <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> says: <quote>There's a reason they call you people animals</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 1 p. 73)</ref> it becomes clear that their relationship is beyond repair.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> telling <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> <quote>Get out</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 3 p. 73)</ref> shows how he is used to giving orders and other people obeying these orders.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is perceived as being <quote>duplicitous</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> which <quote><qs>makes you such a good agitator.</qs><qs>But it's impossible to trust you</qs></quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5-10 p. 73)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By not answering that accusation the effect is conveyed that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> denial has stopped and that he can see some truth in that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> consules <quote>I'm gonne get you that coffee</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 20)</ref> the <choice><orig>fragement</orig><reg>fragment</reg></choice> of their relationship is revealed.</s>
        <s>She cares for him and he is <choice><orig>dependend</orig><reg>dependent</reg></choice> on her admiration.</s>
        <s>That could be a reason that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> is so unhappy in the relationship.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is <quote>by himself</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 22 p. 73)</ref> the audience is shown how <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> sees himself.</s>
        <s>All alone.</s>
        <s>No family he can depend on because they are all <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice>, no work he can depend on because <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> was made partner, and slowly he comes to the realisation that she also doesn't have a wife to depend on, because she is having an affair.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> comes back he confronts her <quote>Are you sleeping with him?</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 27 p. 73)</ref>, deeply frightened of the answer, frightened that the last <choice><orig>fragement</orig><reg>fragment</reg></choice> of what is holding up his character is about to vanish.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By calling her <quote>Em</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 25)</ref> it is shown that he cares for her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> finally admits to having slept with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> all <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> frustrations are <foreign xml:lang="de">ausgeladen</foreign> on her.</s>
        <s><quote><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> hits <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> in the face</quote><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> and <quote>uncontrolled violance as brutal as it needs to be in order to convey the discharge of a lifetime of discretly building resentment</quote> is put on <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion one could say that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is a character with many conflicts within himself.</s>
        <s>He is torn between the man he wants to be and the man he is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The frustrations he endured through his life, he carries with him every day which results into him being very aggressive.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
