<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g44_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>This sequence shows that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is a confident and popular guy who knows how to <choice><orig>cop</orig><reg>cope</reg></choice> with relationship problems.</s>
        <s>To prove this statement the scene to be analyzed can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into three parts.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>Analyzes</orig><reg>analysis</reg></choice> is making use of it.</s>
        <s>The introduction part starts with <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looking at <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> while he is presented in a medium shot to show how he checks with his hands other students and laughs.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is coming up to her.</s>
        <s>While he is going through the floor the camera drives backwards to make his walk look even more realistic.</s>
        <s>His walk is show in slow motion to make it look even more dramatic.</s>
        <s>In the background of the introduction part is slow and a bit sad music to emphasize what <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is feeling in this moment while looking at <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the close-up to her face you can see her emotions, to show the viewer that she is feeling sad.</s>
        <s>The music and her facial expressions are used in this scene because the producer wanted the viewer to know that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> doesn't like being mad at <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and that she was maybe having an inner sadness because she can't open herself to him.</s>
        <s>Another important detail to their relationship are the shoes that are shown the viewer in an extreme close-up.</s>
        <s>The extreme close-up is used because <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is talking in the background about the <name type="misc">Jordans</name> <add>(shoes)</add> that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is wearing, and it shows the viewer why she is talking about them.</s>
        <s>In their relationships his shoes mean a lot to <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> because <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> one of their things they both like.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is wearing the shoes to show <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> even though they are in an argument he still cares about their relationship.</s>
        <s>The main part begins when the viewer sees <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> in a point of view shot of <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> seeing <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> for the first time.</s>
        <s>The sad music <choice><orig>stopps</orig><reg>stops</reg></choice> to show that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is happy when <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is around.</s>
        <s>Even though she tries to act angry which can be seen by another close-up of her face, she is smiling when she hears his beats after he put on his headphones to her head.</s>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> likes <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> <choice><orig>Hobby</orig><reg>hobby</reg></choice> and wants to support him by what he does.</s>
        <s>But when she puts the headphones down she confronts <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> by what he did by looking deep in hiy eyes, that shows the over-the-shoulder shot which is used in this sequence.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> complains about him not meeting her family even though they are dating <choice><orig>sice</orig><reg>since</reg></choice> six <choice><orig>month</orig><reg>months</reg></choice> he does the same by looking deep in her eyes.</s>
        <s>These looks which are shown in close-up to their faces are presented in this field size to get the viewer to see their emotions and that both of them really mean what they say.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This scene also shows that both <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> can behave like grown-up and solve their argument in an adult and the ending part of this sequence begins.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is dancing he is presented in a full shot to show his action.</s>
        <s>That he can dance in the school floor <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of many students shows his confidence and popularity at <name type="misc">Williamson Prep</name> because everyone <choice><orig>sheers</orig><reg>cheers</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>clapps</orig><reg>claps</reg></choice> for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> starts laughing at <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> when he starts dancing.</s>
        <s>The viewer can see her facial expressions because the camera moves from <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> medium shot to an close-up one so the viewer can focus on her.</s>
        <s>That <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> thinks it's funny what <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> does, makes clear that she likes the beat that he made and that she loves his open and self-confident being.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all is <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> a confident and popular teenage boy at his school who can act funny and grown-up in <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> situations.</s>
        <s>Also you can say that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> cares about his relationship to <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> because he wants to get to know <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> parents.</s>
        <s>He loves <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and likes to being her to laugh.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
