<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g15_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As stated in the summary the speech <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="title">Remarks of president Barack Obama at student roundtable</ref> is about building connections between different countries and cultures through student exchanges.</s>
        <s>In the following, I will analyse which structure, stylistic devices and choice of words <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack</ref> uses, to convince the listeners on cross-cultural experiences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The text is <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into four main paragraphs.</s>
        <s>In the first paragraph <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1-3)</ref>, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> tells, why he came to <name type="geo">Turkey</name>.</s>
        <s>It is the shortest paragraph and it can be seen as an introduction.</s>
        <s>Through this, the author creates tension and enlightens his audience with the <add>(roughly)</add> theme of his following speech.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second paragraph <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1-12)</ref> deals with the passionate young civils of the <name type="geo">USA</name>, of which the president seems to be very proud.</s>
        <s>That's why he wants to support them.</s>
        <s>After that, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> lists a few advantages of student exchanges.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Talking about his nation, is a great lead to supporting them and that is a great lead to the advantages of student exchanges.</s>
        <s>His line of argumentation seems to be reliable and fluent.</s>
        <s>That makes his points even more convincing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The theme of the fourth paragraph <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13-17)</ref> is to <quote>break down walls</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Here, the author talks a lot about togetherness and equality.</s>
        <s>That forms a sense of togetherness not only between those two countries, but in the room he speaks in and between the people he speaks to.</s>
        <s>In line 17 <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack</ref> uses the sentence <quote>And that's where the progress begins</quote>.</s>
        <s>This phrase creates tension and is a great lead to the next paragraph!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last paragraph <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 20-23)</ref> is an appeal to the audience to be a part of global connections.</s>
        <s>Because it is the last paragraph, his request stays in mind and gets underlined.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> doesn't use any scientific or <choice><orig>buissness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice> English.</s>
        <s>He tries to stay understandable by using easy words but tries to be convincing at the same time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He doesn't use much colloquial <choice><orig>eather</orig><reg>either</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He stays professional.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through the word <quote>deeply</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> underlines his interest to partner with <name type="geo">Turkey</name>.</s>
        <s>Moreover, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack</ref> uses words like <quote>passionate, engaged, [...], deeply informed</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>, <quote>supporting</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>, <quote>spirit of activism</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> and <quote>productive and purposeful</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>All those words have deep meanings and everyone has <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> imagination how passionate they are.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses these words to convince his audience, because they sound like forming quite good cooperation between <name type="geo">Turkey</name> and <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The ex-president uses a lot of stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>break down walls</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> is used to make clear, how big intercultural connections are.</s>
        <s>He uses this metaphor to make his point more vivid and understandable.</s>
        <s>To break down walls, you need a lot of motivation and strength.</s>
        <s>To get past stereotypes, you need that too.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In l. 4, 5 and 6 you can find the alliteration <quote>I've seen</quote> and <quote>I saw</quote>.</s>
        <s>It gives the <choice><orig>speach</orig><reg>speech</reg></choice> a <choice><orig>rythm</orig><reg>rhythm</reg></choice> and structure and makes it more interesting.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In l. 14, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses the word <quote>common</quote>, two times.</s>
        <s>Through that, he is able to form a convincing statement through explain his point in detail.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The direct advice <quote>So to all of you</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref>, appeals to the audience's <choice><orig>awarness</orig><reg>awareness</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>They feel included and it forms a sense of togetherness.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In l. 21, the ex-president uses personal pronouns such as <quote>I</quote> and <quote>you</quote>.</s>
        <s>Using personal pronouns in a speech forms a connection between <choice><orig>speeker</orig><reg>speaker</reg></choice> and listener, which creates a sense of trust.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> structures his <choice><orig>speach</orig><reg>speech</reg></choice> interesting and understandable.</s>
        <s>The vivid stylistic devices help him to catch the audience's <choice><orig>awarness</orig><reg>awareness</reg></choice> and the choice of words fits the purpose of the text.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
