<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g21_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Did you ever have done a student exchange or something like that?</s>
        <s>In the following comment, I will talk about the pros and cons whether a simple <choice><orig>exchanges</orig><reg>exchange</reg></choice> can break down walls between us.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think it is a really bis step to go abroad or do a student exchange and it needs a lot of courage because often you don't know anybody.</s>
        <s>Maybe you have to learn the new language and that is the beginning not always easy.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand, you can meet new people, maybe you get also new friends and you learn something about a new culture and a new way to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think if a lot of people do something like an exchange year, it could break down walls between us because there is a better interaction between the people.</s>
        <s>Everybody knows somebody from an other country so you know now they life.</s>
        <s>I think that really join together when everybody knows somebody from an other country because often, you share something with those people and therefore, people from all over the world grow together and to for <choice><orig>exemple</orig><reg>example</reg></choice> together something against the climate change or something like that and not every country for his own.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, I think that a student exchange is a nice start for a good interaction between the world and I think it is the start to break down walls between us.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
