<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g15_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The present extract from <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="title">Remarks of president Barack Obama at student roundtable</ref>, spoken by <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref>, during a visit to <name type="geo">Istanbul</name> in <name type="geo">Turkey</name> at the <name type="misc">Culture and Arts Center of Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University</name> in <name type="geo">Tophane</name>, at <date>April 7th 2009</date>, deals with student exchanges and intercultural understanding.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> states, that he is very proud of his country and their inhabitants.</s>
        <s>He tells the audience about their engagement in volunteering.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack</ref> wants to support the young people experiencing different cultures by doing a student exchange.</s>
        <s>The ex-president thinks that exchange <choice><orig>programms</orig><reg>programs</reg></choice> can help people learning new languages, and that it can help building a connection and a sense of togetherness all around the globe.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through going abroad, people can share their culture and their common experiences to rebuild the sense of a common humanity.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Student exchanges are a first step to peace, because of them, we are able to build new bridges.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> explains the advantages of student exchanges and wants to convince the audience to go abroad.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
