<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g17_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As stated in the summary <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama's</ref> speech is about the importance of student exchanges.</s>
        <s>Now, I will analyse the structure and choice of words the <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses in order to encourage his listeners to take part in intercultural exchanges.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As I already <choice><orig>menshioned</orig><reg>mentioned</reg></choice> in the summary <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> is the 44th president of the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
        <s>He gave his speech in <name type="geo">Istanbul</name> before a student's roundtable in <date>2009</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt can be structured in four different parts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first part, he starts off with his main goal to immediately get the interests of the listeners.</s>
        <s>He supports that with adverbs like <quote>deeply</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> to underline that.</s>
        <s>Another indicator is, that he repeats the adjective <quote>mutual</quote> in the same sentence.</s>
        <s><quote>One that's grounded in mutual interest and mutual respect</quote><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 2-3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This also underlines, how important these goals are to him.</s>
        <s>In the second part he talks about his own experiences made with people who have done something to help others in other countries.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He calls these people <quote>passionate, engaged and deeply informed about the world around them</quote>.</s>
        <s>These three adjectives and adverbs in relation to people who have done something to help others in other countries support his opinion, that these people <choice><orig>ar</orig><reg>are</reg></choice> not only very important to their country, but also very special.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third part, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> <choice><orig>mensions</orig><reg>mentions</reg></choice> the advantages of student exchanges.</s>
        <s>Right at the beginning he uses the <choice><orig>metapher</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> <quote>Simple exchanges can break down walls between us</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Thes</orig><reg>These</reg></choice> walls resemble the cultural barriers that can be forgotten when you visit other countries in <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> student exchange.</s>
        <s>This would lead to <quote>a life that's productive and purposeful...</quote>.</s>
        <s>This alliteration also supports his opinion about the importance of student exchanges.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the fourth and last part, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> encourages the listeners to change something to make the <choice><orig>word</orig><reg>world</reg></choice> a better place.</s>
        <s>He supports that by saying: <quote>... the world will be what you make it</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Directly after that, he refers to his <choice><orig>methafer</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> about the <quote>walls between us</quote>.</s>
        <s>He says, that <quote>[We] can choose to build new bridges instead of building new walls</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 18-19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This leads to the listeners remembering the <choice><orig>metapher</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> what results in thinking about it.</s>
        <s>In the very last sentence, he calls the <name type="geo">USA</name> <quote>a partner and a supporter and a friend</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 21-22)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He does this to underline the important role of the <name type="geo">USA</name> in this process.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
