<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g25_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> gave a speech at <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> <choice><orig>University</orig><reg>university</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">Istanbul</name> in <date>2009</date>.</s>
        <s>In his speech, he mentions the importance of bringing people together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I will discuss now on <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama's</ref> statement that <quote>simple exchanges can break down walls between us</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(line 13)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So first of all, these simple exchanges could break down walls between us, because you can get people together, mostly young people.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> mentions in his speech, he has seen that many young people go abroad or are already deeply informed about the whole <choice><orig>wordl</orig><reg>world</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Here you can see that it could be a good idea to bring people together.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand it isn't that easy because you <choice><orig>cant</orig><reg>can't</reg></choice> just bring people from different countries together because not everyone can afford an exchange year or something like that.</s>
        <s>So it isn't that easy to do <quote>simple exchanges</quote> so that <quote>walls can break down between us</quote>.</s>
        <s>And the question is what are these <quote>simple exchanges</quote> even?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But on the other hand, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> is right because yes, little or simple changes can change the world even if it's just a little bit.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, his statement is motivating for everyone because he gives the feeling that everyone can do something small and it has a big appearance of the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So, I personally would say that I agree with his statement because I think that he is right with his statement and yes, we can break down walls between us by doing small simple exchanges and if everyone can do a little change, we could change the whole world.</s>
        <s>I think he creates a community by saying this statement.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
