<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b12g03_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello Mr. Johnson,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A few decades ago you said that we cannot let the future generations down because we already have the opportunity to fight against climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I agree with you fully.</s>
        <s>The climate change was already when I was n teenager in <date>2021</date> a big issue for us all and it would have been much worse now in <date>2050</date> if we did not handle it the way we did in <date>2022</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though we did not started this problem it is our duty to protect our children of caring the whole responsibility of that problem.</s>
        <s>We also have to help, only because in 2021 most people still could live normally does not mean we have to let the future generations our children and grandchildren suffer under this problem.</s>
        <s>I am so grateful that the <name type="misc">COP26</name> really made a change throughout the years so that my children and my little grandchild can live at least as good as I could when I was young.</s>
        <s>I think you were right.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">COP26</name> is an wars the turning point of the climate change and I hope it is gonna be handle as good from the future generations as from my generation.</s>
        <s>I hope you are well and happy about the change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
