<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g15_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The British Premier Minister <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> gives a speech on <name type="misc">COP26</name> about the importance to take action now.</s>
        <s>He speakes to all the members of <name type="geo">COP26</name> who are Premier Ministers or presendents of their home countries and came together at the climate summit.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He tries to draw a convincing picture of the <choice><orig>climat</orig><reg>climate</reg></choice> crisis but also gives hope by making use of inclusive language and drawing a picture of the <choice><orig>scotish</orig><reg>Scottish</reg></choice> films <name type="person">James Bond</name> so the very importance of taking action against the climate change.</s>
        <s>Therefore he also makes use of inclusive language and strong adjectives, some parts of formal and colloquial language to encourage his audience to take action.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> starts his speech by welcoming everybody in a friendly tone <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 1f.)</ref> and immediately starts to talk about the <name type="person">James Bond</name> films <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 2ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He points out that the world is <quote>strapped to a doomsday device</quote> because of the climate crisis<ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> to directly present the danger of climate crisis and to draw picture of it.</s>
        <s>This brings the danger to the audience because everyone knows about the <name type="person">James Bond</name> films and that there is never room for a mistake for him because if he does not find a solution for the problem, here to defuse bomb, maybe the <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> humanity gets killed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He goes on by comparing the situation with the climate more and points out the role of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> members as <name type="person">James Bond</name> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 4ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Therefore he also makes use of facts like the global <choice><orig>raise</orig><reg>rise</reg></choice> of temperatures <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> and that <name type="misc">COP26</name> has to lie trust on scientists <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This introduces to the topic and is the base of his argumentation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Ongoing he describes the history of the fight against the climate crisis in <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> <date>2010</date> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> and <name type="geo">Paris</name> <date>2015</date> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> they realised a problem and came to goals.</s>
        <s>He comes to the conclusion that <name type="misc">COP26</name> is the moment to take action and not just talk about the dangers <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 12-15)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He arguments in the following that the industrialized countries have the <choice><orig>technologie</orig><reg>technology</reg></choice> to fight against the crisis and to help the other countries so that the whole world is able to turn climate change around and save the world <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 16-21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Therefore he appeals to the <quote>duty</quote> of the industrialized countries to help the others to <quote>move to green technology</quote> (ll. 20f).</s>
        <s>This is the base for his following argumentation to work together <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 24)</ref> and not only spend money <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> but to help their friends to become independent on coal and things like that <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 24-29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He outlines the example of the <name type="geo">UK</name> becoming independent on coal and to <quote>become the Saudi Arabia of wind</quote> to put reliance on his argument <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22f.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover he appeals to the world of everyone.</s>
        <s>He says that money and technology are not the problem but the will of the <quote>fellow leaders</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 31)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He comes to the point everyone is talking about the future in <date>2050 or 2060</date> but the action has to be taken now, because he notices the following generations and the young people (<quote>under 30</quote>) <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 34f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He arguments by giving the opposite that everyone in the room is over 60 <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 35)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows the discrepance between the initional will of his generation and the duty to not destroy the world for the next generaions because they are mostly affected by the climate change <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 35ff.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For him it is important to turn things around and he points out the negative effects of not taking action now to convince everyone of the urgency to take action now.</s>
        <s>The generations will not forgive them and they would enter the posterity with being judged by those children and the next generations for destroying their world <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 38-42)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The end of this paragraph he tries to encourage the audience by his argumentation and is optimistic to spread hope that climate change can be turned around <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 43f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His statement gets clear through his argumentation that they have to take action together and he comes to the conclusion that the world has everything to turn around the climate but they have to pull the trigger now <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 45ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>At the very end he refers to <name type="person">James Bond</name> and his theory of the beginning again.</s>
        <s>He concludes his results by drawing the picture of <name type="person">James Bond</name>.</s>
        <s>He personificates the cliamte change as a tickning time bomb and presents the summit as the moment to defuse this bomb <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 48-51)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His appeal <quote><s>Yes, it's going to be hard.</s><s>But yes, we can do it</s></quote> underlines his optimism and his intention to spread hope.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The argumentation is underlined by his use of language and some stylistic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly he tries to the draw the picture of <name type="person">James Bond</name> and repeats the term <quote>doomsday device</quote> and words that mean the same to pull this figure throughout the whole text (e.g. <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> <quote>doomsday device</quote>, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> <quote>doomsday device</quote><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 43)</ref> <quote>cannot, be the end</quote>) to remind everyone of the importance of the topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore he makes use of inclusive language to take everyone to their responsibility and duty to take action and to help other countries to turn the climate change around (<ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> <quote>we now have a duty</quote>, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref> <quote>because if we fail, they will not forgive us</quote>, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> <quote>And we can</quote>).</s>
        <s>He also points out the word they <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 38-43)</ref> for that reason and to put a dramatic affect on the duty for the next generations.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His general use of language is in some parts formal but also colloquial in some moments.</s>
        <s>For example in the beginning his language is more colloquial to catch <choice><orig>everyones</orig><reg>everyone's</reg></choice> and to introduce the summit.</s>
        <s>The more dramatic and important arguments are presented in a more formal language to point out the importance <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 22-28)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides he tries to show his most important arguments and appeals by using a <choice><orig>similie</orig><reg>simile</reg></choice> (<ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">l. 30</ref>: <quote>He can... we must... we have...</quote>), an enumeration (<ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">l. 16</ref>: <quote>coal, cars, cash and trees</quote>) and by <choice><orig>repititions</orig><reg>repetitions</reg></choice> and an anaphora (<ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">l. 46</ref>: <quote>We have... We have... We have... We have...</quote>).</s>
        <s>This encourages the audience to take action and creates hope.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His intention gets clear through his argumentation.</s>
        <s>He wants to encourage the audience to take action by drawing the picture of <name type="person">James Bond</name>, pointing out the dangers and demonstrate strength in unity.</s>
        <s>All in all one can state that he draws a very convincing and shocking picture which makes clear that there is no time left to take action and to do it now.</s>
        <s>Ongoing his argumentation does not only create a shocked atmosphere but also hope through his appeal to the unity.</s>
        <s>This encourages the audience to turn the climate change around.</s>
        <s>His use of language does not create any other effects but it underlines his argumentation.</s>
        <s>His strategic use of colloquial informal language creates a strong atmosphere and encourages the listeners to do something.</s>
        <s>My hypothesis gets confirmed through the analysis.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
