<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g05_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello my English-speaking e-pal,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope <choice><orig>your</orig><reg>you're</reg></choice> doing well.</s>
        <s>I read the article about <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> you sent me and I am happy to tell you about it.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> is a project at my school, that was started because more and more students showed interest in protecting the environment and acting against climate change.</s>
        <s>Especially through protests like <name type="misc">Fridays-for-future</name> the topic gained more popularity.</s>
        <s>The school thought it would be nice to deal with questions like <quote>how does my acting affect the environment</quote> inside of school workshops.</s>
        <s>Students, parents and teachers had the opportunity to request workshops, that they think could be interesting.</s>
        <s>All the workshops, that they think could be interesting.</s>
        <s>All the workshops will then take place at one day and there will be not normal lessons.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Examples for workshops that existed are discussing how to save water or a second hand flea market.</s>
        <s>Another thing they did is making sure, that the trash is more environment friendly and they made a café with vegan waffles and coffee.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One special thing they did is invite two poetry-slammers, one of which taught kids how to properly use their voice, helping them in discussions etc.</s>
        <s>The teachers were very pleased with the event and it will probably take place again if it's possible due to COVID-19.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
