<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12g17_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the text <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="title">British Prime Minister address at COP26 World Leaders' Summit Opening Ceremony</ref> from the <date>November 1st of 2021</date>, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> talks about our possibility and our duty to take action now in stopping climate change in order to rescue our future and within our future generations.</s>
        <s>The perception of climate change is still <choice><orig>quiet</orig><reg>quite</reg></choice> unreal.</s>
        <s>It is hard to invest money and work into a problem that is not a visual threat to someone, but still: talking was yesterday and today the time has come to act.</s>
        <s>We have to pay climate fonds to countries that need it in order take action theirselfes, but not only money is needed: we need to work joint and offer development assistance.</s>
        <s>We can use green energy to become a wealthy country.</s>
        <s>All our actions should intend preserving our future from destruction.</s>
        <s>Our future generations will depend on dad and will also be <choice><orig>thankfull</orig><reg>thankful</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris</ref> has already made impressions on how these big events like <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> ended and surely the talking should be converted into action.</s>
        <s>Since 200 years industrial countries only offered <choice><orig>ignorace</orig><reg>ignorance</reg></choice> of the problem and this is still taking place when we look at the promised fonds from the <name type="geo">Paris</name> agreement.</s>
        <s>Despite that decarbonization is needed in order to reach the goal of 1.5 degrees per century.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">COP26</name> is the last <choice><orig>oportunity</orig><reg>opportunity</reg></choice> to shift our mindset into preserving out earth from great danger and working joint as we got the same enemy: climate change.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
