<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g12_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear friend,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you are doing good.</s>
        <s>I'm fine, thanks.</s>
        <s>Of course I can tell you about the newspaper article you found.</s>
        <s>The head line <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="title">Mehr Bio nicht nur am Freitag</ref> means <quote>More Bio not only on Fridays</quote>, where <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="author">Joachim Neubauer</ref> the author, <choice><orig>referres</orig><reg>refers</reg></choice> to <name type="misc">Friday for Future</name>.</s>
        <s>The article is about a project of our school called <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> it's a project where our entire school has no lessons.</s>
        <s>Instead we work in over <choice><orig>fourty</orig><reg>forty</reg></choice> workshops, which are all related to thematic of the safety of our environment.</s>
        <s>Our school started this project because the <choice><orig>student's</orig><reg>students</reg></choice> started to become interested in politics regarding to <name type="misc">Fridays for future</name> and many took part in the demonstrations.</s>
        <s>Thereforethe students, teachers and parents were supposed to bring in ideas for workshops.</s>
        <s>So workshops like saving food through food sharing, saving water <choice><orig>throught</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> showers instead of taking bath or a second-hand-flea-market, came off.</s>
        <s>Two students even managed to open up a Fairtrade-Café, where they sold vegan waggles and fair trade coffee.</s>
        <s>Also <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>two</reg></choice> people who do poetry slam came to our school and showed how to we can use our coices and words correctly.</s>
        <s>I hope I was able to help you and you now have a better idea about our school project <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours sincerely John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
