<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g13_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Johnson,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have just remembered the speech you have given at the <name type="misc">COP26 World Leaders' Summit</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> in <date>2021</date>.</s>
        <s>Now we find <choice><orig>ourselfs</orig><reg>ourselves</reg></choice> about 30 years later and still are in a similar position, trapped in the cage of climate crisis.</s>
        <s>You promised <name type="misc">COP26</name> Will be the turning point in history but all I see is the same <quote>blah, blah, blah</quote> as in <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> and <name type="misc">Paris</name>.</s>
        <s>You said you have the necessary funds to make progress but in reality not much has changed.</s>
        <s>Climate change still moves <choice><orig>foreward</orig><reg>forward</reg></choice> in a rapidly speed and the 1.5 degree goal is left in the past long ago.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Economical success and money is still more important for all the governments than the people dying because of the consequences of climate change.</s>
        <s>To be honest you were right.</s>
        <s>The anger of the billion young people that build the new generation is great.</s>
        <s>Especially because they feel like they are trying their best to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice> sustainable and take measures against global warming besides other problems that also are not solved yet like social issues such as discrimination.</s>
        <s>But what I am trying to say is that it is really frustrating to see the world dying and not <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> able to do some thing as an individual except of hoping and try to evoke attention by little things in daily life like avoiding plastic bags.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I I am fully aware of the fact that global challenges such as climate change requires collaborative action among many governments, international organizations, NGOs and so on and <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> be mastered by you or the <name type="geo">UK</name> alone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But I wish that this collaborative work will finally be realized and also the big concerns and global players understand that they have to give up on some things in order to keep going.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
