<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> tries to convince the audience on his view on climate change by <choice><orig>reffering</orig><reg>referring</reg></choice> to the future generations and the responsibility we all have.</s>
        <s>The given speech can be divided in three different parts.</s>
        <s>The first part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 1-17)</ref> includes the welcoming of the audience and information why they all meet together on this day.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> shows what the plans were for the past years and shows that nothing happened since that days.</s>
        <s>He tells that we have the technology today to do something against climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 18-44)</ref> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> tells what he thinks would make sense to do.</s>
        <s>He suggests that not only <choice><orig>goverments</orig><reg>governments</reg></choice> should spend money for climate change.</s>
        <s>And his opinion also the market, so like <choice><orig>nongovermental</orig><reg>non-governmental</reg></choice> organizations (NGOs) and multilateral development banks, should be part of the progress and spend money.</s>
        <s>He appeals on working together.</s>
        <s>In addition to that the speaker refers to future generations and that they will judge us for not acting now.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 45-52)</ref> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> comes back to his idea of all being <name type="person">James Bond</name>.</s>
        <s>He wants his listeners to understand that this is an opportunity to make a difference and to act now.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>the <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> Prime Minister <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> starts his speech with an allusion on <name type="person">James Bond</name>.</s>
        <s>He tries to illustrate a situation of <name type="person">James Bond</name> being strapped on a doomsday device which will explode when the time on the clock stops <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(i.g. line 1-5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Then <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> starts to compare the situation to their own situation, by comparing the doomsday device with the climate change.</s>
        <s>But with the appeal <quote>the tragedy is not a movie</quote> he shows how urgent climate crisis is.</s>
        <s>So he alludes everyone to be <name type="person">James Bond</name> on this day <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(i.g. line 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By using inclusive language in the whole speech he wants his listeners to follow his words and they start to feel personal addressed and <choice><orig>ephasize</orig><reg>empathize</reg></choice> with him and his words <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(e.g. line 9, 16, 30 - many more)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It also creates a feeling of community.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> enumerates two different meetings of the past years which were also about climate change and what to do against it <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 10-13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>And then he starts with the these that <quote>all those promises will be nothing but blah, blah, blah</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 13-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This idea is followed by the conclusion that <quote>this COP26 in Glasgow [is] the moment when we get real about climate change</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 14-15)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that he underlines his opinion by enumerating different problems of climate change and economy we have today and concludes that these all can be solved by the technologies of today <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 16-17)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To intensify his his idea by using the <quote>ticking doomsday device</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 17)</ref> as metaphor for climate change.</s>
        <s>This should also underline how urgent it is to act fast now.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following part that it were 200 years of complete ignorance <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This should show the audience that they waited <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> long already.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following sentences he underlines with the ellipses <quote>no question</quote><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 23)</ref> that it is unquestionable that the <choice><orig>goverments</orig><reg>governments</reg></choice> have to become partners for spending money for climate change <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(i.g. line 22-29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is followed by his explanation that we have to act now and not talk about years like <date>2060</date> when we didn't even start acting <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(i.g. line 30-37)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Then <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> starts to refer to the future generations and the children that are not born yet and their future <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(i.g. line 38)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By saying that they <quote>will do judge us</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 42)</ref> he appeals on the responsibility for future generations.</s>
        <s>In the last part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> <choice><orig>reffers</orig><reg>refers</reg></choice> to his idea of the beginning with <name type="person">James Bond</name> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(i.g. line 48)</ref> and appeals to <quote>defuse the bomb</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(line 51)</ref>.</s>
        <s>So he wants then to act now and make a difference.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all you can see that <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> wants his listeners to act now and understand how urgent climate crisis is.</s>
        <s>This is underlined by the responsibility for future generations and the metaphors like <quote>bombs</quote> for climate change.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
