<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12g12_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given speech by the British Prime Minister <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> on the occasion of the <name type="misc">COP26 World Leaders' Summit Opening</name>, was delivered on the <date>1st of November in 2021</date> and discusses <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson's</ref> idea of the <choice><orig>climat</orig><reg>climate</reg></choice> crisis and his view of the role of <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> starts his speech by welcoming everybody to <name type="misc">COP</name>.</s>
        <s>He says, that they all know about the climate crisis and that they learned not to ignore it.</s>
        <s>He continues by saying, that <name type="misc">COP26</name> must be the starting point of handling with the climate crisis if they want to have a chance.</s>
        <s>He says that money will not be enough, they first have to find projects they can help to de-risk before money should be moved.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> also mentions that they should not talk about what they'll do in <date>2050</date> because they will be too old and they have to act now, because the people who will judge them are not born yet and if they do not act now they will never forgive them.</s>
        <s>They will know, that <name type="misc">COP26</name> could have been the starting point of fighting against the climate crisis.</s>
        <s>Therefore he says, that <name type="misc">COP26</name> cannot be the end of the story and they cannot lead the future generations because they still have the time and technological devices to stop the crisis but only if they start today.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
