<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g04_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As I already said this political speech, which was given by the British Prime Minister <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> on the <name type="misc">COP26</name>, which is the global climate change <choice><orig>conferenz</orig><reg>conference</reg></choice> <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> all the leaders of the nations of the world come together, is about the climate crisis and role of the <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speech was given on the occasion of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> and <choice><orig>off course</orig><reg>of course</reg></choice> also because of the <choice><orig>rapitely</orig><reg>rapidly</reg></choice> <choice><orig>continueing</orig><reg>continuing</reg></choice> of climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The audience of the speech are obviously the leaders of the countries of the world, because <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> gives his speech in front of them.</s>
        <s>But the speech is also addressed to all the people in the world, who can hear the speech with radio or television.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this speech, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> tries to draw a convincing picture of the dangers and to give his audience hope and encourage them to take action, by comparing the whole situation with a <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Just in the beginning of his speech <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> claims that climate change is real a danger for mankind and that we have to find a solution for it, by comparing the whole situation with the <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He says that every <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie has <quote>doomsday device</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> and <name type="person">James Bond</name> is the man who has to save the whole world by finding the right <quote>colored wire</quote> to turn turn the doomsday device <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice>, while the clock for the end of the world is ticking <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>So in this metaphor of <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> the <quote>doomsday device</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> is the climate change, which puts a risk on the whole mankind and the audience of <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> speech, so the leaders of the <name type="misc">COP26</name>, are <name type="person">James Bond</name> and have to find the right <quote>colored wire</quote> so the solution to stop the climate change and to save the world, while the clock is ticking, because climate change is already happending <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> shows the danger of climate change for the mankind, so that it could destroy everything and it also underlines the duty of the leaders of <name type="misc">COP26</name> to act now like <name type="person">James Bond</name> and to save the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that comparison <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> shows that nothing happened by now, although it is obvious that there is a real problem, by the anaphora <quote>I was there...</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10, 11)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This anaphora shows that the conferences in <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> or in <name type="geo">Paris</name> were just <quote>blah blah blah</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> and nothing changed over the years.</s>
        <s>So <name type="misc">COP26</name> has to be the part <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> this changes, as <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> says.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next paragraph, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> stresses that we are able to solve the problem and that we have the remedies for it.</s>
        <s>He underlines that with the repetition of <quote>We can</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> and enumeration <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 16)</ref> which shows that we are able to solve all the problems that come within climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that, <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> <choice><orig>make</orig><reg>makes</reg></choice> clear that industrialized countries have the duty to help the other countries as they created the climate change.</s>
        <s>But he says that this financial help cannot be enough if just the governments are spending <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 22)</ref>, so he wants the market and the private sector to also help, by e.g. investigating in screen technology <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 23)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To underline how important this is, he makes clear that only the private sector made the <choice><orig>brithish</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> independence from coal possible.</s>
        <s>He describes the UK as <quote>the Saudi Arabia of wind</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 29)</ref>, which is a metaphor and also and antithesis, because <name type="geo">Saudi-Arabia</name> is very rich by there large deposits of oilm which is in contrast to the green technology that the wind stands for.</s>
        <s>This metaphor underlines the independence of the <name type="geo">UK</name> from coal or oil, so they do not need <name type="geo">Saudi-Arabia</name> anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following he points out, that the people who will suffer the climate change, or not the people who live now on the planet, but the posterity <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref>.</s>
        <s>To <choice><orig>underlines</orig><reg>underline</reg></choice> that he <choice><orig>repeads</orig><reg>repeats</reg></choice> the word <quote>children</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref>, which also stands for the <choice><orig>innocense</orig><reg>innocence</reg></choice> of the following generations as <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> did not create the climate change, but they have to suffer.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> also wants to play to sympathy for the following generations by this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> comes to the conclusion that we have to act for the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">praprity</gap> that we have the duty to do something as we are able to stop it <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 45)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He underlines it by the anaphora <quote>We have</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 46)</ref> to show that we are able to solve this problem so we have the duty to do it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> comes back to his comparison with <name type="person">James Bond</name> from the beginning.</s>
        <s>He says although they won't feel or even look like <name type="person">James Bond</name>, they have to act like him.</s>
        <s>By that he underlines <choice><orig>aggain</orig><reg>again</reg></choice> the duty but also a little bit the honour to save the world, like <name type="person">James Bond</name> does it every time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> appeals to the audience to begin to act and to fight against the climate change <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 49)</ref>.</s>
        <s>To put it in a nutshell <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> appeals to fight against the climate change, as it is a real danger and is already happening and that we have the remedies and the duty to something not just for us, but also for the following generations.</s>
        <s>He tries this by the comparison with <name type="person">James Bond</name>, to show that it's even possible, as <name type="person">James Bond</name> is also able to save the world every time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
