<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g17_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Pal,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I <choice><orig>witnissed</orig><reg>witnessed</reg></choice> that you are interested in the project <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> which is explained in the article <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="title">Mehr Bio nicht nur am Freitag</ref> from <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="author">Joachim Neubauer</ref>, which I am going to <choice><orig>summerize</orig><reg>summarize</reg></choice> for you in order to give you a <choice><orig>brive</orig><reg>brief</reg></choice> impression.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Do you wonder about the amount of CO2 that you cause, or how to use water in a sustainable way?</s>
        <s>Despite that you will be also informed about vegan and vegetarian food and how it effects our environment.</s>
        <s>40 workshops are given in one day distributed in <choice><orig>classroms</orig><reg>classrooms</reg></choice> and also outside.</s>
        <s>The political interest of the students has risen over time which also show itself the amount of people that take part at the <name type="misc">Fridays for Future-movement</name>.</s>
        <s>They gather ideas for workshops from students, teachers and parents.</s>
        <s>720 students got freetime in order to take part in these and if you want to have the feeling of causing something you can collaborate with them.</s>
        <s>Topics are for example saving food, foodsharing, an efficient usage of water, or second-hand-fashion.</s>
        <s>Another big topic is fairtrade and biological products.</s>
        <s>There is also given a <choice><orig>caffee</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice> with fairtrade food.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There you can try vegan waffels or cakes which are bio-based with fairtrade <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>they taste delicious and give you a good feeling on having an impact on climate change.</s>
        <s>Last time we were visited from two poetry-slam-stars which <choice><orig>tought</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> us a bit in speaking in order to hold speeches about climate change.</s>
        <s>I hope you gained an overview of this topic.</s>
        <s>Everyone, me included, was quiet <choice><orig>contented</orig><reg>contended</reg></choice> with that idea and I hope you can take part in it next time!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
