<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g04_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Steven</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I how to read your email on the article <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="title">Mehr Bio nicht nur am Freitag</ref> and I want to answer your questions on <name type="misc">School B goes green</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="misc">School B goes green</name> was a day <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> the whole school, so teacher, students and also parents concerned themselves with a climate change, and thought about different ways how everyone of us can do his little part in his every day like <choice><orig>aggainst</orig><reg>against</reg></choice> climate change.</s>
        <s>The day was organized by the students and the teachers, as the students have become more and more political and wanted to contribute theirselve more.</s>
        <s>Another example of this growing interest and also initiative of students is the <name type="misc">Friday for Future</name> movement.</s>
        <s>I think you have heard about it, haven't you.</s>
        <s>So on that day, <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> were over 40 workshops in our school and also all over the city, were <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">lere</gap> the students, thought about, how we could improve our everyday life to make it more environmental friendly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example we thought about food sharing or environmental friendly <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">spedes</gap> in our school kiosk.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion this day was a great idea and it should be repeated, because it's important that everyone contributes hisself with climate change and thinks how he can do his little pod for fighting <choice><orig>aggainst</orig><reg>against</reg></choice> the climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I was really surprised, but also happy that you heard about <name type="misc">School B goes green</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If you have any questions left you can ask myself.</s>
        <s>In hope to hear from you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours <choice><orig>sincelary</orig><reg>sincerely</reg></choice>, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
