<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g11_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Paul,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>you wanted to know what <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> was about I will tell you what it was.</s>
        <s>My school <name type="misc">Königin-Luise-Schule</name> organized a day where every student took part in a workshop with the topic environmental protection.</s>
        <s>There were 40 different workshops which took place in the school but also in the city where my school is located which is <name type="geo">Cologne</name>.</s>
        <s>Teachers, parents and students organize this day because of the increase of interest in political and social issues.</s>
        <s>Especially, <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> caused this increase.</s>
        <s>Because of that they had the idea of organizing a day about environmental protection so that the students can learn new things.</s>
        <s>There were many different workshops for example about <choice><orig>nutriation</orig><reg>nutrition</reg></choice>, the decrease of waste caused by food and how to cut your use of water.</s>
        <s>In addition that was a workshop about carbon dioxide footprint, and one about how snacks in school can be more sustainable.</s>
        <s>Some students also organize a secondhand flea market where they sell weared clothes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore two students made a fairtrade-cafe where you could buy sustainable food.</s>
        <s>A highlight for many students were to poets who showed students which function different kinds of speaking have.</s>
        <s>That helps students to learn how to talk more self-confident which is important for discussions about climate protection.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> why is a successful project because the students learned a lot and were interested.</s>
        <s>Maybe my school will organize such a day again.</s>
        <s>I hope that I could help you.</s>
        <s>If you have more questions to <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> just <choice><orig>asks</orig><reg>ask</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best regards, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
