<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12g10_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech on the <name type="misc">World Leaders' Summit Opening Ceremony</name>, held on the <date>Nov. 1, 2021</date> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> addresses is the climate change and the duty to act now.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> seize the climate crisis as a huge danger for the current and following generations.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore he states that the <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> needs to be the moment where the world reacts and starts to change things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is Full of hope that using the money of the industrialized countries will help all countries to achieve their climate aims.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition he tells the audience the responsibility they have to do for future generations.</s>
        <s>Due to this responsibility the <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> needs to be the stars for taking action in order to achieve to <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">ristain</gap> the rise in the temperature of the planet to 1.5 degree.</s>
        <s>He makes clear that all assumptions to react against climate change like NGOs and corporations are already <choice><orig>their</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> and just need to be used correctly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end he underlines his message of the importance of a reaction to the climate crisis and tells the audience that he is full of hope that the <name type="misc">COP26</name> can be the beginning of this necessary change.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
