<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12g11_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given speech was delivered by <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref>, the British Prime Minister, at <name type="misc">COP26 Leaders' Summit Opening Ceremony</name> on <date>1st November 2021</date>.</s>
        <s>It deals with <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson's</ref> idea of the climate crisis and his view of the role and importance of <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> thinks that climate change will end our loves as we know it.</s>
        <s>We do not have much time left to do something against it because the temperature of the planet rises faster and fast.</s>
        <s>This climate change is man-made.</s>
        <s>He has the opinion that the function of <name type="misc">COP26</name> is to agree on things that we will implement.</s>
        <s>In <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> and <name type="geo">Paris</name>, they agreed to a net zero and that the temperature should not rise more than 1,5 degrees but that are just promises which will not change something if they are not following actions.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he thinks that we have the technology to change something In addition we also have the funds to help developing countries.</s>
        <s>He says that we need the help of the market, because they have much more funds.</s>
        <s>But the will to change something is also important.</s>
        <s>He explains that the politicians have the responsibility to decrease global warming.</s>
        <s>They are the people who can change some thing but future generations are the one who will suffer if the politicians will fail.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> thinks that <name type="misc">COP26</name> Will not be the last thing who is about climate change.</s>
        <s>He says that the politicians have everything to do something against climate change and they should not fail because of future generations.</s>
        <s>At the end he makes clear that is not going to be easy but it is feasible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, his opinion is that we have act now because the politicians have no time to wait.</s>
        <s>The <name type="misc">COP26</name> is important to agree on things the politicians will do.</s>
        <s>But in the future there will be more the politicians have to do.</s>
        <s>They also have the possibilities and responsibility to act now.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
