<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g01_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey John</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>since you kindly asked me about the <name type="misc">School B goes green</name> article, I will gladly elaborate its contents to you.</s>
        <s>The guiding question was on how to ac more eco-friendly, by for example looking at <choice><orig>ones</orig><reg>one's</reg></choice> CO2-footprint.</s>
        <s>The project took place in the <name type="misc">School B</name> but was not confined to its area.</s>
        <s>Within the project were 40 workshops all of whom shared the common theme of environment.</s>
        <s>This project was started, because the political and social interest of studennts grew, especially when regarding the popularity of the environmental movement <name type="misc">Fridays-for-future</name> in which many students participated in.</s>
        <s>Additionally the topic also arose in talks between the school and the student representation, this they came to the idea of bringing the topic to the school officially.</s>
        <s>They created the motto <name type="misc">School B goes green</name> <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> collected ideas for workshops, from teachers, students and parens, which will all take place on a selected school day.</s>
        <s>Thus when the day came all students were <choice><orig>realesed</orig><reg>released</reg></choice> from all classes, as long as they partake in the project.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The ideas were varied ranging from foodsharing to stop the work of food, over to the efficient handling of water by bathing less and showering more all the way to a second-hand flea market.</s>
        <s>They even opened a fairtrade coffeeshop in the school <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>two</reg></choice> seniors sold <choice><orig>vegane</orig><reg>vegan</reg></choice> waffels, cake and fairrade <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The seniors say that they look at home at their <quote>ethical consumption</quote>.</s>
        <s>Two poety-slammers  visited the schools and made a workshop in which they taught the children about their <choice><orig>pronanciation</orig><reg>pronunciation</reg></choice> and their tone and how to use it objective oriented.</s>
        <s>They did so by letting the children read out funny and scary stories.</s>
        <s>All in all the students were very <choice><orig>interestended</orig><reg>interested</reg></choice> and the event is <choice><orig>prably</orig><reg>probably</reg></choice> going to be continued, which I can confirm since I did take part in an event.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours faithfully, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
