<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g18_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear James,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Who are you?</s>
        <s>I am good but I hope we can see each other soon.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="title">mehr Bio nicht nur am Freitag</ref> is about a workshop day named <name type="misc">School B goes green</name> at my school.</s>
        <s>On this day we <choice><orig>dealed</orig><reg>dealt</reg></choice> with many questions we had about the topic climate protection.</s>
        <s>During the day we had aóver 40 workshops on which we could take part.</s>
        <s>This workshop day was made by our teachers and students and took place for the first time.</s>
        <s>It came into existence because of the social and political of our students which rised through the <name type="misc">Fridays-for-future-actions</name>.</s>
        <s>Also in our school council this topic got mentioned so they got the idea of a workshop day to this topic.</s>
        <s>We had workshops about food-sharing, the efficient dealing with water and a second-hand-market for example.</s>
        <s>Some students <choice><orig>als</orig><reg>also</reg></choice> informed themselves about opportunities for our school cafeteria with fairtrade products.</s>
        <s>Two students also <choice><orig>opend</orig><reg>opened</reg></choice> up a fairtrade-café for that day where they sold vegan waffles, biological cakes and fairtrade coffee.</s>
        <s>Also a poetry smaller was as a guest at our school who showed some students the effect that our voice has on stories.</s>
        <s>At the end of this article a teacher of my school says summarizing that he was happy with that day and thinks that we could do something like that again.</s>
        <s>I hope I could help you with that and I am excited when we see <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice> hopefully soon.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Hopefully soon. Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
