<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g16_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Leo,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>in your last email you wrote about the new project <name type="misc">School B goes green</name> and asked me if I could give you some more information about this topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the newspaper article of the <date>Nov/19/2019</date> <ref target="b12gk1_2" type="author">Joachim Neubauer</ref>, who is the author of the article, informs about our new project, <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> we try to be more environmentally friendly.</s>
        <s>We had 40 different workshops to the topic environmental protection in our school for only one day.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It why is the first time of some workshops for this important topic.</s>
        <s><name type="person">John Smith</name>, who was an organizer of the project recognize that many students went to <name type="misc">Fridays for future</name> in the last couple of weeks and month.</s>
        <s>After this he and some students came to the decision to begin the project <name type="misc">School B goes green</name>.</s>
        <s>Every students of the 720 got free time but we had to go to the workshops.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They were some different workshops for example food sharing or a secondhand flea market.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore our school only want to sell fairtrade products at our school shop and our on fairtrade-café produced only vegan waffles.</s>
        <s>They wanted to show that vegan can be delicious.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition Vera came to poetry-slamer (<name type="person">John Smith</name> and another one), who wrote some different <choice><orig>storys</orig><reg>stories</reg></choice> with some students.</s>
        <s>It was so funny that they skipped they pause only to talk about their <choice><orig>storys</orig><reg>stories</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It was very important in which way they talked about their <choice><orig>storys</orig><reg>stories</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This workshop could be important for a better way of a discussion.</s>
        <s>We are trying to create this cool project again next year.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best regards, John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
