<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g08_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Johnson,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>My name is Jane Smith and I was born in <date>2030</date>.</s>
        <s>I'm writing you because of your speech in <date>2021</date> addressed at the <name type="misc">COP26 World Leaders' Summit</name>.</s>
        <s>I have found your speech in an old newspaper article and it really interested me.</s>
        <s>Specially because it includes me as one <quote>of the billions more of the unborn</quote>.</s>
        <s>And I want to thank you for not giving up.</s>
        <s>I am really sure you helped this process to get climate change under control.</s>
        <s>Because of you the audience awaked and made it more better for us nowadays.</s>
        <s>You were the one who made the difference and without you we maybe wouldn't even be alive today.</s>
        <s>Because of you and your speech we can have a perspective these days.</s>
        <s>I think you were absolutely right with what you said, but I also think they have done some thing against climate change.</s>
        <s>Of course I agree with you that it wasn't enough but they tried it.</s>
        <s>But in fact I am amazed by the way you were convincing the audience to act.</s>
        <s>Of course today isn't everything perfect but because of you the politics do some thing against climate change.</s>
        <s>Active.</s>
        <s>We all have to thank you and have to <choice><orig>appreciate</orig><reg>apprechiate</reg></choice> what you have done.</s>
        <s>I just wanted to thank you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Kind regards, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
