<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11g01_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The side-character <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> from the book <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="title">Gun Love</ref> is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> 8 year old girl, who is in the same foster home as <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is a very small girl that looks like a five year old <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She smells like burned marshmallows <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> and is very energic.</s>
        <s>You can say that she is acting very silly because she dreams of a <quote>white Christmas in Florida</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 18-19)</ref> which is almost impossible.</s>
        <s>It is also very obvious that she is confused about her own life because she doesn't really know where she came from <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 7-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She is confused because there were too many changes in her life.</s>
        <s>The narrator calls her a <quote>true-blue foster child</quote> because she was in too many homes <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The fact that she stayed in homes where she only got cereals to eat <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> and that she doesn't drink enough water <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> shows us that she is probably very skinny and undernourished.</s>
        <s>Even though her life is very hard she is still happy and can be childish, which you can tell from the questions she asks her friends.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> pointed out a few times that she had to deal with bugs which shows that she lived under bad conditions <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 21-22)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She even recognized the smell of bug-off on <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref>, which is a clue for her living conditions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You can also tell that the <choice><orig>familys</orig><reg>families</reg></choice> she lived at weren't rich because she had to reuse dental floss and tea bags.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is looking for love from others as you can see from her love for forehead kisses.</s>
        <s>She likes to have contact to others <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19, l. 41)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The fact that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> speaks in 3rd person to herself shows that she isn't educated.</s>
        <s>She has a few friends that she talks to with her phones.</s>
        <s>They talk about simple questions which shows that her friends aren't much older than her.</s>
        <s>She had been in 17 foster homes as you can see from the number of her phones.</s>
        <s>She doesn't have a good relationship to all of them because she doesn't know what house the phones belong to.</s>
        <s>She was in <choice><orig>familys</orig><reg>families</reg></choice> with other religions or ethnic groups <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 6-10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Her <choice><orig>familys</orig><reg>family's</reg></choice> didn't care enough for her because they didn't teach her the most important things.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
