<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>b11g07_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the novel <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="title">Gun Love</ref> by <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="author">Jennifer Clement</ref> in <date>2019</date>, the protagonist <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl France</ref> is living with her teenage runaway mother in a trailer park in <name type="geo">Florida</name>, where they live in poverty and homeless in a car.</s>
        <s>So they are the fools of the American Dream.</s>
        <s>But should the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Service</expan></choice> have taken <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away from <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> and the trailer park, put her into a foster home and help her to get a good education and prepare for a better and <choice><orig>independant</orig><reg>indenpendent</reg></choice> way of life?</s>
        <s>In the following part I will <choice><orig>disguss</orig><reg>discuss</reg></choice> the question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The arguments for bringing her into a foster home, mentioned in the text, are that she can improve her education and become <choice><orig>independant</orig><reg>independent</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Another point is that she may has better chances for improving her situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But an important aspect for growing as a person is a person she can relate to, which is <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref>.</s>
        <s>That gives her secure and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> teaches her things even better as the teachers at school, so it is not always an improve to bring homeless <choice><orig>childs</orig><reg>children</reg></choice> or <choice><orig>childs</orig><reg>children</reg></choice> with a tough childhood to a foster home.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An example for this statement is <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref>, who had a tough life even though she always lived in foster homes.</s>
        <s>She never had a person to relate to so she never grew as a person and nobody showed her important things for her life as <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> did for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is more an individual weigh up, <choice><orig>who's</orig><reg>whose</reg></choice> situation become better in a foster home, which I would support.</s>
        <s>Another important aspect is that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> is living in a broken system with a lot of poverty, insecurity, inequality and injustice.</s>
        <s>I would not make a big different for her living conditions where she is living because when she is out of the system it is hard to get (back) into it.</s>
        <s>This is because there is no functional health sysmte in the <name type="geo">US</name> and the state does not help them with money for improving their situation.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> system is even worser as the <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> system because we actually have a health system even though it could also be improved.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, for her living conditions there is no big different by living in the trailer park or living in a foster home, but for her psyche and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> as a person she can relate to, it is better for her as an individual to live in the trailer park.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Even tough</orig><reg>Even though</reg></choice> her mother is dead, there are still important people around her, like <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Corazón</ref>, who can get a better attachment figure <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> a person she does not really know and maybe is as horrible as the foster parents <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> had before.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
