<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>b11g13_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following comment I am going to discuss, if the Child <choice><orig>Protectiv</orig><reg>Protective</reg></choice> Services should have taken <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away from her mother <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> when they were living together in an old <name type="misc">Ford Mercury</name> on the visitors parking lot of the <name type="misc">Indian Waters Trailer Park</name> in the middle of nowhere in <name type="geo">Florida</name>.</s>
        <s>It is very <choice><orig>difficuilt</orig><reg>difficult</reg></choice> to say what a child in the age of 14 needs in such a situation.</s>
        <s>I have to admit that the living conditions on the trailer park are very rough.</s>
        <s>The park is located next to a dump that intoxicates the whole area and there is no shower for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> and her mother, but it is not that easy to say that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> should get taken away.</s>
        <s>On the trailer park she has found a home that she has lived in for her whole life.</s>
        <s>She has made friends and her mother really loves her, teaches her a lot of important things and sends her to school to get a good education.</s>
        <s>The fact that they need to be afraid of the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Service</expan></choice> is only hindering them to earn more money and making more friends and on the example of <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> you can see how terrible the life conditions of a child can get when it is <surplus>is</surplus> trapped in the supposedly helping system of being passed around by the foster homes.</s>
        <s>So in my opinion the work of the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Service</expan></choice> is innecessary or even negatively impacting the life of <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> and I really think that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> is raising <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> to a well educated, independent and clever woman.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Taking everything into <choice><orig>acount</orig><reg>account</reg></choice> I think that taking <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away from <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> and that her life in the trailer park is better for her and her future than it would be in a foster home.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
