<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>b11g08_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The novel <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="title">Gun Love</ref> written by <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="author">Jennifer Clement</ref> and published in <date>2019</date> deals with the first-person narrator <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> and her mother <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> who live in a <date>1994</date> <name type="misc">Mercury</name> at a trailer in the middle in a bad part of <name type="geo">Florida</name>.</s>
        <s>There they live in bad conditions and are rather socially isolated.</s>
        <s>In the following text, I will comment the statement <quote>CPS should have taken Pearl away from Margot and the trailer park, put her into a foster home and help her to get a good education and prepare for a better and independent way of life</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all, the area where <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> live is very dirty, unhealthy because of the dump, and lost place because there are not many people.</s>
        <s>It is also far away from any cities.</s>
        <s>That is why they are rather socially isolated but they got used to it and it was the way for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> in order to protect herself and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> from her abusive father.</s>
        <s>The conditions in which they live with not electricity, no gas burner, no furnitures etc. shows that they have not much opportunities especially <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> has not much opportunities for a good education.</s>
        <s>It should be a big help to help them financially because they really needed and her dream of a desk and a chair also underlines that her education is important for her but you do not have to forget that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> nevertheless goes to school.</s>
        <s>This is possible for her because of the American Dream.</s>
        <s>The American Dream offers all the people <choice><orig>independet</orig><reg>independent</reg></choice> on your money, on where you live, your religion etc. a better life.</s>
        <s>Everyone has the opportunity to go to school and has a right for education.</s>
        <s>Without the American Dream <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> would not go to school because she is homeless and has not enough money.</s>
        <s>For that reason there is no reason to take her away in order to help her to get a good education.</s>
        <s>However, it could be a good decision to take her away in order to offer her a better life, to live in a house and meet new people because at the trailer park, she is not allowed to have many friends because of their of the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> but if they took her away, they would not have any fears.</s>
        <s>With taking the results of my work on <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref>, you can see that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> would be still feel her alone because she <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> know if she will change her foster homes as much as <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> did which leads to psychological problems.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> also would feel <choice><orig>her</orig><reg>here</reg></choice> alone like <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> because of not getting love from anyone.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot's</ref> love to <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> is very important for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref>.</s>
        <s>Without her family she <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> live a happy and perfect life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, even though the American Dream <choice><orig>promiss</orig><reg>promises</reg></choice> you to have a better life, it could be failed.</s>
        <s>Many people mistrust the American Dream because the dream of many people did not get true.</s>
        <s>That is why <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl's</ref> dream of having a good education could be also failed and then she would live her life without her mother.</s>
        <s>To the point taking <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away in order to prepare a better and independent way of life you do not have to forget that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> is still independent because at the trailer park you even do not have a shower.</s>
        <s>It is <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl's</ref> task to find a shower.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> is also independent because she is brave enough to steal cigarettes which also shows that she is able to organize her life herself.</s>
        <s>Especially with painting their car like a home and finding other thing in the car as furniture shows that they are really <choice><orig>independet</orig><reg>independent</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>There are maybe more independent that people at cities because there everything is still ordered.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, I do not agree with the statement because <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen's</ref> life and situation <choice><orig>shows</orig><reg>show</reg></choice> that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> would have a terrible, sad and lonely life without her mother and she still goes to school because of the American Dream.</s>
        <s>She does not need the help of the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Service</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>That is why I think she had to stay with her mother but maybe they could help them financially.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
