<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b11g01_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote>CPS should have taken Pearl away from Margot and the trailer park, put her into a foster home and help her to get a good education and prepare for a better way of life</quote>.</s>
        <s>In the following I am going to discuss if this statement is right or not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all we can say that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> had to live in a car for her whole life.</s>
        <s>This is one of the main reasons <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> should have taken <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away because she wouldn't have to live in a car her whole life.</s>
        <s>She could have lived in a house with her own room and her own bed.</s>
        <s>Another reason to take <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away is that the trailer park is a very dangerous area because you can buy guns anywhere in the park.</s>
        <s>The lack of safety is also shown with the murder of <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> without a reason.</s>
        <s>You could say that the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> would have helped <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> to get a better education but on the other hand we have the example of <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref>.</s>
        <s>She didn't get enough education even though she got taken by <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>On the one hand you could get a better life and live in a house with your own room and bed, but on the other hand you could also end up like <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref>, who had to sleep on the floor and only got cereals to eat.</s>
        <s>Even if she wouldn't have to live in a car anymore she could still live under bad conditions like <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> did.</s>
        <s>Furthermore you could add that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> wouldn't get enough love from her foster family like she got from <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is a good example for this because she never got to experience the love from her real parents.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The American Dream tells us that you can get a better and independent way of life, no matter who your parents are, just by working hard.</s>
        <s>This statement tells that the American Dream is possible to achieve if <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice>  takes care of you, even if you didn't get enough education.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Alltogether it can be said that this statement is not always true because <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> <choice><orig>proofs</orig><reg>proves</reg></choice> the opposite.</s>
        <s>On the one hand <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> would get a house to live in but or the other hand we can tell that her life with her mom wasn't that bad because she got enough education.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
