<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>b11g05_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <name type="misc">Indian Waters Trailer Park</name> is the place where <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> grew up.</s>
        <s>It is place in northern <name type="geo">Florida</name> far away from the <choice><orig>civilisation</orig><reg>civilization</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Close to the park is a dump that pollutes air and water.</s>
        <s>As a result the air and water get poisonous and the people get sick.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> descibes this as <quote>we breathed in the garbage</quote>.</s>
        <s>Especially for kids the unhealthy environment can be very dangerous.</s>
        <s>They are still growing and the poison could make them sick.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the schools and working places are far away and not reachable.</s>
        <s>They also got not working infrastructure there.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is an aspect of humanity to offer them the possibility of better living conditions.</s>
        <s>For example they could move them into manufactured houses or give the children into foster homes.</s>
        <s>That would give them the chance to get educated and to get a good job.</s>
        <s>They could <choice><orig>achiev</orig><reg>achieve</reg></choice> the American Dream and get from poor to rich.</s>
        <s>For this they only need good education which can be provided by the government when they move into foster homes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They also get financial help and health care.</s>
        <s>But the most important thing is that <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> would be safe and can live in a safe and healthy <choice><orig>enviorment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>As we saw living in a car is not safe.</s>
        <s>Because of the missing safety of living in a car her mother <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> got shot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> likes the community in the trailer park and wants to stay by her mom.</s>
        <s>She has friends there and gets treated very well.</s>
        <s>In a foster home can be abusive or bad people who let you live on circumstances that are worse than in the trailer park.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> for example lived in 17 foster families and was treated very bad.</s>
        <s>She is now traumatized and is not normal compared to kids in her age.</s>
        <s>This also can be a point against the foster homes.</s>
        <s>But if she wants to achieve something in life she must get out of the trailer park and enjoy a better education for a better future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Compared with the American Dream she can get from poor to rich but everybody knows that this is not possible anymore.</s>
        <s>In <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> society, especially in <name type="geo">America</name> the gap between the rich and the poor is increasing in number.</s>
        <s>The possibility to have a good future is today only reachable when you live in a wealthy or good educated family.</s>
        <s>But is it necessary to get traumatic like <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> to achieve this?</s>
        <s>Is there no other way?</s>
        <s>Another solution could be to move the families of the trailer park into a manufactured house neighbourhood.</s>
        <s>There they have schools and jobs in range and can get educated well.</s>
        <s>Furthermore they can stay together with her family.</s>
        <s>This is the most important aspect here.</s>
        <s>Who wants to get taken away from his family?</s>
        <s>Exactly nobody.</s>
        <s>It is the most terriblest thing you can do to a child.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To put it all in a nutshell getting education to achieve the American Dream is a good aspect but not good enough to take a child away from her mother.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
