<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11g41_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>After the decision <add>of the judge</add> is announced <name type="person">Starr</name> wants to show her disappointment, so she, <name type="person">Chris</name>, <name type="person">DeVante</name> and <name type="person">Seven</name> come to the neighbourhood to demonstrate their anger.</s>
        <s>The first demonstration runs out of control and its participants begin to riot.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> and the three boys try to leave with <name type="person">Seven's</name> car, but they run out of gas.</s>
        <s>They walk on foot and meet and peaceful demonstration.</s>
        <s>Its participants point black hairbrushes into the air, as a symbol of why <name type="person">Khalil</name> got shot.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> recognizes her lawyer <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>, the member of <name type="misc">Just Us for Justice</name>, standing on a police car and shouting into a bullhorn.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> is moved back and mixes the past with the present.</s>
        <s>After she remembers the shots by <name type="person">Officer Cruise</name>, she is brought back.</s>
        <s>That moment <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> recognizes <name type="person">Starr</name> in the crowd and asks her if she wants to fight with her voice.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> agrees and is set on top of the car.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Ofrah</name> gives her the bullhorn and <name type="person">Starr</name> thinks its effect is like one of a weapon.</s>
        <s>At first <name type="person">Starr</name> is anxious, but after a cop says demonstrators need to exit the street immediately her fear gives way to anger and new courage.</s>
        <s>She introduces herself to the crowd and says that this demonstration is about that <name type="person">Khalil</name> lived and his life mattered, not about how <name type="person">Khalil</name> died.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
