<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11g51_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name><name type="person">Seven</name>, <name type="person">Devante</name> and <name type="person">Chris</name> are getting to the intersection where <name type="person">Khalil</name> was killed by <name type="person">Officer Cruise</name>.</s>
        <s>There are protestors who are holding hairbrushes in the air and scremaing that a hairbrush is not a gun.</s>
        <s>The crowd is <choice><orig>leaded</orig><reg>lead</reg></choice> by <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>, <name type="person"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></name> attorney.</s>
        <s>She gota bullhorn and she is standing on the top of a police car.</s>
        <s>In the process where <name type="person">Starr</name>, <name type="person">Chris</name>, <name type="person">Devante</name> and <name type="person">Seven</name> trying to reach <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>, <name type="person">Starr</name> gets flashbacks of <name type="person">Khalil</name> getting shot.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> <choice><orig>reconize</orig><reg>recognizes</reg></choice> <name type="person">Starr</name> in the crowd she does a double-take and is surprised to see her here.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> says she is here for doing something.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> asks <name type="person">Starr</name> if she wants to fight the system and <name type="person">Starr</name> wants to.</s>
        <s>She gives <name type="person">Starr</name> the bullhorn and <name type="person">Starr</name> gets on top of the police car.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name>  got problems to start talking to the crowd and police but after a short period of time she reveals herself as the witness.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> is encouraged by the crowd and she starts to tell the true story of what happened that night.</s>
        <s>She also says that she is sick of being discriminated and now wants justice for <name type="person">Khalil</name> because he was a living human being and that there was no reason for killing him.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
