<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g38_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Carlos,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>you have recently told me that you think there were no losers of globalisation and everyone profited from free trade and free market.</s>
        <s>I have just read an article about three bloggers who published their experiences of seamstresses in <name type="geo">Cambodia</name>.</s>
        <s>Since I want to raise your awareness, I will briefly mediate it for you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The bloggers have spent one day in a garment factory and lived like a native worker.</s>
        <s>One states that she had never thought of such a place to exist.</s>
        <s>In her opinion, it was not comparable to what the media show.</s>
        <s>Another says despaired, she kept doing the same, and questions, what that was a life.</s>
        <s>She realises when speaking to the workers, in fact everyone should be equal.</s>
        <s>In the end, she states to have learned we were rich because other people were poor.</s>
        <s>The bloggers decide to campaign against the exploitation of garment workers in the future due to their experience.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To put it in a nutshell, they are stunned of the workers' situation and can't believe that people have to live in such a place.</s>
        <s>I hope I could make you aware of the fact that there <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>are</reg></choice> global issues, too, and you now look from another perspective on free trade and market.</s>
        <s>I am looking forward to hearing from you soon!</s>
      </p>
      <p>Greetings,</p>
      <p>
        <signed>John</signed>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><abbr>P.S.</abbr><expan>postscript</expan></choice>: How are you doing?</s>
        <s>Is everything fine with school etc.?</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
