<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g16_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following it will be analysed how <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> uses rhetorical devices to convince the reader/listener <quote>that dreams are worth fighting for</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 25f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>To begin with he first talks about the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">EDIT</gap> of division in the American country.</s>
        <s>He uses the comparison <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5f.)</ref> <quote>... by geography and ideology; race and religion; wealth and opportunity</quote> to show the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="word"/>.</s>
        <s>Americans should be divided.</s>
        <s>This has the effect of bringing the people to look on there certain aspects and questioning them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally he then uses various contrasts <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 9f.)</ref> <quote>In big cities and small towns; among men and women; young and old; black, white and brown</quote> to underline, that every American has the same vision and faith for the future.</s>
        <s>This has the effect of uniting the people because of their similarity and also increases the idea of the American Dream.</s>
        <s>Apart from that he then talks about his mother and her vision and passion for the same values of <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
        <s>To underline the unity between the different people and to eliminate the idea of circumstancial luck he uses an anaphora <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 19f.)</ref> <quote>no matter what colour you are, no matter where you're from, no matter how much money you have</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly he uses a climax <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 24)</ref> <quote><s>The steel plant had closed.</s><s>Jobs are disappearing.</s><s>In a forgotten corner of America, the American Dream was slipping away</s></quote> to underline the fact that he is needed as a president to turn the life of the Americans to the good.</s>
        <s>This also has the effect of showing himself in a better way and make people think up to him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To put in a nutshell <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses a lot of rhetorical devices to convince the listener of a better future with him as a president and <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to unite the Americans to fight for the American Dream.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
