<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g23_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>You can easily cut the sequence into 3 parts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>1: the dinner</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>2: <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav</ref> arguing</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>3: the police</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first scene <choice><orig>theres</orig><reg>there are</reg></choice> quick changes between the settings.</s>
        <s>There's much talking from all sides of the family, everytime someone talks, a close-up of their face is shown.</s>
        <s>It's easy to tell the director wanted to show the emotions of the characters with that.</s>
        <s>After <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Chris</ref> giving the interview they're all happy and relieved.</s>
        <s>In their prayer it's all together, the faces with expressions and the <choice><orig>dialog</orig><reg>dialogue</reg></choice> with the thoughts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the part with <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> the director wanted to do a slow change from the happy family feeling to the feeling of being in danger.</s>
        <s>That's shown by the dramatic position of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and his gangsters.</s>
        <s>They're standing directly in front of the window, standing still and starring through the window.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> first sees them, you see them from the point of her view with a little zoom.</s>
        <s>While all this happens the sounds of the diner and the rest of the family get muffled.</s>
        <s>All this creates a dark atmosphere that makes you feel the danger that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> <add>(and later <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav</ref>)</add> get to feel.</s>
        <s>The lights outside the diner are also more dark than bright, what supports the feeling of danger and not being safe.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene with the police is the most dynamic.</s>
        <s>It has a steady growing tension.</s>
        <s>When the police gets out of the car <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav</ref> tries to back <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> to the door of the diner.</s>
        <s>They catch up and press him against the wall.</s>
        <s>For the whole scene the red and blue light of the police car refelcts on the nearby buildings, persons and objects.</s>
        <s>This gives the watcher the regular tension of the police <choice><orig>presense</orig><reg>presence</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Also the short camera settings in scenes with much movement like <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav</ref> being pushed on the ground etc. are more settings per second.</s>
        <s>You for example see <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Seven</ref> making a quick move back as the cop tries to touch him, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav</ref> being pushed down and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav's</ref> face.</s>
        <s>It helps to build up tension.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the scene where the cop realises, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is the witness you see his face for a long time before he speaks his thought.</s>
        <s>The director used that to make the watcher think himself, what the policeman is thinking and what he'll do after realizing.</s>
        <s>This gives everything a special kind of tension.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up it's easy to see that the director used many devices for one purpose; building up tension.</s>
        <s>He uses light, movement, perspectives and even the <choice><orig>watchers</orig><reg>watcher's</reg></choice> own mind to do it.</s>
        <s>As for violence <add>(that is more shown indirectly than directly in this scene)</add> the director used quick camera jumps and fast movement in the scene.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
