<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g32_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given scene starts with a peaceful family dinner in a restaurant.</s>
        <s>The music playing in the <choice><orig>backround</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> is relaxing and calm and the family prays, thanking God for their family.</s>
        <s>Everyone's in a good mood.</s>
        <s>In this scene there are a lot of <choice><orig>close-up's</orig><reg>close-ups</reg></choice> and two-shots, which makes us focus on the shown <choice><orig>persons</orig><reg>person's</reg></choice> facial expressions and body language to read the emotions.</s>
        <s>At the beginning you can see everyone is happy and relaxed, but then we get to see a close-up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face.</s>
        <s>She looks serious out of the window and the background music starts to become thrilling.</s>
        <s>In the next long shot we get to see <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and two men standing in front of the family's car.</s>
        <s>It's dark outside and the camera starts zooming out which makes them seem dangerous.</s>
        <s>Then we see the family in the restaurant having dinner and the camera starts zooming out slowly again which makes it seem as if the two sides were in a fight and we see them for a second before the fight starts.</s>
        <s>This long shot of the family is from the outside of the restaurant and it seems as if the point of view we have is from <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s>This situation puts up the suspense in the scene.</s>
        <s>After that we get a close up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and now also he sees <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s>He tells his family to stay inside and goes outside to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and the other men.</s>
        <s>It's dark outside and now <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> doesn't seem like this nice father of a family anymore, he looks like that person with tattoos that can <choice><orig>punsh</orig><reg>punch</reg></choice> you to death.</s>
        <s>He tells <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> to leave his family in a loud, dark voice and <choice><orig>punshes</orig><reg>punches</reg></choice> him.</s>
        <s>The situation <choice><orig>seem</orig><reg>seems</reg></choice> very dangerous, it's dark outside, there are only some lights from the restaurant and we get a medium shot of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>.</s>
        <s>As soon as <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> punches <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> there's a long shot of the police car coming and we hear <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> <choice><orig>sirenes</orig><reg>sirens</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and his <q>friends</q> leave.</s>
        <s>The officers get out the car and we see a close up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>.</s>
        <s>He and the camera are moving backwards while explaining what happened, to show <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick's</ref> caution before the police men.</s>
        <s>The black officer pulls <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> to the window where his family is behind and they look at him.</s>
        <s>We get a close up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, to show how she feels in this situation.</s>
        <s>She's breathing heavily and her mother tells her to just breath.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> tells his wife to get his pocket with his <choice><abbr>ID</abbr><expan>identification</expan></choice> and she brings it outside while the police pushes <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> to the ground.</s>
        <s>He isn't feeling good in this situation, maybe even a little bit <choice><orig>week</orig><reg>weak</reg></choice> laying on the ground in front of his family and not able to protect them, which we see through a close up on his face.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> starts filming the situation and so do others which we see in a long shot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The music in the <choice><orig>backround</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> starts getting sad and calm again and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> shouts, she has every right to film the situation.</s>
        <s>That shows how she decided to not stay violent and speak up against racism.</s>
        <s>That moment the white police man realizes she's the <choice><orig>whitness</orig><reg>witness</reg></choice> we see his face in a medium close up and he <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> tells the black officer to leave <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> so he can stand up.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks angry at them and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> gets up while we see the police leaving.</s>
        <s>Now everyone checks on each other and the mother goes to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Sekani</ref>, to care for him, because he started crying.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The main purpose in this scene is to show the cohesion in <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> family.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> wants to protect <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> from <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and when he's laying on the ground under the cops, his family starts speaking up for him.</s>
        <s>The given scene has a lot of close-ups to show everyone's feelings and emotions in their facial expressions.</s>
        <s>This helps the movie-watcher to understand the scene and the people's thoughts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion this scene gives another example of how strong the bond in the family is and it shows <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> speaking up against police officers in person in first time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
