<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b10g27_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary recount">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to summarize the given sequence from the movie <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> directed by <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="director">George Tillmann Jr.</ref>, published in <date>2018</date>, it's about a black teenage girl named <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who has to switch between her two worlds; the poor black neighbourhood where she lives and the fancy suburban prep school she attends.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene begins with <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> family sitting in a diner, praying before they start eating, till <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks outside of the window and sees <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> standing in front of a big car watching her and her family with two other gang members.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> then realizes what's going on and goes outside very fast, he starts pushing <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> after he said something against <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, they are having a little fight, till suddenly the police comes, so <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and his gang members are driving <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Two police officers walk towards him with their hands already on their guns, the one is white and the other one is black.</s>
        <s>The police officers start pushing him against the window where <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and the others are sitting on the other side of it.</s>
        <s>They ask for his <choice><abbr>ID</abbr><expan>identification</expan></choice>, so <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> comes out to show it to them, the others follow her, they won't go back in, even after the police officers command them to.</s>
        <s>The next thing that's happening is the black police officer pushing <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> on the ground, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> takes her phone out to film everything, she and the black officer then have intense eye contact while he realises that she is the <choice><orig>whitness</orig><reg>witness</reg></choice>, there is already a crowd of people watching and filming what is happening around them.</s>
        <s>The police officer starts letting go of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>, they are threatening him to see this as a warning and then drive off.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> makes sure everyone is okay, in the end one can see <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> little brother <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Sekhani</ref> crying.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
