<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g24_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The director presents the actions and fighting <choice><orig>szenes</orig><reg>scenes</reg></choice> as if the viewer was there as well.</s>
        <s>Because of the quick moving camera action, the audience gets the feeling to be right in the middle of the fight.</s>
        <s>The music changed from happy to nervous and <choice><orig>dangorous</orig><reg>dangerous</reg></choice> sounding beats when <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> saw <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>, which made it clear that there will be violence next.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The loud siren sound when the police drove up to them prepared the audience for that there will be no good in the following <choice><orig>szene</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Together with the music, the flashing red and blue lights from the police <choice><orig>carr</orig><reg>car</reg></choice> made the whole <choice><orig>athmosphere</orig><reg>atmosphere</reg></choice> very hectic and stressed everyone out.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that people were filming the police action <choice><orig>proofes</orig><reg>proves</reg></choice> how serious it was and that they finally have to change something about that, posting it and spreading awareness.</s>
        <s>A standing by woman who was also recording told the officers, that this was happening too often and that it's enough.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You also notice how ignorant about the feelings of the people there the police is because they asked <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Seven</ref> for his ID, even though he just said that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> didn't do anything wrong which was obviously the truth.</s>
        <s>Even worse is, that he was an underage minor.</s>
        <s>You get to see the <choice><orig>dissapointment</orig><reg>disappointment</reg></choice> and anger of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> in a close up clip, when the officer pushed him against the glass window.</s>
        <s>His expressions also <choice><orig>shows</orig><reg>show</reg></choice> sadness, that his wife and kids have to see him like that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end of the <choice><orig>szene</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice> we get to see <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Sekani</ref> cyring inside, what shows what violence can lead to.</s>
        <s>All in all the mood of the entire <choice><orig>szene</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice> changed in seconds.</s>
        <s>At first, the <choice><orig>audiene</orig><reg>audience</reg></choice> is presented to a nice family dinner with a loving and greatful family praying, thanking god for <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>At the end of the <choice><orig>szene</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice> everyone is in shock and terrified.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, the purposes of the sequence are showing that such a heartbreaking event can happen anytime anyday and to show under what pressure black <choice><orig>familys</orig><reg>families</reg></choice> in the <q>ghetto</q> constantly live in.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
