<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g30_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence to be analysed has a distinct function for the film.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the beginning the light is yellow, which gives a warm and lovely <choice><orig>admosphere</orig><reg>atmosphere</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>directore</orig><reg>director</reg></choice> chose to use medium close ups in the beginning, when they pray and smile at each other.</s>
        <s>This aspect expresses the feelings of the characters in a more detailed way.</s>
        <s>When they talk about what they are <choice><orig>thankfull</orig><reg>thankful</reg></choice> of, a medium shot of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Sekani</ref> was used to show him <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> happy.</s>
        <s>The scene takes place in the evening, which is noticeable because of the darkness outside.</s>
        <s>Calming music is playing in the background, which gives <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> lovely and nice <choice><orig>admosphere</orig><reg>atmosphere</reg></choice> as well.</s>
        <s>The way the music stops in the second <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> notices the gang outside, draws attention to her inner feeling and gives the viewer the chance to feel what <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> feels.</s>
        <s>The director chose to zoom in slowing from a long shot to a medium shot, when the gang is shown.</s>
        <s>This aspect is used to express the seriousness of the situation that's happening.</s>
        <s>In the moment she notices them, a close up is used to show her facial expression in a detailed way.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> walks forward to them, the <choice><orig>directer</orig><reg>director</reg></choice> uses a point of view shot of the gang to show <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> alone and them <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> three.</s>
        <s>A lot of over shoulder shots are used.</s>
        <s>Those over the shoulder shots, put the viewer in the back of the story.</s>
        <s>It feels like as if they can see everything that happens from a perspective behind of the person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The way <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> is <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> pulled against the window, and the long shot of the rest of the family looking at him, expresses the fear in them.</s>
        <s>The viewer feels like another guest <choice><orig>whos</orig><reg>who's</reg></choice> watching.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An important shot the author uses, is the point of view of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, at the end of the scene.</s>
        <s>The viewer feels like he's <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, which gives him the chance to feel more into the scene.</s>
        <s>It feels like the viewer looks down at <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> laying on the floor.</s>
        <s>The medium close up and side profile in the end when <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Sekani</ref> is crying, shows his feelings from another type of angle.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>purpos</orig><reg>purpose</reg></choice> of the scene is firstly to show the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carters</ref> <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> a happy family after all they have been <choice><orig>threw</orig><reg>through</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It shows the strongness of them and the love.</s>
        <s>Another purpose may be is to always stay behind your family.</s>
        <s>The sequence also shows the fear, even <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> who always seems to be strong was in fear, that black people need to live with, with their whole <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
