<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g37_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given scene has a distinct function for the movie.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the course of the scene the viewer is introduced to the cohesion of the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carter's</ref> family.</s>
        <s>Moreover the given scene presents <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> as a loving father, who tries to protect his family <add>(here especially <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>)</add> in every way.</s>
        <s>The scene presents <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> as the witness and her effect on her environment.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene to be analysed especially presents the <choice><orig>cohension</orig><reg>cohesion</reg></choice> of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family in each way.</s>
        <s>The praying and the close ups from <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref>, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa's</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick's</ref> face <choice><orig>emphasizes</orig><reg>emphasize</reg></choice> the loving family.</s>
        <s>Moreover <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> <quote>Thank you for my family</quote> shows the family keeping together.</s>
        <s>The close up shows her happy and thankful expression.</s>
        <s>The calm and melodical music is used to underline the grateful family who seems <choice><orig>hopefull</orig><reg>hopeful</reg></choice> and happy.</s>
        <s>Moreover the warm colors create a comfortable and calm atmosphere.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> notices <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> outside the restaurant her facial expression changes.</s>
        <s>This is done by a big close up.</s>
        <s>The music <choice><orig>change</orig><reg>changes</reg></choice> to a dramatic background music clarifies <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> anxiety again.</s>
        <s>The slowly zooming in of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> emphasizes danger and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> fear.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> is presented as the loving father he is and leaves the restaurant as soon as he notices <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> too.</s>
        <s>The atmosphere directly changes as <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> goes outside and yells.</s>
        <s>He is shown in a long shot and the camera moves with him.</s>
        <s>When they start to fight, the camera follows them and makes a 180 degree move with them.</s>
        <s>By doing so, the hectic, trouble and anger of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> are emphasized and the fact that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> tries to protect <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is underlined.</s>
        <s>When the police car arrives, the blue and red lights create a cold but also dangerous atmosphere.</s>
        <s>The officers seem very violent which also is emphasized of the hectic camera moving.</s>
        <s>The black officer is the one who pulls <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> on the ground, even he has not seen the fight.</s>
        <s>The brutality of the police <choice><orig>cause</orig><reg>causes</reg></choice> the worried expressions of the family.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> lays on the ground the close <choice><orig>up's</orig><reg>ups</reg></choice> from the faces <choice><orig>clarifies</orig><reg>clarify</reg></choice> their worryness and their purpose to fight for each other.</s>
        <s>The family cohesion is reflected again.</s>
        <s>As soon as the officers notice that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is the witness the music gets quiet and they stop being violent.</s>
        <s>The mid-shot of the black officer clarifies his worried expression.</s>
        <s>The mid-shot of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who films the whole <q>pull-over</q> demonstrates her worryness but also her anger against the police.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In summary one can say that the given scene foreshadows the anger of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>, because <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> told in the interview about the drugs he sells in <name type="geo">Garden Heights</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The purposes of the given scene are clearly presented and underlined with camera movements and effects.</s>
        <s>The family <choice><orig>cohension</orig><reg>cohesion</reg></choice>, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> as a loving father and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who <choice><orig>effects</orig><reg>affects</reg></choice> her environment with the fact that she is the witness clarifies in the course of the scene.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
