<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g25_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence introduces <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family in relationship to each other.</s>
        <s>The scene also underlines police violence against the black community.</s>
        <s>The sequence also introduces <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> as caring parents.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene is pretty important for the outcome of the movie, because the relationship between <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> is emphasized.</s>
        <s>The relationship between <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> will play an important role in course of the movie.</s>
        <s>The function of the sequence is to highlight the rivality between <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and to point out the police violence against the black community.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence starts with close-ups of a high number of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family, which mainly show the happy mood of them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family are praying, which means they are thankful for <choice><orig>themselfes</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An extreme close-up shows <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is non-verbal communicating with her mom while praying.</s>
        <s>The extreme close-up <choice><orig>focusses</orig><reg>focuses</reg></choice> on <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> eyes, while <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> prays for <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her school career.</s>
        <s>This emphasizes <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> as a caring parent.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In a sudden everything changes, in front of the restaurant <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and two of his gang members look to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The camera first shows <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looking scared out of the window.</s>
        <s>The viewer wants to see what <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks for.</s>
        <s>This intensifies the action.</s>
        <s>Then the camera zooms in towards <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> from <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> point of view.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> then also sees <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>, he tells <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> to stay here.</s>
        <s>At this point everything changes, no more emotional music and happy faces.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> goes outside and confronts <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>, they seem like rivals.</s>
        <s>Then the <choice><orig>sirene</orig><reg>siren</reg></choice> of a police car sets in and the blue and red lights change very fast and also the high number of cuts make the moment appear hectic.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> drives away, the acceleration of the car and the tires emphasize <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> wants to get away.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The officers put <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> down in front of the family.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The officers realize <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is the witness, a moment of silence emphasizes.</s>
        <s>The over-the-shoulder shots intensify the action when the police officers walk to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
