<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12g37_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> going to comment the claim <quote>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future properity an global standing</quote> by <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> from the text <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref> published in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> on <date>January 27th 2015</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Are foreign language so important for the <name type="geo">UK</name>?</s>
        <s>You can agree with this point by looking the development of the globalisation.</s>
        <s>With new fast growing markets and more trade you need more languages to communicate.</s>
        <s>A other point is that the competition is getting more, so if you are only able to speak one language it can be hard for you to find a <choice><orig>Job</orig><reg>job</reg></choice> in other countries.</s>
        <s>Furthermore cultures are getting mixed or maybe lost.</s>
        <s>When everybody would talk in <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> we would lost much history.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand you can say that <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> is a global language so everybody should be able to speak it.</s>
        <s>Also you can say that in a globalized world <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> more important to speak <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> well, so with high <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> skills, you are in a good position to get high-paied job in westernisated countries.</s>
        <s>In the future everything is getting closer to each other, so cultures and languages are not so important like in fruther times.</s>
        <s>Maybe in 100 years we only have one language and this language will maybe be <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion foreign language are not really important for people from the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>It can be nice if your able to speak different languages, for example like Chinese, but in my eyers nothing will be so important in the future like the global language <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
