<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g47_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name>
        <date>30th November 2021</date>
        <s>In reference to the article <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref></s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Sir or Madam,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>regarding to your article about learning foreign languages in the <name type="geo">UK</name>, I would like to give you some critical feedback.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the beginning I can say that I do not agree that much with your opinion to improve the language skills.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I understand your motivation for <choice><orig>globalizational</orig><reg>globalization</reg></choice> aspect, but you forgot to mention that having the skill to talk and write in foreign languages will not make you instantly successful.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You have to work hard anyways to be successful, <choice><orig>The</orig><reg>the</reg></choice> career is not influenced by talking more or less languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I support your opinion about taking responsibility for educational chances, but opportunities of different and many perspectives.</s>
        <s>It is not <choice><orig>neccessarely</orig><reg>necessarily</reg></choice> important to know a foreign language to be successful, as I mentioned before, but maybe a chance for diversity in universities or schools to be happy and improve the career aspect.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Many people in the world got the best career they could have, but are not happy for what they are working for.</s>
        <s>So I think the aspect to grow the opportunity for language studying as good for itself is superfluous, but for the diversity in the work place and business career it is a good influence for living <choice><orig>happy</orig><reg>happily</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
