<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g51_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the article <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: 'can't, won't, don't</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and published on <name type="misc">Telegraph</name> on the <date>27th of January 2015</date>, <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> writes about the foreign language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name> and how it has gotten worse over the years.</s>
        <s>In <choice><orig>th</orig><reg>the</reg></choice> following article will be summarized focused on <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> statements on the language learning and his own personal view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article is <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> in eleven paragraphs and fifty one lines.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> starts by naming a hypothesis just quoting the last three words of his <choice><orig>articles</orig><reg>article's</reg></choice> name.</s>
        <s>It mentions, that while parimary schools are focused on more, the number of <name type="geo">UK</name> students interested in foreign languages and the amount of people doing <name type="misc">A-levels</name> and <name type="misc">GCSE</name> is shrinking.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> states that, comparing the amount of taken exams in the year <date>2014</date> and <date>at the end of the 1990s</date>.</s>
        <s>After that <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> proceeds to make fun of people that htink everyone on the market speaks <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> and technology is supposed to help with the language barrier.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that, he explains how language learning is essential for the <name type="geo">UK</name> in terms of trade, cultural exports, <choice><orig>keepin</orig><reg>keeping</reg></choice> the nation safe and some other aspects.</s>
        <s>For example in some businesses in the <name type="geo">UK</name>, because two thirds of them require foreign language skills, but can't find people like that in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>Because of that these businesses have to rely on <choice><orig>translaters</orig><reg>translators</reg></choice> or staff from overseas.</s>
        <s>He states, that an employee with diverse language skills is more needed than someone without, which is part of the reason, why the <name type="geo">UK</name> needs more young people taking part in language learning.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He finishes his article by addressing parents of the <name type="geo">UK</name> to help <choice><orig>initiating</orig><reg>initiate</reg></choice> a change, because the educational system is unable to do so alone.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
