<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g45_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne's</ref> newspaper article will be analysed concerning his use of language and communicative strategies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He begins with <choice><orig>underling</orig><reg>underlining</reg></choice> the British mentality towards foreign language learning by using the words <quote>can't, won't, don't</quote> to conclude the national view in both the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">nonne</gap> of his article and in <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">line one</ref>.</s>
        <s>He thereby also creates the comparison to a small, grizzling <choice><orig>Baby</orig><reg>baby</reg></choice>, refusing to eat <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> vegetables even though they're good for him.</s>
        <s>This immediately gives the reader the feeling of not wanting to be seen as one of these <quote>can't, won't, don't</quote>-people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of his most convincing writing traits is his constant reference to studies and numbers which perfectly back up what he is saying, mostly about the <choice><orig>declinig</orig><reg>declining</reg></choice> interest in <choice><orig>youg</orig><reg>young</reg></choice> people to learn foreign languages <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 3-5, cf. ll. 10-12, cf. ll. 13-16, cf. ll. 28-30)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This gives the reader the impression of a super educated, very factual article, even though the author isn't all that, as he manages to also add his own bias to the studies, for example by using the word <quote>sadly</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> to describe the results of a study.</s>
        <s>This gives the reader an instant negative judgement of these numbers without letting him/ her form their own <choice><orig>conlusion</orig><reg>conclusion</reg></choice> from a study.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another part of his article where the author's views on the matter come through heavily are the <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">lines 18-23</ref>, in which he debunks people disagreeing with his opinion by using ironic remarks, which <choice><orig>one</orig><reg>on</reg></choice> the one hand make the author seem more down to earth to the reader but also have a comedic aspect in them which gives the reader the impression of not having to take <choice><orig>counter arguments</orig><reg>counterarguments</reg></choice> seriously.</s>
        <s>This is further supported by a very sly description of the critics: <quote>Perfectly intelligent people</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is a hidden way of saying those people are usually smart, but astoundingly dim concerning the discussed subject, which once again takes credibility from those people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A further communicative strategy the author makes use of is displayed in the <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">lines 24-27</ref>.</s>
        <s>Here the author states his own opinion but doesn't mark it as such by using terms like "I feel", "I think" or "I believe", thus <choice><orig>desguising</orig><reg>disguising</reg></choice> a personal view as a fact to the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> also chooses his pronouns very carefully: He makes multiple use of inclusive and exclusive language.</s>
        <s>On the one hand he makes the reader feel closer to him and makes clear that this is a problem they must fight <quote>hand in hand</quote>, for example in <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">line 6-7</ref>: <quote>of us recommissioning our collective brains</quote>, in which he also underlines the inclusion by using the word <quote>collective</quote>, but also in <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">line 48</ref>: <quote>we as parents</quote> and in <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">line 50</ref>: <quote>our children's</quote>, with one "super-inclusion" in <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">line 46</ref>, in which he on the other hand first of all excludes the reader as parents for his appeal to be recognized as one, but then continues to make sure he himself also has to tackle on this problem and that it's a duty they must face together.</s>
        <s>(This also implies he is already doing it correctly).</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another way of praising the advocates of his opinion and bashing the people who don't give foreign language learning as much importance as <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> feels it deserves is him writing <quote>forward thinking universities</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(line 36-37)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This implies to the reader that any universities who don't have similar programs as the ones he supports are "backward-thinking".</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another way in which the author underlines the immediate <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">vedescity</gap> for action is the combination of the overstatement / hyperbole <quote>There is no doubt</quote> and the personification <quote>the UK needs</quote> in <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">line 42</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This gives the reader the idea of a <name type="geo">United Kingdom</name> which can't "live on" in the future without <choice><orig>youg</orig><reg>young</reg></choice> people having developed their foreign language skills.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally, in his <choice><orig>Appeal</orig><reg>appeal</reg></choice>, <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> makes use of yet another metaphor: <quote>as essential strings to our children's bows</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(line 50)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He hereby paints a picture of <choice><orig>Parents</orig><reg>parents</reg></choice> catapulting their children into a better future by sorting them out with international and language-related experiences <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. l. 49)</ref> and also a of completing the children's tool set and making their feats strong enough for them to get a good job and life when they grow up.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> uses many examples and studies to first of all back up his point that the interest in foreign language learning is decreasing and then follows up by convincing the reader of the importance of learning languages next to English, using many stylistic devices auch as irony and inclusive language.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
