<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g50_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Nowadays learning of foreign languages could be important for living and communicating in different countries of for working <choice><orig>their</orig><reg>there</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> the author of the article <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref> from <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> on <date>27th January 2015</date>, claims that <quote>language larning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Now there comes up the question in how far?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To start you could say that our whole world is embossed by a big global change.</s>
        <s>The globalization includes also the global standing from every country <choice><orig>becaus</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> language plays a big role in trading, working or education sector.</s>
        <s>If <name type="geo">UK</name> students represent now a kind of laziness because they cannot communicate with people all over the world it creates a disliking picture on the whole <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that are languages significant for other sectors like global communication in general or for the main education.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course you can say that our <name type="misc">iPhones</name> could translate all those but it always <choice><orig>take</orig><reg>takes</reg></choice> more time to firstly type in a whole message or text than to just speak to each other.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So to conclude I would agree with <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne's</ref> statement that foreign language learning is vital or very important due to the big usability in much sectors and especially for the global standing in our today's modernized increasing world of new chances and opportunities.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
