<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g34_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal response">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>you asked me three questions about plastic to go <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice> cups.</s>
        <s>I found <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> <choice><orig>news paper</orig><reg>newspaper</reg></choice> <choice><orig>articel</orig><reg>article</reg></choice> of the <name type="misc">Süddeutsche Zeitung</name> which was written by <ref target="a10gk4_2" type="author">Barbara Vorsamer</ref> and was published in <date>22. February 2016</date> and this article gives you answers to your questions.</s>
        <s>You asked me if the <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice> cups to go are in <name type="geo">Germany</name> so popular <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The answer is yes, so many people in big cities in <name type="geo">Germany</name> use these cups because they have no time and are <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> busy to sit in a cafe to drink their <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This is also a little sign to say <q>I have no time, I am very <choice><orig>importent</orig><reg>important</reg></choice></q> or that you have this money to buy this <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Your next question was if they are problematic.</s>
        <s>This is a very easy question because they need 1,5 <foreign xml:lang="de">Milliarden</foreign> liter water, 64000 tons of oil to produce these cups.</s>
        <s>In <name type="geo">Germany</name> every year 2,8 <foreign xml:lang="de">Milliarden</foreign> <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice> to go cups go to the trash and they are not recycling so they were all burned.</s>
        <s>So these to go cups are absolutely problematic.</s>
        <s>Your last question was if it is possible to create alternatives or which alternatives you can use.</s>
        <s>This is the most difficult question because of course you can use alternatives but they are not so good as the to go cups.</s>
        <s>You can buy a cup which you can use very often but you to carry it and the <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice> in this cup is not so delicious.</s>
        <s>The problem is that you do not have good alternatives so everybody uses the plastic cups.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope that I answered your questions if not please answer me.</s>
        <s>I hope we see us soon.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Goodbye John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
