<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g30_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I received your e-mail and the questions you have, regarding <quote>coffee to go</quote> in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>I want to help you with your project so of course I am going to answer all of them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The answer to your first question is yes, coffee cups are also very popular here in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>In fact it is a symbol for being wealthy and busy with work.</s>
        <s>People carry their cups with them like an accessory.</s>
        <s>Even if <quote>coffee to go</quote> is very comfortable it is also very problematic, considering that over 7 million cups a day end up in the trash.</s>
        <s>This is not <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> friendly at all because all of the <choice><orig>ressources</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice> that are being used for a coffee cup are going to waste, after only 15 minutes of using it.</s>
        <s>Furthermore these cups cannot be recycled because the cups are made out of a mix of plastic and paper, so you cannot even throw them away in the right bin.</s>
        <s>I have been thinking about good alternatives and I want to give you some examples.</s>
        <s>You can either buy a sustainable cup, even though it is not the best solution because of the sizes that are available on the market.</s>
        <s>The only solution that makes sense is to not drink coffee while being in a rush.</s>
        <s>You should sit down and take a few minutes out of you schedule to drink coffee.</s>
        <s>If you don't have time for coffee, you should take it as a sign to slow down.</s>
        <s>I hope I could help you and if you have more questions just write me another e-mail.</s>
        <s>I hope your presentation is going to be flawless!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
