<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g10_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The newspaper article <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="title">Langauge learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name>: can't won't, don't</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>, on the <date>27 January 2015</date>, in the <name type="misc">Telegraph</name> is about the development of language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> describes the national view on speaking foreign languages with three words <quote>can't, won't, don't</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>over the number of <name type="geo">UK</name> students which study foreign languages has been steady decline, says <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>there are more languages on the plan and more primary schools, but the <name type="misc">GCSE</name> and <name type="misc">A-level</name> has stalled.</s>
        <s>Most people think they don't mind and the future is mobile devices, like iPhones which translate everything you want.</s>
        <s>But the author gives his opinion to that and says that this is <quote>Cobblers</quote>.</s>
        <s>Language learning is important for <name type="geo">UK's</name> future.</s>
        <s>It is important for their trades, prosperity, cultural exports, diplomacy and national security, so <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Not only this, more than two-thirds of <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses need for language skills.</s>
        <s>The problem is, that the <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses trust the translators.</s>
        <s>The author says that it is good universities are <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">aluing</gap> students to study language alongside another degree subject.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A lawyer with language skills is more worth than a pure lawyer, it doesn't matter how good you are, says the author.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>all in all the author says that foreign language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name> is very important and must be better than now.</s>
        <s>His personal view shows us that he <choice><orig>criticise</orig><reg>criticises</reg></choice> the school and education system.</s>
        <s>There is only one really good thing, he says in line 24.</s>
        <s>That is his opinion.</s>
        <s>Moreover he is <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> parent and he wants to create a better system for his and everyone <choice><orig>else</orig><reg>else's</reg></choice> child.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
