<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g11_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> writes that it is a problem that many young people do not know more languages than <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But is language learning really vital for the<name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>on the one hand not everybody in the world speaks <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> so it is better to know a second language.</s>
        <s>On the other hand not everybody is able or has the skill to learn another language because it can be hard sometimes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But if you can a second language it is possible and easier to study or work abroad and it is easier for workers and students to work/study in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>So the <name type="geo">UK</name> can also get more multinational (-friendly).</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is true that a lot of people speak <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> but not everybody.</s>
        <s>So people who get the chance should learn an other language for people that do not have a chance to learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>And when everybody sees that the number of students who learning an other language goes down, you know that that is a huge problem.</s>
        <s>Humans are social species and they need to communicate and not just in <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The best part of learning new languages is that when you learned one it is way easier to learn more.</s>
        <s>For example <choice><orig>roman</orig><reg>Roman</reg></choice> languages.</s>
        <s>If you can speak <choice><orig>french</orig><reg>French</reg></choice> it is also easy to understand <choice><orig>portogese</orig><reg>Portuguese</reg></choice>, or <choice><orig>spanish</orig><reg>Spanish</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This is also a <choice><orig>roman</orig><reg>Roman</reg></choice> language.</s>
        <s>So what is stopping you from language learning?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In a nutshell language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing.</s>
        <s>To not know a second language is contraproductive.</s>
        <s>With a second language you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> make any mistake.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
