<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>But in his argumentation <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> is methods of persuasion to steer the reader in a particular direction and convince him of his opinion.</s>
        <s><quote>Can't, won't don't</quote><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> which <choice><orig>ist</orig><reg>is</reg></choice> also the title of his comment <choice><orig>ist</orig><reg>is</reg></choice> a <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">frifecta</gap> of in formal words associated with the <quote>national view on speaking foreign languages</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It intends to make the reader feel that the <name type="geo">UK's</name> general public shows to interest in learning foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In contrast to that he advises the readers to <quote>re-commissioning our collective brains</quote><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">adviering</gap> a positive connotation to the act of choosing more foreign language studies.</s>
        <s>Also this implies that there already is a general interest in these topics but it has to be reactivated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Following this he gives a statistic that states that <quote>10.000 fewer language <name type="misc">A-Level</name> exams were taken last year than at the end of the <date>1990s</date></quote><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 9f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>But this number is not very high considering the number of students, the long timespan and higher participation in <name type="misc">GCSE</name>-level exams which are not considered.</s>
        <s>With the high number of 10.000 <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> wants to give his readers the impression of a big decline in foreign language studies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The authors makes an extensive use of the parentheses <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 6f., ll. 13f., l. 32)</ref> in order to weaken counter arguments like in line 6f. where he belittles to pregres in primary schools.</s>
        <s>By saying that <quote>there's a long haul ahead</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> the readers get the impresion that there is almost no development yet.</s>
        <s>Furthermore <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> builds himself as the expert in the topic.</s>
        <s>In line 13f. he regutes contrary opinion and backs up with the colloquial term <quote>Cobblers</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He marks his <choice><orig>opponents</orig><reg>opposing</reg></choice> arguments as nonsense, the reader is <choice><orig>trough</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> the effect <choice><orig>indrectly</orig><reg>indirectly</reg></choice> advised to not pay any further attention to those opposing claims.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also he calls those with opposing opinions <quote>perfectly intelligent people</quote> in an irony.</s>
        <s>As he expects the reader to get the opposite <choice><orig>impressision</orig><reg>impression</reg></choice> through it also being a hyperbole.</s>
        <s>The same stylistic devices are used later <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 14f.)</ref> where <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> presents his contraries always having a solution as comedic so that they less believable to the reader became.</s>
        <s>With oppositions <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll 20ff., l. 26)</ref> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> says how things <quote>should be</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 26)</ref> or how things are.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With the parallelism and <choice><orig>klimax</orig><reg>climax</reg></choice> in the lines 16ff. the necessity of foreign language skills for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> economy are underlined.</s>
        <s>There is an emphasis on language through the alliteration <quote>language learning</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> and an anaphora <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 16f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The enumeration of national traits of employs the impression of a high <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">mee</gap> of languages and how they <quote>are essential</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This impression is aided by the fact that words like <quote>prosperity</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> have a very positive connotation.</s>
        <s>The same is to be found in line 27 <choice><orig>withe</orig><reg>with</reg></choice> an additional language to a profession is more <quote>attractive</quote> to <quote>employers</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 27)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The mentioning of the employers is like when <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> refers to the <name type="misc">CBI/Peasan Education and Skills Survey</name> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> as an authority supporting his claims.</s>
        <s>It achieves even though they might only agree in that particular point to the author that the reader gets the impression that other experts share <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> opinion what makes him more <choice><orig>believeable</orig><reg>believable</reg></choice> down the line.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> employs the inclusive pronouns <quote>we</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 33)</ref> and <quote>us</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 35)</ref>.</s>
        <s>They make the reader relate more to the topic and make them feel more included so that they accept the described problems as their own and fall more easily to <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> proposed solution.</s>
        <s>Especially considering the <quote>tough reality in <choice><orig>thaugh</orig><reg>tough</reg></choice> job market</quote>.</s>
        <s>Considering all these factors it is clear that only through these techniques of persuasion <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> can achieve his goal of spreading his opinion and allowing him to make broad claims <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 30f.)</ref></s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
