<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g07_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The newspaper article <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="title">Language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name>: can't, won't, don't</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and published on the <date>27th of January in 2015</date> at <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> deals with the learning of foreign languages in the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the authors personal view likewise what he thinks works good what bad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article is from a formal paper in this case from <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name>.</s>
        <s>It is <choice><orig>Addressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> to the readers of this paper and <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> wrote it to inform them about the situation and to share his own opinion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The content of the artucle is the loss of learning and <choice><orig>useing</orig><reg>using</reg></choice> foreign languages.</s>
        <s>Besides the fact that there are fewer people studying foreign languages, the number of <name type="misc">A-Level</name> exams and <name type="misc">GCSE</name> went down or <choice><orig>atleast</orig><reg>at least</reg></choice> the uptake stalled.</s>
        <s>This development is not good for the <name type="geo">UK</name> because foreign language skills are essential for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> properity and global standing and also necessary in the <name type="geo">UK's</name> businesses.</s>
        <s>Especially because of their fast-growing markets.</s>
        <s>Furthermore language skills can be really helpful at the job market which means that fore emploers it is more <foreign xml:lang="de">interessant</foreign> or atrractive if you have a combination of a subject with a language <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> just of of these.</s>
        <s>To support the learning of languages there are already some primary schools that start teaching languages and some <choice><orig>universitys</orig><reg>universities</reg></choice> are giving their students a chance to study a language alongside another degree subject.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The authors intention is to inform the readers and to show his own opinion.</s>
        <s>He writes subjective because he wants to make his opinion clear.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To convince the reader of his opinion <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Worn</orig><reg>Worne</reg></choice></ref> makes use of some persuasive techniques.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He makes use of inclusive language for example in line 1 <quote>our national view</quote> or <quote>we as parents</quote><ref target="a12gk1_1">(line 33)</ref>, to include the reader into his article <ref target="a12gk1_1">(line 34, 35)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this <choice><orig>strategie</orig><reg>strategy</reg></choice> the reader feels closer to the author and <choice><orig>automaticly</orig><reg>automatically</reg></choice> thinks more or deeper about what he said.</s>
        <s>He also uses <choice><orig>studys</orig><reg>studies</reg></choice> and examples based on facts to underline his arguments and to make it more <choice><orig>authenticy</orig><reg>authentic</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article is structured in 11 parts.</s>
        <s>Every part is between one and a few sentences and mostly gives one argument or underlines the argument before.</s>
        <s>The first part is from line 1 to line 2.</s>
        <s>The second is from line three to line five.</s>
        <s>The third one is from line nine to line 10.</s>
        <s>From line 12 to line 15 is the fourth part and from line 16 to line 18 the fifth.</s>
        <s>The sixth part goes from line 19 to line 23.</s>
        <s>The seventh part goes from line 24 to line 26, followed by the <choice><orig>eigth</orig><reg>eighth</reg></choice> part from line 27 to line 29.</s>
        <s>Next is the 10 part from line 30 to line 31 and the last part goes from line 32 to line 35.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>John Worn</orig><reg>John Worne</reg></choice></ref> uses formal and educated language for his article.</s>
        <s>He writes long but still clear sentences so that they are easy enough for the reader to understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Worn</orig><reg>Worne</reg></choice></ref> also makes use of some stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>He starts his article with <quote>Can't, won't, don't</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1">(l. 1)</ref> which is a list.</s>
        <s>In this case it is to make the reader curious about the article.</s>
        <s>He makes use of another listing in line 17: <quote>our trade, prosperity, cultural exports, diplomacy and national security</quote> to show the reader how important languages are and to give some examples.</s>
        <s>He also uses an alliteration <quote>Language learning</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1">(l. 16)</ref> to really get the readers focus on this aspect.</s>
        <s>he uses another alliteration <quote>Skills survey showed</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1">(l. 16)</ref> again to get the whole focus of the reader on this point.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the <choice><orig>titel</orig><reg>title</reg></choice> he uses the same alliteration as in line 16: <quote>Language learning</quote>, like this the reader already knows what the artucle is about.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Worn's</orig><reg>Worne's</reg></choice></ref> article the first sentence and also the first paragraph, which is <quote>Can't, won't, don't, three words which sum up out national view on speaking foreign languages</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1">(l. 1-2)</ref>, is very important, because it catches the readers <choice><orig>atention</orig><reg>attention</reg></choice> and based on the first lines the reader decides to either keep on reading or not to do so.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all once can say <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Worn</orig><reg>Worne</reg></choice></ref> is in the opinion that the <name type="geo">UK</name> should give more support on learning foreign languages because languages are really important <choice><orig>nowdays</orig><reg>nowadays</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>To convince his readers he makes use of stylistic devices and also some peruasive techniques.</s>
        <s>So one can say by doing this he has good chances to convince his readers.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
