<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g13_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>If language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing like a <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> claimed in his article in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> is a good question.</s>
        <s>Do you think our phones will take over this part for us or do we still need the direct communication between people to articulate?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>you may think globalization brings the whole world more together and we are all <choice><orig>conected</orig><reg>connected</reg></choice> on one place now but the problem is still the distance.</s>
        <s>We now fly to other countries, meet new people and work for and with different countries but like <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> in his article said <quote>more should learn foreign languages</quote>.</s>
        <s>It may be <choice><orig>helpfull</orig><reg>helpful</reg></choice> to use your phone to make it do everything to you but if you work with people for a long time or went to <choice><orig>finde</orig><reg>find</reg></choice> friends it makes it way easier or even more pure if you can communicate in one language.</s>
        <s>And also you get <choice><orig>includet</orig><reg>included</reg></choice> and meet new cultures.</s>
        <s>And that's what people want when <choice><orig>thei</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> travel or meet people from different countries.</s>
        <s>Best example for that are big companies that expand their culture.</s>
        <s>For example <name type="misc">IKEA</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And how would you feel if someone is always holding a phone in front of himself to wait five minutes to understand you?</s>
        <s>In the beginning you would understand it and try to help him by yourself but just like with <choice><orig>babyes</orig><reg>babies</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>At one point they have to do it <choice><orig>themselfs</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>And if you always need to wait for an answer of your phone you <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice> contact to the person who <choice><orig>originaly</orig><reg>originally</reg></choice> told you <choice><orig>somthing</orig><reg>something</reg></choice> and you lose your whole topic or it gets boring.</s>
        <s>People will think <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> you who is boring and leave you out of conversations.</s>
        <s>Another point is that we all are still deeply <choice><orig>conected</orig><reg>connected</reg></choice> to our language and our countries and it makes us happy when someone makes the effort to learn it.</s>
        <s>So if you stay in your comfort zone and never learn another language to interact with people globalisation will go wrong and it's everyone for <choice><orig>themselv</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice> again.</s>
        <s>How do we go against global problems like the <foreign xml:lang="de">klima</foreign> change and plastic in the oceans then.</s>
        <s>We'll all just think for <choice><orig>ourselfs</orig><reg>ourselves</reg></choice> and again try to let others do everything like with our language.</s>
        <s>We have to work together and for that we have to be one united planet that understands each other and listens <choice><orig>direktly</orig><reg>directly</reg></choice> to the person in front of you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So all in one we all should try to learn at least one other language to keep contacts.</s>
        <s>And if you learned <choice><orig>wille</orig><reg>while</reg></choice> working or traveling somewhere else you may <choice><orig>finde</orig><reg>find</reg></choice> out it's actually pretty fun to understand others.</s>
        <s>Without being <choice><orig>abel</orig><reg>able</reg></choice> to do it at first.</s>
        <s>You will feel <choice><orig>impowert</orig><reg>empowered</reg></choice> and possible to do everything.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
