<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12g06_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the most <choice><orig>european</orig><reg>European</reg></choice> countries, learning two languages is what everybody has done and needed to, to finish school, In the <name type="geo">UK</name> it isn't, but is that really a big problem?</s>
        <s>The average kid is in school till they are 18 and then goes off to college in <name type="geo">England</name> or in the <name type="geo">United States</name>, because they have the highest standing, So they could not need a second language in their whole life.</s>
        <s>Also because of globalisation, everybody is learning English as their second language.</s>
        <s>Plus, even if they're abroad, there are British communities at the most demanded <choice><orig>vaccation</orig><reg>vacation</reg></choice> destinations (for example Mallorca), so there are not many situations, in <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> they actually need a second language!</s>
        <s>Yes, but even though it isn't needed that often it still is needed.</s>
        <s>In the western countries, it is important to be at least bilingual.</s>
        <s>And also, which was mentioned by <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>, it is often required for many <choice><orig>Jobs</orig><reg>jobs</reg></choice> to know a foreign language.</s>
        <s>In a globalized world, there are many international partners, for a big career a minimum second language is needed.</s>
        <s>I personally think that the process of learning a language is a vital part of education, it is different to learning anything else and teaches a lot about consistency and patience.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I also agree with <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> in line 16 <quote> language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> global standing</quote>, not only because of the dependence on other foreign workers, because of the lack of language learning.</s>
        <s>Also how Brits are portrayed, Brits are often portrayed as intolerant and arrogant.</s>
        <s>And I think wanting to learn languages from another culture or country and in general of more open minded international thinking would help against that prejudice, that many have.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> would agree with the statement of <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> think that learning languages is really important for a good <choice><orig>Education</orig><reg>education</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>In a globalized world it's important to be bilingual and <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> like that it's becoming more of a topic in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
