<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12g07_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>to <email>paula.thompson@123.com</email></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Paula,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>how are you?</s>
        <s>We haven't talked in a while so I was very happy when I read you e-mail about your idea of spending a year in <name type="geo">Germany</name> after school.</s>
        <s>Some days ago I read the article <ref target="a12gk1_2" type="title"><name type="geo">Berlin</name> spricht Englisch</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk1_2" type="author">Marina Kormbaki</ref> and published at the <name type="misc">Hannoversche Allgemeine Zeitung</name>, which is a newspaper, on <date>15th of July in 2016</date>.</s>
        <s>The article gives some information why living in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> is so <choice><orig>attractiv</orig><reg>attractive</reg></choice>, especially for English speaking people and now I would like to tell you some of the reasons.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all over the past years more and more immigrants came to <name type="geo">Berlin</name>.</s>
        <s>Besides the tourists who come and leave there are lots of people from different <choice><orig>countrys</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice> who come to <name type="geo">Berlin</name> and stay there.</s>
        <s>Especially from English speaking <choice><orig>countrys</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice> like American, Britain, or Australian people are coming to <name type="geo">Berlin</name>.</s>
        <s>Because of this there are many areas in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> where people speak amost only or at least a lot of English.</s>
        <s>Besides this stores for example restaurants are often on English which makes it more easier for Englih speaking people.</s>
        <s>For example the App-inventor <name type="person">David Walker</name> has a <choice><orig>buisness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice> with workers from 21 different nations and they all speak English together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all you can simpl live in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> even if you only speak English.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could help you a little and would love to hear from you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
