<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g12_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The author used negatively connoted words in line one as a comparison to the <quote>national view on speaking foreign languages, can't won't, don't</quote>.</s>
        <s>These words make it appear worse than before.</s>
        <s>In line four, he used an adjective to show his personal opinion and to show that the development is bad <quote>sadly</quote>.</s>
        <s>It shows that the news of the declining number of foreign languages studied at university level were not taken as seriously as they should have been and that that is a bad development.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he uses arguments of the other side to strengthen his own line of arguments, for example in line six to eight <quote>While there is... has also stalled</quote>, which also weakens the other side of arguments.</s>
        <s>In addition to that, he also gives examples of situations in which you do not have to know languages other than <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> <quote>Perfectly intelligent people... intercultural telepathy anyway</quote>, but <choice><orig>denys</orig><reg>denies</reg></choice> their validity, he lists counter arguments in the following lines <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 16-18)</ref> <quote>language learning... and national security</quote>.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, he lists of facts and comments on it in order to convince the reader of his opinion in lines 19 to 23 <quote>The most recent...and expect that to grow...</quote>, it makes the amount of <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses that require foreign language skills seem larger.</s>
        <s>The author does it again in lines 24-26 <quote>The only reall good...more should</quote>, here he makes the number of students taking a langauge <choice><orig>alonside</orig><reg>alongside</reg></choice> another degree subject seem smaller.</s>
        <s>In the following three lines, he gives example of the advantages someone has who studied a language alongside another degree subject <quote>a lawyer with Chinese language skills is more in demand than a pure lawyer or a pure linguist</quote>.</s>
        <s>In lines 30 to 31, he used to straties to strengthen his message: he says <quote>There is no doubt</quote>, which makes it seem like a fact.</s>
        <s>He brings up his point <quote>more of our young people</quote> and negates the opposite <quote>not fewer</quote>.</s>
        <s>In line 32, he addresses the <quote>parents of the <name type="geo">UK</name></quote> and includes himself <quote>and I'm one</quote>, he also uses inclusive pronouns in the following lines <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 32-35)</ref> <quote>we</quote>m in line 33, <quote>our</quote> in line 34 and <quote>us</quote> in line 35.</s>
        <s>All of the including himself to the addressed creates a feeling of unity among the readers and addressed, in the context it also strengthens the line of arguments.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>to conclude, you can say that <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> used the language to support his argumentation, even creating an emotional feeling <quote>sadly</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His validity is based on facts and supported by communicative strategies and his use of language.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
