<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g12_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> wrote in his article <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="title">Language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name>: can't, won't, don't</ref>, which was published by <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> on <date>January 27th 2015</date>, <quote>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>in his article, he underlined the claim with the <name type="misc">CBI/Pearson Education and Skills Survey</name>, which shows that almost two thirds of <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses require foreign language skills.</s>
        <s>He expects the number to rise since more British companies expand into the global markets.</s>
        <s>These companies often hire their employees from other countries or rely on translators because <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> people often don't have the needed language skills.</s>
        <s>With the rapidly progressing globalisation, language skills receive a new level of importance, international companies and businesses are everywhere when you want to work at a big company, you almost every time need language skills.</s>
        <s>Even when studying, some classes are held in foreign languages, for example when studying chemistry in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>germany</orig><reg>Germany</reg></choice></name>, often the bachelor is held in <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> but the master is held in <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>, requiring foreign language skills on a high level.</s>
        <s>In addition to that, there is a rapidly growing offer of online studying by universities all over the world.</s>
        <s>This allows groups to be created with people from different countries but requires you to break the language barrier.</s>
        <s>The globalisation is everywhere, the world is getting smaller and smaller with every day we live, foreign language skills are essential to communicate and work with people outside of your country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, globalisation has come so far that in every city you go there are so many languages spoken, if people don't acquire foreign language skills they won't be able to communicate well enough.</s>
        <s>Foreign language skills are essential if you want to live in the world and not just your village.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
