<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g33_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this blog entry, <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices and communicative strategies are used to bring the <choice><orig>massage</orig><reg>message</reg></choice> of the text, how bad pollution is for our environment and our <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>, across.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of them you can find in line 6.</s>
        <s>There is an anaphora of the word <quote>no</quote>.</s>
        <s>This is a very negative word which shows the reader how destructive environmental pollution is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>An other</orig><reg>Another</reg></choice> important stylistic device is a repetition of the sentence <quote>field of science and technology</quote> in line 15 and 19.</s>
        <s>It underlines the important role science and technology <choice><orig>plays</orig><reg>play</reg></choice> in pollution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that, the <choice><orig>autor</orig><reg>author</reg></choice> uses a <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> in l. 18 + 19 to bring across his message.</s>
        <s>In this sentence, the effect of our <choice><orig>archievements</orig><reg>achievements</reg></choice> and industrial civilization is compared to <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> bling alley, to show <choice><orig>howe</orig><reg>how</reg></choice> <choice><orig>hopless</orig><reg>hopeless</reg></choice> the situation of our world is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>An other</orig><reg>Another</reg></choice> metaphor in line 20 helps to show how bad and hazardous pollution can be too.</s>
        <s>In this line the author compares the situation of our earth today with the crusades, by naming the enemies of environmental pollution <quote>crusaders</quote> <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>As we all know, due to the crusades many people died and were killed, similar what an effect of pollution and the climate change could be.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some lines later, in line 24 and 25, the author connects a daily situation, drinking water and eating vegetables, with nitrogen fertilizers and pollution, to emphasize that climate change is a topic that you face everywhere in your life, which shows how important the topic is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, the <choice><orig>autor</orig><reg>author</reg></choice> refers to <quote>many scientists</quote> <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 27)</ref> and <quote>experts</quote> <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 33)</ref> two times.</s>
        <s>This makes the reader believe what she is saying.</s>
        <s>This helps <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> to bring her message across.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>An other</orig><reg>Another</reg></choice> stylistic device you can find in line 34.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>Alliteration</orig><reg>alliteration</reg></choice> <add>(<quote>world would</quote>)</add> underlines the importance of this sentence and this part of the text, in which a cruel effect of pollution is named.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that, the last sentence of the text is important.</s>
        <s>In this sentence <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 36, 37)</ref>, the author summarizes the problematic of the text, which makes it to the most important sentence of the text.</s>
        <s>With writing it at the end of the blog entry, it sticks in the head of the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all you could say, that many <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices and communicative strategies are used by the author, but especially the two <choice><orig>metaphoras</orig><reg>metaphors</reg></choice> in line 20 and 18 are important for bringing across the message of the text.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
