<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a10g33_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>A lot of pollution derives from human activity.</s>
        <s>So we <choice><orig>human</orig><reg>humans</reg></choice> are able to stop it, or even responsible.</s>
        <s>But how we could solve the global problem of environmental pollution?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One possible thing you could to is to reduce driving with the car and to fly.</s>
        <s>For example on holiday, just go somewhere near and do not fly to <choice><orig>an other</orig><reg>another</reg></choice> country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>An other</orig><reg>Another</reg></choice> measure to help solving the global problem of environmental pollution is to buy environmental friendly products.</s>
        <s>For example buying food that is not <choice><orig>conterminaded</orig><reg>contaminated</reg></choice> helps.</s>
        <s>And for example when you are buying clothes, try to not support labels that are mostly responsible for the <choice><orig>polution</orig><reg>pollution</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Buy clothes that are produced environmental friendly to reduce pollution and to solve the global problem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But all these things are small measures.</s>
        <s>The most important is to stop big industries to destroy our world.</s>
        <s>Without making new laws for the industry against pollution, it will be hard to stop climate change, even though many people buy environmental friendly products, because the biggest part of the pollution is made by the industry.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though, every human can do his part to reduce pollution.</s>
        <s>An idea is to recycle your things, and not just throw them away, to reduce you ecological footprint.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I would say, that everybody is responsible to stop climate change, but the industry and big labels are responsible especially.</s>
        <s>So the most important thing is to stop them from polluting the globe to solve the global problem of environmental pollution.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
