<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g32_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>Blog</orig><reg>blog</reg></choice> on <choice><orig>Environment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> pollution, by <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> and published on <date>February 5, 2014</date>, is about the environment pollution, there causes and effects on all of us.</s>
        <s>The <foreign xml:lang="de">Autor</foreign> tries to <choice><orig>describes</orig><reg>describe</reg></choice> the theme and <choice><orig>presents</orig><reg>present</reg></choice> the problems of environment pollution for this the <choice><orig>autor</orig><reg>author</reg></choice> uses stylistic devices and her words.</s>
        <s>She starts about the effects of environment pollution.</s>
        <s>At first she says, that the pollution <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> effect on the natural world and all living beings <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 2, 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this she speaks directly to the reader.</s>
        <s>With this the reader feels <choice><orig>conected</orig><reg>connected</reg></choice> with the theme and <choice><orig>want</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to read more.</s>
        <s>Moreover she says, that the earth is the only planet we know, where we can live <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 2, 4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this, she says directly how important this problem is, because if our earth is getting destroyed, we can't get another one so easy.</s>
        <s>Next she says the causes of environment pollution is our mankind.</s>
        <s>This means, she is trying to say, that the reader should do anything against it, because it is our failing.</s>
        <s>Then she uses <choice><orig>simily</orig><reg>simile</reg></choice> to represent, how important the problem is.</s>
        <s>She always <choice><orig>say</orig><reg>says</reg></choice> it has effects on our earth and all human beings <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 22, 3, 13, 14, 24, 25, 26)</ref>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>More over</orig><reg>Moreover</reg></choice> she repeats, that it is our fault <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 9, 10, 11, 12, 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She always <choice><orig>try</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to speak directly to the reader and let him feel effected to this problem, so he tries to do <choice><orig>somethink</orig><reg>something</reg></choice> against it.</s>
        <s>Then she asked a question, if it really <choice><orig>help</orig><reg>helps</reg></choice> us <quote>climb the peaks of prosperity or simply take us down</quote>.</s>
        <s>With this, she tries to let the reader think about it himself and let him build his own opinion.</s>
        <s>Next she says, that a lot of people are demonstrate against it.</s>
        <s>She tries to present <choice><orig>somethink</orig><reg>something</reg></choice> what we can do.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now she repeats another time, that we are the cause of all of this and not only bombs and more <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 22-28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Close to end she <choice><orig>choose</orig><reg>chooses</reg></choice> a real thing, a fail, where gift was leaking.</s>
        <s>Over 2000 people died <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 29-32)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this she tries another time to present, who dangerous and important it is.</s>
        <s>At the end she says a <foreign xml:lang="de">Fazit</foreign> to speak directly to us and try to let us choose to help.</s>
        <s>At the end I would say, that she tries to let the reader help and to present, how big and dangerous this problem is.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
