<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c11g19_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211220</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, I am going to comment on <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Walters</orig><reg>Walter's</reg></choice></ref> and the other <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Youngers'</ref> dreams in the context of the American Dream and African American history.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> says that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> has almost lost his mind thinking about money all the time, she isn't wrong at all, because <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> does really invest an amount of time into his idea with the liquor store, but the other family members are thinking and <choice><orig>planing</orig><reg>planning</reg></choice> with the money too, because they just need the money.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At all the American Dream is a phenomenon about that you can do everything what you want, no matter who you are of what your background is like, like if you are white or black, which <choice><orig>relegion</orig><reg>religion</reg></choice> do you have or if you are small or tall.</s>
        <s>The only thing you have to <choice><orig>belive</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> in is your own work and for what you do work.</s>
        <s>But when the slavery offical ended, the <choice><orig>descrimination</orig><reg>discrimination</reg></choice> of black people still <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> not ended.</s>
        <s>They were humans second class, like in buses they had to be <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice>, in restaurant they had to be <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> and even in the <choice><orig>rest rooms</orig><reg>restrooms</reg></choice> they had to be <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> from the white people.</s>
        <s>Black people do not had the same rights as the white people, although white people made the law that everyone would be the same.</s>
        <s>The problem was that these people who made the laws, were racist from the beginning, so racism is a problem which is there for some hundred years now.</s>
        <s>The things which the <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Younger family</ref> wants to do with the cash are things everyone should be able to get, with or without the money.</s>
        <s>But because of the African American history, they have real struggles <choice><orig>archieving</orig><reg>achieving</reg></choice> things as the whites.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> has the best plan with the money, because he is looking for an income for more than just a few months.</s>
        <s>He wants his family to be financial stable for a long time, while <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref>, <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> want a better house.</s>
        <s>Quite a good idea, but they will have the same income and the same living conditions after buying the house, so it wouldn't be that smart to buy a house.</s>
        <s>And <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Beneatha</ref> <choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to become a graduated doctor, which is quite hard as a black woman in the 20 decade.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But one <choice><orig>import</orig><reg>important</reg></choice> thing which makes all these plans and dreams the same, is that they are kind of American Dreams.</s>
        <s>They want to achieve something.</s>
        <s>They want a better life.</s>
        <s>And <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> their good right to get a better life.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
