<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12l04_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="factorial explanation">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his article <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="title">We are entering an era of pandemics - it will end only when we protect the rainforest</ref> <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref>, the president of <name type="misc">EcoHealth Alliance</name> <choice><orig>who's</orig><reg>whose</reg></choice> goal is to analyse and prevent pandemics explains with regard to the Corona-crisis, how pandemics arise and spread and how they could be prevented through protecting the nature, especially wildlife.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author believes, that diseases are the products of humans disrupting the wildlife.</s>
        <s>He explains that animals, especially those in tropical areas carry millions of diseases in them without us noticing or knowing about them in detail.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If a human being gets in contact with those viruses, for example through butchering animals or entering their caves and <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> exposed to their feces, and infect himself with the virus, according to the <choice><orig>auther</orig><reg>author</reg></choice>, this affects the whole world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He states that the human species is better connected than ever before, and that this fact makes it easier for the disease to spread.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the same time the author also sees a problem in humans expanding their settlements because it brings people in contact with the wildlife which causes the spreading of diseases on humans.</s>
        <s>To prevent this from happening the author proposes to act against the destroying of wildlife and wants people to take measures against wildlife trade and for sustainability.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His goal is to prevent the dangerous contact between infected animals and humans to stop the arise of new pandemics.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
