<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12l02_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="factorial explanation">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="title">We are entering an era of pandemics - it will end only when we protect the rainforest</ref> written by <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref> and released on <name type="misc">The Guardian</name> on <date>28.07.2020</date> mankind is responsible for them and how they could be prevented.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>According to the author every pandemic starts with a human interaction with wild animals, for example <name type="misc">Ebola</name> or <name type="misc">Covid-19</name>, which both stem from bats and were spread to humans.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speed at which they spread has increased with the growing human population and the development of a global ntework of travel and trade that connects the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The majority of viruses stem from rainforests in <choice><orig>west</orig><reg>West</reg></choice> Africa, the <name type="geo">Amazon basin</name> and the south-east Asia, as the wildlife in them is very diverse and in turn <choice><orig>carrys</orig><reg>carries</reg></choice> a vast <choice><orig>ammount</orig><reg>amount</reg></choice> of different viruses.</s>
        <s>An estimated amount of 1.7m viruses exist in mammals and birds alone, which are the main carriers of most pandemics and while most of them don't cause any problems, there are so many, that some inevitably will.</s>
        <s>The spread of diseases was not as serious as it is now, because human populations were less connected, which meant a virus would not reach very far.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This was however changed by the fact that humans transformed many of the rainforests into human territory, which leads to more to more contact between people and the wildlife.</s>
        <s>An estimate of one-third of diseases are due to this factor.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author states that the current way of dealing with pandemics by waiting for them to spread and then fighting them via vaccines or drugs is flawed as many people are infected and die before a cure is invented and sufficiently produced.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his opinion mankind needs to prevent pademics from happening in the first place by blocking them in the early stages.</s>
        <s>He states we should reduce our consumption, which is the cause of deforestation, remove species that are at risk of carrying viruses from wildlife markets, punish <choice><orig>ilegal</orig><reg>illegal</reg></choice> wildlife trade more and try to stop industries that havest tropical forests and wildlife products.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>According to the author the recent <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> crisis should act as a wake-up call that motivates mankind to prevent future pandemics.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
