<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12l06_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="factorial explanation">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given text is an online article called <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="title">Reducing deforestation and the exploitation of wildlife are the first steps in breaking the chain of disease emergence</ref> written by <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref> and published on <date>July 28th 2020</date> on the website <name type="misc">The Guardian</name>.</s>
        <s>In his article <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref> talks about, how the deforestation of the rainforest is the main reason for huge virus outbreaks like in the current pandemic.</s>
        <s>According to <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> every pandemic is caused by the same reason, namely people coming <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> close with the wildlife and catching a virus from the wild animals.</s>
        <s>Additionally <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> is of the opinion that the world is entering a new pandemic era.</s>
        <s>In the <date>1920s</date> <name type="misc">HIV</name> breaks out and now <choice><orig>affets</orig><reg>affects</reg></choice> the whole world, just like <name type="misc">Covid-19</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> things that humans are an agricultural species, which allows viruses to spread very fast.</s>
        <s>In earlier days people had not been as <choice><orig>connectes</orig><reg>connected</reg></choice> as today.</s>
        <s>Therefore viruses only spread as far as infecting a few family members.</s>
        <s>BUt as <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> mentioned, humans are now an agricultural species and destroy large areas of rainforests.</s>
        <s>This means that <choice><orig>humas</orig><reg>humans</reg></choice> come in <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> close contact with the wildlife and catch a virus.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Furthemore</orig><reg>Furthermore</reg></choice> because of our connected in melted world the newer viruses reach every corner of the planet.</s>
        <s>That's why <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref> argues that only by saving the rainforest we can prevent larger virus outbreaks.</s>
        <s>The overconsumption, illegal wildlife markets and trades need to stop according to <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref>.</s>
        <s>Since vaccines and other drugs <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> always be the <choice><orig>soloution</orig><reg>solution</reg></choice> to a pandemic, mankind hast to work together and fight against even more <choice><orig>massiv</orig><reg>massive</reg></choice> virus outbreaks.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
