<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11l05_t3</author>
        <name>diary</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear <choice><orig>Diary</orig><reg>diary</reg></choice>,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><q>Go to hell</q> is what I wished to have screamed in <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> face today!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is my uncle, he is Muslim, but he stands on the wrong side.</s>
        <s>And he doesn't even see it himself?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Therefore he'll probably go to hell anyways.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Did I ever see him wear his Kifur, this <q>Mr. Kapoor</q>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I believe he never set a foot in a mosque since he moved to the <name type="geo">US</name>, either.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sometimes I wonder if it would be best to move OUT OF the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
        <s>Especially now, when these unbelievable <q>authorities</q> <add>(fuck them)</add> might take that decision from me anyways.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As much as I despise <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and his hostile view on his own people, somehow he touched me for a moment today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote><s>There's a reason you father came here.</s><s>He wanted to make a better life for himself and his family</s></quote> or something along the lines is what he said to me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I don't like to admit it, but I think I might have forgotten that aspect a bit lately.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Their sacrifices.</s>
        <s>Am I too selfish?</s>
        <s>But then again - it is not my fault that the US society is such a shitshow.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If I could live here as a Muslim peacefully and as free as I wanted to, I wouldn't go, for sure.</s>
        <s>He'll stay, I know that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is always afraid, I know that won't change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But I am not afraid!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And I don't need no <q><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Ken</ref></q>, no lawyer to speak for me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I can speak up for myself!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> saw that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She might be a bitch, but I'd give her that - she saw me for me.</s>
        <s>Not like <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> who closes his eyes and ignores my identity.</s>
        <s>And she didn't deserve that beating, either.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think I'll go to <name type="geo">Pakistan</name> - but not until I have put up with a fight.</s>
        <s>A big one.</s>
        <s>Maybe with the help of the media?</s>
        <s>I want to show the world who <name type="misc">Hussein Abdullah</name> is.</s>
        <s>And that you can't force a whole ethnicity out of your country with violence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Not with me!</s>
        <s>Not while I'm watching!</s>
        <s>And then, one day, when I'll sit teethless in a fabric company in <name type="geo">Pakistan</name> <add>(How knows?)</add> I might stumble over a rock on the street after work and I will look up to the man who offered me his hands and it will be <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We'll drink tea together, like the old times.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Who knows?</s>
        <s>Maybe he'll come to his senses after all?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
