<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11l06_t3</author>
        <name>diary</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>I really don't know what to do and what <choice><orig>happend</orig><reg>happened</reg></choice> to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s>I needed his help today, but he changed so much in the last months.</s>
        <s>I mean he beat up <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> which is insane, he <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> went crazy and lost his job.</s>
        <s>I can't tell my mother about it, she would <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> freak out that's why I wanted to talk to him today but that's not possible anymore, I guess.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As soon as the topic with my name or our roots in <name type="geo">Pakistan</name> comes up it's done.</s>
        <s>I mean I don't understand him.</s>
        <s>I changed my name to fit better into the American society, he did the same!</s>
        <s>But he always said he <choice><orig>wont</orig><reg>won't</reg></choice> accept calling me <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> now instead of <name type="misc">Hussein</name>.</s>
        <s>Now I changed it back and he is still not satisfied with it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I try to fit into <name type="geo">America</name> but <choice><orig>i'm</orig><reg>I'm</reg></choice> not lying about my roots, I know my status is complicated now but I believe in my religion.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> doesn't he lies about where he comes from and tries to avoid this topic at all.</s>
        <s>I don't think that it will get easier for him when he doesn't get more open minded about his religion and kind of gets back to the old <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> I used to look up to.</s>
        <s>Maybe <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> am able to talk to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> about it again, she tries to understand me and not only calls random guys named <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Ken</ref>, who doesn't even pick up.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
