<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11l02_t3</author>
        <name>diary</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear <choice><orig>Diary</orig><reg>diary</reg></choice>,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am so mad at uncle <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>!</s>
        <s>Today, I came to visit him in his old apartment.</s>
        <s>His ex-wife <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> came with me to stand up for me and support me, but she left fast and then there were just me and my uncle.</s>
        <s>I explained my situation to him, that I was treated racist at a cafe and now the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> is on me because of my immigration status.</s>
        <s>I thought, he would finally see it.</s>
        <s>I thought, if it is a family member that is affected, he would finally stand up for what is right and use his job for something good.</s>
        <s>A lawyer, <choice><orig>who's</orig><reg>whose</reg></choice> job is literally to ensure justice.</s>
        <s>But no.</s>
        <s>He didn't.</s>
        <s>He just stood there, trying to talk himself out of the situation.</s>
        <s>Almost glamourizing it.</s>
        <s>That is so disgusting!</s>
        <s>No matter what I said, what arguments I used, he found a silly way to talk himself out of the situation.</s>
        <s>He can't be serious, can he?</s>
        <s>Does he actually believe, that people believe him?</s>
        <s>Does he actually think, we have a better life in <name type="geo">America</name>?</s>
        <s>We clearly don't!</s>
        <s>Well, it doesn't really matter anymore.</s>
        <s>My immigration is running out, and then I am finally gonna go back to <name type="geo">Pakistan</name>.</s>
        <s>Really get to know my culture, my people, my religion.</s>
        <s>But <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>?</s>
        <s>Poor <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, he is just going to keep on living a lie.</s>
        <s>He is gonna find a new white wife, a new lawfirm and a new apartment.</s>
        <s>But it is just a matter of time until his fassade falls again.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
