<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l01_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical recount">blog</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Is <name type="geo">Germany</name> really as tolerant as many think?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Racism and discrimination is a real thing.</s>
        <s>Many of us might not notice it in our daily lives but some people have to face it constantly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>My name is <name type="person">Caroline</name> and I live in <name type="geo">Germany </name>.</s>
        <s>I was asked to make some research about discrimination within the <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> society and what <choice><orig>chalanges</orig><reg>challenges</reg></choice> Germans with African heritage have to face.</s>
        <s>During my research I came across an article about the famous football player <name type="person">Jerôme Boateng</name>, in which he shared his personal <choice><orig>expiriences</orig><reg>experiences</reg></choice> of racism in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Boateng</name><choice><orig>discribes</orig><reg>describes</reg></choice> that he is noticing <choice><orig>increaced</orig><reg>increased</reg></choice> racism in the German society and that he feels that people judge other on their outward appearance and categorize between Germans and immigrants.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He himself often felt humiliated by others.</s>
        <s>As a child he was spat in the face and he remembers that he could not believe it at first, when he was told that it was because of his <choice><orig>skincolour</orig><reg>skin colour</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This shows that racism is something we <choice><orig>aquire</orig><reg>acquire</reg></choice> and not something we have from the start.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Boateng</name> also feels that the questions <q>What to do with all the immigrants</q> is frequently discussed.</s>
        <s>This shows that a lot of the discrimination is based on fear of the unknown and not on sensible reasons.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However, even though racism is still very present in <name type="geo">Germany</name> the society has also become more open.</s>
        <s>Many people <choice><orig>expirience</orig><reg>experience</reg></choice> the gain in a diverse society every day at work or in their sportsclub.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Jerôme Boateng</name> is a good example for the fact that immigrants are a valuable part of the German society.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is also proof that there is a chance to get to the top despite of all the difficulties.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Apperently</orig><reg>Apparently</reg></choice> there are a lot of people who really believed in him next to those who only saw his skin colour.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Coming to a conclusion I think <name type="geo">Germany</name> has a long way to go and sadly a lot of discrimination and racism still exists but there are also a lot of people who do not judge you because of your skin colour.</s>
        <s>We need to keep fighting against discrimination so that noone has to <choice><orig>expirience</orig><reg>experience</reg></choice> what <name type="person">Boateng</name> <choice><orig>expirienced</orig><reg>experienced</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
