<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l07_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical recount">blog</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>A famous football player on German racism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He doesn't let his daughters go to specific places!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> was a victim on the football pitch, so he explains in his own magazine.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There are fans who shout at him like a monkey when he's warming up, even though he is seen as a German legend by many.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of the causes is the refugee crisis.</s>
        <s>It's still one of the main topics when talking with friends.</s>
        <s>Should it be?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The German people tend to put people from different countries or with ancestors from different countries into different cupboards.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also the news often show aggressive groups, even though the society is so colourful.</s>
        <s>Imagine the World Cup without people with different origins and cultures.</s>
        <s>It wouldn't work.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So you, yes you the reader, enjoy the variety and complexity of our society!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There are so many examples where it's a total win to have so many different cultures in the country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Yet <name type="person">Boateng</name> faced many racist incidents, even as a child.</s>
        <s>There was a guy, a grown man, who ran to his side of the pitch and just swore at him.</s>
        <s>I mean what?</s>
        <s>A child which just wants to play football and doesn't even know about racism has to experience that?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But all that stitches can't harm him anymore and if you experienced something like that, I'm sure you can build that shield too.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His parents had to tell this young boy that there are people who hate others because of their skin.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It's unbelievable what happens in every day life and often you don't notice it because the stories are not told.</s>
        <s>So if you have a story where you were mistreated because of your skin colour, your <choice><orig>cultur</orig><reg>culture</reg></choice> or whatever, go and tell us.</s>
        <s>It's a chance to make the world a better place.</s>
        <s>That's it from my blod today.</s>
        <s>I'm still in a shock.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
