<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Both of the characters, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref>, are introduced to the audience in the first scene of the play <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 4</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To analyse the connection and relationship of those two characters their single behaviour should be looked at first.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is being presented as an American with <choice><orig>south asian</orig><reg>South Asian</reg></choice> heritage.</s>
        <s>He grew up in a conservative, <choice><orig>islamic</orig><reg>Islamic</reg></choice> household and was fully commited to his religion in his childhood days.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> that is <choice><orig>portraied</orig><reg>portrayed</reg></choice> in the play completely changed.</s>
        <s>After coming to <name type="geo">America</name>, he changed his name, values and turned his back to the Islam and everything that has to do with it.</s>
        <s>He changed his name from <name type="misc">Abdullah</name> to <name type="misc">Hussein</name>, and at work he pretends to be Hindu.</s>
        <s>Moreover he married a white American woman and adapted fully to the American lifestyle, as he became a successful <choice><orig>attorny</orig><reg>attorney</reg></choice> in the country.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir Hussein</ref> is a great example of <choice><orig>Assimillation</orig><reg>assimilation</reg></choice>, as when he took over the American lifestyle and values, he left his roots and religion behind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> on the other hand, integrated in the country.</s>
        <s>He changed his name, but only did so because the Quran allows to do so.</s>
        <s>He changed his exterior traits, as he wears American clothes and adapted his name, but didn't quite change his thoughts and values like <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> did.</s>
        <s>In contrast to his uncle he doesn't <choice><orig>denie</orig><reg>deny</reg></choice> where he comes from, and still stands up for his religion and the values that come with it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One can clearly see their different thoughts based on the case of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Imam Fareed</ref>, an Islamic person who got arrested for being a possible terrorist, even though it is clear that he is not guilty.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> asks <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to help him as he would rather have one of <quote>his</quote> people as his lawyer.</s>
        <s>With his people he refers to the <choice><orig>muslims</orig><reg>Muslims</reg></choice>, which shows that they still believe <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is one of them, even though he often states that he doesn't want to belong there.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that he asks his uncle shows that he still feels like he is one of them and looks up to them.</s>
        <s>In the first scene, he clearly has respect for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The turning point of the play is the third scene and at the end of the scene also highlights the turning point of the relationship between <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> broke down and became physically aggressive, his <choice><orig>forcefull</orig><reg>forceful</reg></choice> assimilation and his adapted value faded.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given 4th scene shows the final identities of the characters.</s>
        <s>In contrast to the beginning of the play, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is now fully commited to the Islam and the islamic culture.</s>
        <s>He changed his name back and it seems like the few American values he adapted, faded away completely.</s>
        <s>In the scene he states, that he laughed, when the officers brought up his immigrant status and that fact that it's up fo renewal <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 1-3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This makes the audience think, that he doesn't care anymore and thinks not only this situation, but the whole country is hilarious, as the police symbolizes the legal term of a country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> from the beginning, who looked up to his uncle who managed to adapt to the country completely faded and now it seems like he even looks down on him as he tries to convince him with his perspective and values <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. 10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Throughout the whole play, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> was the <q>white savior</q> of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> who tries to adapt him to <name type="geo">America</name> and <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> society.</s>
        <s>It seems ironic, that now <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> also seems like a saviour, but one that tries to overbring his <choice><orig>islamic</orig><reg>Islamic</reg></choice> values.</s>
        <s>It is a strong contrast that probably stands in <choice><orig>conection</orig><reg>connection</reg></choice> to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Amirs</orig><reg>Amir's</reg></choice></ref> outburst, in which he outlived certain Islamic values, that according to him are written down in the Quran.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another <choice><orig>diffrence</orig><reg>difference</reg></choice> in their relationship is the <choice><orig>fadding</orig><reg>fading</reg></choice> trust, that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> gives his uncle.</s>
        <s>In the beginning he counted on <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> his help, as he volunteered to come to him and ask for help.</s>
        <s>In the fourth scene, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> needed to bring <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and forced him to talk about the situation.</s>
        <s>The question <quote><qs>So what?</qs><qs>You don't believe that either?</qs></quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>, shows that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is deeply <choice><orig>dissappointed</orig><reg>disappointed</reg></choice> by his uncle and doesn't feel like he understands him anymore.</s>
        <s>This can also be the case, as he is disappointed in the values <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> outlived.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> turned his back on every little piece connected with the Islam.</s>
        <s>Every beautiful and positive thing.</s>
        <s>How came in the end, he only acted upon everything negatively and <choice><orig>aggressiv</orig><reg>aggressive</reg></choice>?</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> probably feels betrayed as <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> always said, that the Islam is a backway of thinking, but in the end <choice><orig>fulfiled</orig><reg>fulfilled</reg></choice> all prejudices people have against the Islam.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Correspondingly one could also say, that as a result of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Amirs</orig><reg>Amir's</reg></choice></ref> acts and <choice><orig>aggressiv</orig><reg>aggressive</reg></choice> bheaviour, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> commited to the Islam again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He probably thinks that even <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, who seems so perfectly adapted to American society, isn't able to help but fall back to the Islam, why should he try to integrate anymore and not just outlives his values as well.</s>
        <s>It seems like in the end both of them lost their connection to <name type="geo">America</name>, because of racism on a daily base and their corresponding acts against it.</s>
        <s>The differenceis that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is clearly ashamed of him for falling back to his past, while <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> thinks the other way around, as he is proud to be a fully commited muslim again and even denies his <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> past <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 54-73)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Moreover there is a difference between how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> handles the legal situation.</s>
        <s>In the beginning of the play, he decided to go to the trial of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Imam Fareed</ref> and acted upon <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Abes</orig><reg>Abe's</reg></choice></ref> wish.</s>
        <s>Even though <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> convinced him, he went there as a sign of support towards a muslim.</s>
        <s>Now he doesn't even suggest helping <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> himself, as he's a lawyer too, but directly calls <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Ken</ref>, another lawyer to take over <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> case <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This symbolizes the way they slowly became strangers.</s>
        <s>A thing that didn't change, is that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> thought of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> as a kid in the beginning and still does so.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>When you <choice><orig>stepp</orig><reg>step</reg></choice> out your parents' house</quote><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He <choice><orig>portrais</orig><reg>portrays</reg></choice> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> as a childish, naive person, who doesn't quite understand the consequences that can come with certain behaviour.</s>
        <s>He indirectly shames him for not having fully adapted to American values and society even though ironically he hasn't himself.</s>
        <s>But <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> obviously wants to change things, which is highlighted, when <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> asks him <choice><orig>wheather</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> he would work for the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>, if he was asked to.</s>
        <s>Again this seems like <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> thinks of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> as a traitor, someone who denies his roots and origin.</s>
        <s>He states that he's not on the side of the authorities side, even though <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> wants to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. 33-35)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This again underlines the <choice><orig>naivity</orig><reg>naivety</reg></choice> of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Abes</orig><reg>Abe's</reg></choice></ref> character, as he actually is from <name type="geo">America</name> and grew up with the legal forms of the country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Here one again can see the contrast between <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> denies his country and still wants to go back to <name type="geo">Pakistan</name>.</s>
        <s>He can't believe that <name type="geo">America</name> could provide a better life for them <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 39-50)</ref>.</s>
        <s>That's probably because he always had to face the bad sides of society.</s>
        <s>A society full of racism against people who come from there, but are treated like outcasts just because they look <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He differs himself from <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> by the fact, that he <choice><orig>wansn't</orig><reg>wasn't</reg></choice> born here and doesn't feel like he belongs there.</s>
        <s>He also wants to make <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> see, that the country only provides problems, as he talks about him <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> his job and his aggressive outburst <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 48-50)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end both of the fight about how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> lost his respect for <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s>He eventually reveals that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <choice><orig>hurted</orig><reg>hurt</reg></choice> him by turning his back on him and that from <choice><orig>nowon</orig><reg>now on</reg></choice> he will handle things himself <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 74-75)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The fact that he still calls him uncle seems ironic here.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion one can say that the <choice><orig>realtionship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> between <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> changed drastically throughout the play.</s>
        <s>Especially after the turning point in scene 3 and the following scene, one can analyse the obvious difference.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
