<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l07_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The relationship between <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> takes a big developing step in the fourth scene.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> nephew and both have a Muslim background.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Whereas <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> changed his name from <name type="misc">Abdullah</name> and also resented his Muslim fate, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> decides to <choice><orig>chang</orig><reg>change</reg></choice> back his name to <name type="misc">Hussein</name> and wants to live a Muslim lifestyle.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Both of them live in the fear of racism and therefore tried to fit into American society.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It turns out their fears are rightful because <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> was taken in by the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> because of his Muslim look.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One can see that they have different thoughts and opinions but are also both victims of American racist society.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> has developed a negative view on the American government.</s>
        <s>After he got taken in and the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> checked his immigration status, he laughed <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It shows that he doesn't have respect for American authorities anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also thinks they're <quote><qs>looking for people whose immigration is vulnerable.</qs><qs>Then they push us to start doing stuff for them</qs></quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 10-11)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> doesn't disagree on that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 13-14)</ref> but thinks it's not clever that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> laughed.</s>
        <s>He thinks <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> wanted to <quote>antagonize them</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Here it gets clear that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> still has big fear and respect of the American authorities.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> on the other hand, developed a strong mindset and questions the American authorities.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It gets clearer when <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> says that <quote>There are ways... to let the authorities know that ... you're on their side</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 31-32)</ref>, after <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> asks him what he would do in <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> makes his position clear saying <quote>But I'm not on their side</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 33)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One can see that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tries to convince <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> of his perspective because <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> wants to protect <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and not because he doesn't like or share <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> opinion, when <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> says <quote>It's not a mistake</quote>, but <quote>If you're not smarter about this, you're going to get deported</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> still doesn't want to change his opinion and is arguing that it <quote>wouldn't be the worst thing</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref> to get deported.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene finds <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> climax when <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tries to explain to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> that the reason <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> and his father came to <name type="geo">America</name>, was to live a better life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> explodes and answers with <quote>You don't have a better life!</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 46)</ref> and then going on with saying that he knows <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> got fired and that he beat up <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From that point on their relationship get unstable and they talk to each other in a rage.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> questions <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and his loyalty to who he really is <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 67)</ref> and tells him he changed his name back which also causes <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> being triggered and escalating.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is telling how he feels about <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> living a Muslim lifestyle and that he doesn't think it's the right way, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> interrupts him and counters with what he thinks.</s>
        <s>They both don't have respect for each other anymore and let out what they think about each other, without thinking about it before.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, he doesn't look up to him anymore aswell as that he finds it <quote>disgusting</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 66)</ref> how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> turns on his own people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He goes on comparing <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to the prophet and that he <quote>wouldn't be trying to be like one of them</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 69)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That again not only shows the disrespect of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, but also that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is really dealing with the Islam.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Having said what he wanted to say, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> he will handle it himself and leaves.</s>
        <s>It highlights how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> relationship has collapsed in that conversation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> exits with naming <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <quote>uncle</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 75)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It expresses even further how their relationship had a massive downfall with <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> not calling <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> by his name.</s>
        <s>He could also have done that because he thinks <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> name isn't his real, reflecting what he said before, namely, that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> isn't loyal and so on.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion one can say that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> relationship had a negative development throughout the scene.</s>
        <s>Whereas in the beginning they were nephew and uncle with a healthy relationship and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> even looking up to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, in the end just family and blood connects them.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
