<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11l09_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary recount">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The one-act play <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 4</ref> was written by the American author <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="author">Ayad Akhtar</ref> and published in <date>2012</date>.</s>
        <s>It deals with the deep effects of racism and Islamophobia and appeals to be aware of the difficulties Muslim Americans face on a day-to-day basis.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The setting of the play is an apartment on <name type="geo">New York's Upper East Side</name> in <date>2011</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Scene 4 takes place six months after the huge fight with <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Jory</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> beating his wife <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> come over to the apartment.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> tells his uncle <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> about how he and his friend <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Tariq</ref> got arrested and interrogated by the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>, as they were suspicious of the boys having ties to Islamistic terrorism.</s>
        <s>While checking <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> immigration status, who recently immigrated from <name type="geo">Pakistan</name>, the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> realized that it was up for renewal.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref><choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> calls <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Ken</ref>, the lawyer of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Imam Fareed</ref>.</s>
        <s>He reminds <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> about how being muslim is not a neutral fact anymore and that he should be aware of that.</s>
        <s>However, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> clearly states that he would not work for the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> as he is not on their side.</s>
        <s>After reminding <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> that he could get deported, the conversation gets tensed.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> talks about how they should have never left <name type="geo">Pakistan</name> in the first place.</s>
        <s>Being out of rage, he accuses his uncle of beating <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> and his problems at his working place.</s>
        <s>Moreover, he tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> that he changed his name back to <name type="misc">Hussein</name>.</s>
        <s>Getting emotional, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> continues insulting his uncle and talks about how the discrimination against Muslim people is going to come to an end, as they, as a Muslim community, are going to fight back to get what they deserve.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
