<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l31_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> written by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is a sonnet with three <choice><orig>quatrins</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> and a doublet.</s>
        <s>The <foreign xml:lang="de">metrum</foreign> is iambic pentameter.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> is about describing the fading beauty of a loved person getting old with the beauty of nature.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first <choice><orig>quatrin</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> is about the natural cycle of life.</s>
        <s>A metaphor for that is <quote>the waves</quote>, it describes the life span as well because it stands for your time running up.</s>
        <s>The hard work shown is the 4th verse describes your life and daily work brings you to your last battle, this is a metaphor for your death that comes closer <choice><orig>everyday</orig><reg>every day</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second <choice><orig>quatrin</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> is about the birth of the individual person.</s>
        <s>Every person only sees the light for a first time once.</s>
        <s>The second verse is about the maturing of the people and the changes they make and being <quote>crowned</quote> afterwards.</s>
        <s>This is a metaphor for being rewarded.</s>
        <s>The <quote>crooked eclipses</quote> in the third phrase are a metaphor for all the dark times in life that try to make <quote>his glory fight</quote> which means his life harder.</s>
        <s>The last verse in this <choice><orig>quatrin</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> is about the <choice><orig>susprising</orig><reg>surprising</reg></choice> gift he gets for making it through all those hard times.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third and final <choice><orig>quatrin</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> is about the fading beauty of a loved one symbolised by the nature.</s>
        <s>In verse one the fading of beauty is symbolized by <quote>the flourish set of youth</quote>, this describes that the beauty fades by time just like in the nature.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second verse in this <choice><orig>quatrin</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> is about searching the parallels of the beauty while fading.</s>
        <s>The last two verses in this <choice><orig>quatrin</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> are about the rarities and <choice><orig>specialitys</orig><reg>specialities</reg></choice> in life and nature and that in the end there isnot very much left in life and that the beauty always fades.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The doublet is about <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> hoping that this sonnet will last long and that he hopes that the beloved one sees that he praises his worth.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
