<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l24_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> is about how the lyrical I talks about time and actions and about their dependancy of each other.</s>
        <s>The lyrical I also mentions examples for it and reflects it on his or her life.</s>
        <s>This sonnet was probably published around the late <date>16th century</date> or at the beginning of the <date>17th century</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This <choice><orig>sonnets</orig><reg>sonnet's</reg></choice> structure contains three quatrains and at the end a couplet.</s>
        <s>The <foreign xml:lang="de">metrum</foreign> of this sonnet is iambic pentameter and it is firstly about how the lyrical I illustrates to his addressed person that their time has come to an end <quote>so do our minutes hasten to their end</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> and it seems to justify it by saying each is changing with mostly what was before <quote>Each is changing place with that which goes before</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the second quatrain the lyrical I gives an example of how time change affects your doing.</s>
        <s>He uses the example of <name type="person">Jesus Christ</name>, who raises up and just <choice><orig>receive</orig><reg>receives</reg></choice> admiration, but was then betrayed, so he was no longer beloved by the people and starts to fall.</s>
        <s>In the couplet, the lyrical I praises that there are now hopeful times, although not everything seems to go right for the lyrical I <quote>Praising thy worth, despite his crual hand</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now to analyze the language of this sonnet it begins witha simile already in the first two lines.</s>
        <s>The lyrical I comapres floating waves towards a pebbled shore with the lasting minutes between it and its <choice><orig>addresse</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It does that also to metaphorize that the high tide is now over and the low tide begins.</s>
        <s>So after the minutes end between the lyrical I and its <choice><orig>addresse</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> the tide is our in their relationship.</s>
        <s>In general illustrates this particular sonnet the worth of time.</s>
        <s>It is the main topic it also gets different perspectives.</s>
        <s>At first, it is about time in a relationship with somebody, then it is viewed as the cause of a downfall and in the end it is illustrated to bring hope and stamina across an also brutal time at that moment.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another <choice><orig>wordfield</orig><reg>word field</reg></choice> which is, compared to the first <choice><orig>wordfield</orig><reg>word field</reg></choice> about time, more indirect, it also involves time, but in a certain aspect.</s>
        <s>It is about how progressive time can affect a person.</s>
        <s>About how people change an through that the loss in interest e.g. in a person change their sanity and now they might fight against mental issues or even death.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But now I want to focus back on the analysis of the language.</s>
        <s>In line 3 <quote>each changing place with that which goes before</quote>, shows the perspective of the lyrical I about changes.</s>
        <s>It views it like it is always going in circles and that there is no opportunity that it changes this time differently.</s>
        <s>The only way how it might not go in circle is when you put hard work into it that it will go forward.</s>
        <s><quote>In sequent toil all forwards do contend</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> means that you have to do something actively against it, otherwise it will remain the same over and over again.</s>
        <s>The second quatrain contains an example of how time can affect somebody.</s>
        <s>The lyrical I uses this illustration of the life of <name type="person">Jesus Christ</name> to underline his opinion of the cruel influence of time.</s>
        <s>He firstly emphasizes the appearance of <name type="person">Jesus Christ</name> together with his rise.</s>
        <s><quote>Nativity, once in the main of light</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He creates this image of the Chosen One by not saying he was born in Nativity to very poor parents in a stable somewhere between <name type="geo">Egypt</name> and <name type="geo">Israel</name>.</s>
        <s>By saying, <quote>once in the main of light</quote> and going on <quote>crawls to maturity, wherewith being crowned</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> the lyrical I uses a hyperbole of <name type="person"><choice><orig>Jesus</orig><reg>Jesus'</reg></choice></name> development just to create a greater contrast in the following lines of this quatrain.</s>
        <s><quote>Crooked exclipses 'gainst his glory fight, And time that gave doth now his gift confound</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 7-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This underlines the statements about affection of time by the lyrical I.</s>
        <s>By using <quote>his glory fight</quote> and <quote>his gift</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 3-4)</ref>, the lyrical I justifies or puts a positive light on the actions and opinions of <name type="person">Jesus Christ</name> to keep up this contrast.</s>
        <s>It even uses the word <quote>glory</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>, so the lyrical I makes his fight sacred and through that no one would ever believe that he has done bad things to provide himself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third quatrain the lyrical I goes on that time has a major influence on development.</s>
        <s><quote>Time doth transfix the fourish set on youth</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> shows that the lyrical I again creates a constrast by telling that time transfixes a lovely, flourish set on youth.</s>
        <s>It emphasizes the beauty of the flourish set just to get transfixed by time.</s>
        <s>Also using the word <quote>transfix</quote> shows that the lyrical I tries to persinificate time to bring the impact of time closer to the reader by the use of a human action that everyone is familiar with.</s>
        <s>This goes on in the next verse: <quote>And delves the parallels in beauty brow</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It starts with an enjambement from line 9 to line 10 to connect the two mentioned actions caused by time.</s>
        <s>It again reproaches time to take something away.</s>
        <s>This time it takes away the beauty facial expressions, which the lyrical I is heavily searching.</s>
        <s>That is why these lines are connected and not <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> as the rest of this poem, because they share the same topic about reproach.</s>
        <s>Line 11 <quote>Feeds on the rarities of nature's truth</quote>, shows that the mentioned person lives minimalistic and just has not a lot of things.</s>
        <s>And everything gets taken from him.</s>
        <s><quote>And nothing stands but for his scythe to mow</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> shows this point of the lyrical I either.</s>
        <s>These two verses are <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> and do not belong together through an enjambement, but they both portrait the same umage and symbol.</s>
        <s>The concerned person the lyrical I talks about is at first a symbol who stands for a low possession of <choice><orig>matreliastic</orig><reg>materialistic</reg></choice> things, who still gets taken everything he has, doesn't matter how much he possesses.</s>
        <s>The imagery begins with mentioning <quote>but for his scythe to mow</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This illustrates the image better due to mentioning he only has left one thing.</s>
        <s>And this scythe symbolizes the now even cruel poverty he has to go through.</s>
        <s>The last two lines of sonnet 60 reverse the image of the lyrical I.</s>
        <s>Then in the couplet the lyrical I starts talking about positive aspects time brings within.</s>
        <s>That you can achieve hope during a tough time and appreaciating the worthiness of the poeple around.</s>
        <s>This contrast gets illustrated in line 14: <quote>Paising thy worth, descpite his cruel hand</quote>.</s>
        <s>By using the word <quote>despite</quote> the lyrical I wants his readers to know that these two things are connected.</s>
        <s>With that he creates this contrast, but leaves this sonnet with a dark personification of the times he lives in, although he or she now sees the positive affects of time with hope and love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all this sonnet by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> shows how talented he was at writing.</s>
        <s>In 14 lines he created a whole story, where you discover or understand new things, although it is the second or third time you are reading it.</s>
        <s>You get immediately fascinated through the beauty of words and the imagery they come along with.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
