<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l26_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare's</ref><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> was written between the end of the <date>16th and the beginning of the 17th century</date>.</s>
        <s>It is mainly about how life, despite its beauty, <choice><orig>foces</orig><reg>forces</reg></choice> a cruel and inevitable end.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet has the tpyical structure of a sonnet, containing 14 verses with ten to eleven syllables each, three quatrains with a crossing rhyme and a rhyming couplet at the end.</s>
        <s>It is also written in an iambic pentameter, meaning that in each verse one syllable is accented and the next one is not.</s>
        <s>This gives the sonnet the effect of a heartbeat so the readers know that the writer of the sonnet really relates or feels what he writes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first two quatrains, as usual, introduce or develop the idea of the sonnet:</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first quatrain is about how life slowly comes to an end and there is nothing anyone can do about it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second quatrain illustrates the process of life, from being born to growing up.</s>
        <s>Then there is a turn between the second and the third quatrain, a so called volta.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While the first two quatrains talk about a human's life from birth to death, the third quatrain focuses on what happends to a human and what time does to hum after growing up, his excitement for life fading away, him being unaware of life's beauty anymore etc.</s>
        <s>In the third quatrain the reader can precisely understand what happens with one's psyche on the way to death which is completely different from the first two quatrains.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The couplet then summarizes the idea of the sonnet.</s>
        <s>The writer reaches this by saying that despite the cruelness of life he wants to show his love and in a way he tries to say that his lover made life and the thought of dealing with death a bit easier for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In order for his idea to be more understandable, <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses a few lyrical devices.</s>
        <s>At the beginning of the sonnet there is a comparison: <quote>Like as the waves make towards the pebbled shore, So do our minutes hasten to their end</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 1-2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He compares life with waves, like the waves head towards the shore, life heads towards death.</s>
        <s>This comparison shows not only that life will come to an end no matter what, but also that it is beautiful while it lasts.</s>
        <s>Because as we know waves are beautiful to watch and people enjoy them, just like they should enjoy life while they are able to.</s>
        <s>Also in line two he uses the word <quote>our</quote> when he talks about death.</s>
        <s>In that way he stresses that he is describing a process which concerns everyone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another lyrical device Shakespeare uses is a metaphor in the second quatrain.</s>
        <s>He portrays being an adult as a human's main goal, as he describes it as <quote>being crowned</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also he mentions the word <quote>glory</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>, which illustrates the same idea.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another metaphor is the word <quote>gift</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>While talking about what happens to humans when time goes by he uses the word <quote>gift</quote> which shows the worth of a human.</s>
        <s>For <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, a human is a gift which unfortunately gets taken away.</s>
        <s>The writer then uses an alliteration <add>(<quote>'gainst, glory, gave, gift</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 7-8)</ref>)</add>, intending to stress the importance of the process of growing up.</s>
        <s>Because in the first 16 years of a person's life he focuses on growing: physically, mentally and emotionally.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third quatrain there is a personification of time <add><quote>Time doth transfix the fourish set on youth</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref></add>.</s>
        <s>By personifying time in that way the writer stressing what time is able to bring about.</s>
        <s>Of course, time itself cannot do anything as it is no person, but <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> wants the reader to understand what can happen with time, which is quite a lot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another personification can be found in the third quatrain as well.</s>
        <s>This time the scythe is personified <add><quote>[...] for his scythe to mow</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref></add>.</s>
        <s>This personification is just a different expression for dying.</s>
        <s>A scythe is typical for death.</s>
        <s>People mostly associate death with a black-hooded man with a scull for a head and a scythe.</s>
        <s>So instead of directly mentioning death <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> describes it as a scythe mowing.</s>
        <s>Finally, in the couplet, the speaker addresses the addressee directly for the first time in the sonnet.</s>
        <s>He does that by firstly talking about his own verse and then addressing his lover's worth <add><quote>Praising thy worth, [...]</quote>, <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref></add>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up one can say that Shakespeare's <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> is a very meaningful poem which deals with the problems, as well as the reasons to enjoy life.</s>
        <s>It is also a sonnet filled with lyrical devices which bring the reader as close as possible to the writers mind and thoughts.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
