<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12l26_t3</author>
        <name>dialogue</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
        <listPerson type="speaker">
          <person xml:id="A">
            <persName>Speaker A</persName>
          </person>
          <person xml:id="B">
            <persName>Speaker B</persName>
          </person>
        </listPerson>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Do you think it makes <choice><orig>sence</orig><reg>sense</reg></choice> to read <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> although it is over 400 years old?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Yes, I think it is very important!</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Why?</s>
        <s>This is such an old way of speaking English.</s>
        <s>Nobody talks like that nowadays.</s>
        <s>Besides, we live in <name type="geo">Germany</name> so why do we have to deal with this language anyway?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>You see, reading Shakespearean plays and sonnets is not just about undersanding the language.</s>
        <s>It is about grasping the real meaning.</s>
        <s>In his poems, especially sonnets, he always talks about love, death, greed, hat, jealousy etc., which are timeless themes!</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Timeless themes?</s>
        <s>What do you mean by that?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Timeless themes are topics that are and always will be relevant to humanity.</s>
        <s>Love for example, as I already meantioned.</s>
        <s>Love is a topic which for most poeple is the most important thing in life.</s>
        <s>So by reading <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> sonnets you can really understand what love is about and how <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> saw it.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Yes that is true, but he is not the only one who wrote about these topics.</s>
        <s>There are plenty of other writers who use normal English and still write beautiful works.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>You are right, there are other writers.</s>
        <s>But <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is not like any other writer.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> manages to write about the beauty and the ugliness of life at the same time, which is incredible.</s>
        <s>When reading his sonnets you really get how complicated life is, how there are things in life which are beautiful, but <choice><orig>devistating</orig><reg>devastating</reg></choice> at the same time.</s>
        <s>I don't think that any other writer was or will be able to do it the way he did.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I have not thought of it this way.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Also, and now I am talking about his plays, every person, at some point in his life, will be able to relate to certain characters from <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays.</s>
        <s>Because these characters experience things like love, murder, hate etc. which eerybody will eventually make the same experiences with.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Yes, you are right.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Another reason why <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is still relevant today are his quotes.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> gets quoted on a regular basis in our everyday life, and not only in English, to answer your question why we need it in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>Quotes like <q>to be or not to be</q> get translated to almost every language in the world, and get used by many people.</s>
        <s>Beside from that, almost everybody knows <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>, or at least has heard his name at least once in his life, which proves just how important he is.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>These are some good points.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>In addition, he invented more than 1700 words we use nowadays.</s>
        <s>Many words we use are invented by <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>, without us even knowing.</s>
        <s>So all in all, Shakespeare plays a big wole in our loves and will, I think, still be relevant a long time from now.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>You totally convinced me, now I understand why we deal with Shakespeare at school.</s>
      </u>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
