<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12l29_t1</author>
        <name>sonnet_paraphrase</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary recount">sonnet_paraphrase</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref>, written by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> and published in <date>1609</date> is about the aspect of time and how valuable it is in different parts of life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This sonnet wants to address the topic, that every minute with your loved one is special and valuable because everything one day comes to an end.</s>
        <s>Furthermore are topics like beauty standards in the Elizabethan Era, the process of developing to a mature individual and the aspect of respecting and loving a person from within concluded.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet of 14 lines falls into the typical structures of <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear's</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></ref> sonnets since it is subdivided into three <choice><orig>quatrain</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> and a heroic couplet in the end.</s>
        <s>The quatrains contain a cross rhyme following the rhyme scheme <name type="misc">ABAB CDCD EFEF GG</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The Shakespearean sonnet is written in an iambic pentameter, which reminds with its unstressed and stressed <choice><orig>rythm</orig><reg>rhythm</reg></choice> and monotonous sounds of a heart beat.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>authors</orig><reg>author's</reg></choice> train of thoughts corresponds to the structure produced by this very natural rhyme scheme and therefore functions as a remedy to follow.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To emphasise the natural sound of his sonnet, <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> makes use of a cross rhyme.</s>
        <s>Additionally he also lets his sentence sometimes run into the next line <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 9-10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Which is called a <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">red-on</gap> line.</s>
        <s>Or uses <choice><orig>engjambments</orig><reg>enjambements</reg></choice> like in <choice><orig>line</orig><reg>lines</reg></choice> 10 to 11.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He ends the scene with a heroic couplet to make a statement.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to paraphrase <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <lg type="sonnet">
        <lg type="1st quatrain">
          <s>
            <l>It can be compared to when it is Mood and the water rises <add>towards you</add>,</l>
            <l>Do does our time run to the finish line,</l>
            <l>With each step you go forwards in life,</l>
            <l>the awaining misery fights to come loser.</l>
          </s>
        </lg>
        <lg type="2nd quatrain">
          <s>
            <l>We are born once in a lifetime,</l>
            <l>Grow to a young adult, the highlight of a lifetime</l>
            <l>the darkness tries to be an obstacle for your battle to victory,</l>
            <l>And the time you <choice><orig>supassed</orig><reg>surpassed</reg></choice> will reward you woth a praiseworthy present.</l>
          </s>
        </lg>
        <lg type="3rd quatrain">
          <s>
            <l>Time will be the climax in thriving your stunning set you youth,</l>
            <l>And making a seperation between your eye brows,</l>
            <l>Expand the hidden minorities of nature's reality,</l>
            <l>And the only thing that matters is his razor blade shavingthe excess hair.</l>
          </s>
        </lg>
        <lg type="final couplet">
          <s>
            <l>In hopes my verse will everlast,</l>
            <l>it is time to celebrate your value to me, even though it can be hurtful.</l>
          </s>
        </lg>
      </lg>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
