<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g47_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211123</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Many people think that <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> works are still relevant today, but I think that it is not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course the most people know <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> but mostly not because they like his books or read them in their <choice><orig>free time</orig><reg>freetime</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The most people know <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> because of school because they have or had to read one of his books.</s>
        <s>I think the most people don't really like the books of <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> which they had to read in school because they are <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> old.</s>
        <s>In the books are many old words which no one uses today.</s>
        <s>This makes the book hard to read and I think this problem causes the book to be boring because I have the experience if I read a book <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> slow it <choice><orig>borows</orig><reg>bores</reg></choice> me.</s>
        <s>Also these stories are not relevant in <choice><orig>these</orig><reg>this</reg></choice> time.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> is about a man who tries to kill a king.</s>
        <s>I think today no one can <choice><orig>realy</orig><reg>really</reg></choice> relate to <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> because this scenario is just <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> old and cannot happen today because there are no kings.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Overall I think some people of course still like what <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> wrote but the most people do not like it.</s>
        <s>In my opinion school tries to keep <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> relevant for everyone but it is not for the most people.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
