<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12g35_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211123</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>After dealing with the content of the argument between <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> and his wife it is neccessary to analyse how <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> tries to persuade her husband.</s>
        <s>In my analysis I am going to focus on her choice of language, including stylistic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One aspect that becomes obvious while just looking at the excerpt is that <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> speaks much more than her husband.</s>
        <s>This could already be a technique of <choice><orig>her's</orig><reg>her</reg></choice> for trying to make <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> speechless and overwhelmed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After he tries to convince her to not committing the murder by using <q>noble</q> words like <quote>golden</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> and <quote>gloss</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> to describe the good opinions from many, maybe important, people, she uses the metaphor <quote>[...]the hope [...] [w]herein you dressed yourself</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 8-9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this stylistic device she refers to clothes you put on everyday to show her husband that he changes his mind as quickly and frequently as he changes his clothes and to make him think and feel bad about this.</s>
        <s>She also personificates the hope <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 9-11)</ref> to show <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> how disappointed she is about the fact that the motivation he had some time ago <quote>fell asleep</quote>.</s>
        <s>By relating his mixed feelings about the plan to his love for her <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 11-12)</ref> she wants to make him insecure and emotional in order to convince him more easily afterwards.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She questions and insults his masculinity by asking him if he was not strong enough to fight for what he is wishing for <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 12ff.)</ref> and even calls him <quote>a coward</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This must be really hurtful and insulting for him because he is a brave fighter and <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> probably knows that she has to say things like these to make him angry and to make him want to prove her wrong.</s>
        <s>When the ruthless lady calls the crown <quote>the ornament of life</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref> she wants to make her husband realise that becoming king is the only important thing in his life and that nothing should keep him from fighting for his (<quote>in thine own esteem</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>) dream.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By saying <quote>Letting I dare not wait upon I would</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> portrays him as a weak lazy person and as someone who will not do anything to get what he wants.</s>
        <s>This attacks his pride and makes him even more insecure and submissive which helps her with her intention of persuading him of killing the current king.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The simile and question <quote>Like the poor cat i'th adage?</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref> should also make him feel bad because of the comparison with a sweet, weak animal and should make him want to prove that he is very masculine.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth's</ref> try to defend himself with an antithesis <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 21-22)</ref> is not very convincing and seems a <choice><orig>bis</orig><reg>bit</reg></choice> desperate.</s>
        <s>His wife knows about this and continues to question his manhood by saying that the only way to be man again is to say <quote>I dare</quote> again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this context she repeats the word <quote>man</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 26, l. 28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The whole conversation is about her making him feel weak and by repeating this word she supports the effect of her statements on her husband.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> then wants to make <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> realise how little sense his change of mind makes by saying that the now existing <quote>fitness [of] time [and] place [...] [d]oes unmake [him]</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 28-31)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> probably knows about this but hearing it from a beloved person might make him insecure in his opinion and thus easier to persuade.</s>
        <s>After that she gives an extreme, brutal example of killing her own child if she <quote>had [...] sworn as [he has] done to this</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 35-36)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Here she uses phrases like <quote>plucked my nipple</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref> and <quote>dashed the brains out</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 35)</ref> that probably shock her husband.</s>
        <s>The fact that she has <quote>given suck</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 31)</ref> shows that the two of them could have had a child which maybe died and confronting him with this dark past is a ruthless but good technique to make him shocked and submissive.</s>
        <s>The example should also show him how far she would go to keep a promise she made to him and how disappointed she is about him not thinking the same way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth's</ref> question <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref> shows that he already is very insecure and partly convinced and the answer of his wife <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref> should tell him that even a failure would not be that bad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She is using the imperative <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 40-41)</ref> to clarify that he is the one who can prevent them from failing and to show him that she is really angry about his doubts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By using a parenthesis from line 41 to 43 she gives <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> extra information about the plan that should take his last doubts away and show him that everything will work out.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Using the hyperbalion <quote>Will I with wine and wassail so convince [...]</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 44f.)</ref> and the imagery of the memory as <quote>warder of the brain</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 45)</ref> she illustrates that if she makes the guards drunk and deletes their memory, everyone will suspect them and they will not even know if they are innocent or not themselves.</s>
        <s>This should make her husband more confident regarding the plan.</s>
        <s>Also the imagery that the memory disappears through the limback <add>(brain)</add> shows that the <choice><orig>guard's</orig><reg>guards'</reg></choice> brains will not be able to hold on to any memory.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> uses the phrase <quote>swinish sleep</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 48)</ref> to make <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> associate the guards with pigs which might make it easier for him to put the blame on them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Her rhetorical questions at the end <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 50-53)</ref> and the use of the word <quote>great</quote> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 53)</ref> to describe the crime might also assure her husband that there is nothing to worry about and thus lead to a more convincing end.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth's</ref> last words show that he is shocked and surprised about his wife's attitude but he seems convinced and talks about the strong gender again <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 55-57)</ref> which was very important throughout the whole argument.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Generally <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> uses long, hypotactic sentences <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 31ff.)</ref> and many questions <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 9ff., l. 24f.)</ref> to make <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> speechless and think about his <quote>bad</quote> decision.</s>
        <s>Her tone and choice of words are often slightly <choice><orig>agressive</orig><reg>aggressive</reg></choice> <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 35)</ref> what should make her husband shocked and submissive.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all one can say that <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> uses many techniques and stylistic devices to make <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> speechless.</s>
        <s>She knows her husband very well and says the right things to get him to agree with her.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
