<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g05_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The informative text, written by <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref>, talks about unions and how they changed throughout the years.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following <choice><orig>im</orig><reg>I'm</reg></choice> going to analyse the text where I will focus on the communicative strategies the author uses.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author uses the <choice><orig>retorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> question <quote>Is the usefulness of unions coming to an end?</quote> <add>(title)</add> to get the reader interested and also gives them a question to keep in mind, while reading the text.</s>
        <s>It creates also a space for the reader to create their own opinion <choice><orig>eventhough</orig><reg>even though</reg></choice> the question is already answered in the title.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By using words like <quote>the truth</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>, the author includes their own strong opinion.</s>
        <s>It also gives away, that the author really dealt with the topic and is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> expert.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This impression gets underlined in line five, where he mentions how <quote>long</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> she supported the unions, which concludes to <choice><orig>allot</orig><reg>a lot</reg></choice> of knowledge he must have.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> uses the positive connoted word <quote>best</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>, he expresses how much he liked and supported the unions.</s>
        <s>Because the author only uses the past tense, while <choice><orig>positivly</orig><reg>positively</reg></choice> talking about the unions the reader can <choice><orig>alredy</orig><reg>already</reg></choice> tell, that the opinion might change further down the text.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 10 you can clearly see the change, by using the word <quote>today</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> the author talks about the present.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This change gets also more clear, when the negative connoted word <quote>victims</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> is used to really describe how bad the unions have gotten.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 21 the author directly speaks directly to the <choice><orig>goverment</orig><reg>government</reg></choice>, which leads the reader to the urge to really change something.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> briefly underlined his opinion in the article and really influenced the reader to change their opinion throughout the article.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
