<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l10_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following the formal and poetic devices, that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses to illustrate and to intensify his view, are going to be analysed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sonnet 138 consists out of three quatrains and a couplet being a typical Shakespearean sonnet form.</s>
        <s>Additionally an alternating rhyme scheme (<name type="misc">abab cdcd efef</name>) is used in the quatrains in the cabinet rhymes in a <name type="misc">gg</name> constellation.</s>
        <s>The rhythm is clearly <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> iambic pentameter, which supports a heartbeat-like structure and is typical for a Shakespearean sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>the Volta happens in line 9 <quote>But</quote>, where are the speaker questions the necessarity of those lies and then realizes the consequences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now moving on to poetic devices, the personification <quote>speaking tongue</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> catches the exe of the reader.</s>
        <s>It gives the impression of the speaker not giving his loved one the full responsibility of her lies.</s>
        <s>In addition the reader gets the vivid image of a self speaking tongue, which employs a rather odd feeling inside the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The two rhetorical questions <quote>But wherefore says [...] And wherefore say not [...]</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 9f.)</ref> mark the turning point, the Volta of the sonnet.</s>
        <s>They show the indecisiveness of the speaker in an inviting way for the reader to also think about this topic more actively.</s>
        <s>At this point the speaker is questioning the whole construct of love which is based on the lies in his case.</s>
        <s>A feeling of sadness and helplessness is conveyed towards the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore the anaphora <quote>Wherefore, Wherefore</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 9f.)</ref> supports the situation the speaker is in already.</s>
        <s>Paired with the rhetorical questions it is clear that the speaker questions his love and does not understand why the lies have to keep on going.</s>
        <s>The inner conflict is brought directly to the reader, which strengthens the feelings of sadness and helplessness.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The personification <quote>loves best habit is in seeming trust</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> gives love a rather critical and malicious connotation.</s>
        <s>Love you seen here as a tricky feeling, which does not always involve the truth but can fake truth and trust.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As a conclusion one could say that the author<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> intensified his view on love being still love even though it is based on lies.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
