<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l05_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, it will be analysed how<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses formal and poetic devices in order to illustrate and intensify his view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>sonnets</orig><reg>sonnet's</reg></choice> formal structure is typical for a Shakespearean sonnet, as it is made up of three quatrains and a heroic couplet.</s>
        <s>The rhyme scheme also supports this structure.</s>
        <s>There is a cross rhyme in each quatrain (abab, cdcd, efef) and a pair rhyme in the couplet (gg).</s>
        <s>The cross rhyme, makes the lines flow into <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice> and the pair rhyme at the end <choice><orig>add</orig><reg>adds</reg></choice> emphasis to the message of the couplet.</s>
        <s>The poem follows and I am big pentameter, which is an unstressed syllable followed by a stressed one.</s>
        <s>This metre, when read out, imitates a heartbeat, which is supportive of the theme of love in the poem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When looking at poetic devices one can notice a lot of <choice><orig>repititions</orig><reg>repetitions</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Words such as <quote>truth</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 1, 8)</ref>, <quote>lies/lie</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 2, 13, 14)</ref> or <quote>false</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 4, 7)</ref> are repeated throughout the poem to really emphasize this theme which makes the reader realize how important the topic of truthfulness is to the speaker.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>repititions</orig><reg>repetitions</reg></choice> of the word <quote>love</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 1, 11, 12)</ref>, also serves the <choice><orig>purpos</orig><reg>purpose</reg></choice> of stressing this theme.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another word that is repeated, is the word <quote>simple</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 7, 8)</ref>, which<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> deliberately repeated, to make it clear to the reader, that the lies, which the narrator speaks of are not very big or meaningful, but only <choice><orig>smal</orig><reg>small</reg></choice> lies and niceties.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When examining <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> use of words, it is interesting that one can find a lot of <choice><orig>word</orig><reg>words</reg></choice> having to do with time, age and youth (beauty), such as <quote>young</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 5)</ref>, <quote>old</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 10)</ref> or <quote>years</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> often reoccuring them in <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> poems ad it always influences how he talkes about love.</s>
        <s>And in this sonnet, the age of the narrator is brought up as an insecurity, as he/she says <quote>my days are past the best</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This makes the speaker more human and therefore more <choice><orig>relateable</orig><reg>relatable</reg></choice> for the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p><s>A further stylistic device employed by<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is the rhetorical question.</s><quote><s>But wherefore say she not she is unjust?</s><s>And wherefore say not I that I am old?</s></quote><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 9, 10)</ref>; <s>these two rhetorical questions are the volta, the turning point of the poem and they invite the reader to think with the speaker and to follow his/her train of thought.</s><s>Furthermore, there is a parallelism within these rhetorical questions, which expresses to the reader that the speaker and the beloved woman, are similar in a way, that being that they both lie to each other.</s></p>
      <p>
        <s>The personification <quote>love's best habit</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 11)</ref> is used to make love seem like an entity, which has <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> own will.</s>
        <s>In the poem, love makes the speaker and the woman lie to each other, in order to make each other feel good.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>age in love loves</quote><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 12)</ref> is a personification of age as well as an alliteration.</s>
        <s>The alliteration helps to enrich the poetic effect and once again <choice><orig>stress</orig><reg>stresses</reg></choice> the theme of love.</s>
        <s>Whereas the personification expresses that the speaker is old and that his/her age has human qualities, such as a will.</s>
        <s>It is then said, that the age, meaning the speaker does not want to be reminded of his/her age by his/her loved one.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> employed this personification to stress the importance of age to the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>she is made of truth</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 1)</ref>, creates an image of someone who is expremely truthful and when<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> writes in the next line <quote>she <choice><orig>lie</orig><reg>lies</reg></choice></quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 2)</ref>, it makes her seem very dishonest.</s>
        <s>Because of the antithesis that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> used, the reader thinks of the woman as a dishonest, not nice person, which also makes her human and understandable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses different formal and poetic devices, to on the other hand characterize the speaker and the woman.</s>
        <s>In a very flawed and therefore human way and on the other hand he employs poetic devices to clearly state his message, that lies in a loving relationship are acceptable.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
