<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l02_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this romantic sonnet, <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> uses really simple, but effective formal and poetic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first you can see, that <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> wrote 14 verses.</s>
        <s>They are connected through a cross rhyme scheme.</s>
        <s>Which means that the fitting rhymes are crossed.</s>
        <s>For example, the first and the third verse do rhyme, and the second and the fourth verse do rhyme.</s>
        <s>It's crossed and often recognized as abab-system.</s>
        <s>He wrote 14 verses, which means that the sonnet has seven pairing rhymes.</s>
        <s>It's very significant that he uses many alliterations, which means that words start with the same letter.</s>
        <s>For example, he used it at the second verse with <quote>travel tired</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 2)</ref>, which is better recognizable for our minds.</s>
        <s>The human mind can recognize things better when they get repeated or when they rhyme.</s>
        <s>Same stating letters make it also sound better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In verse nine and ten he also uses alliterations, to <choice><orig>itensify</orig><reg>intensify</reg></choice> the meaning and the expression behind his words.</s>
        <s><quote>Save [...] souls, [...] sight [...] shadow [...] sightless</quote><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 9f.)</ref>, those alliterations, over two, not rhyming, verses give them power and also highlights them.</s>
        <s>I would say that this two verses are the most important in the whole Sonnet, because they are highlighted, through the alliterations, and they describe exactly what he wants to express.</s>
        <s><quote>Even though <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> can't see, my soul still sees you, in the darkest times I only think of you, even my soul is deeply in love/connected with you</quote> are a couple of things he wants to express.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With the <choice><orig>Anapher</orig><reg>anaphora</reg></choice>, which means that the beginning of sentences are repeaed or the same <quote>by day my limbs, by night my mind</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(v. 13)</ref> he expresses that his whole life, his whole body and personality is focused on the person he loves.</s>
        <s>HIs whole life is influenced by her/him.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> doesn't use a lot of devices alone by the words he chooses, he creates a beautiful atmosphere.</s>
        <s>He still manages to express exactly what he wants to say.</s>
        <s>It's impressive.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
