<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l11_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following the format and poetic devices used by<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> in his sonnet in order to illustrate his view is going to be analysed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To begin with structure, <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> is a typical Shakespearean sonnet <choice><orig>divided</orig><reg>devided</reg></choice> into three quatrains, each concluding four lines, and at the end there is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> ending couplet.</s>
        <s>The three quatrains are written in cross rhyme <name type="misc">abab cdcd efef</name> and the ending couplet in pair rhyme <name type="misc">gg</name>.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, the famous metrical pattern by Shakespearean sonnets iambic pentameter is also use by him in this sonnet, which sounds like a heartbeat and it <choice><orig>strengents</orig><reg>strengthens</reg></choice> the feeling of love for the reader.</s>
        <s>This usual Shakespearean rules that also <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> follows makes his sonnet more understandable and easier for the reader, as this is typical of <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnets.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The Volta or turn, which can be found in line 9 and can be signalized by the word <quote>But [...]</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> or <quote>yet</quote>, makes already the poem more interesting for the reader, because it usually changes the meaning or the message.</s>
        <s>Not only in the given sonnet, but also in most of <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnets is the ending couplet known as the conclusion, which <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">wether</gap> answers the question asked in the sonnet, or it summarizes the sonnet as an ending.</s>
        <s>Regarding the use stylistic devices in the given sonnet, the author emphasizes in the first and second line <quote>When my love sweats [...] I know she lies</quote> enjambment, which makes clear that the speaker's beloved person is lying in their relationship.</s>
        <s>This is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> exciting start of the sonnet for the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to, the <choice><orig>hyperbel</orig><reg>hyperbole</reg></choice> <quote>simply I credit her false speaking tongue</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> means that even the speaker knows about the lies, he does not mind it.</s>
        <s>This strengthens the poetic feeling of love because the reader understands how much the speaker is in love with his beloved person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 9 and 10, the author utilizes repetition <quote>wherefore</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>, <quote>wherefore</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> in order to keep the sonnet interesting for the reader by asking the questions, which is an interior monologue of the speaker because he asks himself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, as one can realize that <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">W. Shakespeare</ref> sonnet is alive because of the always used feeling of love.</s>
        <s>The findings of the speaker are clear and they are underlined by the devices used by the author.</s>
        <s>Like always, not only the given sonnet but also most of the Shakespearean sonnets touch the the reader's heart.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
