<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l06_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following the formal and poetic devices that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses will be analysed in order to understand how he conveys his view on the problem of false pretend between lovers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sonnet 138 follows strictly the formal structures of a typical Shakespearean sonnet since it composes strictly of 14 lines which can be divided into three quatrains and one concluding couplet.</s>
        <s>Moreover, it is written in the rhyme scheme <name type="misc">abab cdcd efef gg</name>, which also supports the speaker's argumentative train of thought in the quatrains with a cross rhymes and his more accepting concluding couplet through the harmonic pair rhyme.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another very typical formal aspect is the volta in line nine <quote>(But)</quote> as it introduces the <choice><orig>speakers</orig><reg>speaker's</reg></choice> changed perspective and inner trouble with the lies.</s>
        <s>As regards the rhythm, the sonnet mostly follows the iambic pentameter quite regularly which results in the rhythm of a heartbeat that symbolizes how the sonnet is a matter of the heart.</s>
        <s>The only time the rhythm falls out of order is during the volta making the reader even more able to feel the <choice><orig>speakers</orig><reg>speaker's</reg></choice> troubled change of heart.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The typical and very neat structure of the sonnet can also be seen as a support for the content, since the poem is about pretending that there is nothing wrong and keeping up the nice and good facade.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When looking at the poetic devices one can see that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses quite a few in order to illustrate and to intensify his view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Right at the beginning the introduction of the topic employs the paradox <quote>I do believe her, though I know she lies</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The speaker states his problem and that he is actually also lying to himself and presents that troubling situation to the listener who has to think about the phenomenon for a second and feels as though an explanation is missing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Therefore the explanation is given in the next lines and due to the repetition of the word <quote>to think</quote> (<quote>think</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>, <quote>thinking</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>, <quote>thinks</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>) the reader understands that all the lying and pretending originates from the fear of the speaker of what his love and even himself might think of him and her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>false speaking tongue</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> describes the lover's lies and creates a less negative image which supports the feeling of the speaker that he likes to be lied to because it spares him from the ugly truth of time.</s>
        <s>With a less negatively connotated word it is therefore easier for the reader to understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When taking a look at the volta, one can identify two parallelistic rhetorical questions in lines nine and ten.</s>
        <s>The persona of the poem does not only question his lovers behavior but also his own and the parallelistic structure represents just how much they are the same.</s>
        <s>Moreover these lines are really the only time the speaker ever expresses himself stright forward and even though he does not have or want and answer the audience sees his truth for the first and only time during the sonnet.</s>
        <s>When ending the third quatrain the doubled alliteration <quote>and age in love loves</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> sets a focus on the doubt of love's nature in the whole.</s>
        <s>While love is at the same time personificated it makes the listener understand that the speaker sort of lost <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">contrall</gap> because with love, pretending is easier and more enjoyable <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> the harsh truth.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude one can say that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses the formal appearance of the poem to illustrate the expected idealistic picture of a relationship during Elizabethan and Petrarchan times ans uses his language to <choice><orig>examplify</orig><reg>exemplify</reg></choice> why it is also nicer and easier to also lie about meeting those standards.</s>
        <s>However, he also employs <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices in order to break though this ideal view and question the unrealistic perfect love the speaker and his lover pretend to have and the true trust they sacrifice in the process.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
