<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11g07_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The foster child <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> in the novel <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="title">Gun Love</ref> is a talkative, lovely child with a tough childhood and she often mixes her true memories with her false memories up.</s>
        <s>It is remarkable that she is traumatised and much influenced by her childhood and that she is a fool of the American Dream, because she never get in better conditions.</s>
        <s>In the following part, I will analyse her in detail.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> eight-year-old foster child who <choice><orig>lookes</orig><reg>looks</reg></choice> like a five-year-old child and is built very small <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 1-2)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She has a childish and lovable appearance which is shown by <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref>, thinking she was younger <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 2)</ref>, her behavior <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 41)</ref> and the things she likes <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 18-20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By talking <quote>nonstop</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> she <choice><orig>find</orig><reg>finds</reg></choice> a way in dealing with her tough childhood.</s>
        <s>On the one hand she may disregard her trauma but on the other hand it could <surplus>could</surplus> help her talking to others about it for dealing with her problems indirectly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She also has <quote>no idea</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> about what she is talking because she is very young and <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> understand her life and her experiences fully.</s>
        <s>It also shows that she missed out being a child and doing childish things because she had to handle hard topics, for example poverty, so that is a reason for her younger and childish appearance.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>One</orig><reg>On</reg></choice> the other hand she never learned much about growing up, because there were too many different homes and people in her life <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 11-12)</ref>, which is also an aspect for her childishness.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Her surrounding was not like a home and not very loving because she had for example to sleep on the <quote>floor</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>That is why she is so lovely, soft and childish now, because she likes lovely things like <quote>forehead kisses</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> and <quote>cats</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref> which are <quote>cute</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref> and soft like her personality.</s>
        <s>Her behaviour towards <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 41-42)</ref> shows her needing of love and a mother figure that she never had.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She has no <quote>sense</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref> in her life so she adds things that did not happen.</s>
        <s>She speaks about herself in the third person <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 17)</ref> because it is a senseless life for her which not feels like she is the person that is living it so she hides it before herself.</s>
        <s>Nobody corrects her <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 17)</ref> because they have sympathy for her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The other foster <choice><orig>children</orig><reg>child</reg></choice> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Leo</ref> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> is like a family member because he always hangs out with her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She loves her family and her friends <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Lulu</ref>, <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Gina</ref> and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Romey</ref> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 32-33)</ref> because she would call them if she <choice><orig>new</orig><reg>knew</reg></choice> how to use the 17 phones she got for every foster home she were before <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 30)</ref> so she a place to call home.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of her hard childhood and missing of love, she is very lovable and needing nowadays and she talks very much to deal with her past.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
