<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11g11_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>To really understand <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Helens</orig><reg>Helen's</reg></choice></ref> situation you have to look very deep into the excerpt from the novel <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="title">Gun Love</ref>, by <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="author">Jennifer Clement</ref>, published in <date>2019</date>, which deals with 14-year-old <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> and her situation living in a car with her mother and her situation after her mother gets shot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In her new foster home <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> meets two other children, <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Leo</ref> and <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is eight years old but <quote>look[s] about five</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She smells like burned marshmallows, which reminds <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> of her past, burning marshmallows in her car with a lighter <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 3,4)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is also very talkative and has no idea who she is or where she comes from <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 5,6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>You can see that when she tells <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> about her different mothers with different ethnics, her ten brothers, eleven sisters, her twin brother and two twin sisters.</s>
        <s>She is also from <name type="geo">Ethiopia</name> and from <name type="geo">Finland</name>.</s>
        <s>She was told she was born in a house, but another foster home told her she was born in a hospital <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 6-9)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is described as a <quote>true-blue foster child</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref>, because she has had many different homes and families, still remembers every little detail about them and sees them as her real family.</s>
        <s>She also does not even try to figure out her real past, because she really believes these people are her family.</s>
        <s>All these families gave her a phone and charger to keep in touch with her.</s>
        <s>And <choice><orig>eventhough</orig><reg>even though</reg></choice> she does not know which phone belongs to which family she kept all of them to call her family and friends, which shows that she is very loyal.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is not complicated rather a simple human being.</s>
        <s>She dreams of snow on Christmas in <name type="geo">Florida</name>, she loves forehead kisses and she tells <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref>, that she feels better after a shower <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 18-20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Everything she is talking about is out of order <quote>there is no way to follow her and attempt to make sense of her life</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The different homes, many changes and not knowing the truth affected her in a way that her thoughts are <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">hona</gap> mixed up and twisted in her head.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> has a twisting nature.</s>
        <s>Shortly after meeting <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> she is already sitting close besides her and <quote>rubb[ing] her forehead against [Pearl's] upper arm</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 41, 42)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is speaking about herself in third person, which highlights her identification issues.</s>
        <s>Her thoughts are expressed very simple in a few words for example <quote>Helen loves forehead kisses</quote> <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is proof for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Pearls</orig><reg>Pearl's</reg></choice></ref> thesis, that nobody had <choice><orig>thaught</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> her things <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> and nobody is correcting her <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Normal eight year olds do not really think about simple things like this and they also do not talk in third person about themselves.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> does not know anything about her real mother and her real father but she also does not question it because her foster families told so many different stories and she is believing them all.</s>
        <s>She also talks about three friends, who she wants to call, which means that their numbers are somewhere in her 17 different phones and it will probably take very long to find them, which again shows <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen's</ref> messy life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref> is a simple but gullible person and has a loving and affectionate personality shown through her knowledge about all her past foster homes, even though she has not had contact with them in years.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
