<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l40_t2</author>
        <name>characterize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">characterize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given excerpt from <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>'s comedy <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> <add>1596/97</add> <name type="person">Shylock</name> encounters <name type="person">Tubal</name> who has both good and bad news for him, which puts <name type="person">Shylock</name> into a conflict between grief and excitement.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <name type="person">Shylock</name> spots <name type="person">Tubal</name> on a street in <name type="geo">Venice</name>, where this scene takes place, he is filled with excitement but he is also nervous and even still a little hopeful that <name type="person">Tubal</name>, who has been looking for <name type="person">Shylock's</name> daughter <name type="person">Jessica</name>, might have been able to find her.</s>
        <s>That he can barely wait to hear the news is conveyed to the audience by the direct address of <name type="person">Tubal</name> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> and his direct questions about the topic and whether or not <name type="person">Tubal</name> has been successful.</s>
        <s>As <name type="person">Tubal</name> tells him that he had not been able to find <name type="person">Jessica</name>, <name type="person">Shylock's</name> mood changes quickly into a quiet form of self-pity which he shows in the exclamation <quote>[...] there, there, there, there</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He still needs some time to realize that his daughter, who was so very dear to him as the metaphor <quote>A diamond [...]</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> implies, is now forever gone.</s>
        <s>The repetition of <quote>two thousand ducats</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 3ff)</ref> and the alliteration <quote>precious, precious</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> show his anger about his losses but also how important money is to him.</s>
        <s>It might be something that makes him feel safe because throughout the course of the play it becomes clera that most Venetians only respect him for being good as a merchant.</s>
        <s>Now this source of safety got taken by his own daughter and he has to come to the realization that he lacks control over the life of <name type="person">Jessica</name> as her very own father and even over his own life for when his daughter and his money were away he did not know how to react.</s>
        <s>Therefore he feels the loss and grief deeply and can even feel cursed; as if all the bad things in the world only always happen to him <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 4+7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>chiasme</orig><reg>chiasmus</reg></choice> <quote>The thief gone with so much, and so much to find the thief</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> reflects his pity for himself, especially for having lost so much money.</s>
        <s>The anaphora <quote>no satisfaction, no revenge</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 8f)</ref> add to the previous stylistic devices but show another character trait of <name type="person">Shylock</name>: his revengeful side.</s>
        <s>He is mad and angry at his daughter and even at the whole world.</s>
        <s>Moreover, he is unable to wish his daughter the best or forgive her in any kind of way: <quote>no satisfaction</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> which implies that there is no way she could turn things around again.</s>
        <s>Finally the parallelism <quote>no sighs but of my breathing; no tears but of my shedding</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 9f)</ref> ends <name type="person">Shylock's</name> passage of self-pity and anger.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> opens self-reflected but lacks empathy for other people and since so many bad things have happened to him he acts very self-centred and seems to always putting himself.</s>
        <s>This can also be noticed throughout the dialogue for <name type="person">Tubal</name> speaks very little and only gives new information to <name type="person">Shylock</name> and the audience while <name type="person">Shylock</name> finds himself expressing all his meotions and hateful thoughts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Tubal</name> remarks his egoistic perspective <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> while telling him about <name type="person">Antonio</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is pleased to hear this name in combination with <quote>ill luck</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> and gets filled with excitement immediately which is shown in his interruption of <name type="person">Tubal's</name> speech.</s>
        <s>His repetition of <quote>what</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> and <quote>ill luck</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> show his eagerness for the bad luck of a foe of his.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> appears quite moody as his mood changes so quickly from his sadness to happiness about his brand.</s>
        <s>The rhetorical system <quote>Is't true, is't true?</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> make <name type="person">Shylock</name> seem a little bit childish which makes sense in a way of him finally getting what he was hoping for and gaining back at least the feelign of more control over his life.</s>
        <s>The direct address of <name type="person">Tubal</name> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> expresses <name type="person">Shylock's</name> thankfulness towards <name type="person">Tubal</name> for being a good friend to him by lifting him up.</s>
        <s>The alliteration <quote>good news, good news</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> underlines how badly he has been waiting for a good thing to happen but also make <name type="person">Shylock</name> appear in a bad light for he is able to find happiness in the defeat of somebody else.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> continues on by asking more questions for he is so excited that he wants more details.</s>
        <s>Though the details that <name type="person">Tubal</name> can provide are that his daughter spent a lot of his money already which he will never get back.</s>
        <s>This realization hurts <name type="person">Shylock</name> and he shifts back into his sad mood of grief and loss.</s>
        <s>The repetitive exclamation <quote><qs>foursome ducats [...]!</qs><qs>Foursome ducats!</qs></quote> express his anger and disbelief in <name type="person">Jessica's</name> behaviour.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> falls back into his self-pity but <name type="person">Tubal</name> reminds him of the ruined <name type="person">Antonio</name> which puts <name type="person">Shylock</name> into a rather neutral tone.</s>
        <s>He does not show his excitement as extremely anymore but his contentment about being able to finally get revenge.</s>
        <s>The repetition of <quote>I am [...] glad of it [...] I am glad of it</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> remark his revengeful side and also build a bracket for the parallelism <quote>I'll plague him, I'll torture him</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> which underlines his assertive way to follow his intentions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As <name type="person">Tubal</name> mentions his dead wife's ring though, <name type="person">Shylock</name> drifts back again to his angry mood and expresses how hurt he is by the fact his daughter gave this ring away in the hyperbole <quote>I would not have given it for a wilderness of monkeys</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 25)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock's</name> emotions about this ring portray him as a loving and caring husband and father because if he would not care so much about his daughter he would not be so hurt that she left him.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> appears to be quite emotional but not very good at expressing his feelings towards other people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Tubal</name> retrieves him from his thoughtfulness once again by reminding him that <name type="person">Antonio</name> is certainly ruined.</s>
        <s>But after all the bad news about his daughter <name type="person">Shylock</name> is unable to convey as much excitement about this as before.</s>
        <s>Still, he lets go of his thoughts about his daughter and wants to forget about them as soon as possible which is delivered to the audience through his action of planning the case at court two weeks ahead.</s>
        <s>The repetition <quote>Go, Tubal</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 27)</ref> and <quote>Go, go <name type="person">Tubal</name> </quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 29)</ref> but also <quote>at our synagogue; [...] at our synagogue</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 29f)</ref> underline his enthusiasm about a thing going right in his life and finally getting the chance to get revenge for all the bad things that have happened to him lately.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude one may say that in this excerpt <name type="person">Shylock</name> appears very self-centred by the way he pities himself.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, he seems very moody because he feels emotions strongly and changes between anger about his losses and happiness about <name type="person">Antonio's</name> bad luck.</s>
        <s>In addition to that <name type="person">Shylock</name> appears revengeful but the audience also gets to know his loving and caring side through his emotions over a ring.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
