<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l39_t2</author>
        <name>characterize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">characterize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given excerpt from <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>'s <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> <name type="person">Shylock</name> and <name type="person">Tubal</name> meet each other on a street in <name type="geo">Venice</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following <name type="person">Shylock</name> will be characterised.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is a Jewish man who lives in <name type="geo">Venice</name> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 0)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He has a daughter who ran away with a Christian man <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock's</name> wife called <name type="person">Leah</name> is dead which means he is now on his own <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 24)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His daughter ran away and his wife died.</s>
        <s>Because of these two aspects one can say that <name type="person">Shylock</name> is a melancholic character.</s>
        <s>By saying <quote>nor, no in <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">luuh</gap> skipping but what lights on my shoulders</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> <name type="person">Shylock</name> presents himself as a very unlucky and unhappy person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> cares a lot about money.</s>
        <s>He is very rich but he wants to keep his money.</s>
        <s>These two aspects are shown his reaction to <name type="person">Tubal</name> telling him that he cannot find his daughter <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 3-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Before his daughter left him he really liked her because he bought her earring with jewels which are worth two thousand ducats <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 3-7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>But now because she ran away <name type="person">Shylock</name> hates her.</s>
        <s>He wishes she was dead lying in a coffin in front of him <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This line shows that <name type="person">Shylock</name> is a cruel person.</s>
        <s>He wants his daughter to die because she stole a lot of money and it costs him a lot to try and find her <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This view <name type="person">Shylock</name> presents shows again that <name type="person">Shylock</name> loves money and really cares about it.</s>
        <s>Because of <name type="person">Shylock's</name> religion he was not in a good position in the society lock in this time.</s>
        <s>Although he was a rich person many people used to have <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> opinions so many people looked down on him for being a Jew.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of these people who look down on him is <name type="person">Antonio</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Antonio</name> is a Christian man who lives in <name type="geo">Venice</name> who also has a lot of money.</s>
        <s>The difference between <name type="person">Shylock</name> and <name type="person">Antonio</name> is their religion and the outward appearance.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> does not care aobut other people's opinion and he is very direct.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Antonio</name> on the other hand really cares about what people think about him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They both hate each other.</s>
        <s>As soon as <name type="person">Tubal</name> says <name type="person">Antonio's</name> name <name type="person">Shylock</name> reacts really surprised.</s>
        <s>By repeating the word <quote>what</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> three times this points gets proven.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As soon as <name type="person">Shylock</name> receives the information that <name type="person">Antonio</name> may break their bond he is really happy.</s>
        <s>By repeating the sentence <quote>I am glad of it</quote> twice his <choice><orig>happines</orig><reg>happiness</reg></choice> is shown.</s>
        <s>At the same time he is really cruel <choice><orig>aswell</orig><reg>as well</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><quote>I'll plague him; I'll torture him</quote><ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 27)</ref> shows how brutal he is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock's</name> use of language changes a lot.</s>
        <s>He asks a lot of rhetorical questions <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 7, 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He also repeats himself very often <quote>I thank god</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>, <quote>good news</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> and <quote>that's true</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 26)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The level of his languages changes a lot too.</s>
        <s>During his monologue he uses more high society words but if he asks questions or repeats himself he uses basic words.</s>
        <s>This proves the point that he could be part of the high society but he is not because of his religion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all one can say that <name type="person">Shylock</name> is a very lively character who can also be very brutal and direct.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
