<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l39_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Kit,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>How are you?</s>
        <s>How is your family and your dog?</s>
        <s>I hope you are all doing fine.</s>
        <s>I think I forgot to tell you that I will come and visit you in five weeks!</s>
        <s>I can't wait.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So I heard that you hvae to work on a presentation about unsual school projects worldwide.</s>
        <s>Two days ago I found a perfect example for you in a newspaper.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Two years ago there was a huge chess proecjt in a <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> country called <name type="geo">Bremen</name>.</s>
        <s>The project was called <name type="misc">Schach macht schlau</name>, that means something like chess makes you clever.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Pupils from primary schools had chess lessons once a week for a year.</s>
        <s>2400 children took part in this project.</s>
        <s>72 percent of the teachers said that their students enjoyed playing chess and 23 percent of them said that a couple of students started playing chess outside of the school in their freetime.</s>
        <s>A third of the teachers also said that playing chess helped their students to focus on things and it was good for their social skills.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This project was not the only one we had in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At a school in <name type="geo">Hamburg</name> chess is a normal subject.</s>
        <s>Instead of music or art the pupils have one lesson of chess.</s>
        <s>They have been doing this for more <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> ten yeras and the schools' headmaster said that chess is good for students' communication.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The outcome of another project was that also younger people can beat older ones and with a couple of rule changes also good players can loose to bad players.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So all in all I can say that according to the projects chess is good for students at a young age.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could <choice><orig>helped</orig><reg>help</reg></choice> you with your presentation and hopefully one of your slides is about the <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> chess project in <name type="geo">Bremen</name> and its outcome.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We will see each other in five weeks!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Have a nice week and say hi to your parents from me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best regards,</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
