<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l32_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Emily,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I just got your email about your presentation concerning unusual school projects worldwide and I did some digging.</s>
        <s>Turns out we actually have a lot of unusual school projects in <name type="geo">Germany</name> like circus projects or chess projects.</s>
        <s>Latter really sparked some interest in me so I found this article from <name type="misc">Der Tageszeitung</name> named something along to lines of <quote>Not check mate: chess as a subject in schools</quote> it was written by <ref target="a12lk3_2" type="author">Joachim Görres</ref> and published on the <date>30th of June 2020</date>.</s>
        <s>It deals with the positive effects of playing chess in schools.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Teachers believe that playing chess in schools from a young age improves concentration, logical and strategic thinking and helps improve how the studens interact with <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice> in class.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There has been a lot of projects all over <name type="geo">Germany</name> in <name type="geo">Bremen</name> and <name type="geo">Hamburg</name>.</s>
        <s>The kids in <name type="geo">Bremen</name> played chess one hour per week for a whole year and at the end had a little tournament.</s>
        <s><name type="geo">Bremen</name> has, by the way, the most chess projects in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>They polled the teachers who were part of the project about the effects the chess program had on them.</s>
        <s>72% said that the kids loved playing chess.</s>
        <s>About half of educationalists in <name type="geo">Germany</name> expected positive outcomes like better concentration and improved logical thinking and the teachers claim that these positive effects are noticeable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From learning how to play chess early on the kids also learn to really think about a decision before making it.</s>
        <s>Obeying the rules and how to be good <choice><orig>looser</orig><reg>loser</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>In <name type="geo">Hamburg</name> they had had this project for over ten years now and the teachers there are convinced that the project improved the overall performance of the kids, bettered their communication skills, helped with social interactions and improved concentration.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But of course there are some problems: good players can easily get bored and not so good players might get frustrated.</s>
        <s>The kids could also <choice><orig>develope</orig><reg>develop</reg></choice> a hatred toward chess if forced to play it.</s>
        <s>So the teachers have to make sure not to pressure the kids too much.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I honestly think this is a really cool idea, you should totally add it to your presentation.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Eventhough</orig><reg>Even though</reg></choice> I am convinced that I am the worst chess player I am sure such a proect would be more fun than our <name type="person">Business@school</name> project.</s>
        <s>Well, I hope I could help you, if you need anything else let me know.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Love, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
