<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l23_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Though just having got to know eachother, <name type="person">Juliet</name> and <name type="person">Romeo</name>, the protagonists of <choice><orig>William Shakespeares</orig><reg><ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>'s</reg></choice> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref>, have a strong love for eachother <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> they do not hold back to express and confess to eachother making vows and promises.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>There</orig><reg>Their</reg></choice><choice><orig>thougts</orig><reg>thoughts</reg></choice> and feeling of love and greatly delivered through the language used in his play.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first sign of their love is from line 58 to line 60 and also 61.</s>
        <s>By stating <quote>My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words of that <choice><orig>tounge's</orig><reg>tongue's</reg></choice> utterance, yet <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> know the sound: art thou not Romeo and a Montague</quote>.</s>
        <s>Although not directly speaking at love this metaphor states how she still recognizes <name type="person">Romeo</name>, only by his voice, because of the dark.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> recognizing him despite only having spoken a few words to eachother shows how much he <choice><orig>stayed</orig><reg>has stayed</reg></choice> on her mind and how much she has thought of him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo's</name> direct <choice><orig>aswer</orig><reg>answer</reg></choice> <quote>Neither, fair saint, if either thee dislike</quote> shows how he would even give up his own name and also family name, if <name type="person">Juliet</name>, by any means, does not like either of them.</s>
        <s>This is a great example of how much <name type="person">Romeo</name> is willing to sacrifice for their love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Aswering</orig><reg>Answering</reg></choice><name type="person">Juliet's</name> question of how he climbed the high walls of their garden, <name type="person">Romeo</name> says: <quote>With love's light wings did I o'er perch these walls; For stony limits cannot hold love out and what love can do that dares love attempt</quote><ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 66-68)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> firstly uses the phrase <quote>loves light wings</quote> as a metaphor for the lightness and feeling of freedom that come with being in love that make one feel like they can accomplish anything and that led him to climb the dangerous walls of the <name type="person">Capulet</name> garden.</s>
        <s>By stating <quote>For stony limits cannot hold love out</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author"> Shakespeare</ref> makes <name type="person">Romeo</name> refer back to the garden walls, he just defeated as a metaphor for anything in their love's way, even the families' feud.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This adds to the effect of <name type="person">Romeo</name> being maniacally in love to a point where he even thinks he is invincible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His thought of being invincible with <name type="person">Juliet's</name> love is proven again in line 72 and line 73 as he states <quote>Look thou but sweet, And I am proof against their enmity</quote> <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> means that armed with <name type="person">Juliet's</name> love and kindness he would not be in danger of <name type="person">Juliet's</name> family's hostility.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>During this part of their conversation <name type="person">Juliet</name> is still very concerned of her family finding <name type="person">Romeo</name> <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> she repeatedly expresses <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 65,70,74)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name><choice><orig>therefore</orig><reg>therefor</reg></choice> answers <quote>I have night's cloack to <choice><orig>hid</orig><reg>hide</reg></choice> me from their sight</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 75)</ref> as a metaphor the darkness giving him the opportunity to hide, but also <quote>And but thou love me, let them find me here: my life were better ended by their hate, than death prorogued wanting of thy love</quote>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> rather being dead and killed by the <name type="person">Capulets</name> again adds to the effect and feeling of him being maniacally and blindly in love <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> intensified the <choice><orig>watchers</orig><reg>watcher's</reg></choice> connection to him and his love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Yet again <name type="person">Romeo's</name> love is visualized <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 82-84)</ref>: <quote>I am not a pilot; Yet wert thou as far as that vast shore wash'd with the farthest sea, I would adventure for such merchandise</quote>.</s>
        <s>Comparing a treasure to <name type="person">Juliet</name> and the <quote>farthest sea</quote> as anything standing in their love's way once again once can see that <name type="person">Romeo</name> would do literally anything for <name type="person">Juliet</name>.</s>
        <s>Confirming what she just said in her monologue, <name type="person">Juliet</name> <choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to reassure that <name type="person">Romeo</name> really loves her by telling him to <quote>pronounce it faithfully</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 94)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This could be a sign of doubt in her mind, given everything <name type="person">Romeo</name> just said to her and her still needing reassurement.</s>
        <s>As <name type="person">Romeo</name> begins to swear by the moon he is interrupted by <name type="person">Juliet</name>: <quote>O swear not by the moon, that monthly changes in her circled orb</quote> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 109f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>For <name type="person">Juliet</name> the moon is a metapher of inconsistency because of <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> <choice><orig>continiously</orig><reg>continuously</reg></choice> changing shape.</s>
        <s>She rather wants him to <quote>not swear at all; Or if thou wilt, swear by thy gracious self, Which is the god of my idolatry</quote><ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 113-115)</ref>, with the last line implying that to her, <name type="person">Romeo</name> is even godlike and then she'll believe him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum it up, the audience gets to feel and see the intensity of <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet's</name> love, going as far as willing to die for eachother and is given the opportunity to further sympathize with both characters, through the feeling of <choice><orig>strog</orig><reg>strong</reg></choice> love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
