<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l28_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Peter,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>thank</orig><reg>Thank</reg></choice> you for your last letter!</s>
        <s>Yes, I'm doing well, how about you?</s>
        <s>It sounded like you were very stressed out about this essay you're writing, so of course I will help you!</s>
        <s>I found a rather interesting article explaining why producers in <name type="geo">Brandenburg</name> still put on <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays.</s>
        <s>Since it's in German, I will sum it up for you and attach the link below!</s>
        <s>The article was written by <ref target="a12lk2_2" type="author">Karim Saab</ref> in <date>2016</date> and published in the rather serious newspaper <name type="misc">Märkische Allgemeine Zeitung</name>, it's called <ref target="a12lk2_2" type="title">Darum spielen wir Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article deals with the question of why <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is still the most popular playwright of all time and interviewed some theatremakers in <name type="geo">Brandenburg</name> to answer.</s>
        <s>The first one states that modern invention and society have not managed to dissolve human exmotion and the other interviewees seem to agree.</s>
        <s>They all claim that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has a unique way of sharing these emotions and depicting humanity at its worst and best in a way no one else could.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second interviewee is convinced that there is always something new to discover about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> and that it helps us understand the past but confronts us with <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">thuuues</gap> of the present.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another interviewee adds that without <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> we would not even have other famous poets like <name type="person">Schiller</name>, <name type="person">Goethe</name> and more.</s>
        <s>He also comments on the variety of things that are portrayed in these works, such as women in power, people grasping for happiness and more, which <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> portrayed in an incredibly complex and unique way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The next interviewee thinks in a similar way and points out <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> rhetorical and stylistic power and how <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> touched people with his art in ways no one else could because he appealed at all of hteir emotions with his words.</s>
        <s>The last interviewee also states that the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">cueruht</gap> of works and the amount of languages they have been translated to make it almost impossible to get past <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>.</s>
        <s>He thinks that the playwright is not just timeless but also includes thoughts that are very interesting and appealing to us nowadays.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So as you can see, there are many reasons to portray <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work, not just in general, but also in <name type="geo">Germany</name> specifically.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I was able to help you along and, if that's alright with you, I would love to read your essay when it's finished!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best wishes,</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
