<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l29_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In scene 2 <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 58-116)</ref> of the second act in <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>'s <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref>, <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> talk on the <name type="person">Capulet's</name> residence, <name type="person">Juliet</name> on the balcony, <name type="person">Romeo</name> down in the orchard.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> voices concerns about <name type="person">Romeo</name> he denies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the given extract, <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> conversation first concerns <name type="person">Romeo's</name> identity then his safety, with <name type="person">Juliet</name> pointing out that if he was found by the other <name type="person">Capulets</name>, he would be killed but he denies her feaers, saying that his love to <name type="person">Juliet</name> makes him strong enough to take on anyone attacking him and that it was reason enough to put himself into this danger.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Juliet</name> is not yet convinced he says that if she was to <choice><orig>looks</orig><reg>look</reg></choice> kindly at him he would be <choice><orig>save</orig><reg>safe</reg></choice> against any attack and when she replies that she does not want <name type="person">Romeo</name> to be seen there he answers that he can't be seen in the night and that he'd rather be killed by <name type="person">Juliet's</name> family than to not talk to her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that <name type="person">Juliet</name> gives up and asks <name type="person">Romeo</name> how he knows about the place to which he replies shortly that he asked for directions and then continues with his confession of love for <name type="person">Juliet</name>.</s>
        <s>She then admits to a monologue earlier in the scene in which she confessed her love to <name type="person">Romeo</name> and adds that she would ignore their family feud if <name type="person">Romeo</name> was to love her back honestly and that he shouldn't be taken aback by her quick confession since it does not diminish how seriously she means it.</s>
        <s>To confess his love to <name type="person">Juliet</name>, <name type="person">Romeo</name> starts to swear by the moon which concerns <name type="person">Juliet</name> again, thinking that may could mean that <name type="person">Romeo's</name> love is as changing as the moon.</s>
        <s>She doesn't want him to swear by anything except maybe himself.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
