<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l25_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In lines 60-61 there is a personification <quote>My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words</quote>.</s>
        <s>This personification shows that while <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> don't even know each other for a long time, they could hear them just by some sounds.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally the author gives a simile for a contrast in line 71-72 <quote>there lies more peril in thine eye than twenty of their swords</quote>.</s>
        <s>This shows how <name type="person">Romeo</name> feels the love of <name type="person">Juliet</name>.</s>
        <s>In <choice><orig>line</orig><reg>lines</reg></choice> 72-73 <name type="person">Romeo</name> <choice><orig>say's</orig><reg>says</reg></choice> <quote>look thou but sweet, and I am proof against their enmity</quote>.</s>
        <s>This also shows how strong <choice><orig>there</orig><reg>their</reg></choice> love can be against their problems.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <choice><orig>line</orig><reg>lines</reg></choice> 77-78 <name type="person">Romeo</name> says <quote>My life were better ended by their hate, than death prorogued, wanting of thy love</quote>.</s>
        <s>He can't wait longer to be together with her just because of the clash between the <choice><orig>familys</orig><reg>families</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Lines 83-84 give another point that <name type="person">Juliet</name> is everything for <name type="person">Romeo</name> and that he will go everywhere and pay everything to get with her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 98 <name type="person">Juliet</name> contradicts her sentences before where she criticizes <name type="person">Romeo</name> in his behaviour with her statements <quote>In truth, fair <name type="person">Montague</name>, I am too fond</quote>.</s>
        <s>This shows that however the situation between them and their <choice><orig>family's</orig><reg>families</reg></choice> is, they will love each other <choice><orig>for ever</orig><reg>forever</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His <quote>gracious self</quote> should be her god <quote>of idolatry</quote><ref target="a12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 114-115)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This also underlines the opinion of <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> to themselves.</s>
        <s>To conclude it's to note that extract is written in informal language and the narrative perspective is the first person narrator.</s>
        <s>This perspective is chosen to get clear about the character's feelings.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
