<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12l21_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Everyone with a basic education of English language has heard of <name type="person">William Shakespeare</name>.</s>
        <s>But are the works of the playwright that lives more than 400 years ago, still relevant today or might they be outdated?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works have already been translated into more than 100 languages worldwide.</s>
        <s>There are most likely more languages to follow, which will have a major impact on world's literature even in the future.</s>
        <s>Besides, <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> influenced an important part of today's English language and he is told to have created 1700 - 2200 new words.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> works are about timeless topics like love, hate or family.</s>
        <s>These topics will also play a role for future generations which still makes <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> relevant.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other side, it is to be said that students suffer <add>more and more</add> to understand the special and unique style of writing, which was different to the known English even back in the 16th century.</s>
        <s>Another argument for <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work being outdated is that it is irrelevant today, as we are facing enormous challenges like climate change or a growing population.</s>
        <s>There are thousands of authors who write important and famous books.</s>
        <s>Why should today's students not read a story from somebody alive that refers to the globalized world or an even picture of male and female, unlike <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion, <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> was a genius far beyond his time.</s>
        <s>He influenced a lot of other authors and the English language in the last 400 years.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand students suffer reading his work, topics with growing relevance and books about these topics exist and there are thousands of authors worldwide that may have a chance of creating an impact as <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has until now.</s>
        <s>We should give these authors a chance and start a new chapter in literature, in which you can spot pieces of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> impact, but also new works by new authors.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
