<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l20_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text extract from Act II, scene 2 by <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare's</ref> <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="title">Romeo and Juliet</ref> is about them talking and reflecting about their love for each other.</s>
        <s>The meaning of language has an important aspects concerning their <quote>relationship</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name> both know that their love is against their <choice><orig>families</orig><reg>families'</reg></choice> <choice><orig>will</orig><reg>wills</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Juliet</name> realizes that <name type="person">Romeo</name> is in the <name type="person">Capulet's</name> orchard she immediately begins to worry about his life.</s>
        <s>She is <choice><orig>scarred</orig><reg>scared</reg></choice> that her relatives could find <name type="person">Romeo</name> and is convinced of them killing <name type="person">Romeo</name> in that case.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Romeo</name> otherwise, seems blended by the love, so that he does not care what happens to him, as long as <name type="person">Juliet</name> loves him.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Juliet</name> is flattered by these words and expresses her feelings for <name type="person">Romeo</name> in a monologue.</s>
        <s>After that, both of them seem to have enough <choice><orig>corage</orig><reg>courage</reg></choice> and strength to fight together for their love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The language also shows this development of the stability of their relationship.</s>
        <s>At the very beginning in line 58f when <name type="person">Juliet</name> thinks she is alone and talking to herself, she makes use of a personification: <quote>My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words of that tongue's utterance, yet I know the sound</quote>.</s>
        <s>She is talking about <name type="person">Romeo</name>.</s>
        <s>They just have seen one time before this scene and <name type="person">Juliet</name> means by this choice of words that even they have spoken that little and hears have not even heard a hundred words of him because there was no time to talk yet, she can still imagine the sound of his voice and the words he spoke.</s>
        <s>The effect of using this stylistic / poetic device is that her words concerning <name type="person">Romeo</name> are becoming more real.</s>
        <s>They are literally coming to life.</s>
        <s>Even if it's only a memory of <name type="person">Romeo's</name> presence, with the personification it becomes easier for the reader to be able to have this reference.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 78 <quote>Than death prorogued, wanting of thy love</quote> the author, <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>, is making use of an oxymoron.</s>
        <s>At this point of the scene <name type="person">Romeo</name> , who hides in the dark to be with <name type="person">Juliet</name>, is talking about how he does not care about being killed by <name type="person">Juliet's</name> relatives, the <name type="person">Capulets</name>, if that means <name type="person">Juliet</name> would love him.</s>
        <s>By that he means that he is willing to take the risk just for the love, which is very romantic.</s>
        <s>The constellation of the word <quote>death</quote> and <quote>love</quote> in one sentence and line gives a dramatic effect, which is typical for the oxymoron.</s>
        <s>It also has the effect that the contrast of these especially in the meaning two completely opposite words are drawing attention to the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Further in the text extract where <name type="person">Juliet's</name> gives her monologue takes place there is a repetition in line 88: <quote>Fain would I dwell on form, fain, fain deny...</quote>.</s>
        <s>By that <name type="person">Juliet</name> means that she would be glad to conform to social norms, but there is just no way to do that because she is in love with <name type="person">Romeo</name>.</s>
        <s>So the convention of such should be abolished.</s>
        <s>To focus on the language there is to say that <name type="person">Juliet</name> employ with the repetition of the word <quote>fain</quote>, which appeals to have the meaning <quote>gladly</quote>, that even she thinks the social norms have usch an impact on everything, she still is willing to love <name type="person">Romeo</name>.</s>
        <s>With the repetition she can point out how much she wants him and the whole statement is given more strength.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude one can say that the poetic / <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices, chosen by <ref target="a12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>, definitely have their sense of underlining the meaning of the validity.</s>
        <s>The thesis, that the language is sufficient for showing the development of the love of <name type="person">Romeo</name> and <name type="person">Juliet</name>, is therefore to confirm.</s>
        <s>In addition the <choice><orig>lovers</orig><reg>lovers'</reg></choice> reflection on their <quote>love agains the odds</quote> also changed.</s>
        <s>They both now are willing to fight for their love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
