<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12l05_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his article, the author uses lots of facts and examples from our daily lives in order to make his message seem authentic to the reader and causing there to be a connection between pandemics and the actions of every one of us.</s>
        <s>He increases the chance of reaching us as readers that way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The appeal <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> tries to bring across in his article, starts right at the beginning of the text.</s>
        <s>The headline functions as a warning to the readers, informing them about what could happen in the near future, bbut also <choice><orig>mentiones</orig><reg>mentions</reg></choice> the solution for the problem <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 1-2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By doing that, he increases the chance of his audience reading further as he <choice><orig>seemes</orig><reg>seems</reg></choice> to answer the question to a present problem, which is global pandemics.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article starts off by introducing the reader to facts, right at the beginning <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 7-10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Simplifying the outburst of <name type="misc">Ebola</name> in <date>2013</date>, by children playing outside near a tree in which bats were hiding, <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> shows up how fast global pandemics can evolve and where they come from.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Next, he confronts the reader with the fact, that <name type="misc">Ebola</name> was not unpredictable to happen at some point and that there are millions of other viruses in wildlife, we just have not gotten in contact just yet <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By using this fact, on one hand, the author manages to shock the rader, as it may sound concerning to know that there is a potential danger, on the other hand he puts the number of pandemics we had so far into perspective with those that are theoretical and shows up that they can still be avoided.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> does not only pick up on pandemics from the past, but also mentions how problematic globalizations impacts can be on outbreaks all over the world.</s>
        <s>In lines 32-35 he explaines how <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> was <quote>transported</quote> <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 34)</ref> from rural areas in China to us, comparing the virus to a parcel or post and therefore connecting the comfort of our globalized world to the problems that come at cost.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At last, <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref>, once again, underlines what we know already: He shows up the fact that a lot of people have died, due to <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 38-39)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The chances of a reader having lost someone is not as low as it may seem, which is how <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> can reach out to those and stress how near the current topic is to every one of us.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Allthough</orig><reg>Although</reg></choice> he adds, that pandemics, like those mentioned, can be prevented: In lines 50-54 he finishes his article by underlining, that pandemics are also functionable as a chance for use humans to make a change, for example by avoiding wild life.</s>
        <s>By doing this, <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Daszak</ref> <choice><orig>summes</orig><reg>sums</reg></choice> up to the reader that every pandemical situation we have found ourselves in up to now is a result of human actions, <choice><orig>allthough</orig><reg>although</reg></choice> preventing them is a matter of changing out habits.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
