<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b12l04_t3</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Welcome <choice><orig>ladys</orig><reg>ladies</reg></choice> and gentlemen</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you for visiting our international student conference and thank you for allowing me to speak to you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Today is about the future of globalization.</s>
        <s>Today is about our future.</s>
        <s>But let's start with the present first.</s>
        <s>For a long time it was not even clear if this conference could take place because of the current crisis we are in.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A crisis, that is as bad as it is also because of globalization.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref> explains in his article <quote>a globalised network of travel and trade have accelerated the pace of pandemic emergence</quote>.</s>
        <s>But it is not only the pace of a pandemic spreading.</s>
        <s>It is the pace of so many more problems <choice><orig>councouring</orig><reg>conquering</reg></choice> the world.</s>
        <s>Just remember the terrorist attacks in <name type="geo">Europe</name> or think about the climate crisis we are currently facing.</s>
        <s>The ice at the poles is melting, animals are dying and our planet is suffering under our own actions.</s>
        <s>We are the ones responsible for what happens with and on our planet.</s>
        <s>We are the ones responsible for the terrible living and working conditions in outsourced <choice><orig>factorys</orig><reg>factories</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>We are the ones responsible for languages <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> endangered and the loss of diverse culture.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Why don't we act upon it?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Why does it seem like everybody cares more about brands and cheap <choice><orig>prizes</orig><reg>prices</reg></choice> instead of sustainability and fair trade?</s>
        <s>We hold the power of demand and reply.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Why does nobody really act on the climate change?</s>
        <s>Why are plane tickets still cheaper than the ones for trains?</s>
        <s>It is our future we were talking about.</s>
        <s>The future of our own children.</s>
        <s>Why aren't governments acting on this matters?</s>
        <s>If we start to make drastic <choice><orig>changs</orig><reg>changes</reg></choice> right now it is already late but maybe not <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> late.</s>
        <s>Globalization does not only have these bad sides.</s>
        <s>We need to use the food ones to fight the bad ones.</s>
        <s>We need to make use of the shrinking of the world.</s>
        <s>Governments need to work together closely and we wil be able to overcome the spreading problems.</s>
        <s>Just like we worked together while developing a vaccine and made it <choice><orig>accessable</orig><reg>accessible</reg></choice> to other countries.</s>
        <s>We need minimum wages that are defined by law in every country in the world.</s>
        <s>And we need to appreciate and protect our diversity in language, cuisine and culture.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>People are better connected nowadays than ever before we must not let people get frustrated with globalization because the new technology is a danger to their jobs or because everything is changing to quick.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Integrating and retraining them would be a way to prevent the rise of nationalism and xenophobia.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Trying to cut ourselves and our countries out is not an option.</s>
        <s>We can see it in Britain.</s>
        <s>Thanks to <name type="misc">Brexit</name> the supermarket shelves are empty now.</s>
        <s>No, globalization brings so many <choice><orig>opportunities</orig><reg>oportunities</reg></choice> and enrichtments, that need to be <choice><orig>supportet</orig><reg>supported</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But without fighting <choice><orig>agains</orig><reg>against</reg></choice> the bad ones it's future will not look like we wish.</s>
        <s>Our future will not look like we wish.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
