<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b12l03_t3</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear ladies and gentlemen, dear politicians,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I feed deeply honored to speak to such an illustrious audience tonight.</s>
        <s>First, let me thank you for giving me the opportunity to speak at such an amazing event.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Please ladies and gentleman look to <choice><orig>you</orig><reg>your</reg></choice> left and right sides.</s>
        <s>Yes, tonight we have gathered here coming from different parts of the world and al this thanks to globalization.</s>
        <s>But all of us are also wearing masks which is due to the current pandemic, which is also because of globalization.</s>
        <s>So let me ask you this question: Is globalization a blessing as a cures?</s>
        <s>On the one side it is a cures, especially after reading the article from <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref> about globalization and the spread of viruses.</s>
        <s>Because we live in a globalized world viruses can spread fast because of global migration and all these travel opportunities we have.</s>
        <s>Only a few hundred years ago this would not have been the case.</s>
        <s>But globalization and all these travel opportunities also give us the solution to the problem.</s>
        <s>Because of our so much networked world with low to even no tarifs the cure, the vaccines can be <choice><orig>sphipped</orig><reg>shipped</reg></choice> very fast saving millions of <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The article I have read, which had a huge impact on me also claimed that our current approach of dealing with pandemics is the wrong way, becuase we first let viruses spread <choice><orig>globaly</orig><reg>globally</reg></choice> and then try to find a solution when it is already to late, but in my opinion this statement is outdated, ladies and gentlemen.</s>
        <s>Because of globalization our smartest brains from all around the globe had the opportunity to come <choice><orig>togeather</orig><reg>together</reg></choice> personally or even digitally because of our technological advancements that allowed us to <choice><orig>develope</orig><reg>develop</reg></choice> a <choice><orig>vacciene</orig><reg>vaccine</reg></choice> only in a few months.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The next point I wanted to talk about is the claim that globalization has many as even only caused the import of <choice><orig>negativ</orig><reg>negative</reg></choice> trends, such as the fact that all of us love fast food, which means more pollution and obesity or the fact that all of us love <name type="misc">Nutella</name> which contains palm oil from rainforests.</s>
        <s>Yes, these examples are negative trends which we have in- and exported but again globalization is also in this case the cure.</s>
        <s>Globalization not only means the import of bad but also of good trends.</s>
        <s>For instance, we a very young person from a young generation that fights for a better future for example through the movement of <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> made by a young person <name type="person">Greta Thunberg</name> that was capable to motivate millions of people all around the world to fight against these global issues on a global level.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear politicians,</salute>
        <s>without globalization I <choice><orig>wound</orig><reg>would</reg></choice> not be able to speak in front of you, because I am only here because of global migration.</s>
        <s>Because my family came to <name type="geo">Europe</name> I was able to <choice><orig>acces</orig><reg>access</reg></choice> high <choice><orig>standarts</orig><reg>standards</reg></choice> of education, hence I am able to speak in front of you about complex matters in my third language which <choice><orig>ist</orig><reg>is</reg></choice> <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> that all of us understand.</s>
        <s>Let me assure you: Globalization may have had and still has negative impacts but in order to solve this global issues we have to work on them <choice><orig>globaly</orig><reg>globally</reg></choice>, which is why we can't escape globalization anywhere and instead we have to look for solutions and see this as a challenge.</s>
        <s>I <choice><orig>belive</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> that <choice><orig>togeather</orig><reg>together</reg></choice>, I, you, politician, expert, <choice><orig>scientis</orig><reg>scientist</reg></choice>, student and everyone else have to use globalization to <choice><orig>garantee</orig><reg>guarantee</reg></choice> a better future.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
