<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g40_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the scene the director presents <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> <choice><orig>selfconfident</orig><reg>self confident</reg></choice> and their relationship is happy, because they seem to know each other well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first shot, is a full shot, which shows <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> walk to <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and draws attention on the other students, who give a high-five to <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to point out that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is popular in the school.</s>
        <s>Additionally the director makes use of a high-angle and medium shot to highlight the <name type="misc">Jordans</name> from <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> because <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> loves these shoes and <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> know that, this makes clear that he exactly knows how to impress her.</s>
        <s>Apart from that, when he reaches <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, the director decides to use a close up, to emphasize that he <choice><orig>let</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> listen music on his headset.</s>
        <s>The following close up underlines her smile, when she hears the music, so she reacts nice to the music, accordingly <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows which music gets <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> in a good mood.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, when <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> apologizes, the director makes use of a lot of close ups to draw attention on their faces and on <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face it's possible to see that she is not even really angry and that they are extremely understandable for each other.</s>
        <s>Their good relationship is additionally underlined by the eye level shot, while their <choice><orig>dialog</orig><reg>dialogue</reg></choice>, it points out, that no one is in a superior position and that they both are in their relationship on the same position, how it should be in a justice relationship.</s>
        <s>At the end of the scene, the director decides to use a full shot to highlight <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> dance and to show how <choice><orig>selfconfident</orig><reg>self confident</reg></choice> he is, moreover <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> <choice><orig>suceeds</orig><reg>succeeds</reg></choice> again to make <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> happy with his dance.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude you can say, that they have a wonderful relationship and <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> really loves his girlfriend and <choice><orig>get</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> the love he gives back.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
