<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g45_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>How does the <choice><orig>directore</orig><reg>director</reg></choice> present <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in the sequence?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented as the popular high-school boy, everyone likes.</s>
        <s>This effect is underlined by many stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>The sequence is set in the school-hallway, because it shows <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> confidence and social contacts.</s>
        <s>A love song is playing while he walks up to <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> in slow-motion.</s>
        <s>He talks and smiles at many of the other <choice><orig>studends</orig><reg>students</reg></choice>, which makes clear that he has many friends.</s>
        <s>The camera follows him and he is seen in a full shot, so the viewer can see the background and him moving.</s>
        <s>We can see that everyone looks at him and that he gets attention.</s>
        <s>When he arrives, there is a close up of <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> getting <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> headphones on and the love music stops.</s>
        <s>Instead we can hear instrumental music, so we notice that the love music comes of <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> mind, when she thinks of him.</s>
        <s>It also takes the viewer back to reality, because the slow-motion stops.</s>
        <s>The sequences when they talk is filmed in close ups, so the facial expressions are shown.</s>
        <s>This stylistic device is very important, because <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is smirking, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> shows that she isn't as angry as she says she is.</s>
        <s>The shots are changing from over-the-shoulder to <choice><orig>revease</orig><reg>reverse</reg></choice> shot, because the director wants us to see that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> <choice><orig>seemes</orig><reg>seems</reg></choice> really sorry about what <choice><orig>happend</orig><reg>happened</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>An important part is the close up of <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris'es</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> shoes.</s>
        <s>For <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, her shoes are very important, because it is the only thing she wears that doesn't fit in with her personality at school.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> wears the same pair, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> underlines the image of the <q>perfect boyfriend</q>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Afther</orig><reg>After</reg></choice> the talk he <choice><orig>release</orig><reg>releases</reg></choice> that he made the music we can hear for <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> says <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> okay, so <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> takes the headphones out of his phone and dances to the music <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of everybody.</s>
        <s>It makes clear that he is really confident and <choice><orig>embarrise</orig><reg>embarrasses</reg></choice> himself just because he wants <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> to laugh.</s>
        <s>While doing that, the sequence is in slow-motion again and the camera <choice><orig>zoomes</orig><reg>zooms</reg></choice> in which <choice><orig>acheaves</orig><reg>achieves</reg></choice> the effect of the <q>perfect boyfriend</q> again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene is set at the beginning of the film.</s>
        <s>It's important because a new character is introduced.</s>
        <s>It also shows what type of a relationship they both have.</s>
        <s>The high amount of shots makes the scene very hectic.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>clothe</orig><reg>clothes</reg></choice> they wear are school uniforms which underlines the fact that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> has a strong <choice><orig>personallity</orig><reg>personality</reg></choice>, <choice><orig>allthough</orig><reg>although</reg></choice> everyone wears the same outfit and we can see the contrast between his uniform and his shoes.</s>
        <s>The colours are mostly blue and white, that presents a calm and light <choice><orig>atmosphear</orig><reg>atmosphere</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>All in all the producer of the film presents <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Chris</ref> as a confident, creative and popular guy and the perfect boyfriend for <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
