<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g17_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Now I am going to analyze the communicative strategies and the use of language, used by the author to present his personal view of the situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Starting of, the author uses a repetition <quote>Can't, won't, don't</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1">(l. 1)</ref> to really show how miserable the situation is.</s>
        <s>This stylistic device used in the first sentence puts the reader into a more focused and interested state.</s>
        <s>Following this opening sentence the author leads the reader into a straight fact underscored by a striking <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>metephoros</orig><reg>metaphors</reg></choice><quote>collective brains</quote> and <quote>on the menu</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1">(ll. 5-6)</ref> are really important to catch the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>reader's</reg></choice> eye and bring <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">faus</gap> to them.</s>
        <s>This structure of the text is very important if we look at the communicative strategies, where the author is really sticking out.</s>
        <s>Especially the next two phrases are interesting.</s>
        <s>The first one <ref target="a12gk2_1">(ll. 9-11)</ref> is filled with strong facts, data and formal languages.</s>
        <s>In contrast the second phase is very different.</s>
        <s>In this phrase, arguments against the learning of foreign languages are <choice><orig>braught</orig><reg>brought</reg></choice> up and <choice><orig>immedeatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> shut down.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>Author</orig><reg>author</reg></choice> uses a super long hypertactic sentence, filled with <choice><orig>ironys</orig><reg>ironies</reg></choice> and informal, opinion-drafted arguments.</s>
        <s>This structure shocks the reader but then shows the importance of this specific topic.</s>
        <s>For example <quote>perfectly intelligent people</quote> <choice><orig>a irony-masterpiece</orig><reg>an irony masterpiece</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>To use this to start <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> the sentence requires stunning writing skills and the understanding on how to convince the reader.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the irony <quote>the next generation of wearable tech will enable intercultural telepathy anyway</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1">(ll. 14-15)</ref>, is brilliant, not just because it is very striking and even funny to the reader, it also is cut <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> with a simple <quote>cobblers</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1">(l. 15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This phrase has a really big impact on the reader because of the simplicity.</s>
        <s>Moving on the author is now moving back to the more formal and <choice><orig>fact based</orig><reg>fact-based</reg></choice> language.</s>
        <s>In line 16-17 there is a list of arguments that underscore the <choice><orig>authors</orig><reg>author's</reg></choice> opinion.</s>
        <s>In the next phrase the author is focussing on the straight facts.</s>
        <s>Besides he also is pointing out the importance of <choice><orig>foeign</orig><reg>foreign</reg></choice> languages in the modern society of globalisation.</s>
        <s>Bringing in the study of a high <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">clasr</gap> industry points out that he is not on a <quote>wrong way</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1">(ll. 19-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Heading into the next sentence, the author starts <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> with <quote>the only good news</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1">(l. 24)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This statement shows how bad the situation and the importance of this topic.</s>
        <s>In line 27 and 29 there are two anaphoras which are used to repeat two words in pairs.</s>
        <s>The language of this phrase is kept formal due to the seriousness of this topic.</s>
        <s>The next sentence is a statement which is brought up by the author to once again make his point clear <ref target="a12gk2_1">(ll. 30-31)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He is finishing his article with <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> appeal to the readership, especially to the parents of students and kids.</s>
        <s>He is using a truly beautiful <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice>: <quote>... essential strings to our children's bows</quote>, to once again appeal and bring the importance to the readership.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he is stepping into direct contact with the readership by using the phrase <quote>we</quote> <ref target="a12gk2_1">(ll. 33 and 35)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To summarize this article it is safe to say, that the author has done a brilliant job.</s>
        <s>The topic is not easy and there are several other opinions but there are no mistakes in the way it is presented.</s>
        <s>The language changes from super formal to a very informal language to create <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">tonse</gap> and a close bond between the reader and the author.</s>
        <s>Filled with stylistic devices and arguments it is hard to not instantly <choice><orig>belive</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> and support the opinion of the author.</s>
        <s><gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">Glazed</gap> by this article I must say it was truly astonishing.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
