<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g16_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Is it important to learn foreign languages for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future and for the global standing?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>It is a world where the importance of close cooperation all over the world will be decisive every day.</s>
        <s>There are global problems like the climate change or the pandemic.</s>
        <s>If you work together, you will speak together.</s>
        <s>There you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> use a translator on your <choice><orig>mobil</orig><reg>mobile</reg></choice> phone or your dictionary.</s>
        <s>There is it important that you can also communicate with people who do not speaking English.</s>
        <s>There will be the same problem, if you work.</s>
        <s>Every big company has an international network for example through outsourcing.</s>
        <s>You must communicate with other <choice><orig>countris</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>There is not the certainty that everybody <choice><orig>speak</orig><reg>speaks</reg></choice> English.</s>
        <s>The globalisation gives the people the chance to travel all over the world.</s>
        <s>And if you <choice><orig>traveled</orig><reg>travelled</reg></choice> in a country where the people <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> speak English, you would be not communicate with other people and language is also a part of culture.</s>
        <s>Without a foreign language you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> learn about so much about a culture.</s>
        <s>Also it shows respect, if you learn another language.</s>
        <s>When you don't learn a foreign language it is a kind of arrogance.</s>
        <s>Another argument is that you can work in other countries.</s>
        <s>So for example you can speak German and you are a teacher.</s>
        <s>There is a chance that you can go to Germany and then you work in Germany as a teacher.</s>
        <s>You are more free.</s>
        <s>You can say that there is a smartphone with a <choice><orig>translater</orig><reg>translator</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But is your smartphone more reliable than your brain?</s>
        <s>Your brain is working in every situation, your mobile phone can switch off or can have no connection.</s>
        <s>You can also say that English is a <quote>world-language</quote> but there are all over the world many people who do not speak English.</s>
        <s>So there is no problem to learn <choice><orig>anoter</orig><reg>another</reg></choice> foreign language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all there will be different chances, if you learn foreign languages.</s>
        <s>It is important for your job and it is also important for the global standing of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>It <choice><orig>showes</orig><reg>shows</reg></choice> that the <name type="geo">UK</name> is not arrogant.</s>
        <s>Also you have the opportunity to work all over the world and to learn better about other cultures.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
