<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g18_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As the globalisation is a topic that is getting more and more important in everyday life the question about the importance of worldwide communication is coming up.</s>
        <s>That is why I want to make everyone clear how important it is in <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> world and also how important it is for the future of the <name type="geo">UK</name> to speak foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> already mentioned in his article <quote>Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</quote>, learning languages is important for prosperity and global standing in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some people might say that there is no need to learn languages because of <choice><orig>online-translators</orig><reg>online translators</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But I totally disagree with that argument because two people can not have a fluent dialogue if they have to <choice><orig>tip</orig><reg>type</reg></choice> everything they want to say in their mobile phone at first.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some people might also say that there is no need to learn languages because it is not necessary for their everyday life.</s>
        <s>They think that it is just necessary to speak the language of the country they are living in.</s>
        <s>But let me <choice><orig>proof</orig><reg>prove</reg></choice> you that they are wrong.</s>
        <s>Speaking different languages is not just helpful for work but also for <choice><orig>yor</orig><reg>your</reg></choice> private life - your freetime.</s>
        <s>No matter where you go, you will always meet somebody from <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> other nation.</s>
        <s>Sometimes this person can speak your language but sometimes this person <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>To be able to talk to them anyway it is important to speak their own language.</s>
        <s>Or if you travel it is helpful to speak different languages too.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But more important is the aspect of work.</s>
        <s>Because of the globalisation a lot of jobs are outsourced and international teamwork is necessary.</s>
        <s>People from all over the world come together in the internet and work together and not everyone can speak English even thought it is the <quote>worldlanguage</quote>.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> already mentioned a person who is able to speak different languages has more chance to get the job <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> someone who just speaks English.</s>
        <s>Furthermore <name type="geo">England</name> is a country with a high quote of export.</s>
        <s>For the export, it is important to communicate with the firms from the other nations.</s>
        <s>If that is not possible the firms will probably export from another nation where it is easier to communicate.</s>
        <s>Because otherwise there is a high risk of misunderstanding.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>less</orig><reg>Less</reg></choice> exports would also mean less prosperity for the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>But not only for export but also for import it is important to speak different languages.</s>
        <s>A lot of clothes in the <name type="geo">UK</name> come from developing countries like <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name>.</s>
        <s>Especially the workers in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> are not really educated.</s>
        <s>That is why they probably just speak their mother tongue.</s>
        <s>To speak with them anyway it is important to speak their language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There are also reasons why it is important for the global standing for the <name type="geo">UK</name> to be able to speak foreign languages.</s>
        <s>The economical situation as well as the political situation in one country is important for the global standing.</s>
        <s>Both situations just can be done good with the right communication.</s>
        <s>Communication is the key to success in a country!</s>
        <s>And communication is just possible if the people speak and understand the same language!</s>
        <s>That is why it is so important to learn a foreign language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If more people in the <name type="geo">UK</name> start to speak more different languages the process of globalisation can get even more forwards and the <name type="geo">UK</name> will have a good global satnding because of <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> many workers who are able to work international.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
