<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g16_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The comment <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: 'can't, won't, don't'</ref> written by <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and published in the daily newspaper <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> on <date>27th January 2015</date> deals with the speaking of foreign languages in the <name type="geo"><choice><orig>United Kingdoms</orig><reg>United Kingdom</reg></choice></name> and the importance of this topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly the author points out that the number of persons who speak a foreign language is going down.</s>
        <s>But there is also a progress at primary schools because there is also the number of students with a foreign language fallen.</s>
        <s>Furthermore <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> criticizes people, who think that English is a language which you can speak all over the world and a translator for example is not reliable.</s>
        <s>Besides the author means that foreign languages are important for the future of the country and for yourself.</s>
        <s>It has a decisive influence on your job because of the fast-growing market you need this skill.</s>
        <s>But <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> thinks there is also a positive point because students can study a language and another degree course.</s>
        <s>Moreover the author points out that a person with a foreign language skill rather <choice><orig>get</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> a job than a person without this skill.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the text deals with the importance of foreign languages for the future of people.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
