<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12g19_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Greg,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You good?</s>
        <s>What is going up there in Canada?</s>
        <s>I heard you are going to spend a year in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>germany</orig><reg>Germany</reg></choice></name> after school.</s>
        <s>That is very cool, I would recommend <name type="geo">Berlin</name> for you I think you heard that <choice><orig>aswell</orig><reg>as well</reg></choice> really often it is very interesting there even as <choice><orig>English speaking</orig><reg>English-speaking</reg></choice> guy I will tell you in the following.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Many people are speaking English in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> you could even compare it to other big cities where everybody speaks English.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Thats</orig><reg>That's</reg></choice> because <name type="geo">Berlin</name> is a big tourist attraction and evry much students are studying at unversities in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> nearly everybody goes back to from where they cam maybe the <name type="geo">UK</name> or the <name type="geo">USA</name> but a few of them stay and it is not unspecial that you hear more English than German on the streets of a few <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">glcks</gap> named <name type="geo">Mitte</name> or <name type="geo">Neukölln</name>, these blocks <choice><orig>where</orig><reg>were</reg></choice> known as <choice><orig>arabic</orig><reg>Arabic</reg></choice> or <choice><orig>turkish</orig><reg>Turkish</reg></choice> blocks but now it is literally hard to get something to eat there without speaking English.</s>
        <s>You could say <name type="geo">Berlin</name> is more international than ever.</s>
        <s>Many people think <name type="geo">Berlin</name> is not like other parts of <name type="geo">Germany</name> it is its own little country by itself.</s>
        <s>Many restaurants and cafés could <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">alws</gap> be the same in other big cities but the prices in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> are much better than in the big cities all over the world.</s>
        <s>Many people use <name type="geo">Berlin</name> as their chance to create their own business or live their dream because of the low rent for shops and flats.</s>
        <s>Everything is perfect to do whatever you want and find yourself.</s>
        <s>The hype about <name type="geo">Berlin</name> is very cool and also very fair.</s>
        <s>I hope you know now what you are facing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Until soon in <name type="geo">Germany</name></signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
