<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g19_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The claim that <quote>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's </name> future prosperity and global standing</quote> is right in my opinion.</s>
        <s>You could say that everybody can speak English it is the language of the world but I think that is wrong there are enough people who <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> speak English or do not want to speak it so it always good to know other languages and to know how to <choice><orig>comunicate</orig><reg>communicate</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Now many people can say why would somebody not want to talk English if he can speak it, <choice><orig>thats</orig><reg>that's</reg></choice> <choice><orig>particullary</orig><reg>particularly</reg></choice> right but if you are a little <choice><orig>business man</orig><reg>businessman</reg></choice> and you want an answer from a big <choice><orig>business man</orig><reg>businessman</reg></choice> who leads many businesses you have to use his language to create attention on your project.</s>
        <s>But you could say you can use  <name type="misc">Google Translate</name> to know what to write to him.</s>
        <s>That is completely correct but what if you meet the person in real life and what if your phone dies when you want to look up a word.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>business man</orig><reg>businessman</reg></choice> would not think you are authentic and maybe even reject you <choice><orig>It</orig><reg>it</reg></choice> is also not important to learn another language than English when you only work together with other people from the <name type="geo">UK</name>, that is correct too but if you want to have more chances to get promoted it is always helpful to speak other languages like it is said in the text in addition to that the country of the <name type="geo">United Kingdom</name> could not create new partners or alliances so this mindset would weaken the <name type="geo">UK</name> on long time.</s>
        <s>Another <choice><orig>con argument</orig><reg>con-argument</reg></choice> against learning foreign languages in the <name type="geo">UK</name> could be that the <name type="geo">UK</name> is proud of their own language and they do not think it is helpful to learn a new one.</s>
        <s>That is wrong because there is not only the fact that you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> talk easily to people from other countries there is also the fact that English people could be seen as very partiotic maybe a little <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> patriotic and that is bad for the influence of the country all over the world.</s>
        <s>Furthermore people from other countries would not feel well and do not come to the <name type="geo">UK</name> again which is really bad when the tourism goes back and the <name type="geo">UK</name> does not make money with that.</s>
        <s>You could say that it is very much <choice><orig>afford</orig><reg>effort</reg></choice> to learn a new language and many people do not have the time to do that next to a job or school.</s>
        <s>I know that it is not esy to do but for example many universities give students the chance to do a language course next to the subject they are normally studying.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I would say <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> claim is right but I would change the word <quote>vital</quote> to <quote>very important</quote> because the people in <name type="geo">UK</name> could live without other languages and the global standard could be good <choice><orig>aswell</orig><reg>as well</reg></choice> but it is very much harder to do it without foreign languages in my opinion.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
