<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g60_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As a teenager you have to go through lots of problems.</s>
        <s>Your body changes and suddenly you are responsible for more things than before and often don't know how to deal with it.</s>
        <s>Furthermore you start to <choice><orig>develope</orig><reg>develop</reg></choice> your own way of dealing with others and how to run a good relationship.</s>
        <s>In the following task I will comment on why films can help you to get over these problems, but also why it's necessary to go through some of these problems alone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all it can be <choice><orig>helpfull</orig><reg>helpful</reg></choice> to see teenager problems in films, because you experience how you should act or not act in certain situations.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The film <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> does this in a very good way.</s>
        <s>The problems in <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> <choice><orig>live</orig><reg>life</reg></choice>, equally if they having to do with racism or relationships to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> or <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Hailey</ref> are always shown very good and also had a big impact on me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example I always asked myself why <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> isn't ending her friendship with <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Hailey</ref>, because it was obvious that she won't get any advantages through this friendship anymore.</s>
        <s>Like this I experienced that it's better to take distance from someone who may not have a good impact on you, but also that it will never be easy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also from the given scene you can learn very much about social behaviour and how to act in critical situations of your relationship.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> goes to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> showing her that he is sorry but also gives her the reasons why he did it.</s>
        <s>Then he tries to understand <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starr</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> <choice><orig>perspectif</orig><reg>perspective</reg></choice> by not forgetting about <choice><orig>hiself</orig><reg>himself</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So as you can see films can teach you much about social behaviour, but in my opinion it's still better to go through problems like this in real life, because movies often are made extra happy to give the audience a good feeling.</s>
        <s>But in real life it's often harder to deal with these situations and you have to decide more individual how to react on certain problems.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To have a conclusion I think movies are a good medium to experience possible problems you could face and can give you possible solutions but in real life it's not the same and you have to deal with your problem in your own way to develop yourself and to find the best possible solution.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
