<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g55_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the scene, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented as a funny and sociable chap who prays the relationship with <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> much importance.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first shot, the floor is presented in a long shot, while the camera focuses on <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>He greets different persons, laughs much and is presented as a funny and sociable chap.</s>
        <s>We don't hear sounds of the actions, just the music.</s>
        <s>It's the song <name type="misc">Ocean Eyes</name>, by <name type="person">Billie Eilish</name>, which gives <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, in addition of a slow motion, a beautiful look.</s>
        <s>After this first few seconds, we see <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> legs and shoes in a medium long shot.</s>
        <s>This is because <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> speaks about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> <name type="misc">Jordans</name> and it draws the attention to his shoes.</s>
        <s>After this first changing of the shot size, the camera angle changes and we see from the side.</s>
        <s>The shot size also changes to a medium close up and a close up, probably because <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is talking about his lips in this moment which we can see better with this shot size.</s>
        <s>During <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> walk through the floor we sometimes see <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> in a close up to see her facial expressions while talking about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>When he arrives <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, we see him again in a frontal medium long shot and the slow motion and the music are fading out.</s>
        <s>This signalizes that the first shown of <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is over and now something different follows.</s>
        <s>The camera pans to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and we'll see a conversation with <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> now.</s>
        <s>Her face is shown in an extreme close up while looking in her locker.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref><choice><orig>put</orig><reg>puts</reg></choice> the earphones on <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> head and we can hear his beat <choice><orig>whis</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> is dominated by much bass and a simple melody.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> puts the earphones down and the beats <choice><orig>stops</orig><reg>stop</reg></choice> instantly, through this instant stop the ending of the funny showing of the beat is signalized.</s>
        <s>Why they speak, we can hear just noises of other people in the background.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> are shown in a medium long shot standing at <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> locker and the camera changes between <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>two</reg></choice> angles.</s>
        <s>But after a few seconds of the conversation, they are shown in a close up to show their facial expressions while talking in a more detailed way.</s>
        <s>The nonverbal communication through mimic doesn't give new <choice><orig>informations</orig><reg>information</reg></choice> about their thoughts but it underlines their verbal communication.</s>
        <s>After this conversation, they laugh and the beat is the conversation theme again.</s>
        <s>While joking about the quality of the beat, they're still in a big close up and while <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dances he's in a medium long shot.</s>
        <s>We can hear the beat again which sounds cool and fresh and gives <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> dance this look too.</s>
        <s>The dancing is again shown in a slow motion and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> expressions are sometimes shown again.</s>
        <s>These are parallels to the first shot, and show the difference of <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> expression better.</s>
        <s>Now she's laughing and looks happy which was different in the first scene.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As a conclusion you can say that the scene starts and ends with a funny cut one has an important conversation between these cuts.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is shown as a popular and funny person and the dynamic between him and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is, especially through the close ups during the conversation, very well presented.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
