<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g05_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will comment on the impact that the movie had on me and the impact it can have on other viewers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The movie did not have a big impact on me but I think it can have it on other people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For me the movie was interesting but not eye-opening.</s>
        <s>I think I'm a well-informed person in regards to social unequality and political topics.</s>
        <s>This may be the cause why the perspectives shown in the movie weren't that new for me, but still I think the movie is a good visualization of struggles black teenagers have growing up in systems that discriminate them.</s>
        <s>I think this visualization can have a quite strong impact on people not that well-informed.</s>
        <s>The film presents a serious and important topic to the viewer but in a Hollywood-like way, so it can be seen and understood by most people.</s>
        <s>It is made to let the viewer feel with <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and see her struggles which can be seen by analyzing the movie and although it is a movie for the mainstream it doesn't lose the seriousness the book had.</s>
        <s>I also want to say something to the publishing year, because I think if I watched the movie in <date>2018</date> it would have had a stronger impact on me.</s>
        <s>In just three years the <name type="misc">Black lives matter</name> demonstrations grew to a level, which was never reached before so the world was confronted with the topic of systematic racism.</s>
        <s>That's why I think the movie had a big impact when it was first published.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So the movie can, as proven in my comment, have an impact on people and show them other perspectives, but for me it didn't do or have that.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
