<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g09_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the course of the scene certain elements are to be observed which describe the way <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> perceives <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and in which state their current relationship is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The director uses several devices to present <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> from the point of view of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who is annoyed and upset by <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> on the surface loves <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and puts up this act due to not wanting to be treated badly by her boyfriend.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene mainly consists of long shots in a eye-level or low angle with the camera following each of his interactions when portraying <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>That way, the spectator observes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chrises</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> sociability and general superficial character traits that can be concluded by things such as the accessoires he wears or his gesture.</s>
        <s>The low-angle shots let <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> stand out from the other people.</s>
        <s>That way the director points out <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> attention focusing on only her boyfriend, which is stressed through little to no noise and the blurred portrayal of other students in the school as well.</s>
        <s>While <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is watching <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, each shot is in slow motion.</s>
        <s>This visual effect emphasizes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> drifting away from reality with only <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> filling her mind.</s>
        <s>This effect is underlined by the music as well, which sounds soft and admiring while at the same time lively and not warm nor cold.</s>
        <s>The music perfectly portrays <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> current position towards <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>: She is torn between her cold facade towards him and her actual feelings.</s>
        <s>This pretentious coldness is supported by the colour scheme of the sequence: It consists of only cool toned greens and blues which is another factor that proves <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> attitude at <name type="misc">Williamson</name> is adding on to her current conflict.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> then spots <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, the slow motion stops and the camera abruptly shifts from <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, who snaps out of her admiring thoughts and breaks the eye contact and tries to act unbothered by <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> presence through packing her bag.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> approaches <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who is then only seen a big close up turned away from <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>The spectator can now observe her true reaction to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> track after he puts his headphones on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, which is positive, opposing her/following words that don't reflect her shown emotions, which breaks the moment breaks when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in the face and acts upset.</s>
        <s>They both then have a talk and the more their discussion goes into depth, the closer gets the camera to their faces to portray their emotions and the way <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> see each other.</s>
        <s>The atmosphere then continues to change to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> point of view which is contradicted in slow motion.</s>
        <s>Every time this mood sets in, <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> thoughts are heard which all consist of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chrises</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> positive traits and prove her true feelings for him and all the other sounds and people are being blurred out.</s>
        <s>When their conversation reaches the end, <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> begins to avoid eye contact since she is unable to upheld the <choice><orig>fassade</orig><reg>facade</reg></choice> of being upset any longer and tries to suppress her increasing amount of smiles.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> lets this pretence fall down through laughing when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> begins to dance.</s>
        <s>He dances for her while making a fool of himself which proves his love to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and assures her that she is important to him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, the stated hypothesis turns out to be proven through many symbols that are cold such as lighting but are disproven by <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> actual reaction towards <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> which she tries to cover by a pretence until it falls down at last.</s>
        <s>A possible assumption is that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> puts up this act to find out whether <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is truly sorry and will treat her better in the future since it is obvious that she is not deeply upset.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
