<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12g28_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>Tragedie</orig><reg>tragedy</reg></choice> of <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> is a tragedy by <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>It is thought to have been first performed in <date>1609</date>.</s>
        <s>It dramatises the damaging physical and psychological effects of political ambition on those who seek power for its own sake.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A brave Scottish general named <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> receives a prophecy from a <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">trio of witches</ref> that one day he will become King of <name type="geo">Scotland</name>.</s>
        <s>Corrumped by ambition and spurred by his wife, <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> murders <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">King Duncan</ref> and takes the Scottish throne for himself.</s>
        <s>The following scene <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="scene">number seven of the first act</ref>  deals with a conversation between <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> and his wife <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref>, where she tries to persuade <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref>, that he must kill the actual <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">King Duncan</ref> to <choice><orig>fullfill</orig><reg>fulfill</reg></choice> his destiny.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the beginning <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> meets his wife <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> secretly after finishing the dinner in the chamber.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> states that he will not kill <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Duncan</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> does not understand why <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> stops seeking for power and a better life, not only for himself, even for her because she thought he loves her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At this point <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> wants to end the conversation and says that he will gain power with the time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> states that she would do everything to gain power and improve both of their <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Now she wants that <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> takes the chance to act the same way.</s>
        <s>He begins to think about the possibility, but is still insecure.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However, <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> starts to create a plan how they could kill <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">King Duncan</ref> when he sleeps and make his chamberlains responsible for his death, because she will invite them to beer and wine so that they get drunk.</s>
        <s>At the end <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> accepts the plan even if he is not secure by one-hundred percent.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
