<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12g23_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> uses a particular choice of words and <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices to convince her husband of murdering <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">King Duncan</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all she is talking much more in this scene than her husband.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> talks just a few sentences, his wife speaks the most of the time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line nine she uses a rhetorical question: <quote>Was the hope drunk wherein you dressed yourself?</quote> to make fun about her husband and his hopes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 19 she uses a metaphor <quote>like the poor cat i'the adage?</quote> in a rhetorical question.</s>
        <s>She is saying with this metaphor that if he want to get or reach something he <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> to do something or work hard for it.</s>
        <s>She wants to open his eyes that nothing in life comes by doing nothing and if he has a goal he must be prepared to make his hands dirty.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> is not with her.</s>
        <s>He uses a metaphor in line 22 <quote>who dares do more is none</quote> to contradict her.</s>
        <s>He just says doing less is sometimes doing more like sometimes you have to wait everything is happening time by time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> is absolutely other opinion.</s>
        <s>She says <quote>what beast was't, then, that made you break this enterprise to me?</quote> with this choosing words she wants to stress out how important this enterprise was for her.</s>
        <s>She wants to give him a bad feeling, like it is that important for her and he just says from one minute to the other he wants to do it other way.</s>
        <s>She uses <quote>beast</quote> to make clear that the plan was so strong that just a beast could change his mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this part <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 23-35)</ref> she tries many times giving his husband a bad feeling for example in line 32 to 35.</s>
        <s>She names things she would do and sweared him to do it like he had sworn to her their enterprise.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By this <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> is becoming a little bit weak.</s>
        <s>He asks <quote>if we should fail?</quote>.</s>
        <s>By his question he seems unsure like standing between <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>two</reg></choice> choices.</s>
        <s>First he was against his <choice><orig>wifes</orig><reg>wife's</reg></choice> plan but now he relates her but is still not amused.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She is trying further and further with many manipulations and a go to plan <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 38-39)</ref> <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 41-45)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She plays their enterprise down and takes it for granted.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
