<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12l36_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Antisemitism plays a big role in the play <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref>, because the two main characters are part of different religions.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Antonio</name> is a <choice><orig>christian</orig><reg>Christian</reg></choice> and <name type="person">Shylock</name> is a <choice><orig>jew</orig><reg>Jew</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Antonio</name> however has a way better reputation than <name type="person">Shylock</name> because he's a <choice><orig>christian</orig><reg>Christian</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>In the time the play was written and plays, Christians were generally looked at as something better than <choice><orig>jews</orig><reg>Jews</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That obviously raises the quetsion whether <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes or raises awareness for it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is no secret that there is antisemetism in the play.</s>
        <s>As you can see in the characterization of <name type="person">Shylock</name>, he is portrayed in a very unpleasant way.</s>
        <s>He fulfills all the negative sterotypes of Jews.</s>
        <s>He is a very rich moneylender who seems to only care about money and is very greedy.</s>
        <s>He also wants to kill <name type="person">Antonio</name>, the nice, sympathetic, Christian man, who the audience loves.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> clearly is the monster in this play.</s>
        <s>So yes, the play surely deals with antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But in my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> that alone can't fuel antisemitic stereotypes since the story is not real.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that it depends on who's watching.</s>
        <s>For some people the bad character traits of <name type="person">Shylock</name> may be a reason to be <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice>but for <choice><orig>others</orig><reg>other</reg></choice> people may feel like it raises awareness for the problem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The play itself can't do either it depends completely on the viewer and how they interprete it in my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However I personally felt like it raised awareness for the problem of antisemitism for me.</s>
        <s>You have to remember that the play was writen for an audience of mainly Christians who did not like <choice><orig>jews</orig><reg>Jews</reg></choice>, which is why the Jewish people were portrayed so terribly and that's not actually how jews are.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
