<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l36_t2</author>
        <name>characterize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to analyze <name type="person">Shylock</name>, the Jewish <choice><orig>money-lender</orig><reg>moneylender</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is a wealthy man living in <name type="geo">Venice</name>.</s>
        <s>He is not very respected by a lot of people in <name type="geo">Venice</name>, since he is a <choice><orig>jew</orig><reg>Jew</reg></choice> among a lot of Christians.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is a father of his daughter <name type="person">Jessica</name>, who ran away with a Christian and had a wife named <name type="person">Leah</name>, who passed away.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the beginning of the extract <name type="person">Shylock</name> <choice><orig>appeares</orig><reg>appears</reg></choice> to be a good father worrying about his daughter since he even sent his friend <name type="person">Tubal</name> off to look for her.</s>
        <s>This first impression however changes quickly when complaining about <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> a lot of money and jewels.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> then adds that he wishes his daughter <quote><s>were dead at his foot and the jewels in her aer!</s><s>Would she were hearsed at my foot, and the ducats in her coffin...</s></quote> in lines 5 to 7.</s>
        <s>This shows that <name type="person">Shylock</name> cares more about the money than his own daughter.</s>
        <s>He would not mind if she were dead if that would bring back his lost treasures.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name><choice><orig>appreares</orig><reg>appears</reg></choice> to be very greedy in this extract which is underlined by stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>In line 5 he calls the treasures he lost <quote>precious, precious jewels</quote> underlining how much he cares about them by saying precious twice.</s>
        <s>He does the same when talking about the amount of money he has lost saying <quote>two thousand ducats</quote> twice.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> also has a lot of self-pity when saying <quote>no satisfaction, no revenge: nor no in luck stirring but what lights on my shoulders; no sighs but of my breathing; no tears but of my shedding</quote> in lines 8-10.</s>
        <s>Since self-pity is often not liked this makes <name type="person">Shylock</name> seem even less sympathetic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another trait of <name type="person">Shylock</name> is that he is very mean and wishes bad things for other people.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Tubal</name> tells him that <name type="person">Antonio</name> has had bad luck, <name type="person">Shylock</name>  gets very excited <quote><s>What, what, what?</s><s>Ill luck, ill luck?</s></quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He completely forgets about his own problems and wishes the worst for <name type="person">Antonio</name>.</s>
        <s>He even thanks god when hearing about <name type="person">Antonio's</name> problem.</s>
        <s>Here again he says all the things twice, which agin underlines what he is saying.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Tubal</name> then goes on telling about <name type="person">Jessica</name> who had spent <quote>fourscore ducats in one night</quote>.</s>
        <s>Again <name type="person">Shylock</name> gets very angry, again showing how greedy he is and that the only thing he cares about is money.</s>
        <s>Another time you can see how mean <name type="person">Shylock</name> is, is in line 22.</s>
        <s>After finding out that <name type="person">Antonio</name> is ruined, <name type="person">Shylock</name> says <quote>I am very glad of it: I'll plague him, I'll torture him: I am glad of it</quote>.</s>
        <s>Again <name type="person">Shylock</name> is repeating himself which underlines how much he enjoys other people having problems and being able to hurt them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is clearly looking forward to hurting <name type="person">Antonio</name> which makes him appear as a very unpleasant man.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <name type="person">Shylock</name> is portrayed as a very mean guy.</s>
        <s>He seems to be a terrible father who doesn't care about the wellbeing of his daughter but only wants her back so that she doesn't stay with the Christian man.</s>
        <s>He cares more about material thins like money and jewels than his daughter and would not care about her death if that would bring back his goods.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is a very greedy man who cannot wait to hurt <name type="person">Antonio</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
