<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12l14_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> tries to appeal to the audience's humanity and their sense of community by using inclusive language and many contrasts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> begins and ends his speech by <choice><orig>refering</orig><reg>referring</reg></choice> to the one number everything comes down to <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(see ll. 3-4 and ll. 48-49)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This acts a frame to the speech on one hand, but on the other hand is also illustrates that, regardless of the long times that will be spent <quote>debating, negotiating, persuading and compromising</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>, the issue at hand is clear.</s>
        <s>He picks this up again in the end of his speech by asking the attendees directly from a future perspective, <quote>Did that number stop rising and start to drop, as a result of commitments made here?</quote>.</s>
        <s>By directly allocating the drop in global temperature to the <name type="misc">COP26</name>, he emphasizes the importance of this climate summit.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A very noticeable theme in <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David's</ref> speech is the <choice><orig>continuos</orig><reg>continuous</reg></choice> stress on humanity as a collective rather than as individuals.</s>
        <s>This can be observed multiple times throughout the entire speech, but is most notable in his usage of inclusive language.</s>
        <s>For example, when talking about the damage being done to the planet, he talks about <quote>our burning of fossil fuels, or destruction of nature, our approach to industry [...]</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 14-16)</ref> to underline that this is a case of shared responsibility.</s>
        <s>A bit later he says <quote><s>We now uderstand this problem.</s><s>We know now [...].</s><s>We must [...]</s></quote>, so he uses pronouns such as <quote>we</quote> or <quote>our</quote> very often.</s>
        <s>Another time <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> appeals to the audience's humanity rather than their individualistic tendencies, is when he refers to humanity's history and the drastic changes in weather that have prevented human's ancestors from building civilization for a very long time <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(see ll. 7-13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>One could argue that this is supposed to remind the audience of either the true importance of a stable global temperature and urge them to learn from what our common ancestor went through.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> works with contrasting facts or statements quite a bit.</s>
        <s>While talking about who has contributed the most to the climate crisis and who has been affected the most, he begins in sentences with the words <quote>Today</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> and <quote>ultimately</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref> to underline that the current situation is not permanent and thought it would be wrong to assume that we can continue our way of life in the west without much regard for the environment because we are not affected.</s>
        <s>Towards the end of <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David's</ref> speech, he says <quote>In my lifetime [...], in yours [...]</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 51-52)</ref>, which puts the current dire situation in contrast to a possibly, nicer future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The statements of the six different speakers vary in content and style based on the content of <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough's'</ref> speech.</s>
        <s>When speaking about the damage done by global warming, they are statements are much more individualistic, e.g. <quote>I am absolutely terrified to bring a child into this world</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>, but when he is speaking about possibilities and goals, the speakers are much more optimistic and underline the sense of community that <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David</ref> is emphasizing in their statements, e.g. <quote>This is a challenge that we should try to solve [...]</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 45-46)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Therefore the speakers are meant to underline <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough's</ref> statements from a more individual perspective that might be relatable and less abstract to the audience.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David</ref> coins the term <quote>new industrial revolution</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 32)</ref> to not only propose possible solutions but also to reference a historical process that is significant to the climate crisis as it has caused it.</s>
        <s>By reminding everyone that <quote>we will all share the benefits</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref> of a <quote>new industrial revolution</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 32)</ref>, he tries to motivate the attendees to make their economies more sustainable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Generally though, the tone of <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> is rather optimistic.</s>
        <s>This is also reflected in his wordings such as <quote>to turn this tragedy into a triumph</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 28)</ref>, which also includes an alliteration, or <quote>we are powerful enough to save it [the planet]</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 51)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also, his speech is easily understandable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end, he <choice><orig>adresses</orig><reg>addresses</reg></choice> the audience just as he has in the beginning when greeting them <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(see ll. 1 and ll. 52-54)</ref> to urge them once again to take action as well as instill a sense of responsibility in them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion one can say, that <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David</ref> chose to appeal to the audience's feelings and their sense of community, which was chosen appropriately considering his position as a people's advocate.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
