<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12l11_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Attenborough</ref> tries to appeal to the emotions of the politicians and give them a bad conscience with the use of <quote>we</quote> and <quote>our</quote> to create a feeling of cohesion and the use of <quote>must</quote> to underline the urgency of the results if this climate conference.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> begins his speech with <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> drastic image, the concentration of carbon in our atmosphere and its <choice><orig>concetion</orig><reg>connection</reg></choice> to global temperatures defines our relationship to the world <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 3-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This serves the purpose to remind the politicians of the urgency of this topic, which makes the conference so important and <choice><orig>lifechanging</orig><reg>life-changing</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He then talks about humanity's ancient history, with a number of carbon concentration in our atmosphere would bounce around and no predictable seasons and weather existed <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 7f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With the numbers being suddenly stabilized humans were able to <choice><orig>envolve</orig><reg>evolve</reg></choice>, <quote>Everything we've achieved in the last 10.000 years was enabled by stability...</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 12f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The global temperature has not wavered much until now <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 13-14)</ref>, the phrase <quote>until now</quote> expresses the urgency of this problem, because everything was fine for thousands of years <quote>until now</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>, it has a shocking and disillusional effect.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A feeling of cohesion is created by <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> because he talks about <quote>we</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 17)</ref> and <quote>our</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 14)</ref>, this is shown with the quote <quote>The stability weall depend on is breaking</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In addition he uses a lot of short and condensed sentences <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 17)</ref>, to make it easier for the audience to understand and follow him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, in this way the urgency of this conference is emphasized, because these sentences have a disillusional effect.</s>
        <s>This disillusional effect is stressed with the use of the first three different speakers <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 21-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>They say very negative, hopeless and shocking things like <quote><s>I'm absolutely terrified to bring a child to this world</s></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref> and <quote><s>You since you have control.</s><s>We actually have no control</s></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> or <quote><s>my world is melting</s></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Every speaker expresses a different fear or fact that our strongly influenced by climate change.</s>
        <s>The first speaker draws attention to the issue that the polar ice caps are melting and so is his word melting <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The second speaker appeals to the emotions of the politicians and gives the politicians about conscience because they think they have everything in control but in fact they do not <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 22)</ref>, the speaker alludes how everybody suffers from their decisions (of the politicians).</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> again underlines the urgency of this matter with the rhetorical question <quote>is this how our story is due to end?</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 24)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He draws attention to the fact that climate change will <choice><orig>effect</orig><reg>affect</reg></choice> young people who are alive today and no longer some imagined future generation <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 26-28)</ref>, he emphasizes this fact with the use of the alliteration <quote>to turn this tragedy into a triumph</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 28)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He illustrates the urgency of this matter with the use of <quote>must</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 30f.)</ref>, additionally this is underlined with the anaphora <quote>we</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 29ff.)</ref> in the beginning of every sentences.</s>
        <s>With the use of this repetition <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> tries to get this message into the minds of the politicians.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If people and politics change their behavior and the planet is at balance again <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 36)</ref> everybody will benefit from this change <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 34)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> explains the new nation a sustainable therefore no nation has completed its development <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 36-38)</ref>.</s>
        <s>According to him we will learn this together, with leaving no one behind <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 39f.)</ref>, for the creation of an equal world or motivation should be hope and not fear <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 40f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This team is emphasized with the last three speakers who share his hopeful attitude.</s>
        <s>In their opinion we have to fix the problems <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 44)</ref>, we have to do watch can <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (l. 45)</ref> and even though it will be a challenge <quote>we should try to solve it in a quick way, but with the <choice><orig>long term</orig><reg>long-term</reg></choice> vision</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 45ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> uses the different speakers to get this point across even better and to stress his point of view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He again appeals to the emotions of the politician and <choice><orig>give</orig><reg>gives</reg></choice> them a bad conscience to rethink the consequences of their actions.</s>
        <s>He questions the behavior of the politicians with saying that the future generation will look at this conference and will only consider if the numbers start rising because of the commitment being made at this conference <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">see (ll. 47-50)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> tries to motivate the politicians with saying that <quote>if working apart, we are force powerful enough to destabilize our planet, surely working together, we are powerful enough to sasve it</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 50f.)</ref>, his <choice><orig>hopefull</orig><reg>hopeful</reg></choice> attitude is symbolized with the word <quote>surely</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 50)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Naming a personal aspect, <quote><s>In my lifetime, I've witnessed a terrible decline.</s><s>And yours, you could and should witness a wonderful recovery</s></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 51-52)</ref>, he again appeals to the emotional side of the politicians.</s>
        <s>Furthermore with saying that they <quote>should witness a wonderful recovery</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 52)</ref>, he makes the politicians aware of their duty and kind of forces them into acting and rethinking their behavior.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough's</ref> last sentence again stress is the urgency and importance of the conference, the part <quote>desperate hope</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 52)</ref> and the part <quote>is why the world is looking to you and why you are here</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 53f.)</ref> show this.</s>
        <s>Moreover the part <quote>why the world is looking to you</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 53)</ref> <choice><orig>express</orig><reg>expresses</reg></choice> how was the result of the conference will affect the whole world and also how climate change is affecting the whole world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Attenborough</ref> appeals to the emotions of the politicians to underline the urgency of this matter, in addition he uses six different speakers to bring his opinion across more easily and he uses <quote>we</quote> end <quote>our</quote> to create a feeling of cohesion.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
