<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b12l13_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Two weeks after the end of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> we can now judge if the <name type="misc">COP26</name> was a failure or success.</s>
        <s>We can also discuss about who had a positive impact on the outcome, who negative impacts on the outcome of <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Clearly, <name type="person">Boris Johnson's</name> speech was on these moments at <name type="misc">COP26</name> where you could have asked yourself if everyone understood the dramatic issue around climate change.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Aspecially</orig><reg>Especially</reg></choice> against the background that <name type="person">Johnson</name> was or still is someone who says that <quote>climate change is not proofen</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His speech may have touch upon important aspects, for example that it is now our generation to face climate change.</s>
        <s>However his <choice><orig>unadequate</orig><reg>inadequate</reg></choice> jokes didn make it all look silly.</s>
        <s>Especially because no one laughed.</s>
        <s>His reference to <name type="person">James Bond</name> holding a bomb was, at least for me, not understandable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, his speech seem to be thrown together last minute before presenting.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Quite the contrary was the case with a speech of <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Attenborough</ref>, <name type="geo">UK's</name> most famous natural historian.</s>
        <s>His speech seemed to be planned very well.</s>
        <s>On his screen he showed stunning, cinematic pictures and quoted people expressing their deep fear regarding the climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He did this to really bring his message of the need of <name type="misc">COP26</name> to be a success across.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Attenborough</ref> has been seeing a lot of the world.</s>
        <s>I could imagine that he with his 95 years of life experience could make a striking impression of the political leaders.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I could also imagine that this speech made an impression of the broader public, maybe some of them saw his spectacular films about <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">nan</gap> and now also enjoyed his speech about climate crisis.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However, I personally think, that we cannot say that one particular speech has influenced the outcome of <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
        <s>This would be too easy.</s>
        <s>196 governments <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> be influenced by one speech.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And we should also keep in mind that this conference was not <choice><orig>necessarly</orig><reg>necessarily</reg></choice> a success, although <name type="person">Barack Obama</name>, former President of the <name type="geo">United States</name> might have called it one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It would have been nice if for example the speeches of indigenous people had an impact of <name type="misc">COP26</name> as they are the ones <quote>hit hardest</quote> by climate change, as <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> explained it.</s>
        <s>But this was not the case.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
