<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12l15_t4</author>
        <name>news</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">news</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Small but important steps - Germany remains optimistic after <name type="misc">COP26</name></s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>After the <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name>, opinions have been divided.</s>
        <s>While some may argue that the aims that have been expressed an agreed on, Will not be sufficient to meet the 1.5°-mark, up until then the effects of global warming are still reversible, others are more optimistic.</s>
        <s>Surely, there have been setbacks, most prominently changing the goal from putting a stop to fossil fuel production, to merely ending production step-by-step.</s>
        <s>However, in the grand scheme of things the acceptance of this alone is a success in itself – especially if even states such as <name type="geo">India</name> and <name type="geo">China</name> who still heavily rely on fossil fuel energy agree.</s>
        <s>No, contrary to the conferences about the <name type="geo">Paris</name> agreement in <date>2016</date>, there is a common agreement that fossil fuels are meant to be left in the past, and <name type="misc">COP26</name> proves just that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some States who have experience the effects of climate change stronger than others have urged everyone at <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> to take action against global warming, hopefully <name type="misc">COP26</name> was able to send a sign of hope to them.</s>
        <s>Considering we are currently looking at 2.7° instead of 5-6° like we were in <date>2016</date>, <name type="geo">Germany's</name> optimism is reasonable.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_2" type="speaker">Jochen Flasbarth</ref>, <name type="geo">Germany's</name> negotiator at <name type="misc">COP26</name>, reminds us in an interview with <name type="misc">ARD-Morgenmagazin</name>, that conferences alone will not be able to solve the climate crisis but the legal basis that was created during the conference, surely will help for future negotiations and actions.</s>
        <s>He concludes that <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> might not have been a huge step forward, but it was an important and necessary one.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
