<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12l13_t4</author>
        <name>news</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="review">news</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Mixed feelings about the outcome of <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Germany</name></s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Success or failure?</s>
        <s>This is the question citizen of the whole world ask themselves.</s>
        <s>In <name type="geo">Germany</name> there is no clear answer to this question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_2" type="speaker">Jochen Flasbarth</ref> one of those who considers the <name type="misc">COP26</name> as a success.</s>
        <s>He was <name type="geo">Germany's</name> chief negotiator at <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
        <s>He thinks that we are on the right path and that <name type="misc">COP26</name> helped us to bring us forward.</s>
        <s>Clear failures like the last minute change of word Bring the abolishing of coal from <quote>phase out</quote> to <quote>phase down</quote> apparently good because it shows that <quote>the era of coal comes to an end</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also claims that it depends on the perspective.</s>
        <s>No one drove to <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> calculating that there is a legislation about coal, according to him.</s>
        <s>Oh really?</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Than</orig><reg>Then</reg></choice> I may have been the only one.</s>
        <s>Considering that we should better have stopped using coal in the past and not in the future.</s>
        <s>He also states that we have to be faster in order to counteract the climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>My question: why haven't you been faster at <name type="misc">COP26</name> and use this opportunity to create a more equal world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For me, the whole <name type="misc">COP26</name> again feels like empty promises.</s>
        <s>And I'm asking myself – why is every politician claiming the <name type="misc">COP26</name> be a success?</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
