<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12l09_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech at the opening ceremonies of <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name>, as a <quote>people's advocate</quote>, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Frederick Attenborough</ref> tries to convince and urge his audience to act on climate change, by illustrating now it affects humankind nowadays.</s>
        <s>Therefore he uses stylistic devices and communicative strategies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his introduction he starts off by defining what <choice><orig>need</orig><reg>needs</reg></choice> to be achieved at the end of <name type="misc">COP26</name>, which is to come to a conclusion by what percentage the carbon concentration on earth has to be lowered, and how to achieve that.</s>
        <s>Furthermore explains how a stable climate enabled the civilization and evolution of the Homo sapiens in the past ten centuries.</s>
        <s>And how the current climate crisis in dangers are <quote>stabilised</quote> modern world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his next paragraph he touches upon the topic of younger people living today, having to witness nature decaying under the <choice><orig>humans</orig><reg>humans'</reg></choice> hand, without being at fault for the start of climate change.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> acknowledges and declares that the older generation is responsible for this outcome, should be the ones to act now.</s>
        <s>By pursuing unity and working as a <quote>team</quote> he states that he can imagine to achieve certain goals towards slowing down, and ending climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his conclusion he mentions the aspect of young <choice><orig>peoples</orig><reg>people's</reg></choice> expectations and reassuring his audience the change is possible.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
