<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12l07_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> starts his speech by simplifying the problem by referring to it as a <quote>single number</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> with that people come back to the realization what they are actually aiming for.</s>
        <s>To emphasize on how humankind is affected by the earth, he calls it <quote>our relationship with our the world</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 6-7)</ref>, which makes it more personal.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author alludes to the historic background of undefined ancient times, where the temperature was stabilized and expresses that part quite positive <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(e.g. 7-13)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In contrast to the following part where he enumerates how the planet is being destroyed and adds each to cause the personal pronoun <quote>our</quote> so that people feel addressed <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(e.g. l. 15, 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In addition to that, the contrast highlights the drastic change of times.</s>
        <s>One thing that is striking is that he uses sarcasm when he says <quote>wasted no time in taking advantage</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> because the politicians waste a lot of time when it is actually needed to act.</s>
        <s>To express an urgency of this crisis, he uses an antithesis when he says <quote>until now</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> and correct himself by saying <quote>already in trouble</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His strategy for communication are the statements from different speakers that bring his argumentation on a personal level.</s>
        <s>People are able to identify with those statements that address fear, and the feeling of being desperate <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(e.g. l. 21-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The statements are all negative in contrast to the following statements from different speakers that are motivated and optimistic <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(e.g. l. 42-46)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is supposed to show the development of changing the mindset and way of thinking towards the issue.</s>
        <s>It is also supposed to reflect how the <choice><orig>audience</orig><reg>audience's</reg></choice> opinion should change.</s>
        <s>To make it more personal, he mentions future generations and also underlines the fact that young people alive will have be affected by the crisis <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(e.g. l. 27)</ref> and illustrates the development by saying <quote>turn[ing] this tragedy into a triumph</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 28)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> tries to convince the assembled by pushing their ego and stating that <quote>we [...] the greatest problem solvers</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He underlines the <choice><orig>urgence</orig><reg>urgance</reg></choice> of acting with an anaphora <quote>We are</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 28)</ref>, <quote>We now..., we know, we must</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 29-34)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Can also be seen as a climax when he says <quote>we know, we must, we will</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 29-34)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Instead of blaming one country for not progressing enough or praising a nation for the progress, he states that the countries are on <quote>a journey</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref> together and depend on each other in regards of the global warming.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To illustrate the pressure everyone is supposed to feel, he uses personification of the earth looking to everybody <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(e.g. l. 53)</ref>.</s>
        <s>To evoke pressure again, he uses the antithesis <quote>in my lifetime..., in yours...</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 51, 52)</ref> and distances himself from them.</s>
        <s>At the end he frames his speech by changing the order of the people he addressed at the beginning of his speech.</s>
        <s>In conclusion, one conceive that <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">David Attenborough</ref> tries to strategically persuade the audience by presenting contrast and relying on inclusive language.</s>
        <s>And lastly argument thing on a personal level.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
