<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12l11_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The question of the speech might have an impact on the audience attending it at <name type="misc">COP26</name> and on the broader public, is in my opinion easy to answer - no.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Due to its emotional character=, for example the six speakers is expressing their opinions, or the naming of the fate of future <choice><orig>gernation</orig><reg>generations</reg></choice>, it is very convincing.</s>
        <s>But the real question is whether it will have an effect in climate politics.</s>
        <s>According to <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> we all have to learn to be more sustainable to be classified as a developed nation, we should do this all together with ensuring that no one is left behind.</s>
        <s>Which basically means that the global <choice><orig>noth</orig><reg>North</reg></choice> should help the global <choice><orig>south</orig><reg>South</reg></choice> to become more climate friendly and sustainable.</s>
        <s>In this point the speech indeed had an impact on the audience attending it at <name type="misc">COP26</name> because one of the decisions made was the fact, that the global north should support the global south financially, so they can be able to change and become more eco-friendly for example change from the use of coal for <choice><orig>engery</orig><reg>energy</reg></choice> to renewable <choice><orig>engeries</orig><reg>energies</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This depicts how to speech at least had a small impact to its listeners.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another Factor why I believe this speech is impactful is that it is reliable, because <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> says that <quote>those who've done the least to cause this problem, or being the hardest hit</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 18f.)</ref> which means that the global South did not play a big part in globalization and did not produce so many emissions in comparison to the global North, but they are still being hit the hardest in climate change.</s>
        <s>This is also true because during <name type="misc">COP26</name> it came out that <name type="geo">China</name> is responsible for 31% of the global emissions in the <name type="geo">US</name> for 15%, which depicts the huge impact of the global North.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand many people were dissatisfied with the results of <name type="misc">COP26</name>, one of them would be the famous climate activist <name type="person">Greta Thunberg</name> who described the outcome of the conference with the words <quote>blah, blah, blah</quote>.</s>
        <s>It is also important to add that the 1.5 degrees goal, which is a by scientist suggested limit, means that the man-made global warming should not get over 1.5 degrees otherwise there will be horrible consequences like natural catastrophe like floods, melting polar ice caps and heatwaves, was not reached.</s>
        <s>Not even closely, the conference came to the conclusion that 2.7 degrees as the limit is close enough.</s>
        <s>In addition the goal to stop using coal now was not reached, the phrasing on the coal exit was weakened last minute in favor for <name type="geo">China</name> and <name type="geo">India</name>.</s>
        <s>Therefore one important goal was not reached even though it is such an important aspect to stop climate change and minimize global warming.</s>
        <s>Which means that the speech did not have that big on an impact on the audience like may it seems in the beginning.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore I do not believe that the speech has an impact on the broader public, even though it was very appealing to the emotions.</s>
        <s>Surveys found out that almost everybody thinks that they are already doing enough for the climate.</s>
        <s>They also think that they are doing more <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> everybody else, especially their own government.</s>
        <s>Most people say they would agree stricter laws to preserve our earth and stop climate change but at the same time it is normal for them to fly to a far destination for summer vacation every year or to buy more clothes than they can possibly ever wear.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These factors combined lead me to the conclusion that no matter how emotional appealing and reliable this speech is, it is not impactful enough.</s>
        <s>He did not have a big influence on the politicians of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> because the very important 1.5 degrees goal is very far from being reached.</s>
        <s>Moreover the broader public is not ready to start changing more things because it is uncomfortable for them and need some <choice><orig>affort</orig><reg>effort</reg></choice>, which most people are not ready to invest.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
