<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g10_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The author tries to convince the readers of her opinion by structuring the text well.</s>
        <s>At first she states facts, which are always very convincing <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second paragraph <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Rahman</ref> talks about the bad situation in <name type="misc">Brick Lane</name>.</s>
        <s>In <name type="misc">Brick Lane</name> <quote>drug abuse and crime are on the rise</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> and by showing these bad conditions <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> tries to convince others to learn English so they don't have to live like this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next paragraph <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> explains how she learned speaking English.</s>
        <s>She shows that it is important to learn the language and gives others hope because she could do it so others can too.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end the author talks about the consequences and what one can do to help.</s>
        <s>She thinks <quote>there is much to be gained in getting us all to speak English</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref> and as her last sentence this is very convincing because she promises that people will have less problems to integrate.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author often mentions her parents <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 11-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By using this <choice><orig>repitition</orig><reg>repetition</reg></choice> she tries to underline that parents and generally the family plays a great part in learning a language.</s>
        <s>Moreover one mostly listens to their parents so when she repeats them one sees that her parents wanted <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> to learn English so it has to be something one wants to achieve and what is good for kids.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With a metaphor <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 18-19)</ref> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Rahman</ref> shows that it is important to do something on your own and that one cannot always depend on others.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>If someone is holding you up</quote><ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> all the time <quote>you don't learn to stand on your own feet</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By this she means that if one always uses translations and is constantly <quote>[been] holding up</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>, one does not learn something and <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> <quote>learn to stand on [their] own feet</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This underlines her position and that translating everything and not learning the language does not help.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition she uses personal pronouns like <quote>we</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3, 18)</ref> and <quote>us</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By using these personal pronouns <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> shows that we together can change something and that this only works when we stick together.</s>
        <s>The author mostly uses them in <choice><orig>apeals</orig><reg>appeals</reg></choice>, which is convincing and makes others want to help <choice><orig>beause</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Rahman</ref> directly speaks to them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover the author uses a lot of negative words.</s>
        <s>She uses <quote>drug abuse and crime</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The Bangladeshi community <quote>sits at the bottom of educational achievement</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> which shows that they live in bad conditions.</s>
        <s>The author wants the readers to pity them and have empathy.</s>
        <s>And when one has empathy one is more likely to help because they can put themselves in the position of others.</s>
        <s>As they don't have choice and have to chose between <quote>extremists</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> and <quote>the gangs on the streets</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>They don't have a hopeful future.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
