<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g09_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text is written in four parts with different topics.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first part from ll. 1-4 is about much money <add>(£100<choice><abbr>m</abbr><expan>million</expan></choice>)</add> that was spent on translating and interpreting for British residents that don't speak English.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second part from ll. 5-10 is about the <name type="misc">East End</name> of <name type="geo">London</name>, where Bangladeshi people live like in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> and even the street signs are in Bengali.</s>
        <s>Also the social level doesn't really <choice><orig>exists</orig><reg>exist</reg></choice> because the people who are living there aren't immigrated very well so they can choose between being an extremist in the mosque or <choice><orig>commiting</orig><reg>committing</reg></choice> crime in a street gang.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third part from ll. 11-17 is about the author's experiences being an immigrant and his opinion about immigration in schools.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fourth part is about the integration process in public and how you should do it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second part <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 7-10)</ref> it's said that every year Bangladeshis sit on the bottom of educational <choice><orig>evironment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> [...].</s>
        <s>This example shows how bad they get immigrated because most of the males living in the <name type="misc">East End</name> of <name type="geo">London</name> have to decide if <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> get into a gang or being an extremist in the mosque because they have no other perspectives.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third part <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 11-14)</ref> it's said that the author's parents wanted him to learn English and focus on school because they don't wanted him to end in a street gang or something.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And in the fourth part <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 18-19)</ref> it's said that you don't learn to stand on your own feet, if someone is holding you up.</s>
        <s>This shows that it's important to let someone do his own mistakes and let someone learn things by himself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The examples should underline that the immigration process got two sides that both have to work together because if they don't work together you can't get immigrated.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
