<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g14_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Since we had the topic of learning languages and its meaning for a globalized world in class, I will discuss the sentence <quote>The limits of my language are the limits of my world</quote> from <name type="person">Ludwig Wittgenstein</name> in the following text.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course it is true that you can communicate with other people in a foreign country even if you do not speak their language, but it would be much more easier if you would speak their language and you would understand each other much better as if you do not.</s>
        <s>Apart from that when you speak another language and than speak to a native speaker in his <choice><orig>mothertongue</orig><reg>mother tongue</reg></choice> it is a sign of compassion and commitment to their country and culture.</s>
        <s>Furthermore a multilingual world would bring us the sense of unity we all need to live <choice><orig>peacly</orig><reg>peacely</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>On top of that learning a language makes the process of learning another language easier and it strengthens the cognitive muscles of your brain.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I would say that it is better to learn more languages as to try to communicate with each other without speaking the other's language and hardly understand each other.</s>
        <s>So in the main I agree with the statement from <name type="person">Ludwig Wittgenstein</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
