<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g09_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref> which was published in the <name type="misc">Sunday Times</name> magazine on <date>December 17th, 2016</date> and written by <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> is about immigration from <name type="geo"><choice><orig>Bangladeshi</orig><reg>Bangladesh</reg></choice></name> to the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Rahman</ref> shows the problems and his experiences being an immigrant from <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <name type="geo">London</name> you got a <quote>Bangladeshi district</quote> where English is a foreign language and even the street signs are in Bengali.</s>
        <s>Also most of the people that are living there are at the bottom of educational environment.</s>
        <s>So drug abuse and crime is on the rise in this district.</s>
        <s>If you are a young Bangladeshi male, with no hope of employment, you can choose between extremists in the mosque or gang crime in the streets.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The problem is that the Bangladeshi people don't get immigrated they have to learn everything by themselves.</s>
        <s>And that's why most of the immigrants can't speak <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> very well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another big problem is racism because some people don't accept refugees because they think that they are something different.</s>
        <s>So refugees are confronted with <choice><orig>racicsm</orig><reg>racism</reg></choice> every single day.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author's experiences with getting immigrated shows that if you really want to integrate yourself, it could be done.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His parents wanted him to learn English, because they don't wanted to be absorbed by the <quote>Bangladeshi district</quote> which was like the country they left.</s>
        <s>Also the parents wanted him to do a good job in school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It's important to see that in the mid <date>1970s</date>, the teachers didn't make an acknowledgement of the author's racial difference.</s>
        <s>Because today it's celebrated by schools although the author isn't convinced that celebrating differences can help getting someone integrated.</s>
        <s>Because everyone is the same and if you treat someone like he's something different because of a cultural difference, it <choice><orig>don't</orig><reg>doesn't</reg></choice> <choice><orig>helps</orig><reg>help</reg></choice> getting this person immigrated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also, you don't have to celebrate the diversity of only a couple of people, you have to celebrate the diversity of everyone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another big problem is social media.</s>
        <s>Because <choice><orig>publig</orig><reg>public</reg></choice> figures are fearful being labelled as a racist if they don't speak up for organisations against racism.</s>
        <s>So they are under very big pressure to keep their image good.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The text shows us major problem because bad integration and racism isn't something that only exists in the <name type="geo">UK</name>, it exists in every country and it's very important to do something against this problem.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
