<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>ST1</title>
        <author>Thomas, Angie</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Novel</pubPlace>
        <address>NA</address>
        <date>20190207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>EF</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>aefgk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>Chapter 24</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>We get to the intersection. A red, green, and yellow school bus is parked on the street to our right. It says Just Us for Justice on the side. A large crowd is gathered in the street to our left. They point black hairbrushes into the air.</p>
      <p>The protestors are on Carnation. Where it happened.</p>
      <p>I haven't been back here since that night. Knowing this is where Khalil... I stare too hard, the crowd disappears, and I see him lying in the street. The whole thing plays out before my eyes like a horror movie on repeat. He looks at me for the last time and-</p>
      <p>
        <said>A hairbrush is not a gun!</said>
      </p>
      <p>The voice snaps me from my daze.</p>
      <p>Ahead of the crowd a lady with twists stands on top of a police car, holding a bullhorn. She turns toward us, her fist raised for black power. Khalil smiles on the front of her T-shirt.</p>
      <p><said>Ain't that your attorney, Starr?</said> Seven asks.</p>
      <p><said>Yeah.</said> Now I knew Ms. Ofrah was about that radical life, but when you think <q>attorney</q> you don't really think <q>person standing on a police car with a bullhorn,</q> you know?</p>
      <p><said>Disperse immediately,</said> the officer repeats. I can't see him for the crowd.</p>
      <p>Ms. Ofrah leads the chant again. <said>A hairbrush is not a gun! A hairbrush is not a gun!</said></p>
      <p>It's contagious and echoes all around us. Seven, DeVante, and Chris join in.</p>
      <p><said>A hairbrush is not a gun,</said> I mutter.</p>
      <p>
        <emph rend="italics">Khalil drops it into the side of the door.</emph>
      </p>
      <p>
        <said>A hairbrush is not a gun.</said>
      </p>
      <p>
        <emph rend="italics">He opens the door to ask if I'm okay.</emph>
      </p>
      <p>
        <emph rend="italics">Then pow-pow-</emph>
      </p>
      <p><said>A hairbrush is not a gun!</said> I scream loud as I can, fist high in the air, tears in my eyes.</p>
      <p>Ms. Ofrah heads toward another coworker who's standing near the bus at the intersection: She spots me and does a double-take.</p>
      <p><said>Starr?</said> she says, making her way over. <said>What are you doing out here?</said></p>
      <p>
        <said>We ... I ... When they announced the decision, I wanted to do something. So we came to the neighborhood.</said>
      </p>
      <p>
        <said>Starr-</said>
      </p>
      <p>
        <said>Please? During the other protests, I watched. And talked. So now I wanna do something.</said>
      </p>
      <p><said>Who said talking isn't doing something?</said> she says. <said>It's more productive than silence. Remember what I told you about your voice?</said></p>
      <p>
        <said>You said it's my biggest weapon.</said>
      </p>
      <p><said>And I mean that.</said> She stares at me a second, then sighs out her nose. <said>You want to fight the system tonight?</said></p>
      <p>I nod.</p>
      <p>
        <said>C'mon then.</said>
      </p>
      <p>She takes me to the patrol car and motions at her colleague. The lady climbs off and hands Ms. Ofrah the bullhorn. Ms. Ofrah passes it over to me.</p>
      <p><said>Use your weapon,</said> she says.</p>
      <p>Another one of her coworkers lifts me and sets me on top of the cop car.</p>
      <p>I turn toward the crowd. They watch me expectantly.</p>
      <p>The bullhorn is as heavy as a gun. Ironic since Ms. Ofrah said to use my weapon. I have the hardest time lifting it. Shit, I have no idea what to say. I put it near my mouth and press the button.</p>
      <p><said>My-</said> It makes a loud, earsplitting noise.</p>
      <p><said>Don't be scared!</said> somebody in the crowd yells. <said>Speak!</said></p>
      <p><said>You need to exit the street immediately,</said> the cop says.</p>
      <p>You know what? Fuck it.</p>
      <p><said>My name is Starr. I'm the one who saw what happened to Khalil,</said> I say into the bullhorn. <said>And it wasn't right.</said></p>
      <p>I get a bunch of <q>yeahs</q> and <q>amens</q> from the crowd.</p>
      <p>
        <said>We weren't doing anything wrong. Not only did Officer Cruise assume we were up to no good, he assumed we were criminals. Well, Officer Cruise is the criminal.</said>
      </p>
      <p>The crowd cheers and claps. Ms. Ofrah says, <said>Speak!</said> That amps me up.</p>
      <p>I turn to the cops. <said>I'm sick of this! Just like y'all think all of us are bad because of some people, we think the same about y'all. Until you give us a reason to think otherwise, we'll keep protesting.</said></p>
      <p>More cheers, and I can't lie, it eggs me on. Forget trigger happy - speaker happy is more my thing.</p>
      <p><said>Everybody wants to talk about how Khalil died,</said> I say. <said>But this isn't about how Khalil died. It's about the fact that he lived. His life mattered. Khalil lived!</said> I look at the cops again. <said>You hear me? Khalil lived!</said></p>
    </body>
    <note>
      <p>do a double-take, amp sb up, trigger happy</p>
    </note>
  </text>
</TEI>
