<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>ST1</title>
        <author>Boyle, T.C.</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <pubPlace>Novel</pubPlace>
        <address>NA</address>
        <date>20180815</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>This is the end of Part Two, Chapter 6 (pp. 275-278)</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>"No, no, that's not the problem," Delaney said, and why shouldn't he defy Kyra and Jack and stand up for what he believed in? But then he saw that phantom car again, the one with the rumbling speakers and impenetrable windows, and he hesitated. "Look," he said, "I'll call you," and turned to walk away.</p>
      <p>"Seven-one-three, two-two-eight-zero," Todd Sweet called at his back, but he wasn't listening, his mind gone numb with ambivalence. He went on up the block, barely registering the world spread out before him, glum, dogless, on his own. Nothing was moving.The sun was everything. And then he turned into his own street, Pinon Drive, and saw that life existed after all: another figure was drifting across that static landscape in the blast of late-summer heat. He couldn't be sure, but it seemed to be the bipedal figure of a man, slipping through the heat haze like an illusion, legs scissoring the light. The man had a white cloth shoulder bag slung over one arm, Delaney saw as he came closer, and he was crossing the Cherrystones' lawn with the lingering insouciant stride of the trespasser-which is what he must have been, since Delaney knew for a fact that the Cherrystones had gone to Santa Monica and wouldn't be back till seven. And then Delaney came closer still, and noticed something else, something that struck him with the force of a blow: the man was Mexican. "Hey," Delaney called out, quickening his stride now, "can I help you?"</p>
      <p>The man looked startled, looked guilty-caught in the act-and he just stood there on the lawn and let Delaney come up to him. And now the second surprise: Delaney knew him, he was sure he did. It took him a minute, something missing from the composite, but then, even without the baseball cap, Delaney recognized him: this was the hiker, the illegal camper, the man who'd soured the first half of one of the worst days of Delaney's life. And even then, even in that moment of recognition, the net widened suddenly: didn't Kyra say that the man who'd threatened her at the Da Ros place was wearing a Padres cap turned backwards? The man just stood there, guarding his satchel. He didn't look away from Delaney's gaze, and he didn't respond.</p>
      <p>"I said, can I help you?"</p>
      <p>"Help me?" he echoed, and his face broke into a grin. He winked an eye. "Sure," he said, "sure, hombre, you can help me." And then: "What's happening, man?"</p>
      <p>Delaney was hot. He was uncomfortable. He was aggravated. The man stood a good
		three or four inches taller than he did and he was letting Delaney know just how unimpressed he was-he was mocking him, bearding Delaney right there in his own community, right there on his own street. Camping in the state park was one thing, but this was something else altogether. And what was in the satchel and why had he been crossing the Cherrystone's lawn when the Cherrystones weren't at home?</p>
      <p>"I want to know what you think you're doing here," Delaney demanded, eyeing the satchel and imagining the Cherrystones' silverware in there, their VCR, Selda's jewelry. "This is private property. You don't belong here."</p>
      <p>The man looked right through him. He was bored. Delaney was nothing, a minor annoyance, a gnat buzzing round his face.</p>
      <p>"I'm talking to you," Delaney said, and before he could think, he had hold of the man's forearm, just above the wrist.</p>
      <p>The tan eyes looked down at Delaney's hand, then up into his face. There was nothing in those eyes but contempt. With a sudden violent jerk, the man whipped his arm free, gathered himself up and spat scornfully between Delaney's feet. "I got these flies," he said, and he was almost shouting it.</p>
      <p>Delaney was riding the crest of the moment, trembling, angry, ready for anything. The man was a thief, a liar, the stinking occupant of a stinking sleeping bag in the state forest, a trespasser, a polluter, a Mexican. "Don't give me that shit!" Delaney roared. "I'm calling the police. I know what you're doing up here, I know who you are, you're not fooling anybody." Delaney looked round him for support, for a car, a child on a bike, Todd Sweet, anyone, but the street was deserted.</p>
      <p>The Mexican's expression had changed. The mocking grin was gone now, replaced by something harder, infinitely harder. He's got a knife, Delaney thought, a gun, and he went cold all over when the man reached into the satchel, so keyed up he was ready to spring at him, tackle him, fight to the death... but then he was staring into a flat white sheet of Xerox paper crawling with print. "Flies," the man spat at him. "I deliver these flies".</p>
      <p>Delaney took a step back, so devastated he couldn't speak- what was happening to him, what was he becoming? - and the man shoved the flier into his hand and stalked away across the lawn. He watched, stupefied, as the Mexican headed up the street, carrying his shoulders with rage and indignation, watched as he strode up to Delaney's own house and inserted a flier in the slit between the screen door and the white wooden doorframe. Then, finally, Delaney looked down at the sheet of paper in his hand. <emph rend="caps">A special message from the president of the arroyo blanco estates property owners' association</emph>, it read in block letters across the top. And then, beneath it: "I urge all of you to attend Wednesday's meeting on an issue vital to the security and well-being of us all..."</p>
    </body>
    <note>
      <p/>
    </note>
  </text>
</TEI>
