<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11g22_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt to be analyzed can be consideres the turning point of the play undelining the consequences of suppressing his identity to assimilate into a new society completely.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Many events and conflicts are the reason for <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to <choice><orig>explose</orig><reg>explode</reg></choice> completely leading to the loss of his mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One important event clearly is <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Jorys</orig><reg>Jory's</reg></choice></ref> promotion at their work <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 71, ll. 23)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His disrespectful way to talk expresses <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> anger about it asking <quote>Who are you?</quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 71, l. 25)</ref>.</s>
        <s>While <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is shocked about seeing <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> kissing each other, he still rages about their boss promoting <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> in his place <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 72, l. 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The author underlines <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> anger using the expression <quote>vicious</quote> in the stage direction <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> only focusses on the current happening <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <quote>[exploses]</quote> <choice><orig>canalyzing</orig><reg>canalizing</reg></choice> his anger <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He talks about the mistreatment at the <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> law office where he works.</s>
        <s>They gave him <quote>the closet at the end of the hall [where] [the office] [keeps] the cleaning supplies</quote> whereas <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> got one with a great view <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, ll. 22)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> mentions the mistreatment asking <quote>You think you're the nigger here?</quote> answering with <quote><s>I'm the nigger!</s><s>Me!</s></quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 29)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="author">Akhtar</ref> points out the systemic discrimination against Muslims in <name type="geo">America</name> after <name type="misc">9/11</name>.</s>
        <s>He expresses how the time changed.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref>, who is <choice><orig>afro-american</orig><reg>Afro-American</reg></choice>, is treaten better than <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, a South Asian looking man.</s>
        <s>It also shows the problems between religions in this case Islam and Jewry.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> experiences at work <choice><orig>definetely</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> are an event for his outburst.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As the scene's tension raises higher the conflict between the four protagonists comes to a highlight.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> are facing off he spits in <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face which is a sign of antisemitism <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 72, ll. 39)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is the first moment <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> loses his control.</s>
        <s>He was brought up with antisemitism by his mother who spat in his face as he told her he likes a <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> girl as a child.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> spitting in <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face shows that even if you try to get rid of something you was brought up with like <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> it still consists in you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref>, who is <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice>, discriminates <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> in the following: <quote>There is a reason why they call you people animals</quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>A different conflict is <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> hurting and provocating <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> as her and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> leave.</s>
        <s>She mentions that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Mort</ref>, their boss, will retire promoting <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> for this job <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 73, ll. 4)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She goes on that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Mort</ref> chose her because he thinks <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is <quote>duplicitous and it's impossible to trust [him]</quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The following pause increases the power of <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Jorys</orig><reg>Jory's</reg></choice></ref> words expressing <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is hardly affected by it.</s>
        <s>He probably thought he could trust <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Mort</ref> because he was a good friend ending in not answering <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Amirs</orig><reg>Amir's</reg></choice></ref> calls.</s>
        <s>Right as the reader thinks the tension lowers <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> anger is building up again <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 73, ll. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The protagonist is in a really hard situation <choice><orig>emotionly</orig><reg>emotionally</reg></choice> as he realizes his wife may <choice><orig>cheats</orig><reg>cheat</reg></choice> on him.</s>
        <s>He asks her in a <quote>vulnerable, intense</quote> tone if she sleeps with <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 73 ll. 26)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The meaning and power of this question and its following answer is underlined by a pause <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 73 l. 28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> stops refusing her affair he completely loses his mind hitting her three times in the face <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 74)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The events and conflicts already mentioned were leading up to <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> outbursts and his loss of control.</s>
        <s>The <quote>torrent of rage, overtaking him</quote> followed by <quote>uncontrolled violence as brutal as it needs to be in order to convey the discharge of a lifetime of discreetly building resentment</quote> is the consequence of those events <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 74 ll. 6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But it are not just the events leading to this turning point of the play.</s>
        <s>His whole life <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tried to cover up his origin and his former religion to assimilate completely into the <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>american</reg></choice> society.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As a result he lost his identity and had to suppress it his whole life.</s>
        <s>All the things he suppressed as well as everything he had to deal with <add>(prejudices)</add> justified his outbreak.</s>
        <s>Supported by drinking alcoholic drinks.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> comes back to his senses he says <quote>oh my God</quote>, referring ot a higher power to find help for his behaviour <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. p. 74, l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The negative influence he described the Islam with are representing his behaviour in this excerpt.</s>
        <s>This could be an indication that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> uses the impact of religion as an excuse for his own cruelty.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To come to a conclusion one can say that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> shows his real personality in the given excerpt <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> the control over his personality he suppressed before.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
