<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g01_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given article <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="title">Language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name> can't, won't, don't</ref>, which was written by <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>, outlines the issue about foreign language learning in the<name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author claims first of all, that the three words in the headline are describing the motivation of the entore world, to learn a new language.</s>
        <s>Moreover, <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> says that for the last seven years the number of students in <name type="geo">Great Britain</name>, which are willed to lean another language, is going constantly down.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the author sees the opportunity to learn a language in primary school, but the last outcome of exams at <name type="misc">GCSE</name> and <name type="misc">A-Level</name> presents that the use of language stopped.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides the <name type="misc">GCSE</name> has not taken as many language exams, as the years before.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Going on the author explains that the entire world speaks English and that <choice><orig>their</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> are translator in case you don't know or understand a language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But he also means that language is elementary for the <name type="geo">Great Britain</name> for all aspects of economy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>moreover the most companies in <name type="geo">Great Britain</name> want to see more language skills, <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>, what is the reason for them to search for employers abroad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The authors praises the opportunity from university to study a language next to the main subject.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He states has opinion at the end of the article and presents parents the way to help their kids learn foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
