<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12l04_t1</author>
        <name>present</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> written by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> consists of three <choice><orig>quartrains</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> and one final couplet.</s>
        <s>The rhyme scheme is <name type="misc">ABAB CDCD EFEF GG</name>.</s>
        <s>The rhyme scheme shows that the rhyme of the sonnet is a cross rhyme.</s>
        <s>The metre of the sonnet is the iambic pentameter.</s>
        <s>Therefore there are 10 syllables each verse.</s>
        <s>The first syllable is unstressed and the second syllable stressed.</s>
        <s>That is how it goes on in every verse of the sonnet.</s>
        <s>The <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> deals with the overall theme of love.</s>
        <s>In particular the deals with hard times of love and the passing of time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is said that nothing can destroy the power of love except mortality which means that every day in <choice><orig>lif</orig><reg>life</reg></choice> counts.</s>
        <s>There is so much anger in the world people are concentrating on that they often do not see the good things around them.</s>
        <s>Often the good thing cannot come up against the bad things we concentrate on.</s>
        <s>With the time passing by it seems that all of the those important things are unimportant.</s>
        <s>Because people miss what time has given to them they cannot do anything about it to get their time back.</s>
        <s>But when the author writes about it he catches time and shows his love which should be the most important thing in life.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
