<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g35_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p><name type="person">Jane Smith</name><name type="geo">Germany</name><name type="person">Mr. Rump</name><name type="geo">Texas, USA</name><date>8th December 2021</date>,<name type="geo">Cologne</name></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am writing this letter for explaining you, why I think, that <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> should be a book, that is available for everyone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In your opinion the book is showing the police in a negative light.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I don't think I can approve of this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The problem of prejudiced and racist police officers is <choice><orig>undenyable</orig><reg>undeniable</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is a fact, that there is police officers acting racially motivated and there is enough examples given in everyday news.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that it is very important educating students on the whole issue.</s>
        <s>It is important building the <choice><orig>students</orig><reg>students'</reg></choice> opinion and moral on this topic for life all over the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One can never say every police officer is racist and it is also not presented like that in the book.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The uncle of the protagonist is a police officer, why should the book portray the police in a negative light?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another aspect I want to mention is that the protagonist <name type="person">Starr</name> is 16 years old.</s>
        <s>In my opinion it would be very fitting to making this book available for students and them identifying or recognizing <name type="person">Starr's</name> life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It would make all students think about their actions if they have been unwillingly racist or how they could help in situations of injustice even if it is not relating to racism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You can also say that the book is depicting drug use and containing vulgar and offensive language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first I want to say that the book is doing the exact opposite.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Khalil's</name><choice><orig>dead</orig><reg>death</reg></choice> is attributing to drug use.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His mom has a drug <choice><orig>addict</orig><reg>addiction</reg></choice> and he ended up <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> a drug seller and dying.</s>
        <s>I don't think dying as a drug seller is depicting drug use.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You may be thinking the <choice><orig>present</orig><reg>presence</reg></choice> of drugs throughout the book is a lot but I don't think we should censor this topic for students.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It would be a lesson and an example on how drugs are influencing life and <choice><orig>dead</orig><reg>death</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And concerning the vulgar language: <name type="person">Starr's</name> parents are very strict about offensive language to their three children.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even if the parents say something offensive they are punished with putting money in a jar.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These are the reasons I think <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> is an important book for every student, not only <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> students, and why the book should not be banned from the school libraries.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
