<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g33_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> state of mind will be analyzed through the point of view and narrative techniques used in the text excerpt.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the scene the point of view is first person protagonist, shown through the eyes of <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr Carter</ref>.</s>
        <s>This helps depict her personal emotions and also her state of mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Her memories are easily shown that way, which makes clear that she is not fully there at the moment and is still heavily effected by <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Khalil's</ref> death.</s>
        <s>An example is <quote><s><ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref> drops it into the side of the door.</s><s>A hairbrush is not a gun!</s><s>He opens the door to ask if I'm okay</s></quote> <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 19-21)</ref>, where through the use of <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> flashback that is partially interrupted by the events happening in the present, it shows that she is trying to move on from the traumatic event, but is still stuck by holding back and being scared.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Often used is the technique of the internal monologue, which <choice><orig>depict</orig><reg>depicts</reg></choice> her view on the events and her thought process to the reader.</s>
        <s>This explains to the reader her decisions and sympathize <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> as a protagonist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The obvious <choice><orig>describtion</orig><reg>description</reg></choice> of <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> feelings helps the reader see her character development, like <quote><s>The bullhorn is as heacy as a gun.</s><s>[...] I have the hardest time lifting it.</s></quote> <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 43-44)</ref> where she is scared and unsure of herself which is translated as her <quote>weapon</quote> being heavy and not easy to use, or <quote>You know what? Fuck it</quote> <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 48)</ref> where she stops overthinking things and just says what she wants confidently.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After she makes her decision to be confident and <choice><orig>stand</orig><reg>stands</reg></choice> up for herself the flashbacks stop, which <choice><orig>show</orig><reg>shows</reg></choice> that she is now in the present and ready to not move on from <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref>, but from being scared and feeling voiceless.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Her state of mind changes from unsure and focused to confident and actively present in the situation.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
