<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g30_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Through</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> the news I discovered the fact that <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> is banned from school libraries in <name type="geo">Texas</name>.</s>
        <s>The book is supposed to be vulgar, uses offensive language and contains scenes not appropriate for young people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think even though it is a book worth reading.</s>
        <s>It describes scenes very well and you get a closer look on what effect racism has on the people and how they struggle to deal with it.</s>
        <s>Racism is a major problem in the <name type="geo">USA</name> and that also comes from the lack of education and information about it.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, the accusations are not wrong but stressed out a little.</s>
        <s>The language is stronger than formal English, but that is how the characters and the people speak and it makes it more realistic.</s>
        <s>The point that it depicts drug use is true, but the background of it is different.</s>
        <s>It does not say that drugs are a good thing.</s>
        <s>It is a topic but it explains how the drug use is destroying their society in some way.</s>
        <s>So it does not support taking our selling drugs, it just says what the problem is and where it comes from.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The police is not shown as something negative in particular, but they underline the juristic problem and makes the reader think twice and dig deeper when a police officer is not charged for killing people they stop and search.</s>
        <s>That is why I think it is a good way to bring students the topic of racism closer and can create a view on it, that maybe was not possible before.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I would be glad if you would consider reading it in your school too or make it be accessible in your school library.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours sincerely, Jane Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
