<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11g33_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>to:<email>joan.letterman@gmail.com</email>
		from: <email>jane.smith@web.de</email>
		<s>RE: Racism in the USA</s></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Joan,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>as you may know I read <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> in class and after reading of these experiences I wondered if racism in the <name type="geo">USA</name> was really as horrible as the author had written.</s>
        <s>To get that information I did some research and stumbled upon this <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> news article from <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> rather known <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> news company called <name type="misc">Zeit (online)</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the article it is said that the racism is even noticable in statistics.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first the article makes an example through the death of <name type="person">Michael Brown</name>, an 18 year old African American man who was shot by the police in <name type="geo">Ferguson</name>.</s>
        <s>It is explained that through events like these the racism becomes noticable even though offically racism was banned 50 years ago with the <name type="misc">Civil Rights Act</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Apparently this discrimination already starts in aspects like school, where the percentage of black people succeeding and graduating is smaller than the percentage of white people.</s>
        <s>Most of them also leave the schooling system after graduating high school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>What also stood out to me was that more black people <choice><orig>ar</orig><reg>are</reg></choice> likely to have no work than the amount of white people in the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
        <s>It says that more than a fourth of black people are living in poverty while it is not even a tenth of white people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After reading this article I was very mad to see that so many people are being discriminated through a system that is still going.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To get another point of view I wanted to ask you to tell me about your experiences regarding this topic.</s>
        <s>I'll be waiting for your response.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Love, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
