<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11g31_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="investigation report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>to:<email>micheal@gmail.com</email>
		from:<email>john.smith@gmail.com</email>
		<s>RE: Discrimination in the US</s></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Micheal,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you're alright.</s>
        <s>In the past few weeks I read the book <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> with my English class and got very <choice><orig>intrested</orig><reg>interested</reg></choice> about the topic racism in the <name type="geo">US</name>, which is the main topic in the novel.</s>
        <s>So yesterday I came across a very suprisingly article about the racism in the <name type="geo">US</name>, and I would love to <choice><orig>her</orig><reg>hear</reg></choice> your opinion about it and if you can relate to some of those facts.</s>
        <s>The article is named <ref target="a11gk3_2" type="title">Black in the US: The racism is still present</ref> and was published by a famous German news provider: <name type="misc">Zeit Online</name>.</s>
        <s>The article starts <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> with the fact that the 18 year old African-American <name type="person">Michael Brown</name> got shot by a cop two weeks ago.</s>
        <s>The author <ref target="a11gk3_2" type="author">Alexandra Endres</ref> writes that the chances that something like <q>stop-and-frisk</q> <choice><orig>happends</orig><reg>happens</reg></choice>, is much higher for African-Americans <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> for whites.</s>
        <s>This statistic generally shows that whites have less handicaps than African-Americans, like white-Americans mostly have a better social and economic position.</s>
        <s>In addition I want to let you know that the article says, that African-Americans usually <choice><orig>doesn't</orig><reg>don't</reg></choice> <choice><orig>finishes</orig><reg>finish</reg></choice> school, so they didn't get a chance to make a difference in their <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But if they get their qualifications, it doesn't mean they are going to have the same chances in the future than whites.</s>
        <s>They still get discriminated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I want to know if the article is right about this topic and if you can relate to some of those given facts or not.</s>
        <s>I'm excited to hear from you again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, John Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
