<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g34_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>school district, <name type="geo">Texas</name>
		<name type="geo">Cologne</name>
		<date>8th December 2021</date></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I heard that the novel <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> by <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="author">Angie Thomas</ref> has been banned from school libraries in <name type="geo">Texas</name> due to several reasons.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion this novel should be available for all American students, because it shows the discrimination and oppression of African American people.</s>
        <s>The book portrays it in the way that a white police officer killed a black man for no reason and also that the police was stomping on the neck of the father of the protagonist for no reason.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The book has been banned because of depicted drug use but the African American people only sell or take drugs because they are in a vicious <choice><orig>cirle</orig><reg>circle</reg></choice> which starts with the bad education and a lack of opportunities for these people.</s>
        <s>This vicious circle perfectly portrays the hard life of black people in the <name type="geo">USA</name> and that they need better opportunities and a better education.</s>
        <s>Also the offensive language can easily be explained with the vicious circle because black people go to prison due to the drugs and when they come out of prison and see their families again this vicious circle starts again because their chances of getting a job are lower after they were in prison.</s>
        <s>In <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> the police assumes black people to be criminals even if that's not true and this is the reason why a black person died.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Think about bringing the book back in school libraries worldwide because it is very important that especially young students are getting informed about the life of African American people so that they do not have prejudices or discriminate these people because of their skin color.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I will be glad to answer any queries you might have about this topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Kind regards, John Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
