<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b10g53_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text, I will express my opinion on the question whether the movie <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> changed my perspective on certain things or not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From my point of view, I can clearly say that the movie did a great job at spreading awareness and visualizing the problem for everyone in the world to see.</s>
        <s>Racism is a common problem many people see as annoying as it occurs more and more in the news and in conversations.</s>
        <s>But it is clear that this is in the virtue of the people not being affected by racism.</s>
        <s>I can say that I'm sadly also affected by daily racism and I too try to spread as much awareness on it as I can.</s>
        <s>I can't really say that the movie changed my perspective of the problem but that doesn't mean it didn't change it for other people.</s>
        <s>I fully support how the movie/director showed the systematic discriminating issue towards black people in the perspective of a young black girl who goes to school, has a family and is just trying to live a normal teenage life as white teenagers.</s>
        <s>Thus I like the way the film slowly and easily educates on the problem for everyone to understand.</s>
        <s>It shows the challenges a black teenage girl has to go through when other teenagers have it way more easy <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> her.</s>
        <s>Racism is still a problem and not only in <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
        <s>That's why I appreciate the often silenced topic that <choice><abbr>POC</abbr><expan>people of colour</expan></choice>/black people are even discriminated by the government and nothing is done about it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Considering every aspect I said, one can say that the movie is perfect for educating people all over the world and spreading awareness.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
