<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g59_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this sequence <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is portrayed in a really good way.</s>
        <s>The director uses many stylistic devices to do that, but also he himself as a character is portrayed <choice><orig>positivly</orig><reg>positively</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>While walking down the hallway we see him greeting a lot of people <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> shows that he is popular and also cool.</s>
        <s>In the <choice><orig>backround</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> of this slow-mo shot there is a song by <name type="person">Billie Eilish</name> playing.</s>
        <s>The song talks about pretty blue eyes and not being able to look away <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> matches <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> voiceover and what she's saying in it while he walks.</s>
        <s>The voiceover tells us a lot about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starr</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> feelings towards <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, she says he's nice and that they both share an interest for shoes, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> is also important because sharing interests in a <choice><orig>Relationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> is great.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While walking the camera follows <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> around and changes from seeing him to seeing <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, the shot sizes change from <choice><orig>Medium</orig><reg>medium</reg></choice> to medium close ups.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> goes up to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and puts his headphones on her the camera angle changes to make it look like we are inside <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> locker.</s>
        <s>In this scene the headphones symbolize their mutual love and interest for music.</s>
        <s>It seems to play such an important role that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> even uses it as a help and way of apologizing to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We see an extreme close up of her face, this helps us see her emotions and what she might think better.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> takes the headphones of the shot size changes to a medium shot and while they talk it switches between <choice><orig>Medium</orig><reg>medium</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>Medium</orig><reg>medium</reg></choice> close ups.</s>
        <s>The camera being so close to them while talking makes the conversation feel more private and also a little <choice><orig>intimite</orig><reg>intimate</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>They are whispering and even though they are talking about something more important they still smile, but without making a joke out of the conversation.</s>
        <s>This moment in particular presents their <choice><orig>Relationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> really well, it shows that they are able to have serious conversations with <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice>, tell their problems and not argue while talking about them.</s>
        <s>It shows that they have a healthy <choice><orig>Relationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Throughout the conversation the camera switches to show <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> everytime they are talking something the camera also does is getting closer and closer to their faces everytime it switches between them and then when <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> really close going further away again.</s>
        <s>This happens in the most important part/moment of their conversatoin <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> helps bring suspense in it and making it more interesting.</s>
        <s>The camera then goes back to switching normally.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> starts walking backwards to start dancing he plugs the headphones off and turns the volume of the beat up.</s>
        <s>The mvoie then puts the music as a <choice><orig>backround</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> sound to make us hear it better it also blends out the <choice><orig>backround</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> <choice><orig>noices</orig><reg>noises</reg></choice>, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> then starts voiceovering again.</s>
        <s>The scene plays in slow-motion and towards the end it goes in normal speed again.</s>
        <s>While <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dances the camera moves slowly towards him and switches to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> while also moving closer, this type of movement makes the viewer feel more like they are there with the characters and with <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> voiceover we also find out what she thinks <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> makes us also help to understand her feelings better.</s>
        <s>The volors and lighting stay the same, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> makes sense since the don't change location and stay in the same place the whole time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in <choice><orig>All</orig><reg>all</reg></choice> the scene helps us understand the <choice><orig>Relationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> between <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> better.</s>
        <s>And since it's the first time we see <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in the movie in <choice><orig>indruduces</orig><reg>introduces</reg></choice> us to him.</s>
        <s>It makes us like the characters and feel more <choice><orig>conected</orig><reg>connected</reg></choice> to them.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
