<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g56_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, I'm going to comment on the film <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> with the aspect what impact it had on my life, perspective and my ideas.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion, the movie or the story behind it is a really important topic, which should be talked about more often.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The characters played their roles perfectly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that this movie made me realise even more, how terrible the experience of racism and police brutality can be.</s>
        <s>It must be real hard to experience such racist comments everyday like <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family did.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It hurts to know that some people even get killed only because they're <q>different</q>.</s>
        <s>I don't even think we're different.</s>
        <s>We're actually all the same, just with different skin colours.</s>
        <s>But this doesn't make you a bad person!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We're literally all from the same flesh and blood.</s>
        <s>I don't get what some people makes them even think racist in any possible way.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> represented this topic in a great way and makes you think about it more often.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, the movie <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> represented this important topic in a great and understandable way.</s>
        <s>It makes you think about it more often and makes you realise that racism is unfair and not justified even close.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
