<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g60_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text I will analyse the given scene regarding cinematic devices and the way <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="director">George Tillmann Jr.</ref> presents <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The most important message of the scene is that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> really cares about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> as his girlfriend, but also <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> way of showing him that she isn't ok with what <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> has done before <add>(condom-gate)</add>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> in three parts.</s>
        <s>The first part <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> going through the school hall shaking hands with his friends.</s>
        <s>The second part him dancing on the school hall to his own remix.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As just said before in the first part of the scene the audience sees <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> coming to school and going to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>He is shown in several medium shots or medium close ups to clearly state him as the most important character of this sequence.</s>
        <s>Furthermore we get to see his good mood like this in a very good way.</s>
        <s>He seems like someone who is always smiling and always tries to see the good thing in everything.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides the number of close shots in which <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is shown to the beginning there are also other cinematic devices making him seem more popular.</s>
        <s>One of them is the slow motion.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="director">George Tillmann Jr.</ref> used this slow motion to make <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> seem cooler and more popular to the audience.</s>
        <s>Because of the therefore longer shown handshakings and greetings with his friends we think that he is a guy everybody likes at school and who everybody wants to be a friend with.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That this isn't true in whole and that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> does not fit in this <choice><orig>stereotyp</orig><reg>stereotype</reg></choice> of the popular white guy at an <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> high school the audience experiences in the second part of the scene which begins after the song <name type="misc">Ocean Eyes</name> stopped, which made the first part seem like a foreshadow for the audience saying him <quote>This is Starr's boyfriend, look at him, he is cool but also a good partner for a relationship</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>About the last point I want to talk more specifically because in the <choice><orig>seconde</orig><reg>second</reg></choice> part of the scene the audience gets to know much about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> relationship and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> attitude to their situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the beginning of the <choice><orig>seconde</orig><reg>second</reg></choice> part we see <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> through a close up from the angle out of her locker.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> appears behind her putting his earphones on <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> head.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> now hears a self made remix from <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> which she normally likes very much.</s>
        <s>The audience gets to know this through a voice over in which <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> tells us exactly this.</s>
        <s>But on this day <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> doesn't want to hear <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> music, because she wants to talk with him seriously.</s>
        <s>But that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> feels still happy having <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> as her friend the audience gets to know, otherwise than <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, through the voice over, but also because of the close ups showing her facial expressions fighting between a serious look and a smile.</s>
        <s>Like this the scene is <choice><orig>forshadowed</orig><reg>foreshadowed</reg></choice> for the audience because he/she now knows, that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> will try to act seriously at the beginning of their conversation, but to the end will agree to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> making clear that she doesn't want to have a case like <q>condom-gate</q> again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>About like this their conversation which is shown through many over-the-shoulder and reverse-shots, happens.</s>
        <s>Both characters are shown in several close ups showing their facial expressions, which in both cases show their seriousness.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore all shots are taken an eyelevel which should clearly state that the both youths in general want to come to a good solution for both sides.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This solution is also hitted in the conversation in which <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> clearly shows that he can be a good boyfriend for <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> caring about her and being <choice><orig>their</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> for her.</s>
        <s>Like this the audience gets to see <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> character as a boyfriend which can be clearly stated as <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> antagonist to his <choice><orig>stereotyp</orig><reg>stereotype</reg></choice> as the <choice><orig>populare</orig><reg>popular</reg></choice> guy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third part of the scene <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> turns on his music loud starting to dance to it.</s>
        <s>He is shown in a medium long shot which makes it easy to see his joyness while he is dancing.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he is again shown in a slow motion which again clearly states his coolness but also what <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> likes so much at him, he always gets her laughing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> feelings at this moment are again shown through a voice over.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To have a conclusion in this scene <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented as the cool seeming guy who everybody likes at school.</s>
        <s>He acts like a perfect stereotyped guy for this role, but when he comes to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> he becomes serious.</s>
        <s>He acts like a good boyfriend for <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who wants to achieve a good relationship for both sides.</s>
        <s>At the end he tries to convince <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> by doing what he knows she loves at him <add>(making her laugh)</add>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
