<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g62_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence can be divided into three context-parts.</s>
        <s>In the first part <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is visible for the first time and gets introduced.</s>
        <s>In the second part both of them argue about the incident between them.</s>
        <s>In the last part <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dances <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of all people to hype <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> up.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With this scene the director wants to introduce <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> boyfriend also known as <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, his relation to the other students and the relation between <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> with the help of cinematic-devices like music and camera-movements.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The side-character <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> does not only have a big influence on <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> but also on his <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He is introduced as a tall and handsome guy from <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> school, who is probably very popular under his school mates.</s>
        <s>Some reasons for this are the medium shot size, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> shows his full tall body and the slow and backwards movement of the camera, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> shows him dabbing up randon school mates.</s>
        <s>This proves that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> must he a very popular student of his school, the way he got all of the attention while going down the hallway.</s>
        <s>Additionally the light shines bright on him and his smile <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> underlines that he must be popular.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> describes him of acting black.</s>
        <s>This adds up with his earphones and his shoes <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> points him out of the basic white school.</s>
        <s>Additionally, the way he dabs up people and the way he wears his clothes implements that he acts black and is in a relationship with a black person.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless the music <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> plays in the background doesn't fit with his <q>black behaviour</q>, because it should <choice><orig>symbolyze</orig><reg>symbolize</reg></choice> that he is still white.</s>
        <s>Although the impact of him on the other students doesn't influence <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows that she is already really <choice><orig>familliar</orig><reg>familiar</reg></choice> to him, which is also the reason why she is mad at him.</s>
        <s>Even though she is mad at him the close up perspective from the inside of the locker shows her facial expression and how she still smiles <choice><orig>whe</orig><reg>when</reg></choice> he <choice><orig>put</orig><reg>puts</reg></choice> his earphones on her.</s>
        <s>As the camera <choice><orig>perspektive</orig><reg>perspective</reg></choice> moves the atmosphere automatically switches too.</s>
        <s>It is intense atmosphere because <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> reminds herself why she is mad at him.</s>
        <s>The way they talk fast and with a low voice fits with the atmosphere.</s>
        <s>Moreover there is no music just sounds of people and to add that the camera switches fast into a position in which the person talks to give the viewer the feeling that he is participating in this argument.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the close ups only appear when the person says something really serious or uncomfy.</s>
        <s>Whereas when they joke or say something unspecial the camera <choice><orig>swiths</orig><reg>switches</reg></choice> into a medium shot and shows how students are going down the hallway in the background.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With these switches the director illustrates the facial expression they make when something important was said, including the pauses between the lines, and the <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>With this way of showing the scene he reminds us that there is still a school and people are around.</s>
        <s>Especially when the sound lowers <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> love when the camera <choice><orig>switchs</orig><reg>switches</reg></choice> to a close up and when it becomes very loud and you can hear all the noises everytime the camera switches to a medium shot.</s>
        <s>Considering <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, she must have been really worried because even though she is the protagonist she doesn't speak on her mind.</s>
        <s>When they switch the topic <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> the atmosphere switches too.</s>
        <s>With the music coming in and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> starting to dance, the camera moves in slow-mo in a medium shot, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> shows his dance moves and how other students are positively reacting to it.</s>
        <s>This again underlines the other students emphasize with him.</s>
        <s>Even <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is smiling which shows that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> made her happy and distracted her form her worried and negative thoughts.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>let</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> look like a very confident young man.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up the director introduced <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> as a cool popular and confident guy but also as a very important person for <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
