<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g01_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>First of all has <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> no relevance for <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> young people, because they can't easily access the idea of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, due to the difficult language and the archaic English.</s>
        <s>Furthermore they are unmotivated to interpret <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, because it has no uses for their daily <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice> and future work.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As well as that, they think that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is boring, because <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is made to be played and not to be read.</s>
        <s>As well as that the roles of the people have changed over the time, and also the society.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even if you need to study poems, you could use other contemporary, modern poetry, which is a lot more easier to understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But on the other hand there are also many arguments why <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still relevant today:</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all remains the influence of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> in the English language, (he has created over 100 words and multiple sayings) and therefore is it still important to get to know him and his work.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As well as that are the topics like love, death, loneliness, he speaks about, still relevant today and students can easy c<gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">cenide</gap> with these topic <choice><orig>themselfes</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A next argument for the use of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnets in class is the fact that he inspired multiple young artists and authors and that he is a role model for many.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>even if you don't want to study English <choice><orig>literatur</orig><reg>literature</reg></choice>, <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is a great part of the English history and culture and therefore also still relevant today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has still a great influence on <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> literature and culture, not only in literature but also in plays, sayings or general conversations.</s>
        <s>It follows, that it is a must to read at least one works of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> in class.</s>
        <s>The numbers of sonnets or plays students have to read or interpret could change on the level of English they have.</s>
        <s>For example needs the <name type="misc">A-level</name> to read more of his work.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If students can't understand the archaic English it is <choice><orig>neccessary</orig><reg>necessary</reg></choice> to give them help with translations or extra vocabulary.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But it is important to show, that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> isn't boring or irrelevant.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
