<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g16_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> is a famous <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> poet and writer with big influence on <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> culture and language.</s>
        <s>But is he still relevant for young people today?</s>
        <s>I want to discuss the pros and cons of the relevance of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> today.</s>
        <s>On the one hand there are many arguments for the relevance of Shakespeare.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> had and still has a big influence on the <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> culture and language.</s>
        <s>He made many idioms or figures of speech for example <quote>all that glitters is not gold</quote> and introduced roundabout 1700 new words into <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore he is a big inspiration to young writers and poets because of his own career and influence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover his topics are still relevant today for example the problematic love of Romeo and Juliet which is still used today in many movies or something else.</s>
        <s>His used characters and problems make it more understandable and interesting for the younger generation.</s>
        <s>On the other hand there are also some contra arguments.</s>
        <s>Especially in school <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> seems very boring to young people because they do not know enough about him and his work.</s>
        <s>This is caused by the hard language he uses.</s>
        <s>Because of this it is difficult to understand him and to get into the topic of his work.</s>
        <s>Despite <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> seems to be very old-fashioned because his plays and sonnets are written in <date>1600</date> <add>(17th century?)</add>.</s>
        <s>Many young people think he is not modern enough.</s>
        <s>In addition to that today are many new and young writer who are may be more interesting than <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> because they are also young etc.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion there are many pros and cons of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> relevance today because he had such a big influence but is also difficult to understand.</s>
        <s>In my opinion <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is relevant to young people.</s>
        <s>So who he is and what he has done but I can understand when young people think he is boring and not understandable.</s>
        <s>I think that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> should be known but not as duty for example in school.</s>
        <s>So everybody who is interested in him should be allowed to know more and who is not should not be forced to know him.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
