<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12g08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will analyse how strucuture and language support the speaker's idea of love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 116</ref> is written in the typical Shakespearean form with 3 <choice><orig>quartrains</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> and 1 final couplet.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>raim</orig><reg>rhyme</reg></choice> scheme is <name type="misc">ababcdcdefefgg</name>.</s>
        <s>The whole sonnet is a climax because first he says that love <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> change because of alteration then he says that love is constant and doesn't change it direction and <choice><orig>finaly</orig><reg>finally</reg></choice> he says that love doesn't change until death.</s>
        <s>So the <choice><orig>quartrains</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> are based on each other and the right effect is only given when you read them in the correct order.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 1 there is a metaphor <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> says <quote>marriage of true minds</quote>, it underlines that the speaker doesn't want to marry because he has to but because he loves the person he wants to marry.</s>
        <s>And that you have to be sure about your marriage.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Futhermore</orig><reg>Furthermore</reg></choice> there is a <choice><orig>comparism</orig><reg>comparison</reg></choice> in line 5 which underlines the steadfastness of love and that love leads the lovers the way they want to go.</s>
        <s>Love navigates their life.</s>
        <s>In the following lines there are two metaphors which are also personifications.</s>
        <s>The one metaphor <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>, shows how unshakeable love is and that it gets through every fight between the lovers.</s>
        <s>So even in hard times love is steadfast and helps you to get over it.</s>
        <s>In the metaphor <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> love is pictured as a star which leads the ship on the right way, so love shows the lovers their way and helps them to find back to each other.</s>
        <s>Whenever they lost their orientation their Love helps them to find back again and it doesn't change even if both of them get lost.</s>
        <s>The personification <quote>love's not time's fool</quote> shows that love is not influenced by time in a bad way and <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> <choice><orig>alters</orig><reg>alter</reg></choice> just because of time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>Within his bending sickle's compass come</quote><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> is also a metaphor which means that even when you think it is over, your love hasn't changed.</s>
        <s>Even when you are living your last days you still love somebody.</s>
        <s>To add is the metaphor in line 12 which underlines that you hold on to love until the day you die.</s>
        <s>So that love is strong enough to long until your death, and even further than this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last two lines <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> are very rhetorical and ironic because we know he has written the <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 116</ref> and also other sonnets.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> know if any man has loved is true or not.</s>
        <s>So it shows that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is sure he is right and that nobody can say something <choice><orig>different</orig><reg>diffrent</reg></choice> than this about love and how he sees it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all he compares love to an unchanging, fixed mark which helps the lovers to stay in the right direction and which leads them all their <choice><orig>lives</orig><reg>lifes</reg></choice> until death.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
