<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g46_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text on hand is an excerpt from <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref>, a book written by <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="author">Angie Thomas</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the excerpt <name type="person">Starr</name> visits a demonstration against <name type="person">Khalil's</name> murder and police <choice><orig>Brutality</orig><reg>brutality</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The excerpt can be <choice><orig>labled</orig><reg>labelled</reg></choice> in 3 sections.</s>
        <s>In the first section <name type="person">Starr</name>, <name type="person">Chris</name>, <name type="person">Seven</name> and <name type="person">DeVante</name> arrive at the demonstration.</s>
        <s>The surroundings are described and <name type="person">Seven</name>, <name type="person">DeVante</name> and <name type="person">Chris</name> join in with the <quote>A hairbrush is not a gun</quote> chant.</s>
        <s>In the next section <name type="person">Starr</name> lives through the moment where <name type="person">Khalil</name> was killed again in her mind.</s>
        <s>When it comes to the part where <name type="person">Khalil</name> got shot she cuts out and screams the chant as loud as she can.</s>
        <s>A narrative technique was used here to make readers relate to <name type="person">Starr</name> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 18-22)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After she <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">stots</gap> that, <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> noticed her and drives over to her to speak with her.</s>
        <s>After talking about how she wants to <quote>do something</quote> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 30)</ref> <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> hands her the bullhorn.</s>
        <s>The third section now begins and now she lets out everything she has in mind.</s>
        <s>It doesn't start like this immediately though, at first she stutters a little and cannot talk straight.</s>
        <s>It is only when the police said <quote>You need to leave immediately</quote> she snapped and thought to herself <quote><qs>You know what?</qs><qs>Fuck it.</qs></quote> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 48)</ref>.</s>
        <s>While this line may be considered unnecessary and too vulgar it is nevertheless a great way her point of view was used to stress that she doesn't care what others think anymore and wants to seize her opportunity and to say everythin she ever wanted people to know about <name type="person">Khalil</name>.</s>
        <s>During her speech there is another point where an insight to her thoughts are given <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 57f)</ref>, in which she described how speaking in front of the crowd gives her this positive <quote>speaker happy</quote> feeling, using colloquial language, this causes another effect to make reader identify with <name type="person">Starr</name> because young people tend to speak this way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion I would say the author does a good job in making readers relate with the protagonist of the book.</s>
        <s>It is also great to see how <name type="person">Starr</name>, who actually didn't want to speak out and rather not say anything now completely changed her mind.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
