<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g48_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>At first <name type="person">Starr</name> is really insecure about the situation she finds herself in.</s>
        <s>She wasn't back at the place where <name type="person">Khalil</name> died since it happened so she sees all the images again in her mind.</s>
        <s>This scene gets compared to a horror movie by herself to demonstrate how scared she is or was <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She then snaps out of her vision and sees <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> and the crowd chanting.</s>
        <s>This encourages her to chant aswell.</s>
        <s>She sees the death scene again while shouting but it encourages her to chant louder.</s>
        <s>By recruiting <name type="person">Khalil's</name> death the reader imagines and remembers the scene again and can feel the encouragement and power <name type="person">Starr</name> gets from this.</s>
        <s>By creating a rhythm between <name type="person">Starr's</name> shouts and the scene the reader <choice><orig>emphasizes</orig><reg>empathizes</reg></choice> with the situation <name type="person">Starr</name> is in and <name type="person">Starr</name> herself <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 18-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After she feels confident she went on top of a police car and tries to use her <q>weapon</q>, which is a comparison by <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> and really means her voice.</s>
        <s>She stutters but the crowd tells her to speak.</s>
        <s>In the who passage the crowd and <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> <q>amps</q> her up by chanting to her.</s>
        <s>This is presented by many exclamations, which do make sense because it is an event of protest in which thsi scene does take place <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 40, 45-46, 51)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Near the end she starts to like it.</s>
        <s>This can be seen by her thinking <quote>more cheers, ..., it eggs on me</quote> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 57)</ref>.</s>
        <s>If you <choice><orig>compar</orig><reg>compare</reg></choice> this to the start a large gain of confidence can be seen which was made possible because of <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> and the crowd.</s>
        <s>At the end she shouts <quote><qs>His life mattered.</qs><qs><name type="person">Khalil</name> lived!</qs></quote> which could resemble <name type="misc">Black Lives Matter</name> or could be inspired from it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
