<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11g40_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="investigation report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I did a little bit of research on systematic racism in the <name type="geo">USA</name> and I found a very interesting article on race inequality published by <name type="misc">Zeit Online</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The text is about the fact that segregation was abolished on paper more than 50 years ago but the divide between black and white is still very present in the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Black people are not getting the same amount of education and are way more likely to be stopped and arrested by the police.</s>
        <s>All this is still a problem after 50 years of on paper civil rights for all people.</s>
        <s>And even if they get good education or by a very small chance even get a bachelor or master degree they are still more likely to not get a job.</s>
        <s>And if you are a black perosn with master degree and a good job you are still more likely to get <choice><orig>stoped</orig><reg>stopped</reg></choice> and frisked by the police.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And also way more black people live a life in poverty than white people.</s>
        <s>Have you ever witnessed or experienced something like that or did you know that it is still that bad?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Or do you even think that segregation and social and racial inequality are not a thing anymore?</s>
        <s>Let me know.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Greetings and stay safe, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
