<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g45_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>It is the first time for <name type="person">Starr</name> to get back there where the incident took place.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The whole thing plays out before her eyes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> sees <name type="person">Khalil</name> looking at ther for the last time.</s>
        <s>Getting back to this place is difficult for <name type="person">Starr</name>.</s>
        <s>This part of the novel is written in the first-person narrative.</s>
        <s>This effects that all readers emphasize in <name type="person">Starr's</name> situation ebcause it is only about her feelings and impressions that she remembers from this place.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> went back there again for <name type="person">Khalil</name> and because his murder is not guilty.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The crowd shouts <quote>A hairbrush is not a gun</quote> and the voice snaps <name type="person">Starr</name> from her daze.</s>
        <s>She cannot believe that protests are for <name type="person">Khalil</name> and that this really happens.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> spotted <name type="person">Starr</name> in the crowd she changes her state of mind.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> is not grieving anymore.</s>
        <s>She will fight for <name type="person">Khalil</name> and his justice.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Starr</name> gets on the top of a cop car with <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah's</name> bullhorn in her hands, she seems to be a bit nervous.</s>
        <s>But then she starts to say who she is and she was a member of that incident.</s>
        <s>This is the changing moment where <name type="person">Starr</name> ends up her divided life.</s>
        <s>Her <name type="geo">Garden Heights</name> life with her black friends and family in a black poor neighbourhood and her rich and mostly white life at the <name type="geo">Williamson Prep School</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Everybody should know what <name type="person">Starr</name> had to see and that she is a <choice><orig>taff</orig><reg>tough</reg></choice> and brave young black girl.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She is going to be an activist for black power movements like <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The little and shy girl has changed to a young and strong woman.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
