<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g38_t3</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Michael,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> hope you are doing good.</s>
        <s>I have heard that you want to know my opinion on banning the book <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> because <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> read the book, and <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> want to let you know my opinion in the following.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I do not think, that <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> should be banned from your <choice><orig>highschool</orig><reg>high school</reg></choice> because <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> about a problem in the <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> society everybody knows about, and after reading the book understands, because you get the point of view on how some of these black people are getting treated.</s>
        <s>Yes, the book is about vulgar and offensive language, and the police is there in a negative light, but <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> based on how some people are actually getting treated, and where they are from, <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> normal for them to talk like that.</s>
        <s>And it does not promote drug abuse, it just shows, that some black people are not able to get money elsewhere, because where they are from they <choice><orig>cant</orig><reg>can't</reg></choice> get a good school graduation that easy, because of how broke the schools are.</s>
        <s>And if they <choice><orig>cant</orig><reg>can't</reg></choice> get enough money with no graduation, they have to do stuff like that, because the government is not helping enough to get them money otherwise.</s>
        <s>The book is realistic and everybody should know, that police brutality is a mayor problem for black people and how they feel about that.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Its</orig><reg>It's</reg></choice> a topic the whole world should know about, because this type of discrimination is something not acceptable.</s>
        <s>If everybody would have read the book and <choice><orig>gets</orig><reg>gotten</reg></choice> the point of view from a person getting discriminated because of his race, maybe the problem would be solved.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I was able to convince you with my point of view, and hopefully your <choice><orig>highschool</orig><reg>high school</reg></choice> realizes that this book just shows how these people are living because nobody helps them to get out of the mud.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See you soon,</s>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
