<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g25_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> gave a speech at the <name type="misc">Culture and Arts Center of Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University</name> in <name type="geo">Tophane, Istanbul</name> in <date>2009</date>, in which he mentions the importance of bringing young people together from all over the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text I will analyse the structure and the choice of words from <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama's</ref> speech.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech he makes clear that he has seen everywhere he goes that young people who are passionate and deeply informed about the world around them.</s>
        <s>That's why he wants to <quote>break down walls</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> so young people can come together and speak to <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So first of all <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> uses many stylistic devices to get the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>readers'</reg></choice> attention and to encourage his listeners.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He uses an anaphora three times.</s>
        <s>In line four, he says <quote>I've seen it</quote> and also in line five and seven he speaks <quote>I saw it</quote> and <quote>I've seen it</quote>.</s>
        <s>Because of that, he gets the readers or listeners focused on the importance he is talking about.</s>
        <s>Also in line 18 he uses <quote>I want you to know that</quote> and in line 21 <quote>And I want you to know that</quote>.</s>
        <s>Here he also gets the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>readers'</reg></choice> attention.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, he speaks to the listeners by saying <quote>you can</quote> in line 18, 19 and 20.</s>
        <s>He speaks directly to his listeners and gets so even more attention.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In these three lines he also makes clear that everyone of us can <quote>choose to put aside longstanding divisions</quote> and <quote>can choose to advance a prosperity</quote>.</s>
        <s>By giving these examples, he even more gets the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>readers'</reg></choice> attention to do something and he gives the feeling that he's supporting you and that you can do it and that you can choose to do something.</s>
        <s>He creates a community by giving these examples and by saying <quote>you</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end, he also mentions that everyone <quote>will find a partner and a supporter and a friend in the United States of America</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(line 21-22)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By giving all of these examples and stylistic devices he gets the listeners focused and gets their attention.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
