<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g19_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The special use of the film-stylistic devices and <choice><orig>expecially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> the voiceoverof <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> show the importance of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt can be divided into three parts: <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris's</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> walk through the hallways, <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris's</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> conversation about music and sex and the part when <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> pulls <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to a <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> floor.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the very beginning of the excerpt, <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented in a medium shot with a little zoom.</s>
        <s>The effect of this film-stylistic device is that the audience pays attention to the surroundings but also to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> himself and <choice><orig>expecially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> his body language.</s>
        <s>He is presented as a very confident and popular student because he is smiling and greeting a lot of other students.</s>
        <s>The audience also gets a hint of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> view of her boyfriend <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> through the song that is used while he walks up to her.</s>
        <s>The song is very romantic: <quote>... can't stop staring at those ocean eyes</quote> it says.</s>
        <s>This shows <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> feelings and thoughts while she looks at him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You can see <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> the first time in this excerpt in a medium close up.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This shot size emphasizes <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> facial expressions.</s>
        <s>She is still a little angry at <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> but she still looks very in love.</s>
        <s>The excerpt also shows that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> very well because his <name type="misc">Jordans</name> are shown in a close up.</s>
        <s>In this sequence the voiceoveris the most important stylistic device in which <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> says that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows her weaknesses.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows her very well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This fact is also shown in the next moment.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is shown in a close up but also in a two shot because the audience can see <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> who is standing behind her.</s>
        <s>He is blurred and his head isn't shown on the screen.</s>
        <s>The attention is on <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> facial expressions because this is her first time smiling after their fight.</s>
        <s>She smiles because <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> puts headphones with his own music on her ears.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The audience can hear her thoughts through the voice over: <quote>It gets me everytime</quote>.</s>
        <s>This statement shows as already mentioned how close <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> are.</s>
        <s>They like and know almost everything of each other.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The music is also a part of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> apologize.</s>
        <s>He also irreys his fault and apologizes in words.</s>
        <s>His apologize is shown in a close up to show the importance of his words to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>The audience pays attention to his facial expression and in the background the music starts to play again because he removed his headphones so that everybody can hear his music.</s>
        <s>Both of them are laughing.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> forgives <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and both of them move on.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> starts dancing to make <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> more laugh.</s>
        <s>He is dancing in a medium long shot with music and a voiceoverin the background.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> says that this is how <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is and that he is making her laugh.</s>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is in a happy relationship with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and that he is also a good boyfriend because he always tries to make her laugh also in difficult situations.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last sequence is a two shot of both of them.</s>
        <s>They are shown in a close up so that the audience can see the happiness on their faces.</s>
        <s>Their eyes are sparkling and full of love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
