<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g39_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his comment <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref>, published in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> <choice><orig>in</orig><reg>on</reg></choice> <date>27th January 2015</date>, <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> worries about the number of British students with education in foreign languages decreasing over the past years.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author starts his comment by giving an introduction into the topic.</s>
        <s>Over the last years lower students started learning new languages.</s>
        <s>He states that besides primary schools offering learning of new languages, school qualification in those subjects are decreasing since years.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> then includes the counter argumentation of there being no need for foreign languages learned because English is a lingua franca and the technology being able to translate nowadays which he all negates by commenting that not everyone in the world can speak English and technology is dependent on circumstances like the <choice><orig>acess</orig><reg>access</reg></choice> to roaming.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> instead claims that knowledge of foreign language would be needed for every part of global and states matters.</s>
        <s>He takes the economy as example where major parts of the companies would need skills in other languages, which is the reason they hire from other countries instead of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There actually are universities offering language degrees but too less students would use them, as <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> claims.</s>
        <s>He ends his comment with an appeal that there needs to be a change in the view on foreign languages and that this change must come from the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">hamfelds</gap> and parents because the school system alone could not have success.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
