<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g38_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref>, which is written by <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and published in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> on <date>27 January 2015</date>, is about the fall of learning foreign languages in the UK and the personal view of the author on this issue.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> says, that more and more students <choice><orig>doesn't</orig><reg>don't</reg></choice> want to study any foreign language skills at university level and also the national view is that foreign language skills aren't that important today.</s>
        <s>Also the exam results at national schools show, that the uptake of languages <choice><orig>are</orig><reg>is</reg></choice> coming to a standstill.</s>
        <s>But against, what other people say, that everyone can speak English in the world of working and business, <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> thinks that  <choice><orig>Britains</orig><reg>the British</reg></choice> need to learn other languages for the future perspective and global standing of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>He also thinks, that learning foreign language skills,  <choice><orig>help</orig><reg>helps</reg></choice> the <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses to establish in the global market.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> says, that people with other language skills easier getting a job in the market, than one who only speaks English.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude he says that the education system has to fix, so young people can develop their language skills, but for this it <choice><orig>need</orig><reg>needs</reg></choice> the help of the parents.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum it up you can say, that <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> thinks, that learning foreign languages is important for the global future of the <name type="geo">UK</name> and this issue has to fix in the education system.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
