<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g42_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following it is going to comment in how far language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear</salute>
        <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I read your article about learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>I agree with your point, it is <choice><orig>sadly</orig><reg>sad</reg></choice> that the number of people, who learn different languages goes <choice><orig>negativ</orig><reg>negative</reg></choice> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf.ll. 10-17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Moreover I think also, that the globalization and the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity are depending of the use of language and that the problems in future are very <choice><orig>easily</orig><reg>easy</reg></choice> to tackle, if many people can understand different languages <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 24-27)</ref>.</s>
        <s>But one point I missed, when I read your text.</s>
        <s>The point that it gives nowadays very good <choice><orig>translator</orig><reg>translators</reg></choice>, which gives us the possibility to communicate very easily about the internet.</s>
        <s>So the people, who are trading personally need to work with languages, but not the persons, who trade about the internet.</s>
        <s>Because of this point I think that parents should animate the children to learn foreign languages, but <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> not that important you think.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up I would say, that your intention to animate young people learning foreign languages should be supported.</s>
        <s>In <choice><orig>generell</orig><reg>general</reg></choice> the children should be supported also more by learning.</s>
        <s>But it goes also without.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
