<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g45_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his newspaper article <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> claims that <quote>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> prosperity and global standing</quote></s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand one could argue that nowadays, specifically for the <name type="geo">UK</name>, the importance for international communication could have gone down a bit since Brexit happened, however on the other hand I believe the article has written prior to Brexit happening and this also might mean that the <name type="geo">UK</name> must focus on learning languages of other countries more than ever, especially since learning the <name type="misc">EU</name> might have opened opportunities to trade with new countries and at the same time forces them to focus on not <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> their connections with <name type="misc">EU</name> countries any further and to rely on working with <name type="geo">China</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though English is globally spoken, as also referred to by <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref>, <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 18-23)</ref> I believe that it is still important for British children to learn multiple languages, since Spanish and <choice><orig>chinese</orig><reg>Chinese</reg></choice> are also becoming more and more of a competition to being the global language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also I personally feel there is a huge benefit in leaving other countries' culture and history instead of just focussing on oneself, since it enables people to travel and really live in way adventurers a hundred years ago could only have dreamt of.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though I agree with the critics saying phones will play a more important role and help break language barriers, I feel like relying on phones too much will make people of the future dull and less capable of thinking by <choice><orig>them selves</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>, they will be completely reliant on their device.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally studies have shown that learning a new language is very beneficial to train the brain and thus enhance learning capability overall.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, as already written by <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref>, more and more jobs require language skills that reach further than merely English <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll 28-30)</ref> and more jobs than ever require their employees to travel around the world.</s>
        <s>Also due to globalization more and more <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">hotels</gap> have opened, causing more business partners to be international, in all sectors.</s>
        <s>Furthermore there is <choice><orig>many</orig><reg>much/ a lot of</reg></choice> outsourcing going on (also <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">cf. ll34-35</ref>), which means only people who can move with the tide and build up a life elsewhere can keep up with the role in which everything changes in our world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Last but not least I personally feel there is something <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">levseley</gap> arrogant and nationalistic in refusing to learn anything but the "own" culture and language, simply because so many people speak it.</s>
        <s>This gives one a bad taste of a <choice><orig>superiority-complex</orig><reg>superiority complex</reg></choice> and seems, to me, to lead to a way less diplomatic future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <choice><orig>conlusion</orig><reg>conclusion</reg></choice> I would very much say I agree with <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and feel like the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future is not looking <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> bright if they don't start learning more foreign languages at a young age.</s>
        <s>The market has rapidly expanded and the world is at our feet to be explored.</s>
        <s>If the <name type="geo">UK</name> doesn't keep up with <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> international connections forged by trade, diplomacy and student exchanges, they will quickly fall behind their competitors.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
