<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g51_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following the article will be analysed, with focus on communicative strategies and use of language and how <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> uses them, to underline his view on language learning.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first the words <quote>can't, won't, don't</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> that in itself are dramatic, together with the hypothesis, that those three words sum up the entire view of the <name type="geo">UK</name> on foreign languages, create a hook to catch the reader.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref>, after that, states, that not only the number of students interested in foreign langauges in university is shrinking, but also the number of <name type="misc">A-level</name> and <name type="misc">GCSE</name> exams and <choice><orig>entrys</orig><reg>entries</reg></choice>, although none of this is underlined by any studies or other sources <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 3-5, 13-15)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His statement <quote>More than 10,000 fewer language A-level exams were taken last year than at the end of the 1990s</quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 13f)</ref> works well in his favour, because 10,000 looks like a big number to a lot of people, but can be relatively small compared to the total number of <name type="misc">A-level</name> tests, so <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> could've left those numbers out to strengthen his point.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And even though he names a lot of negative aspects, he also writes about positive things, for example that primary schools can teach languages now <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 8f)</ref> or the fact that some universities are giving the chance to study a language together with their degree subject <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 36-38)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows, that <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> is familiar with the subject and is not focused on talking about the negative aspects, but much rather on educating about the topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of the key aspects of <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Wornes</orig><reg>Worne's</reg></choice></ref> article isn't his strategy in structure or arguments, but his language.</s>
        <s>Through the whole article he is very sarcastic as seen in <quote><s>Everyone speaks English in the world of business (they don't), your iPhone will now translate read signs for you (but you may crash or choke on the roaming data charges) and the next generation of wearable tech will enable intercultural telepathy anyway.</s><s>Cobblers.</s></quote> <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 18-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With that one can see, how unrealistic some solutions are when all we have to do is learn a language to avoid all those negative sides of the <choice><orig>equasien</orig><reg>equation</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>With his humorous way he also seems a lot more <choice><orig>likable</orig><reg>likeable</reg></choice> and genuine.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It also appeals to the audience, specifically to the parents living in the <name type="geo">UK</name>, when he writes about how only the parents can help changing the problem <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 44-50)</ref>.</s>
        <s>And by mentioning that he himself is also a parent, he shows, that he is willing to do something for change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end one could say, that <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> used his strategies and language well to help him undermine his view.</s>
        <s>He appealed to the audience and managed to build an <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> on the topic but not using any sources to back his statement up.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
