<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g45_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given text <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> and published in the <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> on <date>January 2015</date>, addresses the importance of the English language in relation to the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>The author feels that language learning in school has decreased significantly and fewer people are ready to learn new languages.</s>
        <s>Right at the beginning the author says that people are not interested in learning foreign languages.</s>
        <s>He says the number of people learning foreign languages at university level has declined in recent years.</s>
        <s>He also mentions that over ten thousand fewer foreign language exams were passed than at the end of 1990.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk4_1" type="author">Worne</ref> criticizes this in the following.</s>
        <s>He also says that no technology can replace the acquisition of a language because it is essential for the future.</s>
        <s>He brings up the point of globalization and comes back to the importance of language.</s>
        <s>According to him, things like trade between countries or the national security can only run smoothly if you have the language and can communicate with <choice><orig>one other</orig><reg>one another</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>What he also sees critically is that only a few take advantage of the offer to learn a foreign language at university.</s>
        <s>In his opinion, a lot more people have to do that because the possibilities are there just not the desire.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
