<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b11l17_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>I think <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> does right by reviving this relationship.</s>
        <s>We know how <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref> treated his mistress so it's possible that he treats <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> hardly any better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Going from this stance it would be great for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to leave the relationship with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref> especially if she loves <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And in the book the chances are not too bad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She may loved <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref> at one point in her life but in the book it seems like she likes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The only thing coming between her and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is her hitting <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Myrtle Wilson</ref> with her car and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Mr. Wilson</ref> revenging his wife by killing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> because he thought <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> drove the car.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Hadn't they driven <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Toms</orig><reg>Tom's</reg></choice></ref> car and caused <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Myrtle</ref> storming onto the street, the whole thing could have ended lucky for them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In general I would say that it depends on your and the other <choice><orig>persons</orig><reg>person's</reg></choice> situation.</s>
        <s>If one said that the person is married happy, it would be highly unethical to pull them out of their life by rententering it, and maybe ruining their marriage.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But if the situation of the other person in the right state, there shouldn't be a problem reviving a past relationship.</s>
        <s>Especially if you consider that this can lead to new relationships.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
