<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11g20_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given extract of <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Barack Obamas</orig><reg>Barack Obama's</reg></choice></ref> speech on the American Dream, delivered on <date>November, 7th 2007</date> in <name type="geo">Bettendorf, Iowa</name>, is held by the occasion that he <choice><orig>think</orig><reg>thinks</reg></choice> it is worth to fight for the American Dream.</s>
        <s>The text is an extract from <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Obamas</orig><reg>Obama's</reg></choice></ref> speech on the American Dream during his first election campaign, so the audience <choice><orig>are</orig><reg>is</reg></choice> his followers in <name type="geo">Iowa</name> and the American population in general, because he claims his values to everyone not just to the people in front of him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Obamas</orig><reg>Obama's</reg></choice></ref> main idea is that the people see that <choice><orig>wheter</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> you are young, old, black, white or brown they all share a faith in simple dreams.</s>
        <s>So he claims that they all have common hopes and all want to live in freedom and harmony.</s>
        <s>In the last three paragraphs he wants to show that even the generations <choice><orig>befor</orig><reg>before</reg></choice> him <add>(his grandparents and his mother)</add> tried to live the American Dream.</s>
        <s>Another reason why <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> wants to fight for the American Dream is the <choice><orig>Education</orig><reg>education</reg></choice> and opportunity for the children.</s>
        <s>Besides he also claims that it would be worth to fight for the American Dream because of the family and health from everyone.</s>
        <s>So <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> wants to fight for the American Dream because of the opportunities that would follow from it and the freedom and peace that would come between people.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
