<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g23_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his given speech <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> makes use of some rhetorical devices to emphasize special parts of his speech.</s>
        <s>Those will be explained in the following.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example the enumeration <quote>geography and ideology, race and religion, wealth and opportunity</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 5f.)</ref> which is actually also a <choice><orig>paralellism</orig><reg>parallelism</reg></choice>, should show up the many different values segregation can <choice><orig>devide</orig><reg>divide</reg></choice> a country.</s>
        <s>But instead of <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">EDIT</gap> for segregation <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> wants to show the audience the core values of <name type="geo">America</name> that <name type="geo">America</name> is fighting for and therefore the country including the audience <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> to stick together to achieve this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By using the contrast which can be found in line 8 <quote>I haven't been struck by our differences - I've been impressed by the values and hopes that we share</quote> he refers to the enumeration above and shows that he does not see a country where the <choice><orig>seperation</orig><reg>separation</reg></choice> gets bigger and where the people <choice><orig>does</orig><reg>do</reg></choice> not stick together.</s>
        <s>Thus he wants the audience to get the feeling that he <choice><orig>beliefs</orig><reg>believes</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">America</name> and that he will fight for the American Dream.</s>
        <s>In addition the audience <choice><orig>get</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> the feeling that they can help by stopping racism, terrorism and so on to stick together and to stop the segregation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover he makes use of an anaphora <quote>no matter what color you are, no matter where you're from, no matter how much money you have</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 19f.)</ref> to refer to the <name type="misc">Bill of Rights</name> which are included in the American Dream and this appeals to the emotion of the audience because they get remind of how important the values or Bill of the American Dream can be for them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally he uses a statistic data <quote>$12,000 a year</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> to let the audience see how serious it is for him to be part when <name type="geo">America</name> is creating a better country so he wants to <choice><orig>invide</orig><reg>invite</reg></choice> them to be also a part and if more and more people are convince nobody has to give up all like he does as a community organiser.</s>
        <s>So when everybody <choice><orig>taks</orig><reg>takes</reg></choice> part it is not much they have to do to create a better country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude it can be said that <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> makes use of strong arguments, a great choice of language and memorable rhetorical devices to keep the audience in mind with his fighting for the American Dream.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
