<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g26_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following it will be analysed how <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> tries to convince his audience that <quote>dreams are worth fighting for</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 25f.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> started with the enumeration and antithesis <quote>About how we're becoming more separated by geography and ideology; race and religion; wealth and opportunity</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 4-6)</ref> through which he described how many differences <name type="geo">America</name> has and how good they are.</s>
        <s>The effect of the use of those rhetorical <choice><orig>device</orig><reg>devices</reg></choice> is that the audience gets told how close those differences are to each other and that it is a big <choice><orig>content wise</orig><reg>contentwise</reg></choice> contras, but with looking closer they are and work very close together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore the future president used the <choice><orig>klimax</orig><reg>climax</reg></choice> <quote><s>Americans share a faith in simple dreams... Common hopes.</s><s>American dreams</s></quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 10-12)</ref> to clarify his supporters to believe in something and hopefully the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Through this he builded a connection to everybody, because not everyone has the faith in the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice>, but should have faith in something, even though it is just something very small.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> uses a personal histerical argument in the <choice><orig>forth</orig><reg>fourth</reg></choice> paragraph where he tells his audience on how his family lived the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice> at first very small and at the end big enough to rais the future president.</s>
        <s>Thus his family achieved through hard work and the <choice><orig>believe</orig><reg>belief</reg></choice> in the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally the anaphora and <choice><orig>klimax</orig><reg>climax</reg></choice> <quote>no barriers to success - no matter what color you are, no matter where you're from, no matter how much money you have</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 19-20)</ref> <choice><orig>clarifys</orig><reg>clarifies</reg></choice> for the audience that they can believe in <choice><orig>themselfs</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice> and have no excuse for not believing or working hard for their dreams.</s>
        <s>The effect is that everybody feels picked up, because every of those arguments fir to everyone.</s>
        <s>All people are different and believe in different dreams and hopes, but when they work hard they can <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice> their personal American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>All in all <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> convinced his audience through the use of rhetorical devices of the faith in the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice>, because he and his family build a life through hard work from scratch.</s>
        <s>With the example of his own family the audience feels included and it is easier for them to try to believe in the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice> as well.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
