<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11g16_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his last speech <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> talks about the lack of barriers that lead to great <choice><orig>sucess</orig><reg>success</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
        <s>Many people think, that this is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> important aspect of the core American values and the American Dream.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand, I think that this statement isn't very true, because in reality there are many equalities between the people in <name type="geo">America</name>, what makes it hard for people with another racial background or a not wealthy family to achieve great success.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> is talking about his grandparents and his mother about their background and about the things they already achieved.</s>
        <s>This is a thing that stands for the <choice><orig>sucess</orig><reg>success</reg></choice> through the lack of barriers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> talks about his own experiences and his job as a community organizer <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 21f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>If you see that in the context of his election, this shows that you can achieve great success.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I think that this statement is a core value of the American Dream and a great way of convincing the people to vote for him.</s>
        <s>Also I would say that his statement is not completely false, but in the future there will be problems that the Americans have to face.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
