<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g22_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="discussion">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Personally, I still do believe that there are barriers to success in <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though it fits <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama's</ref> image as the first black president, <quote>the President of equality</quote> etc. one cannot ignore the obstacles still in the path of minorities today.</s>
        <s>Statistically, if you grow up poor in <name type="geo">America</name>, you're going to die poor too.</s>
        <s>Colleges in <name type="geo">America</name> require astronomically high tuition fees, the better the college, the more you pay.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Broke your arm or leg?</s>
        <s>Got cancer at 22?</s>
        <s>Good luck, the health care system of the <name type="geo"><choice><orig>united states</orig><reg>United States</reg></choice></name> is not the one to turn to.</s>
        <s>It's true again, the more money you have to begin with, the better your chances.</s>
        <s>Another thing - racism is still present.</s>
        <s>Black people have lower job acceptance rates than white people with the same qualifications.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Just removing the name and photo from your resume helps with even getting an interview.</s>
        <s>How is skin color or being a migrant not a barrier for success then?</s>
        <s>The most <choice><orig>succesful</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice> people in <name type="geo">America</name> are white men, women make up half of the population, still the great majority in congress and in high-paying positions are men.</s>
        <s>With all these facts and factors in mind, I cannot objectively agree with <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama's</ref> statement, though I do understand the rhetorical effect and need for it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
