<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a11g23_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The question arises if it is really true that <quote>In America there are no barriers to success</quote>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It might be right that <name type="geo">America</name> gives most people great chances for a good future especially because of the American Dream including the <name type="misc">Bill of Rights</name> but as <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> said there are forgetten corners, people who have the feeling of being not part of this country.</s>
        <s>Therefore I would not totally agree with this sentence but I am sure that <name type="geo">America</name> offers a lot of chances for their population.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Additionaly</orig><reg>Additionally</reg></choice><name type="geo">America</name> has a strong economy and with the <name type="geo">Silicon Valley</name> also an attractive place for young people who have ideas for better technologies or so on.</s>
        <s>Thus <name type="geo">America</name> is an attractive country for young people all over the world.</s>
        <s>For me as a young student who likes playing soccer, <name type="geo">America</name> is great because of their colleges combined with sports for <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> perfect mix on education and sport <choice><orig>carrier</orig><reg>career</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even if it might be right that <name type="geo">America</name> offers people a <choice><orig>lots</orig><reg>lot</reg></choice> of chances when they have the right attitude one <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> to keep in mind that <name type="geo">America</name> has had difficult problems in the past but especially with racism.</s>
        <s>Situations where a policeman <choice><orig>act</orig><reg>acts</reg></choice> like a <choice><orig>men</orig><reg>man</reg></choice> who does not care who the other person is or if the <name type="misc">Bill of Rights</name> are not for all makes the rest of the world feel scary a world that <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> understand why this can happen in the 21th century.</s>
        <s>It creates a bad <q>picture</q> of <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
        <s>Maybe for some people this is a reason not to go to <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
        <s>But I am sure if those situations <choice><orig>does</orig><reg>do</reg></choice> not happen anymore.</s>
        <s><name type="geo">America</name> will not have a really bad side like this and the sentence in the introduction will be totally true.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, I nearly agree with the sentence from <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> but I want to keep <name type="geo">America</name> and the people in mind that there is something to work on to give all people the chance to be <choice><orig>succesful</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">America</name> because of the reason there are no barriers.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
