<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11g26_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical_recount">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The extract taken from <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama's</ref> speech on <date>November 7th 2007</date> in <name type="geo">Bettendorf, Iowa</name>, during his first election day campaign <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of his supporters, is about the general and his personal American Dream.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> talks about the state he grew up in and how close it is to <name type="geo">Bettendorf</name>.</s>
        <s>But then he says that those states are more than just close to each other.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He went on with the state he now has a life in and <choice><orig>clariefys</orig><reg>clarifies</reg></choice> the audience about the divisions and how <name type="geo">America</name> <choice><orig>becoms</orig><reg>becomes</reg></choice> more <choice><orig>seperate</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thirdly he talks about his experience on his journey so far.</s>
        <s>There he points out that every American has a dream, no matter from where they are, how they they <choice><orig>looks</orig><reg>look</reg></choice> or which job they have.</s>
        <s>That some have small dreams and some big but in the American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice> all of those are included.</s>
        <s>Then <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> telled the story about his <choice><orig>grandfathers</orig><reg>grandfather's</reg></choice> American <choice><orig>dream</orig><reg>Dream</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>How small he started and how hard they worked to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice> a good life.</s>
        <s>How his mother got to raise two children and teached them to save enough to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following he went on talking about how his mother got to raise him and how he learned from her to believe in your own dreams, where it does not matter if you have something or nothing.</s>
        <s>He tells the audience that they just have to work hard to achieve your dreams.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last paragraph <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> got back in his own world.</s>
        <s>There he told the audience how bad he <choice><orig>lifed</orig><reg>lived</reg></choice> once and how hard he worked to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice> and although the dream slipped away for a moment in some places of <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
        <s>But then he did not gave up and worked harder to achieve his dreams.</s>
        <s>He finished the speech with the knowledge what the fighting is worth it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
