<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g15_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Rhetorical devices are often used to lay focus on certain aspects fo a speech.</s>
        <s>In the following it will be analysed how <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses them and what their intended effect is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By using the climax <quote>geography and ideology; race and religion; wealth and opportunity</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5-6)</ref> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> mentions all the things that could <choice><orig>seperate</orig><reg>separate</reg></choice> the people but do not.</s>
        <s>He goes on to say how he impressed he was by all the values and hopes they share <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 8-9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He talks about this to show the people that it does not matter where you live or how wealthy you are; everybody shares the same values.</s>
        <s>The contrast <quote>big cities and small towns; among men and women; young and old; black, white and brown</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 9-10)</ref> emphasizes again that it is irrelevant who you are, every American wants the same thing.</s>
        <s>He does this to make the audience feel included in his dreams for the country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The anecdote about his grandfather <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13-16)</ref> is supposed to give an example of what the American Dream is.</s>
        <s>This is supposed to make Americans proud of their dream and show them how good of a dream it actually is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another anecdote he gives is about his mother <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 17-20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He mentions this story to show that every American should believe in the American Dream.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By mentioning both of these anecdotes <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> creates a bond to show them that he believed in the American Dream and that it payed out.</s>
        <s>He wants to show that the American Dream is reality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The repetition of the words <quote>no matter what</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 19-20)</ref> underlines the fact that it is irrelevant who you are.</s>
        <s>Everybody can make it.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> encourages his audience to believe in the American Dream by doing this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>the American Dream was slipping away</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 25)</ref> is supposed to strengthen the fact that the American Dream was fading away.</s>
        <s>He does this to show the audience that he deeply cares about the people and that he <choice><orig>genuinly</orig><reg>genuinely</reg></choice> wants the best for <name type="geo">America</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Summing up one can say that <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> used rhetorical devices to convince the <choice><orig>American's</orig><reg>Americans</reg></choice> to believe in the American Dream.</s>
        <s>He also wanted to <choice><orig>shows</orig><reg>show</reg></choice> that he cares deeply about the American people.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
