<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g07_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mister Johnson,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>my name is <name type="person">Jane Smith</name> and I was 17 when you delivered your speech at the <name type="misc">COP26 World Leaders' Summit Opening Ceremony</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You said <quote><qs>And let us think of the billions more of the unborn, whose anger will be all the greater if we fail.</qs><qs>We cannot let them down.</qs><qs>We have the ideas.</qs><qs>We have the technology, We have bankers.</qs><qs>We have the corporations and the NGOs.</qs></quote> and well we failed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And that was because the actions you took, the actions most politicians took were not enough.</s>
        <s>You were <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> afraid to ruin your repetition so you rather ruined my <choice><orig>childrens</orig><reg>children's</reg></choice> future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As you said you had all the possibilities to stop climate change but in the end you did not do enough.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And the worst thing is that it was not a surprise, for decaes scientists from all over the world told you and others that these actions are not enough.</s>
        <s>You put me in a position where I question of having children was the right thing to do.</s>
        <s>Because my children are the <quote>unborn</quote> you talked about.</s>
        <s>But not only will they be angry at your generation, their future will be <choice><orig>unsecure</orig><reg>insecure</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end the taking action was not as easy as you made it seem.</s>
        <s>In the end a lot of animals and humans have lost and will <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice> their homes and also will die and I already have died I know it not entirely your fault.</s>
        <s>You were by far not the only one that did too little.</s>
        <s>But you still let the generations after you down even though you had <quote>the ideas, the technology, the bankers, the corporations and the NGOs</quote>.</s>
        <s>In the end all your words full of hope and optimism <choice><orig>ment</orig><reg>meant</reg></choice> nothing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours faithfully, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
