<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12g01_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given speech is from <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref>, who is the <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> prime minister and he addresses it at the <name type="misc">COP26 World Leaders' Summit</name> on <date>the first of November 2021</date>.</s>
        <s>First he talks about <name type="person">James Bond</name> and how they, the world leaders, have to just like him <choice><orig>deffuse</orig><reg>defuse</reg></choice> on doomsday device.</s>
        <s>This doomsday device is very real however and can really end the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that he talks about the previous summits like <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> where they made promises and now they have to act upon then.</s>
        <s>Then he says that they have the required technology and have to act on areas like coal, cars and trees.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Following that he says that the industrial countries created those problems and now they have the duty to act upon it.</s>
        <s>Then he talks about the idea that government spending alone can't solve the problem but they have to de-risk the private.</s>
        <s>After that he says that they have the necessary requirements and now especially since many young people crave for it, they have to act.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then to complete this he states that the majority of affected people are not born yet and they can't miss the opportunity of this historical event, that will be seen as a turning point in history <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> they achieve it or fail it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then he emphasizes again that all the requirements to act are met.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly he points out that this can be a turning point for humanity where returned its tides.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He views the climate change like a world-ending doomsday device that will have its greatest effect in the future.</s>
        <s>The Summit is in his point of view a crucial turning point for humanity and history that will be long remembered.</s>
        <s>This summit can start <choice><orig>humanities</orig><reg>humanity's</reg></choice> quest for a safer future.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
