<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g05_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. President,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>in the speech that you held <date>2021</date> at <name type="misc">COP26 World Leader's Summit Opening Ceremony</name>.</s>
        <s>You said we should think about the then unborn generations, who will be in anger if we fail to act against climate change.</s>
        <s>You even stated, how you had the ideas and technological <choice><orig>abilitys</orig><reg>abilities</reg></choice> to change it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And yet, here we are.</s>
        <s>And I can guerantee you that anger is not all they feel.</s>
        <s>You made life on earth worse than anyone expected.</s>
        <s>You drove humanity as a whole straight into hell.</s>
        <s>Anger is not what they feel.</s>
        <s>There is no feeling that could do justice to the situation we are in.</s>
        <s>And it should not have mattered what the future generations feel.</s>
        <s>You were reducing the problem on one tiny thing.</s>
        <s>It was about saving humanity, but instead you were worried that your <choice><orig>great-grandchilds</orig><reg>great-grandchildren</reg></choice> might hate you.</s>
        <s>By you, I don't mean you specifically, but all the people who were in charge.</s>
        <s>Did you even want the change?</s>
        <s>You didn't miss your cue.</s>
        <s>You did not fluff a single line.</s>
        <s>But the play you put on wasn't about ending climate change.</s>
        <s>In reality you never wanted to, once you realized it would not be profitable.</s>
        <s>You had the technology but didn't want to use it.</s>
        <s>But you don't have to worry, as your life is almost over, and you had the chance to live it care-free.</s>
        <s>I hope you can go to rest well knowing that you have failed.</s>
        <s>Not only the young generations, but humanity as a whole.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours faithfully, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
