<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g15_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Prime Minister,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Your time on this world is over soon but ours isn't.</s>
        <s>The statement of you in <date>2021</date> was really revolutional and the turning point of global politics that year.</s>
        <s>My generation thanks you for standing for us even we weren't born these days.</s>
        <s>I can't imagine your power and wisdom to talk about us.</s>
        <s>Your generation has had the duty to save the planet and they have but your statement is not only revolutional but it also has some points I want to discuss about.</s>
        <s>I was born in <date>2028</date>, seven years after your speech and at this point my mom told me they tried to don't use coal and oil but it didn't work this well.</s>
        <s>Nowadays we don't even use a drop of oil but we still have to handle with your use of oil.</s>
        <s>The oceans are contaminated of plastic and this can't reversed.</s>
        <s>Our anger hadn't be greater if you wouldn't have taken action, the planet would have been dead and our <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice> a pain.</s>
        <s>What if the people went on like this?</s>
        <s>I can't imagine this because I see the amount of rubbish everywhere I go and the contamination stopped a decades ago.</s>
        <s>Your analysis wasn't this good but your message was the right to encourage the others to do something.</s>
        <s>My question is why didn't you take action long before?</s>
        <s>You stated that everything for taking action was there but <choice><orig>noone</orig><reg>no one</reg></choice> did anything.</s>
        <s>That is a real shame.</s>
        <s>Your generation did everything at the last possibility and that is the shame.</s>
        <s>If you would've had this thought 15 years earlier it would be perfect now.</s>
        <s>You were the man to talk about us when everyone focused on thereselves and this shows your big heart so I want to thank you for commitment.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You are a hero.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours faithfully, John Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
