<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g13_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Emma,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>thanks for writing me and asking about the article you have read.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> is a campaign I am gladly telling you more about because it is a great project.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It came into existence because many students at my school are <choice><orig>interestet</orig><reg>interested</reg></choice> in climate crisis and things that we can do as individuals to combat the disaster.</s>
        <s>In my last e-mail I told you about <name type="misc">Fridays for Futures</name> but now my school wants to do some thing itself to show their interest in a sustainable lifestyle and that's why teachers, students and parents brought the project <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> into life.</s>
        <s>This is a project for several days which consists of many different workshops that all have to do something with climate change and environmental protection.</s>
        <s>Let me give you a little insight what these workshops are about:</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example students learn about the right use of water, energy and food.</s>
        <s>A group of people did a workshop about food sharing others made a secondhand flea market with old clothes they brought from home.</s>
        <s>Also there was a fairtrade-coffeeshop where students selled fair traded and vegan products to show that this lifestyle possible and not that difficult as it seems to many people.</s>
        <s>There also were some creative workshops where students could create things by <choice><orig>themselfs</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice> to the topic environmental protection.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the project was really <choice><orig>successfull</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice> and as far as I see everyone learn something new and start to change some things more in their daily life to reduce environmental pollution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The learning was combined with a lot of fun which is what makes it that <choice><orig>successfull</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>We <choice><orig>definitly</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> want to repeat the project <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> next year and include new ideas and workshops.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could answer all your questions and if not feel free to ask.</s>
        <s>I would love to know what you think about the project and maybe you can ever organize some thing similar at your school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Hear you soon!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
