<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g12_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this speech <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> tries to convince the audience, of he need to act know, by pointing out the seriousness of the situation and giving the audience hope so they don't think it's too late.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speech can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into six parts.</s>
        <s>And very part got its own importance in <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> argumentative structure.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> points out the problem and the danger of the problem by omparing the climate crisis to a <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie <quote><qs>[...] a red digital clock tickets down remorselessly to a donation that will end human life as we know it.</qs><qs>And we are roughly in the same position [...] as James Bond today</qs></quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 4-6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He <choice><orig>referres</orig><reg>refers</reg></choice> to <name type="person">James Bond</name> to stimulate the imaginations of the audience and that they have a better feeling of the situation we are in.</s>
        <s>He points out the difference seriousness and danger of the problem by saying <quote>except that the tragedy is not a movie and the doomsday device is real</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 6-7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He also mentions, that this crisis is <quote>entirely man-made</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> and <quote>we know what the scientists tell us, and we have learned not to ignore them</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>, so that the audience know that we are the reason for this climate crisis and we should learn from our mistakes and finally act.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He underlines the point that they knew about the problem for so long but have not done anything but making promises <quote><qs>[...] in Copenhagen 11 years ago, when we acknowleged we had a problem.</qs><qs>[...] all those promises will be nothing but "blah, blah, blah" and the anger and impatience of the world will be uncontainable unless we [...] get real about climate change</qs></quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 10-15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This also points out the need and importance to act now before it's too late.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the fourth part he gives hope by saying <quote>we have the technology, to deactivate that ticking dooms device</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 10-17)</ref> and encourages the audience to actt now as <quote>we have the duty to find those funds [...] to help the rest of the world to move to green technology</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 19-21)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> continues giving the audience hope by pointing out and knowing what they should first do and how they can start <quote>And the task now is to work together to help our friends to decarbonize, using our funds [...] in the key countries that need to make progress [...] we can help to de-risk, so that the private sector money can come in</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 23-27)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He underlines this idea by saying <quote> just in the same way that it was the private sector that enabled the UK to end our dependence on coal, become the Saudi Arabia of wind</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 27-29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It worked once, it should work again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the fifth part he once again points out the need to act now because when they talk about what they will do in <date>2050</date> or <date>2060</date>, they will most likely do nothing because the <quote>average of this conclave of world leaders [...] is over 60</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 35)</ref>, so therefore they will be all in there ninetees so they must act now while they can.</s>
        <s>He continues pointing out the need to act now by saying <quote>the children who will judge us are children not yet born</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref>, <quote><qs>and we mustn't fluff our lines or miss our cue.</qs><qs>Because if we fail, they will not forgive us</qs></quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="geo">Glasgow</name> must be the point where they finally start doing something about the problem because <quote>they will know that Glasgow was the historic turning point when history failed to turn</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 41)</ref>.</s>
        <s>All of them are part of history but now it's their decision <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> they will be remembered as heros or the reasons for the end of the world as we know.</s>
        <s>He continues encouraging them and giving them hope <quote><qs>We cannot let them down.</qs><qs>We have the ideas.</qs><qs>We have the technology.</qs><qs>We have the bankers.</qs><qs>We have the cooperations and the NGOs</qs></quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 40-47)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last part he <choice><orig>referres</orig><reg>refers</reg></choice> back to <name type="person">James Bond</name> and once again says <quote>we have the duty, to make this summit the moment when humanity finally began to defuse that bomb</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 49-50)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> uses many rhetorical devices to convince the audience of the need to act.</s>
        <s>He uses a lot of inclusive language <quote>we can</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>, <quote>we cannot and will not</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref>, <quote>judge us</quote>.</s>
        <s>He does that to make the audience a big group so they all feel like they are a part of it, as they are, and are <choice><orig>effected</orig><reg>affected</reg></choice> by the crisis so they're more willing to act.</s>
        <s>In line 3 and 7 he uses a comparison <quote>lucrative films, strapped to doomsday device - not a movie doomsday device is real</quote>.</s>
        <s>This shows the danger of the problem as the one thing is a movie and the other is real life.</s>
        <s>He also uses a lot of anaphoras, for example <quote><qs>We cannot let them down.</qs><qs>We have the ideas.</qs><qs>We have the technology.</qs><qs>We have the bankers.</qs><qs>We have the corperations and the NGOs</qs></quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 40-47)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He uses the anaphoras to make the line more memorable give it a powerful touch as if represents his main idea.</s>
        <s>I already talked about the allusion towards <name type="person">James Bond</name> earlier.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> uses metaphoras like <quote>fluff our lines or miss our cue</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref> to connect to the readers associating and emotions and pull them on his sound.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref><choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to encourage the audience of world leaders to do something about the climate change by using inclusive language so the audience has the feeling, that they are all on the asme side of the boat.</s>
        <s>He also encourages them by giving them hope and that it's not too late.</s>
        <s>He tells them that this could be a historic turning point so that no one <choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to be the bad person.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
