<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g17_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, I'm going to analyse how the author used communicative strategies and stylistic devices to persuade the reader of his opinion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His first communicative strategy is the headline of the article.</s>
        <s>Here he uses the headline as <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> magnet for all readers.</s>
        <s>The thing with <choice><orig>newpaper</orig><reg>newspaper</reg></choice> articles is that the headline is the most important part to persuade the reader to read the article, because it's the first thing you can think of.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With the title <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="title">Is the usefulness of unions in the protection of workers rights coming to an end? The answer is yes</ref>, <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Pollard</ref> shows the reader immediately his very <choice><orig>strik</orig><reg>strict</reg></choice> opinion.</s>
        <s>This opinion attracts the people a lot because in such <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> important theme <choice><orig>too</orig><reg>to</reg></choice> our economic, it's very <choice><orig>helpfull</orig><reg>helpful</reg></choice> to hear strict opinion so the reader, as he/she/it reads the title, has the hope of an answer for his question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This brings me to another aspect the headline is doing to the reader; with the style of asking a question and answering it directly and short the reader is connecting the headline to the whole text; so he/she/it thinks that the article after the promising headline is going to <choice><orig>answere</orig><reg>answer</reg></choice> all the questions very directly and shortly; so the article would be very extensive.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through the whole text the author confronts the reader with very drastic and controversial opinions, that he doesn't pack in a nice and kind bag; he just tells the reader very clear and extreme his opinion; so in l. 1 he is speaking from <quote>the best thing that ever happened</quote> and in the last line from <quote>one of the major contributions to the economic mess</quote> to the unions, which shows the change he talks about in the main part of this article.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The very extreme descriptions he is using for the situations is giving the reader a clear opinion and shows the big problem that is existing in the economy today.</s>
        <s>You can tell that he is really serious, because the way he says this and how he exaggerates the facts to really give the reader an impression.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover you can see that the reader used both descriptions in the first and in the last line so he <choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to show that the economy and unions have changed from the beginning follow like the text is starting and beginning.</s>
        <s>This point and <choice><orig>strategie</orig><reg>strategy</reg></choice> is very <choice><orig>helpfull</orig><reg>helpful</reg></choice> to really leave an impact to the readers, because he starts with reading that they <add>(the unions)</add> have been good and while reading the article he is changing his opinion and when the reader opinion has already changed because of the facts the author tells the reader, he is ending the text with such a strong statement, that stays in your head.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another <choice><orig>strategie</orig><reg>strategy</reg></choice> to take the distance away is the personal statement in line five, where <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Pollard</ref> talks about his own mistakes and experiences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that a theme like economy and unions isn't as easy as social themes to take the reader in, so he needs their personal stage to keep the reader reading and not stopping to read because the text and its facts are seeming boring and hard to understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 2-4 you can find an enumeration that helps the author to show the reader the urgency of change in the economy and the atmosphere has been <quote>workers need protection from being mistreated, better working conditions, shorter working days and higher wages</quote> is showing that essentials are missing and that it's very much that have had to change when the unions were founded there the enumeration is used in a positive context: <quote>the unions helped with that!</quote> is the message the reader is reading.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line eight you can find another enumeration with the same content in it, but this time <quote>good working conditions, good wages and safe working environment</quote> is getting talks about in a bad context, because in this part of the text he talks about how the unions aren't helping anymore.</s>
        <s>With this method he is creating a strong contrast, that is very impressing for the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But that hasn't been it, in the further lines of the paragraph <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="line">(l. nine)</ref> he gives the reader a third enumeration that talks about which factors are regulating the things that were talked about in the first enumeration.</s>
        <s>This is also creating a contrast in a form of two enumerations.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line eleven <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Pollard</ref> is using the impression <quote>they have become victims of their own success</quote> to show how ironic the situation is and how absurd, that something that has been so <choice><orig>helpfull</orig><reg>helpful</reg></choice> with the protection is failing because of the success it has had.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The picture of the unhealthy <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> between the union and the employees is very strong emphasized with the expression in 18-20 <quote>workers are not exploited by employers, now employers are being exploited by employees</quote>, this shows another time how absurd the situation is <quote>that a project that should help the employees is now a project that made that another group needs help and that the situation has changed to the point where the employers need help</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Conclusional, you can say that the author uses a lot of strategies and stylistic devices to show the negative change of the unions and how they <choice><orig>effect</orig><reg>affect</reg></choice> our economy and themselves.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
