<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g13_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="title">Is the usefulness of unions in the protection of workers rights coming to an end? The answer is yes</ref> is about the <choice><orig>usefullness</orig><reg>usefulness</reg></choice> of unions in the protection of workers rights and in which the author <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> <choice><orig>try</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to bring their opinion against the union and against the big of a role they still have across to the reader.</s>
        <s>In the following I will analyze how the author tries to persuade the reader of his opinion and which stylist devices and communicative strategies the writer makes use of.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the headline of the article the author makes use of a question and directly <choice><orig>answer</orig><reg>answers</reg></choice> it <quote><qs>Is the usefulness [...] coming to an end?</qs><qs>The answer is yes</qs></quote> to speak directly to the reader to question this themself and to bring them right into the topic of the text.</s>
        <s>With the answer the writer makes his position clear right at the beginning what impacts the forming of the reader's opinion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With the line <quote>they have become victims of their own success</quote> <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> the author <choice><orig>use</orig><reg>uses</reg></choice> metaphorical language to show how <choice><orig>succes</orig><reg>success</reg></choice> is not always good and how fast <choice><orig>succes</orig><reg>success</reg></choice> is mistreated and in this case the unions the ended it also.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 15 the author <choice><orig>use</orig><reg>uses</reg></choice> the saying <quote>a noted drop in productivity</quote> to express how with the success the productivity and the work commitment of the unions suddenly dropped what was clearly <choice><orig>noticiball</orig><reg>noticeable</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The line <quote>workers are not being exploited by employers, now employers are being exploited by employees</quote> shows how the roles switched and how the original use and mission is not there anymore and to express the power of the unions, which the governments have given them.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
