<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b11l28_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion a revive of a relationship depends on two factos: 1) it depends on how great the bond or connection between the two partners really is.</s>
        <s>2) how big the time gap between the end of the relationship and the revive is, as it is normally for humans to lose feelings for somebody or something after a certain time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If you look at <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> one can see that <choice><orig>espacially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> still has this <choice><orig>extrem</orig><reg>extreme</reg></choice> bond to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, because he remembered the exact time when they have last seen each other.</s>
        <s>In addition the exaggerated positivity of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, as well as his <choice><orig>embarassment</orig><reg>embarrassment</reg></choice> show that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> still loves <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> the same as before.</s>
        <s>On the other hand <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> didn't remember the exact time they have last seen each other, but she felt the same embarrassment as <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> during their encounter.</s>
        <s>These facts indicate that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> bond to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is way bigger than hers to him as he obviously didn't get over her which gets underlined by him being single.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> on the other hand probably got over <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> as she primarily is married to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref> due to his wealth and secondarily being surprised in one of the first scenes where <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Jordan</ref> mentions <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, shows that she didn't think about him before.</s>
        <s>In conclusion to their situation one can say that on an emotional stage their chances of getting back together are quiet low, due to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> missing <choice><orig>empathie</orig><reg>empathy</reg></choice> and bond for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, but as <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> just cares about wealth and status which her toxic marriage with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref> shows, she could get attracted by <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> wealth and his dedication for her.</s>
        <s>To summarize everything that has been stated so far, I would say that their chances for a revive of their past relationship are quiet low.</s>
        <s>In comparison to a revival of a relationship in general one could say that the chances are equally low, but the normal reason for a break up is an emotional conflict, which was not the case with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> as they broke up because <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> left to the army.</s>
        <s>In conclusion one can say that normally a revival of a past relationship is just possible if both parntners are still attracted or reattract to the <choice><orig>partners</orig><reg>partner's</reg></choice> character, but in the case of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is still attracted to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> character, but <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> would be attracted to him as well, if she wouldn't be seeking for status and wealth which overshadow her true emotions for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
