<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l20_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt shows a complete different side of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> character.</s>
        <s>His usual ease and confidence is vanished and instead he is nervous and portrayed as inconfident and a shell of a man.</s>
        <s>But through the excerpt he finds out something that makes him switch back to his old-self.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The unconfident and nervous characterism of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> in the chapter is firstly portrayed by his description: <quote>Gatsby, pale as death</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84 l. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The pictural description gives his suffering more importance and <choice><orig>depics</orig><reg>depicts</reg></choice> him as even more <choice><orig>misreable</orig><reg>miserable</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His worry that the meeting will not go as planned and his helplessness is also <choice><orig>mirrowed</orig><reg>mirrored</reg></choice> in his behaviour as he is: <quote>turning sharply as if he were on a wire</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 18)</ref> and talking in a muttered voice or little at all <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 3)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To contrast <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> behaviour furthermore <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="author">Fitzgerald</ref> adds words such as <quote>an abortive attempt at a laugh</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 4)</ref> or: <quote>trembling fingers</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>All those detailed descriptions of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> unusual mannerism and characterism are used to contrast it to his usual-self even more.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Outside of this excerpt <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is portrayed as a confident and <choice><orig>independant</orig><reg>independent</reg></choice> man, who loves to show off his belongings and his wealth.</s>
        <s><quote>They're real</quote><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 47, l. 16)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Although you can tell that the opinion of others about himself matter to him a lot: <quote>What's your opinion of me anyhow?</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 64, ll. 21-22)</ref> he is usually more reserved and in a calm distance to everyone: <quote><s>But Gatsby was not there.</s><s>She couldn't find him from the top of the steps, and he wasn't on the veranda</s></quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 47, ll. 3-5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This behaviour is in a big contrast to his behaviour in the given excerpt.</s>
        <s>He needs <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Nicks</orig><reg>Nick's</reg></choice></ref> help and acts like a little boy <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 8)</ref> who has to cautiously plan his next moves.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is repeating himself over and over again: <quote>This is a terrible mistake [...] a terrible, terrible mistake</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, ll. 1-2)</ref> which furthermore stresses his unease and how he is overstretched.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To look into the contrast even more it is interesting to see how he usually acts very carelessnes with his belongings and the things he wants because he wants to be looked up to by everyone: <quote>he asked me my name and address - inside of a week I got a package from Crorrier's with a new evening gown in it</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 45, ll. 18-20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>On the other hand the excerpt shows how destined and desperate he is to win back <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>: <quote>Don't talk so loud</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The narrative perspective contributes to the awkwardness of the situation as well because it involves a lot of detailed description of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> nervous behaviour and the tense situation: <quote>However, as calmness wasn't and end in itself</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 25)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The little excerpts of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> impression of the situation and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> character further <choice><orig>depic</orig><reg>depict</reg></choice> a detailed picture of the setting and aura: <quote>I had them both on their feet with the desperate suggestion that they help me make a tea</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, ll. 19-20)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> narration makes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> seem even more like a helpless child: <quote>You're acting like a little boy, I broke out impatiently</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 8)</ref>, which is a big contrast as to how he usually describes or talks to him: <quote><s>He smiled understandingly - much more than understandingly.</s><s>It was one of those rare smiles with a quality of eternal reassurance in it</s></quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 49, ll. 32-33)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Another contribution to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> flustered behaviour is the setting.</s>
        <s>The way the rain is very strong and increasingly loud when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> arrives till the moment <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> finds the two of them talking on the sofa, could <choice><orig>mirrow</orig><reg>mirror</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> inner feelings and his nervousness.</s>
        <s>As soon as <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> describes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> as: <quote><s>But there was a change in <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> that was simply confounding.</s><s>He literally glowed</s></quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, ll. 13-14)</ref>, it is mentioned that it had stopped raining and the sun came out: <quote>that there were twinkle-bells of sunshine in the room</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, ll. 19-20)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This change back to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> usual behaviour happens suddenly and because of the narrative perspective without the reader knowing.</s>
        <s>To add to the change, the description becomes much more positive than the miserable descriptions <choice><orig>bevore</orig><reg>before</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> came back into the house: <quote>he smiled like a weather man, like an ecstatic patron of recurrent light</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, ll. 20-21)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> mannerism changes as well, which is visible through him calling <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> <quote>old sport</quote> again, which is typical of him <choice><orig>througout</orig><reg>throughout</reg></choice> the beginning of the novel <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He gains back his determination and confidence and orders the others around: <quote>I want you and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to come over to my house</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 25)</ref>.</s>
        <s>From <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> narrative perspective the reader does not know what happened in the living room when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> was outside.</s>
        <s>Furthermore this gives <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> back his <choice><orig>misteriourism</orig><reg>mysteriousness</reg></choice> that he usually carries around because people only know so little about him and which he lost for a moment by surprisingly oversharing his worries to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To come to an end it is clearly visible that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> goes through a big change in his behaviour because of his determination to win back <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>His desperation is unusual of him and his nervousness is conveyed through a lot of aspects and ways of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> narration.</s>
        <s>In addition the change back to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> usual character is a big factor as well.</s>
        <s>The reader is clueless about what the two of them were talking about and it makes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> even more unknown in a way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It also makes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> seem very easy to influence and not very strong in his own self.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
