<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l14_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Considering that this excerpt marks the point at which <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> reunite after almost five years of <choice><orig>seperation</orig><reg>separation</reg></choice>, it is very pertinent to the story as it evolves since <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> love for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is one of the main topics of the novel.</s>
        <s>To <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, being with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> means happiness and this is what he pursues, which this excerpt shows clearly.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, it reveals a side of him which is new to the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all, as <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> enter the living room, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> who has previously been there is gone to knock, just a second later, on the door in a light, dignified way <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is how the first-person-narrator <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>, from his viewpoint perspective describes it.</s>
        <s>That already shows that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> wants to keep his dignity in front of his beloved and impress her with his appearance, but the light slightly hints at his nervousness which makes him careful and hesitant to knock.</s>
        <s>He is obviously trying to overcome it.</s>
        <s>He could have, in fact, stayed in the living room and met <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> there directly, but he goes outside to come back in instead.</s>
        <s>It can be assumed he chose to do so rather than staying to rid himself of his nervousness and to become calmer.</s>
        <s>Whether this surprises <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> or not can't be said surely because he exaggerates his statement <quote>To my overwhelming surprise</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 9f.)</ref> so much that it seems ironic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> enters the house, he is <quote>pale as death</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 14)</ref> and is <quote>glaring tragically</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> into <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> eyes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore his hands are <quote>plunged like weights</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref> in his pockets which might be an attempt at trying to hide their shaking.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Comparing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> face with <choice><orig>dead</orig><reg>death</reg></choice> and thereby putting his actual appearance in a <foreign xml:lang="de">stark</foreign> contrast to his <quote>dignified knocking</quote> conveys how he is internally in turmoil whereas on the outside he is trying hard to remain calm and to control his emotions.</s>
        <s>However this seems exaggerated considering how it is simply a meeting with the woman he loves expecting him.</s>
        <s>Thus it reflects on just how anxious <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> must be.</s>
        <s>Since it has been long since they last met and she is now married, he might fear that she does not love him anymore and will refuse to speak to him.</s>
        <s>It shows his insecurity and the fragility of his self-confidence as well as of their bond.</s>
        <s>Given <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> reaction when they meet, she is thrown aback by the confrontation as well.</s>
        <s>For a while, the three of them are just feeling awkward, especially <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> although he is not really connected to their <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> at first, speaks in a <quote>clear artificial note</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 23)</ref> which makes her seem like the one who has better control over herself.</s>
        <s>It might as well be an attempt to gain time to think of a reaction.</s>
        <s>She remains seated while <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> tries to look calm and confident like the usual version of himself he shows at parties etc. e.g. by leaning against a shelve, hands in his pockets.</s>
        <s>He tries to laugh <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 4)</ref> but is <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> stiff to do so.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> do not know what to say, so he says something as trivial as <quote>I'm sorry about the clock</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 9)</ref> to overcome the awkwardness.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Again, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> steps in and remarks that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and her have not met for many years <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 15f.)</ref>, however due to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> she says it matter-of-factly.</s>
        <s>Thereby the reader can see it is hard for the two of them to open up which is probably due to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> presence.</s>
        <s>That is why he wants to leave when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> takes him into the kitchen to talk in private and lets his emotions out <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 30f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Upon realizing through <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> telling him, that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is just as nervous and embarassed as him <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is surprised.</s>
        <s>Not realizing that others feel the same way as oneself is usually something that occurs with immature, young persons.</s>
        <s>However <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> has behaved quite mature up until now, although it seemed staged especially when he told <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> about his past.</s>
        <s>It furthermore signifies that a person is only focused on herself and does not pay attention to others.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> has even been observing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> for a while from a <quote>shadow</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 23)</ref> while they have been talking, looking very unpleased <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 85, l. 24-25)</ref>.</s>
        <s>And yet he did not notice <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> embarassment.</s>
        <s>Hence he must have been absent-minded.</s>
        <s>Thus when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> tells him about it and he <quote>repeated incredulously</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 5)</ref> that she is embarassed, it seems as if he is awakening from a trance.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> becomes impatient and tells him he behaves childish which makes him come to his senses at last.</s>
        <s>The image of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> draws here is that of a childish, insecure and immature man with a lot of wealth and love for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>He is behaving like a teenager on a first date which stands significantly in contrast to the image created of him before and immediately after meeting him.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> then leaves them alone and when he returns, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> situation has become much better.</s>
        <s>He has gone through a change which <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> illustrates really vividly.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref><quote>new well-being radiated from him and filled the little room</quote><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 ll. 5f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The imagery used here is such a vivid description that it makes him vibrant to the reader and one can feel what is being described here.</s>
        <s>At first glance it might be assumed that he seems like his old self again but if you look closer, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is now even more vibrant and happy <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> before.</s>
        <s>This side of him is only made visible thanks to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> appearance since she is what he has been pursuing.</s>
        <s>Anyhow, he is paying less attention to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> now, greeting him as if he hadn't seen him in a long time thus as if he had completely forgotten about him <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 87 l. 16)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> tells <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> the weather has become better, she responds <quote>I'm glad, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Jay</ref></quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>, but looking at her emotional state she must mean their reunion rather than the weather.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, calling him by his surname <quote>Jay</quote> indicates their intimate relationship.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The antithesis <quote>Her throat, full of aching, grieving beauty told only of her unexpected joy</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 l. 23f.)</ref>, shows <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> sudden burst of contradictory emotions.</s>
        <s>On the one side, there is the accumulation <quote>aching, grieving</quote> along with the personification of her beauty which tells of her pain and makes her come <choice><orig>alife</orig><reg>alive</reg></choice> to reader.</s>
        <s>On the other side, there is joy which is positive.</s>
        <s>Thus in this case, her pain is connotated positively and shows the hardships <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> has endured alone with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref>, <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> from <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s>Yet it was her decision not to wait for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Eventually, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> wants to take <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to see his house.</s>
        <s>Here there is a hint at his deceptive, bragful side.</s>
        <s>He wants to impress <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> with his wealth to win her back.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though due to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> viewpoint perspective one <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> take his narration as objection and factbased, it is not bad to have him as narrator here.</s>
        <s>The author deliberately uses vivid, impressionistic descriptions to give a somewhat tangible impression of what is happening rather than objective reality which could seem too dry.</s>
        <s>That way he is able to characterize <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> so detailed and comprehensible, especially at the end.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is first displayed as immature and insecure, then, however, as glowing, vibrant and content.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
