<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l29_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is really nervous about the visit from <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and firstly reveals his insecurities in front of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>.</s>
        <s>But in the excerpt is a change of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> character and he seems truly happy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Right in the beginning of the excerpt the reader gets an impression how nervous <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is, because of the meeting with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>The author makes clear how hard it is for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> to meet <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, because he is so scared.</s>
        <s>He underlines this with the comparison <quote>with his hands plunged like weights</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 15)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> even tries to escape the situation and changes rooms to not see <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 18f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows how much <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> means to him and how important it is for him, what <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> thinks about him.</s>
        <s>But <choice><orig>eventhough</orig><reg>even though</reg></choice> he is so nervous, he acts calm and <choice><orig>disintressed</orig><reg>disinterested</reg></choice> in front of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This reveals his character because it shows that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> creates a certain picture of himself in front of other people.</s>
        <s>This aspect combines the character of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> in the previous chapters, where he is described at his own parties.</s>
        <s>It shows that he is not throwing the parties to enjoy an evening with his friends, but to show the people that he is able to throw parties like that and to show off his house and wealth.</s>
        <s>This also creates a picture of him, as a <choice><orig>powerfull</orig><reg>powerful</reg></choice> and rich man.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> also enjoys the feeling of power in this excerpt.</s>
        <s>He seems less nervous when he <quote>stared down at <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref></quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 30f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows how insecure he really is, because he needs the power over other people to feel confident.</s>
        <s>His insecurity is also revealed when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> wants to leave the room and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> alone.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> follows him and opens up to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>, how nervous and scared he is.</s>
        <s>His desperation is underlined with the repeat of the word <quote>terrible mistake</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 1f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The narrator points out how silly <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> acts, because he is really nervous but creates this <choice><orig>disintressed</orig><reg>disinterested</reg></choice> picture in front of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>He compares him with <quote>a little boy</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 8)</ref> and tells him that he is also acting rude <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this excerpt <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is not able to overplay his insecurities with his power of being a rich man and showing off his money.</s>
        <s>In previous chapters he does not seem so nervous and insecure because he mostly shows the other people how wealthy he is, what makes him feel self-confident.</s>
        <s>In this excerpt the author shows <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> in a situation, where he is not surrounded by things that make him look rich and give him power, in order to reveal his insecurities and show how materialistic he really is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The absurdity of the situation is underlined when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> leaves the house and goes in the garden.</s>
        <s>From there he can see <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> <quote>enormous house</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 19)</ref> and all the people that work for him.</s>
        <s>This picture of a <choice><orig>powerfull</orig><reg>powerful</reg></choice> and rich man, who owns this is put in contrast to his behavior before and shows that this is just a shell.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> comes back in the house the atmosphere has completely changed.</s>
        <s><quote>Every verstige of <choice><orig>embarassment</orig><reg>embarrassment</reg></choice> was gone</quote><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 10f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This change is also provoked by the change of weather <quote>It's stopped raining</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Rain conveys this feeling of an uncomfortable situation and with the ending of the rain the situation also gets more comfortable and changes in a positive way.</s>
        <s>The contrast between rain and <quote>sunshine</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 20)</ref> underlines the change of the situation.</s>
        <s>This positive change is also portrayed in <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s><quote>He literally glowed</quote><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The use of the comparison <quote>like an estatic patron of recurrent light</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 21)</ref> contributes to this positive picture of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> in this moment.</s>
        <s>The change of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> character shows how much <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> means to him and how her presence influences <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> in a positive way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion the scene reveals a lot about <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> character.</s>
        <s>He seems really insecure and tries to overplay that by creating the picture of being a <choice><orig>powerfull</orig><reg>powerful</reg></choice> and rich man.</s>
        <s>This shell is taken down by <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> seems to really enjoy a moment for the first time in the novel.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
