<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l27_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt is a key moment of the novel.</s>
        <s>It also shows the so <choice><orig>mystereous</orig><reg>mysterious</reg></choice>, self confident and also very brave man <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, in a very different way.</s>
        <s>In a scared, embarrassed almost a little childish way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To start <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> I will talk about the weather which plays a very important role in this excerpts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> first enters the house and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> went outside the weather is very bad.</s>
        <s>This is connected to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> emotions because <choice><orig>hes</orig><reg>he's</reg></choice> scared of meeting <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> after all these years.</s>
        <s>He is scared of what her reaction to him is and whether she feels the same as him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> were outside for some time and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy's</ref> goes very well the weather clears up and it shows the relief and <choice><orig>hapiness</orig><reg>happiness</reg></choice> of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, l. 28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The sun even starts shining which is a generally known sign for good mood and <choice><orig>hapiness</orig><reg>happiness</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The weather also shows the tension of the <choice><orig>excert</orig><reg>excerpt</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The rain keeps getting worse <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 20)</ref> until it is clear that they both are happy to see each other again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Next I will talk about the clock a symbol for the past.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> who had a relationship with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> a long time ago wishes for nothing more than to get <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> back and in some way get the past back or make it his future.</s>
        <s>When the tension is the highest and the conversaton dried out <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> throws the clock down by <choice><orig>excident</orig><reg>accident</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Luckily he catches it without it breaking.</s>
        <s>In this moment it is not yet clear <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> it is going good or bad and that clock which represents the past and the future almost breaks because in this moment <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> life goal or plan to get <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> back could now break and all the effort of the parties and everything he did to get her back could have been just pointless.</s>
        <s>Furthermore his future life with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> could not work out.</s>
        <s>In the end though the meeting goes very well that is why the clock does not break neither does his future plans nor all the things he did and their relationship in the past.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The way <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is described throughout the excerpt changes.</s>
        <s>In the beginning he is being described as <quote>pale as death</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 14)</ref>, <quote>hands plunged like weights</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 15)</ref> and it is said that he looks at <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> in a tragically way <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>These metaphors are all signs for how scared he really is.</s>
        <s>Furthermore they present him in a very different way as in the rest of the book where he is self confident, talkative way.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then when the conversation dries out he stops taking part of it, showed by the metaphor <quote>got himself in the shadow</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This behaviour also does not fit his character.</s>
        <s>Also he seems to be unhappy with how it is going <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 25)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The switch in how <choice><orig>hes</orig><reg>he's</reg></choice> <choice><orig>describes</orig><reg>descibred</reg></choice> comes after <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> enters the house again when their conversation seemed to have been going great and the great relief comes over <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He being described with metaphors like <quote>glowing</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Futhermore</orig><reg>Furthermore</reg></choice> the <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> as we know him is back as he is confident and happy again.</s>
        <s>He even invites them over to his mansion.</s>
        <s>You can really tell how enthusiastic he is by the way he greets <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> and how it is described by an exaggeration <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 l. 16)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To come to an end we really get to know a different side of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s>Moreover we see that this great man also has a soft childish and scared side.</s>
        <s>This really gives the reader a deeper insight into <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> character.</s>
        <s>That and because it is the first meeting of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and the tension which beautifully delivered make this excerpt a very important passage of the book and also one of my favorite ones.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
