<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The communicative strategy already starts with the title.</s>
        <s>The title contains a question that to most would almost seem rhetorical - <quote>of course unions are good!</quote> which is <choice><orig>emidiately</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> contradicted by a simple yes - <choice><orig>grabing</orig><reg>grabbing</reg></choice> attention, raising curiosity and setting an expectation.</s>
        <s>An expectation where the reader prejudges the article to be nonsense, since the expect it to speak against their views.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This is not what happens.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Instead the author tries to smooth into his argument in the lower half by talking about the historic benefits of unions.</s>
        <s>The <q>side</q> starts at <quote>pro union</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The next paragraph is more emotional and personal.</s>
        <s>The author uses personal speech and attempts to signalize that he was once like the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He furthers this emotional connection by using eyecatching keywords in this topic, such as <quote>greed</quote>, <quote>power</quote> and <quote>moral values</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <q>side</q> meanders towards the author, who now seems in the middle and very reasonable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now the ship has set sail.</s>
        <s>The examples he provided earlier were nearly all pro-union - <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>he</reg></choice> talked about the benefits of unions <quote>[...] because workers needed protection from being mistreated by employers and they also needed better working conditions, shorter working days and higher wages [...]</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(line 2-4)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>Unions no longer required [...] [for] good working conditions, good wages, and safe working environment</quote><ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(line 7-9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The same examples given earlier to paint a good picture of unions are now nullified.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With that positive view gone, the author now has free reign to present his arguments against unions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The repetition of <quote>because</quote> creates a simple and clear overview and supports his views, even though no data or objective measurements are presented.</s>
        <s>The previously gained legitimacy by pulling the <q>side</q> towards him, is now used to make his point.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This is finalized by the <q>turn-around</q> <add>(don't know the technical term)</add> <quote>workers are not being exploited by employers, now employers are being exploited by employees</quote> <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(line 17-18)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally the <q>side</q> is finally pulled to <q>anti-unions</q> by finger pointing them.</s>
        <s><quote>unions [...] are one of the major contributors to the economic mess that the world is in today</quote><ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(line 22-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This strategy of smoothing into his opinion and slowly convincing the reader and pulling their <q>side</q> from <q>pro-union</q> to the author to <q>anti-union</q> fulfils its purpose through apparent reason and arguments.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
