<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g01_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>On <date>24th of November 2011</date>, <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> published his <choice><orig>Oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> about <choice><orig>Unions</orig><reg>unions</reg></choice> in <name type="misc">The Gulf News</name>.</s>
        <s>In this publication he states that <quote>[...] workers are not being exploited by employers, now employers are being exploited by employees</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Though in my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> <choice><orig>thats</orig><reg>that's</reg></choice> not quite right.</s>
        <s>I'm gonna agree with <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian</ref> on one aspect, unions exploit their powers to get better working conditions.</s>
        <s>But <choice><orig>thats</orig><reg>that's</reg></choice> what unions are for.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Thats</orig><reg>That's</reg></choice> their purpose.</s>
        <s>Giving workers power to defend from corporations that would and will crush them if they can.</s>
        <s>Having a union to counter this creates a sort of balance.</s>
        <s>But focusing on current legislation, anyone who says that: <quote>Unions aren't needed because legislation does their job</quote>, think about who proposed and made these laws.</s>
        <s>Exactly, unions.</s>
        <s>And do you know what would go, if unions were gone?</s>
        <s>These exact worker rights.</s>
        <s>And no, <choice><orig>morale</orig><reg>moral</reg></choice> <choice><orig>wont</orig><reg>won't</reg></choice> prevent it, since humans have the tendency to put money over anything.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the publication, <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian</ref> also talks about employers being exploited by workers.</s>
        <s>This is not true since many higher-ups, like managers, still live decent <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>There are even many cases still around, where workers still get exploited by <choice><orig>Managers</orig><reg>managers</reg></choice> for the sake of money, like <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> or <name type="geo">Pakistan</name>.</s>
        <s>The only real case, where workers exploited employers was the <name type="geo">USSR</name> and <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> puppet states, where everything was nationalized and run by state-owned-unions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some people say that unions are a blockade in the way to success for companies because they destroy competitiveness.</s>
        <s>However they are not.</s>
        <s>They can't.</s>
        <s>They are still a part of the company.</s>
        <s>If the company fails, they also do so.</s>
        <s>Therefore they can't afford to endlessly raise <choice><orig>waiges</orig><reg>wages</reg></choice> and give every worker a free <name type="misc">Porsche</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Companies with unions also don't get outperformed by companies without.</s>
        <s>The steel market is a good example.</s>
        <s>Even the European steel manufacturers were one of the first <choice><orig>Employers</orig><reg>employers</reg></choice> to even allow unions, they are still one of the biggest producers on the market.</s>
        <s>The only two competitors are the <name type="geo">USA</name>, which has unions and decent working conditions, and <name type="geo">China</name>, which has no unions, workers are exploited and working conditions are terrible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The only case where no-union-manufacturers outperform pro-union-manufacturers is the textile and <choice><orig>garmement</orig><reg>garment</reg></choice> sector.</s>
        <s>But this is a good example of how low working conditions have to be <surplus>to be</surplus> able to outperform a pro-union-company.</s>
        <s>Incentive for workers also still exists, though not through fear of <choice><orig>Job</orig><reg>job</reg></choice> loss, but through higher pay.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
