<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g05_t4</author>
        <name>magazine</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution report">magazine</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey guys,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Im</orig><reg>I'm</reg></choice> an exchange student from <name type="geo">Germany</name> and today I will be talking about fast fashion.</s>
        <s>If you look at the label of your t-shirt you will most likely find a tag, that says <quote>made in Bangladesh</quote>, but what is the textile industry and the atmosphere there like?</s>
        <s><name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> as a whole is in a terrible condition.</s>
        <s>Rivers are <choice><orig>poluted</orig><reg>polluted</reg></choice> and poisoned, because textile factories throw their garbage in the rivers which leads to the water being black and dirty and people are living in junk.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The employees work ten to twelve hours a day and only get a 10 minutes break every two hours.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Most of the workers are proud of what they're doing, most likely because they don't even know how bad their working conditins really are.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now you might ask yourself, how you can help the workers and how to buy more sustainable fashion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The expert <name type="person">Imke Müller-Hellmann</name> states not buying from <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> isn't the right <choice><orig>soludition</orig><reg>solution</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This would take the <choice><orig>workers</orig><reg>workers'</reg></choice> only source of income, instead the big <choice><orig>companys</orig><reg>companies</reg></choice> which are treating their workers poorly, should be exposed and held accountable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also the politicians should focus more on the working conditions and check them regularly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you all are now more aware how much fast fashion affects the workers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See you next time!</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
