<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a10g06_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="title">Is the usefulness of unions coming to an end? sThe answer is yes</ref> written by <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> and published in <name type="misc">The Gulf News</name> on <date>24 November, 2011</date> mentions that the unions do not protect the workers rights anymore <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The author says that unions were the best thing that happened to the labour movement because unions were successful in giving a better working environment and a higher wage to <surplus>to</surplus> the workers <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1-4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He thinks that unions are more about power and greed now.</s>
        <s>Unions are not required to make the workers feels safe anymore since the laws as well as our moral values decide and regulate these factors <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7-9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Another thing that the author points out is that the unions are against the competition between companies <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10-11)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Their products or services are also a lot more expensive that cheaper competitors can easily take their place <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The author says that nowadays employers are being exploited by employees and the fact that unions have become more powerful than their employers <choice><orig>creates</orig><reg>create</reg></choice> an unhealthy business environment <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 17-19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Lastly he mentions that the unions are at fault when it comes to the economic mess the world is in <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 21-23)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
