<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g06_t4</author>
        <name>magazine</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>My article is based on the <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> interview <ref target="a10gk1_2" type="title">Fast Fashion: Unser Kleiderkonsum ist Wahnsinn</ref> which is about buying clothes and the story behind the clothes that we buy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the interview it is mentioned that one of the worst situations that he ever came across to the textile sector was the water source <name type="misc">Buriganga</name> in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> which is completely black and full with plastic because there are a lot of fabrics in the area and all of the trash, plastic that comes out of the fabrics flow straight into the water.</s>
        <s>It is also mentioned that the workers that work in the textile fabrics of <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> work for 10-12 hours a day which is a lot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The people in <name type="geo">China</name> for example are happy and proud when they are able to produce 300 <choice><orig>Boxershorts</orig><reg>boxers</reg></choice> per hour which is quite tragic because it means that they barely get any time to rest.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the interview it is mentioned that protesting isn't a solution since that would make the people lose their jobs and income.</s>
        <s>Instead we should try to help them by trying to make their work conditions better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly the politics have to change and start put more pressure on companies.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
