<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g04_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>Author</orig><reg>author</reg></choice> is smart.</s>
        <s>This is a fact.</s>
        <s>A fact you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> ignore.</s>
        <s>He is smart while getting us, getting us to an opinion we had not support, maybe not even know.</s>
        <s>And the way how he does this starts right at the beginning.</s>
        <s>He starts with giving the reader a taste, a taste of his opponents?</s>
        <s>No, he is giving a taste of what unions can be, what they have been.</s>
        <s>With this he gives us the feeling that we have to fight back to stop the development of unions.</s>
        <s>So he convinced us after 4 lines, without telling us his currently opinion.</s>
        <s>We are getting so obsessed with the old versions of unions by he is using <choice><orig>positevely</orig><reg>positively</reg></choice> connoted words to let the old unions stand in a favourable light.</s>
        <s>Examples are <quote>unions were successful in bringing these essential changes</quote> in line 4.</s>
        <s>After the first part, while talking about <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> unions, he is switching his communicative strategy to negatively connoted words to show the usefulness of <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> unions.</s>
        <s>Examples for this are <choice><orig>phrase</orig><reg>phrases</reg></choice> like <quote>Unions are anticompetitiveness</quote> in line 10 to 11.</s>
        <s>But his mainly used communicative strategy in the body part are <choice><orig>ironys</orig><reg>irony</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a10gk1_1" type="author">Pollard</ref> is using them to bring the reader to ask himself or herself is this not the exact reason why unions should provide and not do.</s>
        <s>But he does not mean this as an irony he is meaning this serious with all his authority.</s>
        <s>Examples for the <choice><orig>ironys</orig><reg>irony</reg></choice> are <quote>Today unions are obstructing companies</quote> in line 10.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>means's</orig><reg>means</reg></choice> unions are slowing down the growth of the company, even though it is in the <choice><orig>employees</orig><reg>employees'</reg></choice> will that the company is growing.</s>
        <s>The last sentences should give the reader the feeling of we and the government are supposed to do something.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
