<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g06_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to comment on whether the unions really do protect the workers rights or not based on the article <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="title">Is the usefulness of unions coming to an end? The answer is yes</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all it is true that in the past the unions helped to protect the employers from being mistreated but even though they managed to make a change at that time they are not ensuring that the workers have a safe work environment anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nowadays they are more focused on obstructing <choice><orig>companies</orig><reg>companies'</reg></choice> abilities to compete or produce expensive products.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have to admit that there are a lot of cases where the workers are still being exploited by their employers especially in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name>.</s>
        <s>With that being said, I do not agree with the statement that employers are being exploited by the employees when it is clearly the other way around <ref target="a10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 17-18)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum it all up I do agree with the author that the unions are not as useful as they used to be.</s>
        <s>But I do not think that the workers are exploiting their employers <choice><orig>esspecially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> since there are still a lot of workers who work under terrible working conditions.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
