<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l16_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The excerpt at hand dealing with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> reunion after so many years is very crucial for an understanding of the complexity of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> characteristics.</s>
        <s>The excerpt reveals <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> character at its purest and most revealing, because he does not and also cannot put up and act, to the extent like he normally does.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> characteristic stages can be divided into two stages, <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> by <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> leaving him and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to themselves in his livingroom.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first impression of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> that you have in this excerpt, is that he seems to be <choice><orig>extremly</orig><reg>extremely</reg></choice> nervous and scared of the situation.</s>
        <s>He is described to <quote>glare tragically</quote> into <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> eyes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84 ll. 16)</ref>, which shows how helpless and scared he is in that situation.</s>
        <s>The fact that he went out of the backdoor only to come in again as if he hasn't been waiting for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> the whole afternoon <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 84 ll. 13-15)</ref> implies how nervous he must be, but also shows again how absurdly desperaet he is to keep up a certain, unphased image of himself.</s>
        <s>This is something which the whole excerpt really sheds light on the contrast between how he's presented in the previous chapters to this excerpt.</s>
        <s>Normally <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> keeps up a <choice><orig>fassade</orig><reg>facade</reg></choice>, a certain image of himself, by his <choice><orig>extremly</orig><reg>extremely</reg></choice> careful self-presentation.</s>
        <s>In this excerpt he is more vulnerable and real.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When first meeting <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> tries to seem relaxed and not phased, as he puts his hands in his pocket in a <quote>strained counterfeit of perfect ease</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 27-28)</ref>, which means that he tries so hard to seem relaxed, that it's clearly visible that he is in fact not relaxed, but very nervous and stressed.</s>
        <s>His <quote>attempt at a laugh</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85)</ref> shows now he is trying to ease the awkwardness and the embarrassment of the situation, which does not work as well.</s>
        <s>Afterwards he replies way too fast and explicit to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Daisys</orig><reg>Daisy's</reg></choice></ref> more <choice><orig>rethoric</orig><reg>rhetoric</reg></choice> statement about how long they hadn't seen each other with the <choice><orig>excat</orig><reg>exact</reg></choice> year and months <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85 ll. 15-17)</ref>, which again shows how he is everything but relaxed and gives a hint to the literal obsession that he has with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>It becomes clear how insecure and miserable <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> really is in the situation, when he speaks to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> with the expression <quote>Oh, God!</quote>, which shows that he knows that the situation is awkward.</s>
        <s>He says that the reunion was a <quote>terrible mistake</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86 l. 1)</ref>, the <choice><orig>repitition</orig><reg>repetition</reg></choice> of the word terrible underlines his own image here, that he doesn't even notice that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> clearly isn't relaxed as well <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86 ll. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This talk of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> marks a change in the excerpt.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> goes out to the gardens after that and when he comes up the situation seems to be drastically different.</s>
        <s>The most striking features of the conversation before, the <choice><orig>embarrasment</orig><reg>embarrassment</reg></choice> and the awkwardness seem to have vanished <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 ll. 10-11)</ref>.</s>
        <s>While <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> has a teary face, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> seems like he is completely changed.</s>
        <s>While the first stage of him was characterized by insecurity, vulnerability and nervousness it is now the complete other way around.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> describes that <quote>a new wellbeing radiated from him</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 ll. 15)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> seems as if he was reborn, like a new person <add> - in a positive way</add>.</s>
        <s>He seems so changed, that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> wouldn't have wondered if he reintroduced himself to him <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86 ll. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>You can see that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> gained some of his self-control back by him using the expression <quote>old sport</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 ll. 16)</ref> again, which he's always used in the previous chapters, but not in his nervousness before meeting <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is so dazed and <choice><orig>reliefed</orig><reg>relieved</reg></choice> and happy, that he hasn't even noticed the change in the weather <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 87 ll. 18-19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His smile has also come back <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 87 ll. 20)</ref>, which effects <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> has discussed in previous chapters already.</s>
        <s>But <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> hasn't forgotten about the image which he wants <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to have of him; he still wants to show off his wealth to impress her, so he invites both of them, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>, to his mansion to show them around <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 87 ll. 25-26)</ref>, even though he knows, that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> has been at his house before.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Looking at the narrative perspective, there are some interesting elements which contribute to the way <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is characterized.</s>
        <s>One of them is the use of the symbol of the weather throughout the excerpt.</s>
        <s>It is interesting to see that when the situation between <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is still awkward by and he is still in his <q>first stage</q>, there are many descriptions of the rainy weather <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 86 ll. 16, p. 84 ll. 14-15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>When the situation has changed and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is in his <q>second stage</q> of positive feelings, the weather has changed without him noticing, now the room is full of sunshine <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 87 ll. 20)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another narrative technique that was used in chapter two as well, is <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> just leaving out parts of situations by either just not mentioning them or as in this excerpt, leaving the scene.</s>
        <s>So when the first person narrator leaves the scene, you obviously can't know what is happening in the time away.</s>
        <s>This is what <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> did when he went out <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 86 ll. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>We can only imagine what <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> talked about and what led to her crying and his drastic change in character.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is described more and that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> talks to him more than to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, so we know more of his thoughts is important for our impression of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> as well.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> could have seemed way more nervous, if <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> had talked to her more are described her more.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> also describes how <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> almost destroys a clock <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(see p. 85 ll. 5-8)</ref> which has very symbolic meaning of trying to turn back time for him and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The setting is also crucial in this scene looking at <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s>We know from the previous chapters that in his mansion, amongst all of his expensive things, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> feels secure and untouchable.</s>
        <s>His normal surroundings are a constant reminder, that he made it and that all of his wealth stands for him.</s>
        <s>In the setting in the excerpt though he has to stand for himself.</s>
        <s>As it takes place in <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> living room, which looks rather basic, the only thing that can make an impression is himself and his character.</s>
        <s>That makes him even more nervous, which is why he really wants <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to come over to his house to see him in all of his glory and wealth and to prove to her that he has become the very thing, that she wanted him to all these years ago.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion you can see that in this chapter one can finally get to know the real <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, not only his <choice><orig>fassade</orig><reg>facade</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It shows, that behind all of his wealth, he is a very vulnerable and insecure person, who <choice><orig>desperatly</orig><reg>desperately</reg></choice> wants validation from <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>Both presented sides of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> the negative and positive feelings are the first real and not controlled or calculated actions of him.</s>
        <s>The reunion with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is so significant, that he loses his most important <choice><orig>feautre</orig><reg>feature</reg></choice>, his extreme self-control.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
