<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l23_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given excerpt the reader is introduced to a new side of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> in which he shows an <choice><orig>unsual</orig><reg>unusual</reg></choice> and non expected behaviour.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is uneasy and scared because of his meeting with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, the love of his life, after 5 years.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> firstly shows up in this excerpt he seems like a new man.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> describes him as <quote>pale as death</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 14)</ref>, his hands are in his pockets, his posture is limp which shows that he is unsure of himself <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84 l. 14ff.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When they enter, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> doesn't talk or only in very short sentences, he doesn't look at <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and his nervousness shows <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84 l. 21  p. 85 l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He sits <choice><orig>stifly</orig><reg>stiffly</reg></choice> on the sofa and all three of them feel <choice><orig>embaressed</orig><reg>embarrassed</reg></choice> but support the <choice><orig>akward</orig><reg>awkward</reg></choice> silence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>No one really starts a conversation and one can feel that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> does not know how to act around <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His uncertainty and <choice><orig>embarressement</orig><reg>embarrassment</reg></choice> probably also make <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> feel uneasy and <choice><orig>embarressed</orig><reg>embarrassed</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene has an odd touch and it seems like two teenagers sit in the same room and do not know how to act around each other because they do not know how the other person feels.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> also realizes this and says this to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> after he pulled <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> aside when he wanted to leave <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85 l. 26 - p. 86 l. 9)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this conversation <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> reveals that he regrets his plan and thinks that he is making a mistake <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86 l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He almost panics because not everything works the way he wanted it to.</s>
        <s>For him, his behaviour is probably also something he does not usually do and maybe he even feels like he does not know himself.</s>
        <s>His nervousness and fear overwhelm him and keep him from talking to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> tells <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> that his behaviour is rude and that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> also feels <choice><orig>embarressed</orig><reg>embarrassed</reg></choice>, he listens and reenters the room more confident <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86 l. 3-12)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> is outside we don't know how the situation inside goes on but when he reenters there is a complete dynamic change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even though <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is crying, the situation is more relaxed and not so tense and <choice><orig>akward</orig><reg>awkward</reg></choice> anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is more quiet but <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is his old self again.</s>
        <s>He is excited, happy and calls <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> by his nickname <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 l. 11-16)</ref> again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There is no sign of the nervous almost childish and <choice><orig>embarressed</orig><reg>embarrassed</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s>A talk between him and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> made him relax and shake off his unsureness.</s>
        <s>He becomes the man he was in the previous chapters again and is now ready to make the next step.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He wants to show <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> his house with his belonging so she knows how rich he is and what he could offer her <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 l. 25)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By this he hopes to win her back so they can start a new life together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> describes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> as glowing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 l. 14)</ref> and his happiness transmits to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> even though she hasn't fully recovered.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> behaviour in this scene especially in the beginning is <choice><orig>extremly</orig><reg>extremely</reg></choice> different compared to his behaviour in the rest of the book.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Usually he is very mysterious and does not reveal <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> much about himself.</s>
        <s>Whenever he can he shows off how wealthy and rich he is.</s>
        <s>Towards <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> he is more open, very talkative and seems like he wants to impress him <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 63-65)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In general he doesn't really show other emotions than happiness which is why it is uncommon that he acts so nervously.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His weird and unusual behaviour is based on <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> or to be more clearly on his meeting with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>He waited for a very long time, his expectations are high and when he sees her for the first time again it is natural that he reacts they way he does.</s>
        <s>Moreover <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> behaviour also suprises <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>.</s>
        <s>He only knows the rich, sure of himself and mysterious <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this chapter a new side is being introduced to the reader as well as <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>.</s>
        <s>The uncertainty of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> transmits to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>, makes him feel uncomfortable and that is why he wants to leave.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A big important part is being left out because we only see the situation through <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Nicks</orig><reg>Nick's</reg></choice></ref> eyes and he decided to go outside.</s>
        <s>This leaves <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> as well as the reader with the question what <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> could have possibly talked about so that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> mood completely changed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To come to a conclusion, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Gatsbys</orig><reg>Gatsby's</reg></choice></ref> behaviour shows that he is madly in love with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> but firstly is unsure of her feelings, which makes him feel nervous and uncertain.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After a long talk, he and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> were able to think about their past.</s>
        <s>Something in this conversation made him relax and gave him hope as well as safety.</s>
        <s>He is now able to become his old self again and do what his plan was in the first place.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
