<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l25_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, who is described as a dishonest and vulgar person but also optimistic by <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> in previous chapters, is characterized in this excerpt as nervous and totally <choice><orig>unsecure</orig><reg>insecure</reg></choice> about his actions <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86 ll. 1-2)</ref> when he says <quote>This is a terrible mistake, a terrible, terrible mistake</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His <choice><orig>nervousity</orig><reg>nervousness</reg></choice> can also be seen, when he runs around the <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> house, just to enter from the front door and not be standing in the living room, when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy Buchanan</ref> enters.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His desperation to impress <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> only be seen in that action, but also when he says <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87 ll. 25-26)</ref> <quote>I want you and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to come over to my house, I'd like to show her around</quote>.</s>
        <s>Since we knew from previous chapters, that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> house is enormous and really luxurious, he asks for the favor to show them around so he can impress <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref><choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> life is about impressing others.</s>
        <s>The big parties he throws, where none of the guests know him, his car, his suits and also his <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> appearance.</s>
        <s>This urge to impress comes from him losing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom Buchanan</ref>, after being called up for the <name type="misc">First World War</name>.</s>
        <s>He mentioned that to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>, when both were sitting together in the car <quote><qs>Then came the war, old sport.</qs><qs>It was a great relief and I tried very hard to die, but I seemed to bear an enchanted life</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 65 ll. 23-24)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This wish for death came from having to leave <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>Who he <choice><orig>thougth</orig><reg>thought</reg></choice>, he lost forever, his desire for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> is show all over the novel.</s>
        <s>Him watching the green light, him throwing big parties and him asking <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> to arrange a reunion, even wanting to pay him so he arranges it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> who first appears as a person kept to himself, does everything to get <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> back.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="author">F. Scott Fitzgerald</ref> shows us this through <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> first person narration.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> who says he is a non <choice><orig>judgemental</orig><reg>judgmental</reg></choice> person, puts a lot of <choice><orig>judgments</orig><reg>judgements</reg></choice> on <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> like him being dishonest, but also tries to band himself to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> with a friendship of some kind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the excerpt, all the impressions we get of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and how they might feel we get from <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref>.</s>
        <s>Of who the reader already knows is a dishonest narrator, who doesn't <choice><orig>tells</orig><reg>tell</reg></choice> everything and leaves out details, for example the lever scene <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 39 ll. 25-31)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> character is described a nervous but also extremely joyful person after <choice><orig>seening</orig><reg>seeing</reg></choice> and having meet <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> again.</s>
        <s>First he is totally unsure about himself, but after having talked to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> alone for some time.</s>
        <s>He is all cheerful and ready to impress <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> with his mansion.</s>
        <s>He feels safe in the company of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>, what you could not have said about his party guest who didn't care for him and he who didn't care for them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The place of setting can also give us some clues on <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> personality change around <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>Since <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> home is described as small in the contrast to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> house or the mansion of the <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Buchanan's</orig><reg>Buchanans</reg></choice></ref> it represents comfort and also <choice><orig>intimicy</orig><reg>intimacy</reg></choice>, which <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> needs to be himself.</s>
        <s>But then also the change of weather can be reflected on <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> mood.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Since first he was all nervous and unsure, which represents the rain, after some time he was getting more and more confident and sure about his action, but also happy and joyful, which represents the clear and bright sun after the rain.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> an <choice><orig>archiver</orig><reg>achiever</reg></choice> of the American Dream, but also of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="author">F. Scott Fitzgerald's</ref> American Dream, says <quote>having enough money to buy fancy cars and enough whiskey to crash them</quote> is firstly <choice><orig>portrait</orig><reg>portrayed</reg></choice> as a mysterious and kept to himself person, which is <choice><orig>show</orig><reg>shown</reg></choice> by all the rumors spread about him.</s>
        <s>As we get to know him better he is described as dishonest, which is shown through him telling <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> stories, which sound like invented but he still has proof of them.</s>
        <s>And then as we move on to him finally meeting <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> again he becomes nervous but also optimistic to get her back after some time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
