<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l21_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is the main character in the novel <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="title">The Great Gatsby</ref> and shown as a rich and <choice><orig>weathy</orig><reg>wealthy</reg></choice> man trying to impress his former lover with his <choice><orig>weath</orig><reg>wealth</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>In a world full of materialistic pursued, <choice><orig>sucess</orig><reg>success</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>weath</orig><reg>wealth</reg></choice>, the world of <quote>old money</quote>, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> symbolises the <quote>new money</quote> since he did not earn his <choice><orig>weath</orig><reg>wealth</reg></choice> through his family but through the down world <choice><orig>buisness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He seems to be very confident and always sure about himself, knowing what he's doing.</s>
        <s>That is why his behavior in the given excerpt is so untypical for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The reader knows, the real purpose of the big parties and the big mansion is to impress <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>Since five years he has been trying to catch her attention, which shows how obsessed he is with his dream of a life with his former lover.</s>
        <s>This is also shown by the symbolism of the clock falling.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref><choice><orig>accidently</orig><reg>accidentally</reg></choice> knocks a clock over and catches it before it could hit the ground and break <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, ll. 5-7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This can be seen as an attempt of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> to stop the time and retrieve the past.</s>
        <s>The fact that the time stopped at a specific point in time refers to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> being trapped, chasing a dream of ideal love with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref>.</s>
        <s>Whereas <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> has moved on and married another <choice><orig>weathy</orig><reg>wealthy</reg></choice> man, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> holds on to the past, even counting the time, which is made clear when he knows the exact amount of time since they had last seen each other <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> then considers the clock as an old one <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> which leads to the <q>old times</q>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In comparison to the previous chapters, this is the first time the reader experiences <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> vulnerability and uncertainty.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> describes his <quote>distraught eyes</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 30)</ref> and the usually confidently talking <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> seems very unsure of himself by muttering and whispering <quote>in a miserable way</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 89, l. 31)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally, his body language also shows how unsure of himself he is.</s>
        <s>As already mentioned he clumsily knocks over the clock.</s>
        <s>His eyes are <choice><orig>deliever</orig><reg>deliver</reg></choice> an impression of what he feels like, when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> <choice><orig>mentiones</orig><reg>mentions</reg></choice> his tragic <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 16)</ref>, distraught <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 30)</ref> and unhappy <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 25)</ref> looks.</s>
        <s>Another hint for his apparent restlessness is that he keeps <choice><orig>trembeling</orig><reg>trembling</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 85, l. 6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into two parts because or a radical change of atmosphere.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> comes back into the living room <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> nervous tension seems gone and by the exaggeration of using <quote>glows</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 14)</ref> a vivid image of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> happiness is created.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, the division is created by the change of weather of the setting.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of the rain <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> could act like he was looking for safety of the rain at <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> and make it seem like a coincidence that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> was there too as if he hasn't been waiting for this moment for the past 5 years.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Later on in the chapter, when the rain created mist, the vision is limited so <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> can't see her house from the balcony, meaning she is far away from her life with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Tom</ref> and her child but in this moment with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>.</s>
        <s>And when the significant rain stops and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> comes back to the room, any sign of <choice><orig>embarassment</orig><reg>embarrassment</reg></choice> seems gone with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> uncertainty.</s>
        <s>Another sign for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> being himself again is that he started adding his typical <quote>old sport</quote> again after addressing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 87, l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After this change, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> gets to his original plan of impressing <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> with his mansion, his clothes and boasting about his wealth.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of the first person narrative perspective of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> the reader gets an impression of his thoughts about the situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He mostly seems annoyed with <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> <quote>(It wasn't a bit funny)</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 84, l. 19)</ref>, <choice><orig>espacially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> when they talk outside of the living room and <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, panicking, repeats what a <quote>terrible mistake</quote> it was, <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> forgets his <choice><orig>usuall</orig><reg>usual</reg></choice> <choice><orig>respectfull</orig><reg>respectful</reg></choice>, admiring behavior towards <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> by calling him <quote>a little boy</quote> and rude <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 86, ll. 8-9)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides that, another scene where <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> seems critical towards <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> tries to let <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> earn money through one of his <choice><orig>buisnesses</orig><reg>businesses</reg></choice>, but <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> expects it has something to do with illegal affairs and rejects <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 81, ll. 21-29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This regards <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> tactlessness, how far out of touch he really is from the <quote>old money world</quote> he is trying to or pretending to be a part of and now he rewards <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> with money instead of something of sentimental value.</s>
        <s>After this chapter <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> is more sure in his suspicion that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> is not honest about the way he earned his money and his past.</s>
        <s>On page 88 in ll. 5-7 you can see that <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> sayings do not add up and when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick</ref> <choice><orig>specificly</orig><reg>specifically</reg></choice> asks in what <choice><orig>buissness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice> he moves he does not tell him straightly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A further scene referring to <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Nick's</ref> annoyance is when <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref> shows them around his house by listing the things they <q>were to see</q> with the repeated use of <quote>and</quote> <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 90, ll. 25-26)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of the most important symbols in the novel is the green light, mentioned in the end of the chapter.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It symbolizes <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby's</ref> dream his love for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> in his attempt to make it reality.</s>
        <s>He reaches towards the green light because of his love for <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> and when he <choice><orig>fullfilled</orig><reg>fulfilled</reg></choice> that dream by being reunited with her this ritual of his has lost it's meaning <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 91, l. 9)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The green light can also be seen as the American Dream and the pursuit of happiness and <choice><orig>weath</orig><reg>wealth</reg></choice>, but once you have fully reached your goal you could lose your purpose in life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, the excerpt shows a totally <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> side of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Gatsby</ref>, pure and revealing, which allows the reader to have an insight into his character.</s>
        <s>The fact that he fell out of his role because of <ref target="b11lk2_1" type="character">Daisy</ref> reveals how important that dream of his is for him and how he <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> through the value of materialism to be rich of love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
