<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g10_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref> by <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> was published in the <name type="misc">Sunday Times</name> at the <date>17t December 2016</date>.</s>
        <s>The text is about the advantages of learning English when one lives in <name type="geo">London</name>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> talks about her own experiences with English as a kid and what helped her to learn the language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first the author talks about the high costs that were spent just on translating and interpreting and that we send the immigrant communities the wrong signals.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second paragraph <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> explains the situation in <name type="misc">Brick Lane</name> in the <choice><orig>East</orig><reg>east</reg></choice> of <name type="geo">London</name>.</s>
        <s>There the community does not have to learn English because everything is in Bengali.</s>
        <s>In this part of <name type="geo">London</name> is a high crime rate and the people who live there don't have many choices on what to do with their <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> talks about her own experiences in learning English.</s>
        <s>Her parents always wanted her to learn this language and achieved this through the head of her primary school.</s>
        <s>In addition, <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Rahman</ref> does not think it helps when you celebrate differences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last paragraph she explains that it is important to celebrate diversity, which helps communities to integrate.</s>
        <s>In addition one has to speak up to change something.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author thinks it is very important to learn English when one wants to integrate in a country.</s>
        <s>The consequences are no employment, no integration and a huge gap between two communities.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
