<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g14_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text is structured into four paragraphs.</s>
        <s>The first is a bit like an introduction by giving an actual fact and the author's opinion.</s>
        <s>The second gives the reader some background information to understand the following paragraph, in which <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> writes about her own immigrant experiences, better.</s>
        <s>The last paragraph appeals the reader to stop translation services by explaining disadvantages and saying that learning English should be a compulsory.</s>
        <s>This structure of first giving a statistic <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> makes it seem more professional.</s>
        <s>The third paragraph has an emotional tone because of explaining her own past, by doing this the reader builds empathy for the author so that it is easier to convince them in the last paragraph.</s>
        <s>The author uses some stylistic devices in her text.</s>
        <s>One of them is the hyperbole in lines 5-10 which criticizes by using this exaggeration the bad conditions in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> and the low chances to rise in their community.</s>
        <s>Another example is the repetition in line 11-15 <quote><qs>My parents [...].</qs><qs>My parents [...].</qs><qs>My parents [...]</qs></quote>.</s>
        <s>This stylistic device <choice><orig>underline</orig><reg>underlines</reg></choice> the emotional tone by mentioning family members but also shows the fact that you need help by immigrating.</s>
        <s>Another stylistic device is the metaphor in line 18-19 <quote>But you don't learn to stand on your own two feet if somenoe is holding you up</quote>, it emphasizes the fact that immigrants have to speak English to integrate completely and to become independent.</s>
        <s>The sentence <quote>we have to celebrate our diversity</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 18)</ref> sounds kind of ironic when you keep the author's view and the third paragraph in mind.</s>
        <s>It stresses the author's opinion that celebrating differences and immigration makes it hard to completely integrate because you always will be seen as an <choice><orig>immigrants</orig><reg>immigrant</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>In lines 20-23 the author uses the words <quote>we</quote> and <quote>us</quote> to build the sense of unity and better convince the reader.</s>
        <s>All these aspects help <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> to stop translation and interpreting services.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
