<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g65_t3</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="discussion">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hi John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>long time no see!</s>
        <s>What's up?</s>
        <s>How is <choice><orig>live</orig><reg>life</reg></choice> going?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Last time we talked I told you about my exchange, I did years ago and you said that you think <quote>student exchanges are a waste of time</quote>, since then I'm thinking about it so I came up with the idea to write you an e-mail with my point of view, because you actually missing something out.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think I already made it clear that I totally disagree with you, because I personally would do an exchange again as soon as I get the opportunity to, but I on the other hand I can understand why you're and many other people are agianst it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To begin, they start with the argument that you're alone and feel uncomfortable as soon as you do an exchange but most people don't know that in many cases your host family have kids, sometimes even in your age <add>(they may come over to your country)</add> so you would <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> get to know someone <add>(around your age)</add> or a friend.</s>
        <s>The schools there are really caring and you <choice><orig>automaticly</orig><reg>automatically</reg></choice> meet up with people around your age.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore you get an advisor who you are able to <choice><orig>asks</orig><reg>ask</reg></choice> any questions and problems.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They accomplished you through your whole exchange and to mention that to, they check on all the host families who decided to welcome someone from <choice><orig>abrod</orig><reg>abroad</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The advantages of an exchange are huge.</s>
        <s>Let me illustrate it to you, you want a job but you need knowledge of another language or <choice><orig>culteral</orig><reg>cultural</reg></choice> understanding, there is no better way to learn a language then to speak it with native speakers, there is no better way to understand <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> culture than to once lived it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Fun <choice><orig>Fact</orig><reg>fact</reg></choice> <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> year or <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> half year abroad looks really good on a <choice><abbr>CV</abbr><expan>curriculum vitae</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>Moreover the experiences you lived are actually very helpful to improve yourself, many people write on their blogs that they gained more confident over the exchange and now have a stronger personality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I, myself can <choice><orig>asure</orig><reg>assure</reg></choice> you that's truth.</s>
        <s>You, yourself even complemented me on my improvement.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I'm still having the opinion that exchanges or going <choice><orig>abroad</orig><reg>abord</reg></choice> in general are an excellent opportunity, but I can't change your mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Hopefully you just think about it again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See forward to discuss this with you again.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
