<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c11g19_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211220</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to <choice><orig>analize</orig><reg>analyze</reg></choice> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Walters</orig><reg>Walter's</reg></choice></ref> dream and his means to realize it, and comare it to the other family members' dreams.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first thing which is conspicious is the <choice><orig>contibution</orig><reg>contribution</reg></choice> of the active characters in the <choice><orig>szene</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>While <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> has kind of monologues, where he just speaks and not really <choice><orig>come</orig><reg>comes</reg></choice> to an end, <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Ruths</orig><reg>Ruth's</reg></choice></ref> longest sentence is 11 words long <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref>, which really states <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Ruths</orig><reg>Ruth's</reg></choice></ref> feelings about that topic.</s>
        <s>She just doesn't want to talk about it, so she does not talk <choice><orig>abut</orig><reg>about</reg></choice> it.</s>
        <s>That is a very clear message as she states to what she stands for.</s>
        <s>Otherwise as <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref>, because he talks a lot about his dream and what he wants to have and what he wants to change, but <choice><orig>infect</orig><reg>in fact</reg></choice> he doesn't get anything done at all as he wakes up and just <choice><orig>tell</orig><reg>tells</reg></choice> his son that the whites are rich and not him or his family <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 42f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Another important thing is the way <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> deals with <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Walters</orig><reg>Walter's</reg></choice></ref> idea.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> called <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Willy Harris</ref> a <quote>good-for-nothing loud mouth</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref>, which speaks for the aspect I already described with the speaking much, but not doing much from <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> says <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> would not help getting better living conditions and that she doesn't want to back <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> up anymore, which is a very accusation, as it would mean <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> is happy with the situation and wants to live like that forever, which isn't true, because her drem with the cash is to buy a new house and better the living conditions like that.</s>
        <s>After <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> told his feelings about the help he gets from <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>, he wants <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> to talk to <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 18ff.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> thinks <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> would like his idea and would try to convince <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>, so that she just starts helping <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref>, but <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> has the same dream with the money as <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>, which makes it hard for <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref>, rather to help her son to <choice><orig>fullfill</orig><reg>fulfill</reg></choice> his dream, or to stand for herself and buy a house, because at the end, it's still her insureance money.</s>
        <s>Also <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Ruths</orig><reg>Ruth's</reg></choice></ref> way of communication shows how bad she wants her dream to come true, because she thinks it would help the family the most to buy a house, while she thinks <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> wants the money to make a dream about a hobby come true.</s>
        <s>So she thinks <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> just wants the money for himself.</s>
        <s>This is why she <choice><orig>sais</orig><reg>says</reg></choice>: <quote>Walter, that ain't none of your money</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> states he would break laws to let his dream come true, as he would bribe the government to get his store license <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 30)</ref>, which shows how bad he wants that liquor store to get safe and good income.</s>
        <s>So his dream can be compared to <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Beneathas</orig><reg>Beneatha's</reg></choice></ref> dream, because she <choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> the money to get a doctors education to get the money to save the family.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Ruths</orig><reg>Ruth's</reg></choice></ref> actors advices also show how she thinks about the liquor store, as she said <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Bobo</ref> <quote>with a frawn</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 26)</ref>, which means she can't stand this guy, because she thinks <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Bobo</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Willy Harris</ref> would convince <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter Lee</ref> to open the liquor store and that these two guys want to make as much money as possible without looking at <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Walters</orig><reg>Walter's</reg></choice></ref> situation.</s>
        <s>One of the arguments for the liquor store in point of view from <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> is that he wants to tell his son <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref> stories about how rich he is and not the whites.</s>
        <s>But <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref> doesn't want the liquor store either, while his dream is just a better place to sleep, like a new couch and a better general place to live in, like a new house, like his mother, and <choice><orig>grand-mother</orig><reg>grandmother</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Which means three people in this family have the same <choice><orig>opionion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> about what to do with the money while <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> stands there alone with his idea.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Although <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> won't give up that easily which isn't dumb at all, looking at the benefits waiting for him.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
