<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c11g21_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211220</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Following I am going to analyze the given dialogue between <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> and his wife <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> with focus on <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> dream, his means to realize it and to the other family <choice><orig>member's</orig><reg>members'</reg></choice> dreams.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given dialogue plays in the beginning of the play <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="title">A Raisin in the Sun</ref> and is about an argument between <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref>.</s>
        <s>Before the given dialogue <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> send her son <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref> to school and after the given dialogue <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Beneatha</ref> wakes up and <choice><orig>enter</orig><reg>enters</reg></choice> the living room.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the beginning <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> talks about last night with his wife and he asks his wife if she wants to know about he was thinking in the bathroom <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 1ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> knows about <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> dream, that he wants to invest the money of his mother in a liquor store.</s>
        <s>The problem is that it is not <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> money and that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Lena</ref> does not like the idea of a liquor store.</s>
        <s>Another problem is that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> thinks that <quote>Willy Harris is a good-for-nothing loud mouth</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> tries to convince his wife while saying: <quote><s>Charlie Atkins was just a good-for-nothing loud mouth' too, wasn't he!</s><s>When he wanted me to go in the dry-cleaning business with him.</s><s>And now he's grossing a hundred thousand a year.</s><s>A hundred thousand dollar a year!</s><s>You still call him a loud mouth!</s></quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 6ff.)</ref> He wants to show his wife that not everyone of his friends is a <quote>good-for-nothing loud mouth</quote>.</s>
        <s>Following <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> ignores his wife because she wants to end the discussion with her husband.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> wants to realize his dream while trying to convince that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> has to talk to his mother and talk about the business idea because <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> has a better relationship with his mother.</s>
        <s>He shows her how to do it.</s>
        <s>They only have to drink some coffee and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> only <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> to say that she is so interested in the <choice><orig>dead</orig><reg>death</reg></choice> of her husband and in the store <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 18-25)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> says with who he wants to work with and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> does not like the people <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 25f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> says that the liquor store <choice><orig>cost</orig><reg>costs</reg></choice> seventy five thousand dollar but the profit will be about thirty thousand dollar.</s>
        <s>To compare his dream to the other family members' dreams his dream costs more money <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> for example the dream of <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Lena</ref>.</s>
        <s>The dream of <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Lena</ref> is that they want better living conditions and a small house with a small garden in another and a better neighbourhood.</s>
        <s>The dream of <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref>, the son of <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> is also cheaper than the dream of <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref>.</s>
        <s>His dream are better living conditions in his term for example an own room for him and probably no money issues anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Beneatha's</ref> dream is becoming a doctor and this is more expensive than <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> dream.</s>
        <s>All in all is <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> dream one of the expensivests dreams of the family and the riskiest.</s>
        <s>The money of the dead husband is not enough to realize every dream.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> wants to realize his dream while bribing other people.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> does not like that her husband <choice><orig>want</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to graft and it is illegal.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref><choice><orig>play</orig><reg>plays</reg></choice> it down in a way that he can't get a bad feeling of what he wants to do <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 31ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> shows her rage while saying: <quote><s>Walter, leave me alone!</s><s>Eat your eggs, they gonna be cold</s></quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> does not like the mindset of his wife and tries to replay the argument of them <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 35-38)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> tries to <q>wake up</q> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> out of his thoughts and says that it is not his money <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 39)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> does not heed to his wife and goes on and <choice><orig>give</orig><reg>gives</reg></choice> back his life which is sometimes of none happiness like in l. 42: <quote>Very, very quietly - and all I got to give him is stories about how rich white people live ...</quote>.</s>
        <s>This sentence is a big contrast to how <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> in the other parts talk.</s>
        <s>It shows that he is not happy with his situation and that he wants to change something especially for his son <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> is in this dialogue the person who stays realistic and she wants to hold on her husband because she thinks that they are bad for him.</s>
        <s>She shows that in for example <quote>(with a frawn)</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 26)</ref> or <quote>(bitterly)</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion is <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> dream not to realize because it is not his money about he talks and plays and his wife does not like his business idea and the friends of him with <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> wants to work with.</s>
        <s>The opinion of <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> does not change in the dialogue because firstly <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> ignores her all the time and secondly she does not like the package.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
