<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>a12g29_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne's</ref> article introduces the statement that <quote>language learning is vital for the UK' future prosperity and global standing</quote> <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> which will be discussed in the following.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Opponents of <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> claim might say that it is unnecessary o learn any foreign language as a native English speaker, because it is a global language or lingua franca, so they can communicate with big parts of the world anyway.</s>
        <s>What they do not take into account is that there are much more non-native then native English speakers which causes the English language to evlve into different versions of English, like Spanglish or Hinglish and many more.</s>
        <s>Learning another language can help understand another English better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the same note, there is more than one global language.</s>
        <s>While English may be the most imoprtant one, other languages like Spanish or Chinese are spoken almost as much, or in the case of Chinese even more, than English.</s>
        <s>That means it is very profitabl to know one of those languages as well, also because there is a possibility that one day English will be replaced as the world language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another argument that opponents of <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> claim might have is that they could just use phone translation if they needed to, which - in essence - is true, but it is not very reliable.</s>
        <s>If you are on your way, your phone might get lost or the battery is empty or something like that and then you would not have that option.</s>
        <s>It also does not have the benefit of giving you a better understanding of languages in general.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An important argument in favor of <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">Worne</ref> with regard to our globalised world is the demand for qualified multilingual employees.</s>
        <s>Knowing multiple languages can increase your chance of employment drastically, because you would be of higher value to the company which could also mean a higher salery.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, I agree with <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne's</ref> statement.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As shown through the arguments in this comment, it is definitely profitable to be multilingual for various reasons.</s>
        <s>Especially because of the globalisation, it can be helpful to acknowledge other cultures and their languages.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
