<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g30_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="title">Language learning the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref> by <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> was published in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> at <date>January 27, 2015</date> is an article <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> deals with the population inside the <name type="geo">UK</name> on speaking foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Firthe</orig><reg>First</reg></choice> the author informs about the steady relapse, where the number of <name type="geo">UK</name> students <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> are choosing foreign languages at university level is in a steady decline for the past seven years.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Following he points out that on the other side that more languages are thought in primary school.</s>
        <s>He describes a decline for the last 30 years in language <name type="misc">A-level</name> exams.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He informs that both <name type="misc">A-level</name> and <name type="misc">GCSE</name> had a decline in language exams.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore he explains how the innovation of technilogies inside the digitalization might comprehend this relapse, but really are not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also he points out how one might only need the <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> language in the world of <choice><orig>buisness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice> but points out that this is not the case.</s>
        <s>Following he informs about the need for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity to expand the language learning.</s>
        <s>The author relates on the <name type="misc">CBI/Pearson Education and Skill Survey</name> in <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> it is pointed out that the majority of <choice><orig>buisnesses</orig><reg>businesses</reg></choice> need foreign language skills.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition he points out that <choice><orig>universitys</orig><reg>universities</reg></choice> are offering to study a foreign language alongsde and tells that the skill of foreign language is also <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> important skills for the professional career.</s>
        <s>Lastly <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> explains how not only the school and education system is responsible for this deficit but also the parents of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To bring everything together the author informs about the decline in high value qualification of foreign language in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>He explains in how far this might be a problem for the future of the <name type="geo">UK</name> and is not comprehendable by high performing technologies.</s>
        <s>And points out that it is not onl the <choice><orig> responsobility</orig><reg>responsibility</reg></choice> from the school and education system but also from the parents of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
