<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g33_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given text at hand <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref>, written by John Worne, is about the situation of foreign language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>It was published on 27the January 2015, and is a column in the newspaper <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>authors</orig><reg>author's</reg></choice> view on language learning in the <name type="geo">UK</name> is that the <name type="geo">UK</name> needs more young people to study foreign languages, since it is only beneficial and advantageous for them.</s>
        <s>He states that there has been a steady decline in foreign language learning on university level as well as school level, despite its growing importance.</s>
        <s>To underline that, the author refers to the current job situation and argues, why additional foreign language studies are compelling for employers.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, he alsoaddresses the arguments of people that support the point a foreign language skills being redundant, and sarcastically answers to those arguments.</s>
        <s>In the end, he again states the importance of language learning for the future of the <name type="geo">UK</name>, and calls for the <choice><orig>parents</orig><reg>parents'</reg></choice> help to teach their children to importance of language learning, since it is not possible without their help.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
