<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12g37_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>it is nice to hear that you think about coming to <name type="geo">Germany</name> for one year.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In search of how to explain why <name type="geo">Berlin</name> could be attractive to you, I found the article <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="title">Berlin spricht Englisch</ref> which can be translated to <quote>Berlin speaks English</quote>, by <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Marina Kormbaki</ref> published in the local newspaper <name type="misc">Hannoversche Allgemeine Zeitung</name> on <date>15th July 2016</date>.</s>
        <s>The author states that <name type="geo">Berlin</name> became <choice><orig>similiar</orig><reg>similar</reg></choice> to <choice><orig>citys</orig><reg>cities</reg></choice> like <name type="geo">London</name> and <name type="geo">Sydney</name>, since a lot of people visited the German capital as you plan to do.</s>
        <s>According to <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Kormbaki</ref> you can walk through <name type="geo">Berlin's</name> central districts without hearing German speech but recognizing English advertisements.</s>
        <s>However you should know that Turkish and Arab are among the most popular languages there.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To illustrate <name type="geo">Berlin</name> 2 people are introduced in the article.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>enterpreneur</orig><reg>entrepreneur</reg></choice> <name type="person">David Walker</name> enjoys his cheap latte in a café.</s>
        <s>He tells that he <quote>of course</quote> communicates with his multicultural colleagues in English.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Orla Baumgarten</name> sells books and profits from the vivid cultural life in the booming city and its relatively pricely living area.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This aspects make <name type="geo">Berlin</name> attractive for you personally, although you already know my general opinion on the city.</s>
        <s>I hope I could have helped you and look forward to meet you in Germany.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
