<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12g28_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>thank you for your nice mail.</s>
        <s>I'm doing well and I hope so do you.</s>
        <s>You told me about your plans about spending a year in Germany, especially in Berlin, so I did some research for you.</s>
        <s>I came up with the article <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="title">Berlin spricht Englisch</ref> (<quote>Berlin speaks English</quote> how you probably could decipher) by <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Marina Kormbaki</ref> from <date>15 July 2016</date> that was published in the daily newspaper of <name type="geo">Hanover</name>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Kormbaki</ref> compares the capital of Germany to London, Brooklyn and Sydney because every year, loads of <choice><orig>english-speaking</orig><reg>English-speaking</reg></choice> people would go to Berlin.</s>
        <s>If you speak English and walk through the city, you should have no problem, even if you don't speak any German.</s>
        <s>It's common that <choice><orig>waitors</orig><reg>waiters</reg></choice> speak even to Germany people in English becuase they aren't sure whether they're locals or tourists.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The difference to London, Brooklyn and Sydnex are the prizes, from latte macchiato in a café up to the rent of an <choice><orig>apartment</orig><reg>appartment</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The style and design of many shops are trendy, there is a good night life and culture.</s>
        <s>For many reasons, Berlin is experiencing a huge hype.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope, I could help you with your decision and I'd love to visit you in Berlin and drink something in a bar with a designer look with you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Greetings, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
