<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g32_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> from <date>27 January 2015</date>, published in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name>, is about <name type="geo">UK's</name> issue losing their own language skills as a <choice><orig>negativ</orig><reg>negative</reg></choice> aspect of globalisation and a system problem of learning foreign language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> this is a <choice><orig>hugh</orig><reg>huge</reg></choice> issue cause his opinion is that learning foreign language is still very important for trading, culture, diplomacy and also for the national security.</s>
        <s>And he lines out that there re two major problems, on the <choice><orig>on</orig><reg>one</reg></choice> hand less students an a bad learning and school ystem, on the other hand no doubt in the use and need of <choice><orig>developt</orig><reg>developed</reg></choice> language skills.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One part of the problem in his opinion is that the <choice><orig>Number</orig><reg>number</reg></choice> of students who learn foreign languages is constantly fallen in the past few years, more <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> 10.000 fewer exams since the end of the 1990s.</s>
        <s>And for the other part of the problem, he is the opinion that the people think the basic English skills are enough to communicate and then is no need of <choice><orig>developt</orig><reg>developed</reg></choice> language skills.</s>
        <s>But <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">Worne</ref> thinks this is the false way he thinks that the technical progress could not solve any problem, so for him it's still important to get this higher <choice><orig>languarge</orig><reg>language</reg></choice> <choice><orig>abbility's</orig><reg>abilities</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
