<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12g38_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Many people recently discussed the topic whether how important language learning is for <name type="geo">UK's</name> future.</s>
        <s>Indeed taking into account the rapid changes in our lives due to globalisation this should be considered a current issue.</s>
        <s>However we should not opt for panicky reactions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand, as <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">Mr. Worne</ref> pointed out, universities are engaged in offering language courses and surveys seemingly prood constantly rising importance in the world of business.</s>
        <s>And while skills of students in <name type="geo">Britain</name> don't relevantly grow, they do in other parts of the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand we should not overestimate the developments.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example the mentioned decrease of language <name type="misc">A-levels</name> by 10.000 over the last 20 years is not that much compared to the number of school children.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Secondly neither technological progress nor the effects of westernization, of which the spread of English language over the world is part, can be ignored or laughed about as <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> did.</s>
        <s>Moreover foreign language skills are unlikely to become a question of life and dead, even if they are important for international business.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Companys</orig><reg>Companies</reg></choice> will find a way to communicate with each other.</s>
        <s>This is an alternative interpretation of the fact that <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses increasingly perfer to hire abroad <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It may be worth considering to rely on the given educational system and let children collect the strings for the bows.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
