<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12g32_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello guys,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>yesterday I read an article written by <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> about the small amount of interested people in learning different languages and one sentence catched me a lot and I want to talk about it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The quotation is <quote>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing</quote>.</s>
        <s>At first this quotation makes sense to me I thought, that you have to learn different languages to communicate with other people in other countries.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand you could say that English is the global language and that everyone has to learn English.</s>
        <s>But I think that this is a problem.</s>
        <s>For example <name type="geo">China</name>: In <name type="geo">China</name> they don't learn English like in other countries.</s>
        <s>So in some intercultural conversations with <name type="geo">China</name> you need to learn Chinese.</s>
        <s>But this you could say the other way around: In the <name type="geo">UK</name> you don't learn <choice><orig>Chineese</orig><reg>Chinese</reg></choice> so they have to learn English.</s>
        <s>I came to the point that English gives you the opportunity to communicate with many countries but not all of them and that learning other languages is definitely not bad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Please let me know your thoughts about this quotation in the comment section.</s>
        <s>I'm looking forward for your answers.</s>
        <s>Bye.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
