<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person"><choice><orig>Delaneys</orig><reg>Delaney's</reg></choice></name> development from standing up for his <choice><orig>believes</orig><reg>beliefs</reg></choice> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> to a prejudice guided being is is indicated by the reported thought: <quote>the man was Mexican</quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His shock is expressed is expressed through this short sentence and the reader immediately knows that this situation reminds him of his own incident.</s>
        <s>The fact that he is <quote>struck with the force of a blow</quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> by this fact is also indicating that he ahs a problem with Mexicans.</s>
        <s>The sudden usage of inner monologue, where <name type="person">Delaney</name> asks himself if this guy is the same man who threatened <name type="person">Kyra</name> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 24-26)</ref> shows the growing panic inside of <name type="person">Delaney</name> and that he will probably listen to his prejudical thoughts than to his rational thoughts.</s>
        <s>Another passage that describes his irrational behaviour is line 34-36.</s>
        <s>In this inner monologue he is jumping to conclusions.</s>
        <s>Even after the chat with the man, <name type="person">Delaney</name> wants to call the police <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 51)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The climax of his prejudical thinking is when he calls the man in a reported thought a liar, thief etc. <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 49f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This sentence also has a climatic structure because his cursing gets worse and worse and ends with <quote>a Mexican</quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 50)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It shows that there is no point of turning back for <name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
        <s>he is controlled by racist thoughts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is not only controlled by his prejudice but also by fear.</s>
        <s>His fear is expressed by a climatic sentence where he desperately searches for someone who could support him in this situation <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 5f)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> is also ready to fight with the Mexican because he expects that the guy has weapons <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 56)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is also the climax in this excerpt.</s>
        <s>It creates tension and makes the reader curious without telling them <add>the readers</add> question if <name type="person">Delaney's</name> thoughts are right.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> realises that he was guided by fear and prejudice at the end of the chapter <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 60f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He wonders what he is becoming <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 61)</ref> or turning into.</s>
        <s>It underlines his self-awareness but also his changing character.</s>
        <s>He is not the <choice><orig>self assured</orig><reg>self-assured</reg></choice> naturalist who tries to act democratically anymore, he now knows how it is when fear and prejudice take over.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
