<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b11l04_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The novel <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="title">The Tortilla Curtain</ref> from <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="author">T. C. Boyle</ref>, published in <date>1995</date> deals with illegal immigrants from <name type="geo">Mexico</name> and the issues they face but also what issues they create for other.</s>
        <s>Big part ofo that is racism towards all illegal immigrants.</s>
        <s>In the given excerpt from <choice><orig>Part Two, Chapter</orig><reg>part two, chapter</reg></choice> 6 <name type="person">Delaney</name> has an encounter with a <choice><orig>mexican</orig><reg>Mexican</reg></choice> guy who's inside of <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco Estates</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney Mossbacher</name> is a white liberalman who lives with his family at <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco Estates</name>, a private community which is thinking of becoming a gated community.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> often claims that he is not racist <choice><orig>becaus</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> it disagrees with his <choice><orig>believes</orig><reg>beliefs</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>During the encounter between <name type="person">Delaney</name> and the Mexican the first thing that comes to <name type="person">Delaney's</name> mind when he sees him is that he is Mexican.</s>
        <s>Also he is sure that he knows him even <choice><orig>tho</orig><reg>though</reg></choice> he really doesn't.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that they guy is Mexican <choice><orig>let's</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> all the prejudice come across <name type="person"><choice><orig>Delaneys'</orig><reg>Delaney's</reg></choice></name> mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is sure that the Mexican must be a <choice><orig>thiev</orig><reg>thief</reg></choice> and that he got himself unallowed <choice><orig>acces</orig><reg>access</reg></choice> to <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco Estates</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> confronts him by asking if he could help him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The Mexican only gives <name type="person">Delaney</name> an unbothered look, but after a second time asking he replies by echoing his question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As they stand in front of each other <name type="person">Delaney</name> spots a <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">sothel</gap> <choice><orig>arround</orig><reg>around</reg></choice> him.</s>
        <s>He thinks that the Mexican has stolen things in it, thing out of the <name type="person">Cherrystones'</name> house and <name type="person">Delaney</name> knows for a fact that they aren't home, which supports his insult.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> demands on the fact that <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco Estates</name> is private property and clearly wants the Mexican to leave.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The Mexican stays unbothered.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Regarding to that <name type="person">Delaney</name> threatens him that he will call the police and knows exactly what he's doing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The Mexicans expression changes as he shows what is inside of his satchel.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Looking into the satchel <name type="person">Delaney</name> notices printed flies and the Mexican tells him that he delivers them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name><choice><orig>let's</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> go off him and reflects on his behaviour.</s>
        <s>He can't believe he insulted him like that just because he is Mexican.</s>
        <s>This <foreign xml:lang="de">szene</foreign> took place in <choice><orig>Part Two, Chapter</orig><reg>part two, chapter</reg></choice> 6 and follows the incident that happened to <name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
        <s>He went on a hike and after he returned to the parking lot his car was stolen.</s>
        <s>The onyl way he could explain it was taht a Mexican stole it, which explains why he reacted like that at <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco Estates</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This passage clearly shows how <name type="person">Delaney</name> thinks and how this prejudice against Mexicans take over him.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
