<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>a12l04_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical_exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <address>
        <addrLine>John Smith</addrLine>
        <addrLine>Elm Street 45</addrLine>
        <addrLine>12345 Cologne</addrLine>
      </address>
      <date>27th September 2021</date>
      <address>
        <addrLine>Ministry of Education</addrLine>
        <addrLine>
          <name type="geo">Germany</name>
        </addrLine>
      </address>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear representatives of the Ministry of Education,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I was astounded to hear about the decision to take off <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> sonnets of the English school curriculum.</s>
        <s>I as a student who is attending his final school year and therefore having thoroughly dealt with and investigated <name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></name> work, <choice><orig>disaprove</orig><reg>disapprove</reg></choice> of the new curriculum.</s>
        <s>I am sure that many of my classmates and parents of upcoming students share the same interest.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is not only of cultural importance but bears way more potential, which was probably overseen by the administrators who are reponsible for the English school curriculum.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This decision is not fair towards students who are exited to attend the English advanced class in the future.</s>
        <s>They will be missing out on everything the English language builds on, if not even getting the foundation of cultural English pulled away from under their feet.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is where real English poetry derived from.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is undeniably a milestone in English history, which we, as a culture which depends on and likes to uphold historical events in form of holidays, have basically no other choice than to <choice><orig>impement</orig><reg>implement</reg></choice> <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> sonnets in class.</s>
        <s>They are more than just texts with arranged words.</s>
        <s>They are a part of the <choice><orig>worlds</orig><reg>world's</reg></choice> story which cannot be forgotten about, not even in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>Imagine the chaos German schools would have to endure if <name type="person">Lessing</name> or <name type="person">Goethe</name> would be <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">fereed</gap> out of the curriculum.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnets are not only of cultural value.</s>
        <s>They strengthen and train complex understanding skills and fuel creativeness in the heart of every student.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> sonnets contain more facets of the English language than regular English nowadays, resulting in a broader need for deeper investigation and sometimes help from teachers or the internet.</s>
        <s>Trying to resolve these <choice><orig>missunderstandings</orig><reg>misunderstandings</reg></choice> of complex verse-structures trains a <choice><orig>students</orig><reg>student's</reg></choice> logical train of thought and his <choice><orig>intelectual</orig><reg>intellectual</reg></choice> strength, making it easier for him to learn new languages with similarly complex sentence structures.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you see that my message is of great importance.</s>
        <s>I am sure that I was not the only one complaining about these changes, so please take out requests into account and review them thoroughly.</s>
        <s>If there is an important reason why you decided to implement this change, I would <choice><orig>appeciate</orig><reg>appreciate</reg></choice> your standpoint on this matter.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours <choice><orig>sincerly</orig><reg>sincerely</reg></choice>, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
