<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l19_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary_recount">describe</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given poem <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> from<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> deals with a relationship between a woman and <choice><orig>an other</orig><reg>another</reg></choice> person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first quatrain the narrator voices that he would believe the other person.</s>
        <s>When she says, that she loves him, though he knows that it is not true.</s>
        <s>The lying one is on the opinion that her partner is unexperienced and young.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following a contradiction comes up in the first two sentences of the second quatrain.</s>
        <s>It says again that the female person thinks that the other other is young but the lyrical eye denies this thesis by saying tht his best days were a long time ago.</s>
        <s>Besides the persona of the poem highlights his opinion that the other person is a liar by repeating his thesis with other words.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third and last quatrain starts with a rhetorical question, where the narrator asks, why the women does not say the truth.</s>
        <s>Therefore he questions, why shes does not mention that he is old and not young.</s>
        <s>After this questions the speaker says that being trustworthy is a habit of herself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet ends with a couplet, where <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">headunits</gap> that both of them lie with the other person and whether they do mistakes because of this, they get difficulties.</s>
        <s>The couplet is like the statement of this sonnet.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
