<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l05_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary_recount">describe</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given poem <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref>, which was written by <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>, deals with the topic of honesty and love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the sonnet the speaker begins by stating that even though he/she knows that the addressed person is not truthful, he/she believes them anyways.</s>
        <s>The speaker goes on to say that the beloved woman sees the speaker as young and <choice><orig>naive</orig><reg>naïve</reg></choice>, because the speaker does not see through the <choice><orig>womans</orig><reg>woman's</reg></choice> lies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The narrator then explains that the woman lies to him/her about him/her still being and looking young, when they both know he/she is not anymore.</s>
        <s>On the other hand the speaker admits that his/her beloved woman lies, but he/she does not care.</s>
        <s>From this the speaker concludes, that he/she as well as the woman or not being truthful.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that the narrator stops explaining the relationship and asks him/herself why he/she and the woman will not admit to the faults, which are being old and being unjust.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>the speaker than <choice><orig>answeres</orig><reg>answers</reg></choice> this question by saying that love can make people believe that there is trust in a relationship, when really there is not.</s>
        <s>Further, the narrator claims that people do not like to admit that they are getting old and especially not to their loved ones.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end, the speaker concludes that by lying to each other he/she and the woman feel good about themselves, which is why they both do it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
