<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l13_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In order to intensify and illustrate his view on how paradox the nature of love is, the author makes use of many formal and poetic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet follows its strict demands for Shakespearean sonnets with its 14 lines divided into three quatrains and a concluding heroic couplet at the end, which (typically) includes the moral.</s>
        <s>The rhyme scheme is <name type="misc">abab cdcd efef gg (cross rhyme and couple rhyme)</name>.</s>
        <s>The metric follows an iambic pentameter, which symbolizes the <choice><orig>rhytm</orig><reg>rhythm</reg></choice> of a heartbeat and is therefore the perfect fit for the topic of love and gives the sonnet a very emotional atmosphere.</s>
        <s>It also underlines that the sonnet is meant to be presented, because the iambic pentameter is the metric utilized the most in everyday <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> and therefore gives life to the poem.</s>
        <s>In line nine there is a <choice><orig>volta</orig><reg>Volta</reg></choice>, which is signalized by the word <quote>but</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line one the author employs the metaphor <quote>made of truth</quote>.</s>
        <s>This symbolizes not only the desperate attempt of trying to uphold the lies the couple created, but also illustrates how unrealistic it is for someone to be 100% truthful.</s>
        <s>A person who has never lied simply does not exist.</s>
        <s>This metaphor helps the reader to visually imagine such person and adds a tragic element to the poem, which is underscored by the verb <quote>swears</quote> in the beginning of line one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Therefore, the antithesis <quote>I do believe her, though she lies</quote> in line two intensifies the paradox nature of this relationship and to an extend love in general.</s>
        <s>The person his or her beloved claims to be <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> ever eist in real life, so why does he believe her so easily?</s>
        <s>The reader is now torn between the perfect image that the beloved created and the harsh truth the speaker knows of.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>her false speaking tongue</quote> in line seven establishes an image of being <choice><orig>tongue tied</orig><reg>tongue-tied</reg></choice> and therefore almost helpless, as if the beloved would not have any control over what she says.</s>
        <s>The speaker simply persuades himself that it is her tongue that is untruthful, but never actually the beloved.</s>
        <s>In this case one does not speak of a poetic conceit, but of a tragic flaw that in the case of the couple emerges in their inability to be truthful to one another and this their ability to uphold the created conceit.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The word <quote>O</quote> in line eleven adds tragedy to the poem.</s>
        <s>It sounds like a sigh and vocalizes the drama in his thesis (<quote>love's best habit is in seeming trust</quote>, <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">line 11</ref>).</s>
        <s>Thus it sounds more alive and awakens a tragic feeling in the listener.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The parallelism <quote>Therefore I lie with her, and she with me</quote> gives the poem not only a round ending, but also shows the listener the couple's willing acceptance of this viscious circle both are trapped in, but do not want to break free from.</s>
        <s>They might make these mistakes forever, but they will always be together, because of their acceptance of each other's tragic flaw.</s>
        <s>It saves and ruins them all at once.</s>
        <s>The listener may feel as though the speaker has exposed them, or given a voice to something they <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> put into words.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, one can say that the author conveyed his message through very <choice><orig>imaginitave</orig><reg>imaginative</reg></choice> language, with the help of metaphors, in order to describe a feeling and the paradox nature of something many struggle to voice.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
