<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>a12l09_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Ministry of Education,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am writing this letter to you because I heard of your decision to take <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> <name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespear's</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></name> sonnets off the English school curriculum.</s>
        <s>I have to be honest and explain to you that I do not think this is a good solution.</s>
        <s>Please hear me out.</s>
        <s>I understand that students are sometimes very anxious of reading <name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></name> and finding it very difficult to understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, I do not deny the number of students who do not have high <choice><orig>intrest</orig><reg>interest</reg></choice> in<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> because they want to focus on relevant and modern writers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly, many <choice><orig>studens</orig><reg>students</reg></choice> are of the opinion that they should focus, in their eyes on <choice><orig>relavant</orig><reg>relevant</reg></choice> topics like grammar.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> understand these arguments but let me explain to you why I think taking <name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespear's</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></name> sonnets out of the English curriculum would be a <choice><orig>hughe</orig><reg>huge</reg></choice> mistake.</s>
        <s>Firstly, it is very educational to have a comparison between the modern and the older English writing style.</s>
        <s>Many students <choice><orig>underastimate</orig><reg>underestimate</reg></choice> this matter because in many jobs students can phase an old historian text or Soares they would have to discover and analyse.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, students would connect so much more with the English language if they would have to understand a Shakespearean sonnet.</s>
        <s>He actually introduced more than 100 words into the English language.</s>
        <s>Students cannot deny the <choice><orig>hughe</orig><reg>huge</reg></choice> impact<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> made to the word and that even nowadays so many authors, schools and professors are <choice><orig>facinated</orig><reg>fascinated</reg></choice> by him and even quote him everywhere.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly, I would also include that the amount of <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> interpretations cannot be measured and are wildly open.</s>
        <s>Students can connect and relate with the sonnet or play and compare their thoughts with other students and teachers.</s>
        <s>It would only bring us together not apart.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To put it in a nutshell, I am of the opinion that this decision would be a <choice><orig>hughe</orig><reg>huge</reg></choice> mistake because of the argument above.</s>
        <s>Please consider my letter and take it into account by your final decision.</s>
        <s>I wish you the best of luck.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
