<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l10_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary_recount">describe</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given poem is <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref>, written by <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>It deals with the topic of love being still love even though it is built on a construct of lies, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> eventually will collapse.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet starts with a direct message towards the reader.</s>
        <s>The speaker states that he still believes his loved one even though he knows she is lying.</s>
        <s>He goes on with mentioning negative thoughts his love might have of him, being inexperienced and naive.</s>
        <s>This is followed by the speaker naming unrealistic thoughts his loved has about him, being young although she knows that he is of age.</s>
        <s>The speaker then again says that he still believes his loved one, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> is connected to his first statement.</s>
        <s>In addition he states that the truth is suppressed not only by her but also by him.</s>
        <s>Moreover he goes further in saying, why the <choice><orig>speakers</orig><reg>speaker's</reg></choice> loved one should say that she is lying or why you should say that he is old.</s>
        <s>The two rhetorical questions do make his believe that the truth is better than lies, clear.</s>
        <s>In the following two lines the speaker states that love consists out of trust, but it does not matter if this trust is fake.</s>
        <s>In the last two lines he comes to the conclusion.</s>
        <s>Even though they lie to each other, those lies will come back and bring negativity to the relationship.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
