<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l01_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following it is going to be analysed how <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses formal and poetic devices to illustrate and intensify his view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Like in most of <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></ref> sonnets he goes after the same pattern and formal structure.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>the</orig><reg>The</reg></choice> sonnet has an iambic <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">patreaneon</gap> with a rhyme scheme of <name type="misc">ababcdcdefefgg</name>.</s>
        <s>With this pattern his sonnets are easier to present die to its rhyming.</s>
        <s>With the dividing of his lines with the quatrains and the couplet <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> can create a <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> topic in every part.</s>
        <s>This makes it more interesting for the reader to read and gets him to think more <choice><orig>aswell</orig><reg>as well</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has another good way to introduce a different part in his sonnet which is called a volta.</s>
        <s>Here the volta is in e.g. and is pointed out by the word <quote>but</quote>.</s>
        <s>In this sonnet the <quote>but</quote> changes the view of perspective from the lyrical speaker and introduces a new perspective to think about for the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another tool he <choice><orig>liks</orig><reg>likes</reg></choice> to work with to clarify his opinion or view on poetic devices, that shows his first device, which is a metaphor, in l. 1 <quote>she is made of truth</quote>.</s>
        <s>Here he wants the lyrical speaker points out that his love is made of truth, so she does not lie.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>this</orig><reg>This</reg></choice> is mentioned so the reader has something about the woman he is going to talk about.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line two is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> antithesis <quote>I do believe, though <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> know she lies?</quote>.</s>
        <s>With that sentence the lyrical speaker wants to illustrate that even tough he knows that she is <quote>made of truth</quote>, he believes her because he loves her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Here the author wants to make the reader clear that everyone lies sometimes and you just have to accept it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore there is a personification in l. 7 <quote>her false speaking tongue</quote> with the author means the lies of his loved one.</s>
        <s>This just again shows the reader the character of the woman mentioned.</s>
        <s>The reader can maybe now picture as a person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The next device is a <choice><orig>repitition</orig><reg>repetition</reg></choice> in ll. 9-10 <quote>But wherefore says she not she is unjust and wherefore say not I that I am old</quote>.</s>
        <s>In these two sentences<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> even uses two rhetorical questions.</s>
        <s>At this point in the sonnet the way of perspective changes and the lyrical speaker shows us the different part of his thoughts.</s>
        <s>This shows the reader that the person you love is not always right and that you can have an opinion yourself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last poetic device is in the last line of the sonnet and it is a metaphor <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> <quote>In our faults by lies we flatter'd be</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To finish <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> the sonnet the lyrical speaker makes a final statement where he points out that between two lovers both know that <choice><orig>their</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> are lies but they do not care and just play along.</s>
        <s>This is suppose to tell the reader that it is okay if there are lies between you and your loved one.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
