<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l13_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary recount">describe</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Sonnet 138, written by<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is about the paradox nature of love and truthfulness.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speaker begins by introducing the guiding idea of the sonnet.</s>
        <s>His or her lover is untruthful, though he or she ignores the lies willingly.</s>
        <s>This is because his or her lover might imagine the speaker to the caught up in ungenuine pleasenties.</s>
        <s>In the second quatrain this idea gets further developed.</s>
        <s>The beloved knows that her lover is not of inexperienced youth, yet persuades herself into believing the opposite and is thus lying to herself.</s>
        <s>However, the speaker does not intervene and lets the deceit play on.</s>
        <s>At this point the speaker arrives at the general conclusion, that both of them are <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">simoly</gap> <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">denrins</gap> the truth.</s>
        <s>In the third quatrain the train of thought abruptly change as the speaker asks himself why the both of them <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> simply tell their truths.</s>
        <s>This is where the speaker establishes his or her thesis.</s>
        <s>The essence of this <quote>seeming trust</quote> is what keeos the truth from coming out and is the foundation the love humans know best.</s>
        <s>The speaker arrives at the moral of the story in the concluding couplet.</s>
        <s>The couple will keep up with their untruthfulness and stay together.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
