<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>a12l12_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Love is never changing and lying is part of <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> in a relationship?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In more over 150 sonnets<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> creates a <choice><orig>multifaced</orig><reg>multifaceted</reg></choice> picture of one of the strongest emotions - love.</s>
        <s>His perception of love is altering.</s>
        <s>Dramatist and poeple dealing with work even think that the first 126 sonnets are addressed to a <choice><orig>men</orig><reg>man</reg></choice>, whereas from sonnet 127<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> talks about a woman, <choice><orig>reffered</orig><reg>referred</reg></choice> to as the dark lady.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Even though</orig><reg>Eventhough</reg></choice> his understanding is never the same and his sonnet highlight different aspects of love, it is still old and not speaking to everyone in the 21st century.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Generally speaking, people think that a connection between two partners is built on trust.</s>
        <s>Acceptance, but also trust and <choice><orig>honesty</orig><reg>honestly</reg></choice> are components of a healthy, <choice><orig>non-toxis</orig><reg>non-toxic</reg></choice> relationship from the modern point of view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> claims different.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> states that lying and <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> dishonest is acceptable in some complex connections.</s>
        <s>From <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">oliv</gap> point of view it is important to be sure that the partner is honest and open about all feelings and problems.</s>
        <s>Whatever it is, talking openly and addressing personal issues, not hiding from the hurtful truth, is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> important aspect of every romantic relationship.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another attribute love shows is illustrated in Sonnet 118.</s>
        <s>The poet compares love with simmer, pointing out that the beauty of love is eternal or should not fade.</s>
        <s>But we all know that love and beauty can fade.</s>
        <s>Both can change, but it is not necessarily something negative as portrayed in Shakespearean work.</s>
        <s>Time is the enemy that slowly is taking beauty away.</s>
        <s>However, some people age beautifully and become smart, confident adults.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> sees onl negatively is aging and the time passing, yet it can be beautiful.</s>
        <s>It is only matter of perception.</s>
        <s>A more realistic love is <choice><orig>exemplyfied</orig><reg>exemplified</reg></choice> in Sonnet 129.</s>
        <s><name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></name> mocks the idealof the Elizabethan age and is honest with the description of the darf lady.</s>
        <s>By comparing his beloved with <choice><orig>goddesses</orig><reg>godesses</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>extremly</orig><reg>extremely</reg></choice> high expectations he comes to <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> conclusion that the speaker likes his partner not only for the looks, but also the character.</s>
        <s>This message speaks to the modern rader, whereas <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> objectiting description of outward <choice><orig>appreance</orig><reg>appearance</reg></choice> is rather negative and unrealistic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In other famous sonnets the poet is claiming that children is <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">preseniag</gap> beauty.</s>
        <s>And even if we can argue that children are beautiful and bring joy into our lives, their aim is not preserve the parents' beauty and fight against him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all,<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> embodies a variety of ways to undersand the emotion of love.</s>
        <s>He has indeed a unique and totally different concept of love in his work, <choice><orig>espacially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> if compared to other, more classical writers in the 16th century.</s>
        <s>By classical traditions, the subject of love was never directly addressed.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> speaker, on the other hand, is talking to his love and asking question <quote>Shall I compare you to a summer's day?</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is also often said that time annot be fought against, which is why the older authors before <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>, try to convey their love to enjoy every moment and live after the concept of carpe diem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is different.</s>
        <s>He wants to fight time and do everything he can to preserve the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">idre</gap> in form of children or poetry, that captures the feelings and <choice><orig>immortalise</orig><reg>immortalises</reg></choice> emotions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In a nutshell, Shakespearean <choice><orig>multifaced</orig><reg>multifaceted</reg></choice> love can speak to the people.</s>
        <s>But as time passes and society changes each individual also has a slightly, or even <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> different view on love.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
