<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l17_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">blog</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>The relationship between <name type="geo">Weimar</name> and <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> - his work's true way into <name type="geo">Germany</name></s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Did you know that the <name type="misc">Deutsche Shakespeare Gesellschaft</name> held its spring conference in <name type="geo">Bochum</name>, which is the, historically seen, wrong city to celebrate its 150th anniversary?</s>
        <s>I certainly did not know, which is why I read the article <ref target="a12lk1_2" type="title">Wie Shakespeares Denkmal in den Weimarer Ilmpark kam</ref>, published on <date>24. April 2016</date> by <name type="misc">Thüringer Allgemeine</name> and written by <ref target="a12lk1_2" type="author">Wolfgang Hirsch</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this article, Hirsch describes how <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work found its way to <name type="geo">Germany</name>, as well as the relationship between <name type="geo">Weimar</name> and <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>.</s>
        <s>Because I am taking part in the international school project <name type="misc">Global Shakespeare</name>, I think it is very interesting to share the information which is given in the article.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_2" type="author">Hirsch</ref> starts off his article by talking about how greatly <choice><orig>celebratet</orig><reg>celebrated</reg></choice> <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is in the United Kingdom and how many tourists come to visit his hometown <name type="geo">Stratford-upon-Avon, UK</name>.</s>
        <s>Here, the question arises how <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work found its way into <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>As <choice><orig>alredy</orig><reg>already</reg></choice> mentioned above, in <date>2016</date> the German <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> committee held its spring conference in <name type="geo">Bochum</name>, which is, historically seen, the wrong city to celebrate him.</s>
        <s>Why you may ask?</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_2" type="author">Hirsch</ref> describes how no one in <name type="geo">Germany</name> knew about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> until the late 18th century, due to missing translations.</s>
        <s>In the <name type="geo">Ilm Arkadien</name> his way through German literature began.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Christoph Martin Wieland</name>, the founding father of German classic, was first to translate <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work into the German language.</s>
        <s>Between <date>1762</date> and <date>1766</date>, <name type="person">Wieland</name> has published 22 of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays.</s>
        <s>However, the Jenaer professor for German studies <name type="person">Klaus Manger</name>, explains that <name type="person">Goethe</name> and <name type="person">Herder</name> also knew a little bit about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> and represent parts of his work in their own work.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Wieland</name>, <name type="person">Goethe</name> and <name type="person">Herder</name>, the leaders of the German <name type="misc">Shakespeare Renaissance</name>, all found themselves in <name type="geo">Weimar</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Manger</name> explains that other famous poets and other men well known in literature have translated <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work and even managed to write modern translations.</s>
        <s>Yet no one was able to translate please like <name type="misc">Sommernachtstraum</name> as magically as <name type="person">Wieland</name> did, <name type="person">Manger</name> claims.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On <date>8. April 1864</date>, the <name type="misc">Verein der Shakespeare-Freunde</name> was founded in <name type="geo">Weimar</name>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_2" type="author">Hirsch</ref> states that it must have been extremely inspiring, because it is the oldest literature society in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>For the 40th anniversary of the <choice><orig>commitee</orig><reg>committee</reg></choice> and <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> 340th birthday, a memorial with all the appropriate attributes, made by <name type="person">Otto Lessing</name> was build forhim.</s>
        <s>On <date>23rd April 1904</date> is was initiated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Today, the memorial is part of the <name type="misc">Unesco-Weltkulturerbe</name>, and has been since <date>1998</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Concluding, <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> found his way into German literature through <name type="person">Christoph Martin Wieland</name> and his highly celebrated, throughout <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>He is especially honored in <name type="geo">Weimar</name>.</s>
        <s>I would love to hear your opinion on this topic in the comments!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
