<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l10_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">blog</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> Conquest of <name type="geo">Germany</name></s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>By John Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>I am sure that everyone has heard of <name type="person">William Shakespeare</name> at least once in their lifetime.</s>
        <s>And when I say everyone, I mean people with different languages in different countries.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has a global impact which is why today, I am focusing on my home country <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>It would make sense to not only look at the origin of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> work in <name type="geo">Germany</name>, but also determine the relationship between the city of origin called <name type="geo">Weimar</name> and the poet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Christoph Martin Wieland</name> translated, as the first <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> ever, Shakespearean drama in <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> language.</s>
        <s>22 of those dramas were published in <name type="geo">Zürich</name> between <date>1762</date> and <date>1766</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>furthermore, there <choice><orig>has</orig><reg>have</reg></choice> been found traces of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> innovation in literature, written by well-known <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> poets, like <name type="person">Lessing</name>, <name type="person">Goethe</name> and <name type="person">Herder</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition <name type="person">Goethe</name>, <name type="person">Herder</name> and <name type="person">Wieland</name> were forming the <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> <name type="misc">Shakespeare Renaissance</name>, which found its way towards the German city <name type="geo">Weimar</name>.</s>
        <s>At this place the oldest literary organization of <name type="geo"><choice><orig>germany</orig><reg>Germany</reg></choice></name> was formed in <date>1864</date> called the <name type="misc">Shakespeare Organization</name></s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">William Shakespeare</name> was welcomed with open arms in the city of <name type="geo">Weimar</name>.</s>
        <s>His works were presented at the <name type="geo">Weimarer Hof Theater</name>, which led to the unification of the <name type="misc">Verein der Shakespeare Freunde</name>, an association on <date>8th April 1864</date>.</s>
        <s>Tendant <name type="person">Franz von Dingelstedt</name> directed a cycle of historic dramas during that time, which had such a big impact on society, to form the <name type="misc">Shakespeare Organization</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Later on, at the 40th anniversary of the organization and the 340th birthday of <name type="person">William Shakespeare</name>, the first ever <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> memorial in Europe was built by <name type="person">Otto Lessing</name> and the <name type="geo">Ilmpark</name> in <name type="geo">Weimar</name>.</s>
        <s>This action show the great honor <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is given by the <name type="geo">Weimar</name> people and how his person and his work will live on in their memories.</s>
        <s>It now becomes clear that this poet had a big impact on our literature by inspiring German poets as well as the people of <name type="geo">Weimar</name> and opening wider aspects of German literature.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Enough said.</s>
        <s>Now is your turn to tell me, how <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> was introduced in your country.</s>
        <s>Please use the comment section for your ideas.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For those of you who want to get a little bit more informed, here is the used source: <ref target="a12lk1_2" type="title">Wie Shakespeares Denkmal in den Weimarer Ilmpark kam</ref> by <ref target="a12lk1_2" type="author">Worlfgang Hirsch</ref>, <date>24th April 2016</date>, <name type="misc">Thüringer Allgemeine</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
