<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>a12l03_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></name> way of conveying the emotion of love to his audience is <choice><orig>definetly</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> one of his most loved aspects as a poet.</s>
        <s>In the following there is going to be discussed how he deals with this topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> way of writing is not really loyal to the Patriarchan ideal or even the original form of a sonnet which came from <name type="geo">Italy</name>.</s>
        <s>Being somewhat of a rebel,<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> created his own form of a sonnet and more importantly: the unusual way of describing love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>especially when writing to the <name type="person">Dark Lady</name>,<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> portrayed love different from the ideal.</s>
        <s>He believed it could be mutual and concrete, and he described it way more human than it was ever described by anyone living in Elizabethan times.</s>
        <s>He did not reduce love to it's perfect form; he described it in all of its <choice><orig>facettes</orig><reg>facets</reg></choice> with all its flaws and imperfections, while also describing the woman <choice><orig>adressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> in his sonnets as ugly, and loyal, even reeking of smell nothing like the ideal.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>a good example for his way of writing is Sonnet 130, which we've discussed in class.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>by doing so,<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> creates his own, very special way of describing the emotion of love and thereby winning the <choice><orig>audiences</orig><reg>audience's</reg></choice> interests or hearts over.</s>
        <s>Although it doesn't always have to be filled with flaws, the poet manages to accurately illustrate the emotion; accurately enough to still be relevant in modern times, while being dead since the beginning of the 17th century.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The same can be said about Sonnet 18 as an example.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Eventhough</orig><reg>Even though</reg></choice> it is far more positively written then some other sonnets of his, it still has a quatrain solely describing the things that aren't perfect, making it complete.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion,<name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has his special way when working with the emotion of love.</s>
        <s>In my opinion, this is his secret of being one of the best poets to ever exist, along with his way of describing feelings extraordinary accurately with only words.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
