<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l15_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>To understand the message of the poem better, <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> deserves a closer analysis of the formal and poetic devices that<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses to illustrate and intensify his view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sonnet 138 follows its strict demands of a typical Shakespearean sonnet with its 14 lines, <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into three quatrains stating the <choice><orig>arguements</orig><reg>arguments</reg></choice> and a concluding couplet containing the main theme.</s>
        <s>The clear structure is helping the reader to understand the speaker's view better.</s>
        <s>This sonnet is written in an <name type="misc">abab cdcd efef gg</name> rhyme scheme, which makes it more poetic.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> follows the typical Shakespearean pattern in terms of the metric.</s>
        <s>The metrical pattern used is an iambic pentameter, which describes how one unstressed syllable is followed by a stressed syllable and just make the poem sound like a heartbeat.</s>
        <s>This makes the poem very emotional for the reader and <choice><orig>perfectally</orig><reg>perfectly</reg></choice> fits the themes of love and tie.</s>
        <s>Moreover, the metric illustrates that the poem is alive and meant to be presented.</s>
        <s>The Volta is given in line nine and changes the train of thought from stating the beloved one lies into questioning why she is lying about the youth of the speaker.</s>
        <s>The Volta creates suspense for the reader and makes them analyse it more deeply.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses many poetic devices to illustrate and intensify his view.</s>
        <s>The simile <quote>I do believe her, though I know she lies</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>, for example describes that the speaker believes his/her beloved woman, yet knows that she is lying, which he/she does not approve of, because the speaker believes that trust is love's best habit.</s>
        <s>This stylistic device is again found when the speaker states that <quote>although she knows my days are past the best</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>, meaning that the speaker knows that the woman he loves knows just as well as he/she does, that the speaker in not young anymore and thus does not experience the qualities of youth anymore.</s>
        <s>Both similes have the effect on the reader, that it creates an image in their mind about the character of the beloved person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, an antithesis is given <quote>But wherefore says she not that I am old?</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This poetic device is signalized by the word <quote>but</quote> and changes the train of though from knowing the beloved one is lying and accepting it, into questioning why she is doing do.</s>
        <s>This creates suspense for the reader and eventually makes them change their mind about the message of lying to the beloved one might <choice><orig>sooth</orig><reg>soothe</reg></choice> the speaker, but they will always know about it and know better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition, a <choice><orig>rethorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> question is given in the same line.</s>
        <s>As already mentioned, the speaker now starts questioning why the woman claims to be truthful, yet is an unjust <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the following line, another <choice><orig>rethorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> question is given, asking why the woman just <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> say the truth about the speaker being old.</s>
        <s>Here, the speaker is accusing his/her beloved person, knowing they are only lying to the speaker to make them feel better about <choice><orig>themself</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Both <choice><orig>rethorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> questions introduce the theme of confusion in the love relationship.</s>
        <s>They, as well, create suspense for the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, an alliteration is introduced: <quote>And age in love loves not to have years told</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The speaker explains how love is timeless with this person he/she is writing about.</s>
        <s>Through this alliteration, the reader realizes the importance of the theme of love in this sentence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally,<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses a <choice><orig>parallism</orig><reg>parallelism</reg></choice>, when the speaker states that the woman, as well as he/she know from each other that they are lying <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 13)</ref> instead of stopping the game of lies, they continue and lie with each other.</s>
        <s>Through this alliteration, the speaker stresses the theme of lying in the love relationship and helps the reader to understand their intense view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude,<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses the formal and poetic devices to illustrate and to instensify his view on the topic.</s>
        <s>The main theme is love, however time and lying to a beloved person are also important themes.</s>
        <s>In this sonnet, <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> fear of getting older is strongly shown.</s>
        <s>Summing up, the speaker states that both of them, him/her and the woman described in the poem know that they lie at each other, thus lie with each other and play up the game of flattering each other through lies.</s>
        <s>It seems like the speaker wants to show the reader that lying does not work in a relationship and only causes both parties to suffer.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
