<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l12_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In order to deliver the message, which is demonstrating that love is possible no matter the age and hiding the reality is acceptable,<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref><choice><orig>make</orig><reg>makes</reg></choice> use of various format and poetic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly, analysing the structure of the poem, it becomes clear that <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref> is constructed typically for a Shakespearean sonnet.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>fourteen lined</orig><reg>fourteen-lined</reg></choice> poem includes three quatrains and a concluding couplet.</s>
        <s>The metric is also no different from his other sonnets, following an iambic pentameter, with five stressed and five unstressed syllables in each line.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Throughout the <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref>, one can detect a constant rhyme scheme <name type="misc">abab cdcd efef</name>, only changing in the last two lines, ending the poem with a pair rhyme <name type="misc">gg</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This typical form is also intensifying the message.</s>
        <s>As metric, rhyme scheme and structure are constant, it demonstrates the constant nature of time.</s>
        <s>Just as time, the three components are consistent and not changing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Time plays an <choice><orig>inderect</orig><reg>indirect</reg></choice>, but major role in this sonnet as it is readon for the age gap between the lovers, establishing differences and creating the need for lying to each other.</s>
        <s>Additionally, the iambic pentameter can imitate the sound of a clock supporting the idea of time playing a big role in the relationship of the speaker and his beloved person.</s>
        <s>Moreover, the iambic pentameter can also demonstrate a <choice><orig>heart beat</orig><reg>heartbeat</reg></choice>, the sound of love, which is also an important subject in his message.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As regards the stylistic devices, the author starts with an antithesis <quote>I do believe her, though [...] she lies</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Making clear that the speaker is trusting and believing in his partner, <choice><orig>even though</orig><reg>eventhough</reg></choice> he is aware of the lie.</s>
        <s>This raises attention and the reader is confused, because <choice><orig>belivieng</orig><reg>believing</reg></choice> and lying are contrast verbs.</s>
        <s>The contrast can be also <choice><orig>interpretated</orig><reg>interpreted</reg></choice> as an oxymoron, because of the irritating use of the verbs, asking the recipient how someone can believe in a person, if she is not being honest.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Further on,<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> utilizes an alliteration to show that not only the narrator knows secrets of the partner, but the partner him/herself is <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> aware of the narrator's false age.</s>
        <s><quote>Thinking that she thinks</quote><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> demonstrates the complex relationship and the secrets within it.</s>
        <s>The addressee is forced to think about this uneasy construct, read twice or <choice><orig>extremly</orig><reg>extremely</reg></choice> concentrate on the performance to understand what<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> wants to convey.</s>
        <s>It shows how intertwined and connected the personal of the poem and his partner are.</s>
        <s>They both know what is going on in the head of the other and what they think about each other without even communicating through words, but understanding the concerns and feelings silently, which also supports the thesis that lying in this situation is not problematic and not necessarily ruining love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To show who is really the problem of the situation<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> makes use of the personification <quote>age in love loves [...] years told</quote> <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By giving age human attributes like loving or hearing, he makes the age difference, time, a guilty figure who is the one forcing the couple to his truth and being <choice><orig>disshonest</orig><reg>dishonest</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Similarly, the personification is line 7 <quote>false speaking tongue</quote> points out that not the beloved is talking, sharing lies, but the <quote>tongue</quote> itself is guilty of untrue words.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
