<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l19_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following it is going to be analysed how<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> makes use of poetic and formal devices to intensify and illustrate his view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>beginning with a formal aspects one can say that this sonnet is a typical Shakespearean sonnet.</s>
        <s>It has 14 lines and is <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into three quatrains and an ending couplet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first twelve lines are cross rhymes <name type="misc">(abab cdcd efef)</name> and the couplet consists of a pair rhyme <name type="misc">(gg)</name>.</s>
        <s>A typical device for a Shakespearean sonnet is the iambic pentameter, which means that the verse starts with an unstressed syllable, followed by a stressed one.</s>
        <s>In a sentence are five unstressed and five stressed syllables.</s>
        <s>This makes the sonnet emotional, because it sounds like a heartbeat.</s>
        <s>The turning point, the so called <quote>Volta</quote> is located in l. 9 <quote>But</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first poetic device takes place in l. 2, which is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> antithesis <quote>I do believe her, though I know she lies</quote>.</s>
        <s>This stands for the trust of the person to the female persons though he knows that she is a liar.</s>
        <s>The effect on the eeader is that the conflict yets underlined by saying that he believes her still.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore the author employs a rhetorical question in l. 9 <quote>But wherefore says she not she is unjust?</quote> It makes clear that it would be unlogical, when she says that she is a liar or unjust, because it throws a bad light on herself.</s>
        <s>The rhetorical question arranges that the reader gets directly addressed and also gets influenced.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, the next sentence is also a rhetorical question in l. 10 <quote>And wherefore say not I that I am old?</quote>.</s>
        <s>This means that he/she questions his/herself, why he <choice><orig>do</orig><reg>does</reg></choice> not tell the trust about his age.</s>
        <s>A direct address gets created again.</s>
        <s>The reader feels influenced, because of the question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The repetition of the word <quote>wherefore</quote> in ll. 9-10 <quote><s>But wherefore says she not she is unjust?</s><s>And wherefore say not I that I am old?</s></quote> shows his train of thought.</s>
        <s>The author does this to enrich the meaning of the two questions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides, the author utilizes a metaphor in l. 6 <quote>Although she knows my days are past the best</quote>.</s>
        <s>He explains that his best time is ago and that he collected experiences.</s>
        <s>This creates an image in the mind of the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By making use of an antithesis, it is said that the lyrical eye gives her still credits, though she lies with him <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This antithesis underlines the conflict that he believes her, though she lies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote><s>And wherefore say not I that I am old?</s><s> [...] And age in love loves not to have years told</s></quote> is an anaphora in <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">ll. 10-12</ref>.</s>
        <s>The author wants to explain that the age does not play a major role in a relationship.</s>
        <s>The effect on the reader is that this anaphora emphasizes a thought.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all one can say that a<ref target="a12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> wants to intensify his views with antithesis, <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">repititiong</gap> rhetorical questions, anaphoras and metaphors.</s>
        <s>He wants to express that two persons have to trust the other person and that age is not important in a relationship.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
