<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>a12l11_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As I've read a lot of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> sonnets and informed myself about his work and life, how he deals with the theme of love, time and beatury is incredible.</s>
        <s>He has around 256 sonnets and 156 is about a man named <quote>fair youth</quote>, which is in love with the <quote>Dark Lady</quote>.</s>
        <s>The way he explains this love in his sonnets and the way he uses his typical Shakespearean language to underline this feeling of ove, is really inspiring.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to theme of love he wrote all his language but also because of the imagination of love he creates in his sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his most famous sonnet, Sonnet 18 or <quote>Shall I compare thee to a summer's day</quote> he compares love with a summer's day.</s>
        <s>Moreover, he tries to make the reader to imagine a summer's day and use his sense of smelling or seing in order to keep his poem alove everytime somebody reads it and to feel love.</s>
        <s>I am truly inspired by his work, by his typical language, how he tells a story in his sonnets with his writing style.</s>
        <s>And I'm truly sure that I'm not the only person, who he has inspired, because there are a lot of world's great artists that have been inspired by the Shakespearean lover.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
