<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l07_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20210927</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In order to understand the true meaning of the <ref target="a12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 138</ref>, the poem deserces a closer analysis of language and imagery, as well of the <choice><orig>stucuture</orig><reg>structure</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sonnet 138 follows its strict demands for Shakespearean sonnets, with its 14 lines, <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into three <choice><orig>quartrains</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> presenting its <choice><orig>argument's</orig><reg>arguments</reg></choice> and a concluding couplet <choice><orig>containg</orig><reg>containing</reg></choice> the main theme.</s>
        <s>This structure helps the reader to understand the poem better.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, this sonnet is written in an <name type="misc">abab cdcd efef gg</name> rhyme scheme which makes the poem more poetic.</s>
      </p>
      <p><s>Moreover the metrical pattern follows an <choice><orig>Iambic</orig><reg>iambic</reg></choice> pentameter, which describes how one unstressed <choice><orig>sylable</orig><reg>syllable</reg></choice> is followed by a <choice><orig>stresed</orig><reg>stressed</reg></choice> syllable and that makes the poem sound like a heartbeat.</s><s>This metric makes the sonnet very emotional and fits the theme of love <choice><orig>perfectally</orig><reg>perfectly</reg></choice>.</s><s>Additionally it symbolizes that the sonnet is alive and meant to be presented.</s><s>The volta is given in line 9, which is also typical, it changes the <choice><orig>Argument</orig><reg>argument</reg></choice>, that his love is <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">trjing</gap> into the true meaning of a relationshio and what <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> about, That creates suspense for the reader.</s><s>But the narrator <choice><orig>intensifys</orig><reg>intensifies</reg></choice> his view not only with the sonnets structure, but with his language and imagery.</s><s>For <choice><orig>exampe</orig><reg>example</reg></choice> the repetition of words and structure in <choice><orig>line's</orig><reg>lines</reg></choice> nine and ten.</s><quote><s>But wherefore says she not she is unjust?</s><s>And wherefore say not I that I am old?</s></quote>. <s>This repetition is about the speaker questioning himself, why his beloved one is lying about him.</s><s>This <choice><orig>intensifys</orig><reg>intensifies</reg></choice> the meaning of the Volta, <choice><orig>beause</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> the narrator needs a lot of pressure to understand why his love is lying.</s><s>It is because of the strong relationship with trust.</s><s>Furthermore his feeling gets <choice><orig>intensifyd</orig><reg>intensified</reg></choice> with a late anaphora.</s><s><quote>And... And... And...</quote><ref target="a12lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 10-14)</ref>.</s><s>The word <quote>And</quote> gets repeated in every new <choice><orig>thougth</orig><reg>thought</reg></choice>.</s><s>That creates a feeling of the speaker really understanding the true meaning behind his love.</s><s>After the volta he <choice><orig>seem's</orig><reg>seems</reg></choice> to <choice><orig>geting</orig><reg>getting</reg></choice> new ideas, or <choice><orig>seem's</orig><reg>seems</reg></choice> to understand why his loved one is not telling the truth.</s><s>Moreover in line 17 one can find an <choice><orig>alitaration</orig><reg>alliteration</reg></choice>.</s><s><quote>And age in love loves not to have years told</quote>.</s><s>This <choice><orig>alitaration</orig><reg>alliteration</reg></choice> is created, due to the fact that the speaker calls his beloved person just with <quote>love</quote>, but it <choice><orig>intensifys</orig><reg>intensifies</reg></choice> the feeling of true love and how trustworthy the loved one is for the speaker.</s><s>On the other hand there is a stylistic device in line 3. <quote>untutor'd youth</quote>.</s><s>That is kind of doubled, because if you are in your youth you are unexperienced due to your age, but this creates more of the feeling how the speaker thinks about his beloved one before the volta.</s></p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, one can say that the narrator's feelings get clear in the sonnet.</s>
        <s>At first the speaker does not know what to think about his relationship, but through the poem it gets pretty clear due to a really strong volta.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
