<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12g17_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to analyse in how far the strucuture and language of the sonnet <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 116</ref> supports the speaker's idea of love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sonnet has the usual Shakespearean strucuture.</s>
        <s>It contains three quatrains and one couplet in the end.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This structure is underlined by the changing theme in each quatrain or couplet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first line, there is a metaphor.</s>
        <s><quote>Let me not to the marriage of true minds</quote><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This metaphor has the effect, that the reader gets confused, because normally everybody wants true minds, but in this case the speaker <choice><orig>don't</orig><reg>doesn't</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This effect gets underlined by the metaphor because a marriage is a very important event fo everybody.</s>
        <s>The confusion of the reader gets bigger.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second line there is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> antithesis, which makes the reader more interested in the idea of live of the speaker, because this antithesis <quote>love is not love</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> makes the confusion of the reader even bigger.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By describing love as something that doesn't bend or <choice><orig>alters</orig><reg>alter</reg></choice> even if the person does <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 3f.)</ref>, the reader gets a really strong impression of love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is something <choice><orig>unchangeble</orig><reg>unchangeable</reg></choice> and because of that something unreachable.</s>
        <s>After the speaker creates confusion, he describes love, by descirbing what love isn't.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By describing love as something that doesn't bend or <choice><orig>alters</orig><reg>alter</reg></choice>, even if the person does <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 3f)</ref>, the reader gets a really strong impression of love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is something <choice><orig>unchangeble</orig><reg>unchangeable</reg></choice> and because of that something unreachable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second quatrain the speaker compares love to an ever-fixed mark.</s>
        <s>He does this by using a metaphor <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 5)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that there is a personification in line six which underlines that love <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> be changed.</s>
        <s>.</s>
        <s>Even if love looks on a storm it never shaken <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore there is another metaphor <quote>It is the star to every wandering bark</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> which makes clear, that love is as important as a mark for barks.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This metaphor is followed by a contrast, which contains another metaphor.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By using the contrast the speaker describes love as something which is existing, but can't get defined exactly <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third quatrain is aboutthe timelessness of love and that love never changes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This quatrain starts with a personification <quote>love's not time's fool [...]</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> which leads into the topic of the quatrain.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the same line <choice><orig>ther</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> is a symbol <quote>rosy lips and cheeks</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> which stands for youth and love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These two stylistic devices create a contrast, because youth ends and changes but love doesn't.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The rest of the quatrain supports this idea of love, by underlining that love never changes, even if the sickle's <choice><orig>compas</orig><reg>compass</reg></choice> come <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Love doesn't change till death.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By the personification, <quote>But bears it out even to the edge of doom</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>, the immortality of love gets clear.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last couplet the speaker shows the reader how sure he is about his idea of love, by saying that something impossible happens if he is wrong.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speaker comares love to <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> ever-fixed mark and he uses a lot of words from a sea voyage which could stand for his longing to love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that it is conspicuous that he uses lots of personifications which could be a connection to a loved person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the structure and language support the speaker's idea of love, because the stylistic devices are underlining the importance of love and by using contrasts and metaphors which confuse the reader it gets clearer, that love can be defined.</s>
        <s>It is longing to love gets clear by his choice of words and the structure matches to the changing themes.</s>
        <s>In every quatrain or couplet the way of describing love is changing.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
