<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12g09_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>It is often discussed <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is important for today's young people or not.</s>
        <s>there are arguments for both sides of view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand, <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> and his achievements are national mnuments, especially for Britains.</s>
        <s>His described topics are timeless and still relevant today and are used in many new stories.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, he created many new words and sayings, for instance <quote>All that glitters is not gold</quote>, that are still popular today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So he is very important for the British and the general history.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand, his writings are 400 years old, this very difficult to understand for native and second-language <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> speakers.</s>
        <s>That causes that most of the students do not like to read his poems and dramas.</s>
        <s>Moreover, only a few, mostly older people, use the sayings he invented and so most of them are not known by young people.</s>
        <s>Last but not least, there exist many other stories today that are easier to understand and nevertheless interesting and important, maybe written about the same theme as <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> writings.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So altogether, <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is not relevant anymore, sometimes even disliked by the youth.</s>
        <s>But that is no reason to forget him and his writings because they are still actual and also beautiful written.</s>
        <s>So maybe the interest of young people could be awakened when the texts are teached in a more interactive way and then today's <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>For example, performing the stories on stage at school or simply letting the students writing poems on their own, and everyone would have fun while talking about <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>So the cars for the shrinking relevance of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> are not his texts but the way the young people get in touch with them.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
