<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12g13_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The poem <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 116</ref> was written by <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>It's about his love to the dark lady, that many sonnet sof his are about.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first <choice><orig>quadrain</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> the narrator talks about his love to the dark lady.</s>
        <s>He says they haven't been able to stay together not to get married even though he wanted to cause there were <choice><orig>obstacle</orig><reg>obstacles</reg></choice> in their way.</s>
        <s>His love for the dark lady is not that kind of love that vanishes or changes even if the circumstances change.</s>
        <s>He'll always hold on to that love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second <choice><orig>quadrain</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> starts <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> by the narrator underlining that his love's going to hold on forever.</s>
        <s>Even storms couldn't bring his love to struggle.</s>
        <s>It's as bright as a star witha value that's priceless though his love is measurable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third and last <choice><orig>quadrain</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> the narrator imagines the lips and cheeks of the dark lady and wishes <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">lirne</gap> to never pass.</s>
        <s>But the death is coming for everybody though the love will never vanish nor fade away.</s>
        <s>It will always stay the same.</s>
        <s>Even till the edge of doom his love will hold on.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the final couplet the narrator finishes by telling that if he's proven wrong, no man has ever written nor loved.</s>
        <s>By saying that he's showing that he can't be proven wrong cause his love really is all these things he's described before.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
