<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12g08_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will <choice><orig>dicuss</orig><reg>discuss</reg></choice> the relevance of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> for young people today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still relevant because he invented new words and phrases, for example <quote>all that glitters is not gold</quote>, which are still relevant and get used today.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Futhermore</orig><reg>Furthermore</reg></choice> he influenced the <choice><orig>englisch</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> culture with his plays and sonnets.</s>
        <s>Young people can learn something over their country and maybe try to understand traditions which been invented by Shakespeare.</s>
        <s>On the one <choice><orig>Hand</orig><reg>hand</reg></choice> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> work deals with topics which are still relevant today, for example love, jealousy or family dramas, so it can help young people to overcome these things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other <choice><orig>Hand</orig><reg>hand</reg></choice> he deals <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> with topics <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> you would normally deal with today, because at that time, for example <choice><orig>woman</orig><reg>women</reg></choice> hadn't as much rights as they have today and were seen in a <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> way.</s>
        <s>To add is that that the language is obsolete because <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has written his work over 400 years ago <choice><orig>therefor</orig><reg>therefore</reg></choice> the language is very difficult to understand and the risk is higher that you <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice> interest in his plays.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To solve this <choice><orig>negativ</orig><reg>negative</reg></choice> aspects and make <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> more interesting again you can try to adapt his plays to today so that more young people want to see them.</s>
        <s>A <choice><orig>got</orig><reg>good</reg></choice> example for this <choice><orig>Adaption</orig><reg>adaption</reg></choice> is for example the movie <name type="misc">Romeo and Juliet</name> which is inspired by <choice><orig>Shakespears</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice> work.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Futhermore</orig><reg>Furthermore</reg></choice> it could be good to deal with <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> in class so that students know why <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still relevant and learn something about him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand it is maybe not good to force young people to deal with him because it could lead them to <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice> interest in him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum it up you can say that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still elevant for young people because he invented many words and phrases we still use today and he is imporant for the culture.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand the language he uses is very difficult to understand and because of that his plays are not really intersting for young people today.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
