<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g13_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still very relevant but also irrelevant at the same time.</s>
        <s>He himself as a person is still very relevant today but his work's relevance is just to a certain extent.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> as a person is very relevant and a huge historical figure because he's benefitted so much to the <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> language as a whole.</s>
        <s>So many words he's made up are still being used to this day.</s>
        <s>Without the influence of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> the <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> language as we know it today would be way poorer in diversity.</s>
        <s>Even though many words of his aren't being used anymore he's benefitted quite a lot.</s>
        <s>Even many quotes from <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> plays are being used as sayings today.</s>
        <s>For example <quote>fight fire with fire</quote> or <quote>not everything that glitters is gold</quote> are such quotes being used today.</s>
        <s>One can say that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has enriched the <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> by a lot.</s>
        <s>On the other hands many people don't believe that a common peasant like <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> would've been able to even come up with everything he's come up with.</s>
        <s>Many believe that it's all been written by a nobleman under <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> name because being a poet wasn't really a well-suited confession at the time.</s>
        <s>This sort of behaviour isn't something that young people should or could learn from in any way.</s>
        <s>In my opinion <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> as a person is a very big historical figure and should be teached in school even for young people cause he's still relevant up to this day as mentioned before.</s>
        <s>The work of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is a whole different thing though.</s>
        <s>For most young people including me <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> work is very hard to understand.</s>
        <s>It just gets annoying and doesn't really educate because most of the language is just so outdated and hard to understand.</s>
        <s>The topics addressed in most of his work is still relevant today but nobody really benefits anyone if they're not able to understand it due to <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> language.</s>
        <s>I do believe though that simplified versions of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> work should even get taught to younger people so they can evaluate their relevance today themselves and they don't have to worry about not understanding the core of it.</s>
        <s>I even think that even the harer to understand original work of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> should be taught at school but only to those who want it.</s>
        <s>In the higher classes students should be able to decide if they want to focus on <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> literature for example or something else.</s>
        <s>by giving this choice only those people who really want to read <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> work will be able to do so in class.</s>
        <s>Even though it's hard to understand, the work of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still relevant to this day and it should be treated so.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> may not have a relevance as huge for young young people as it had 100 years ago but he's still relevant to a certain extent.</s>
        <s>This relevance will probably still be for a longtime but students, especially young students should be able to get introduced to him in a way lighter way than they are today.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
