<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12g16_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to analyse <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 116</ref> with special regard to the way of structure and language and how it supports the speaker's idea of love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first quatrain <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> talks about what love not is for him.</s>
        <s>He says that love not <quote>alter when it alteration finds</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He explains that even if something or somebody changes in your life the love does not.</s>
        <s>In his opinion love is mortal.</s>
        <s>He underlines this by saying that the love does not move with the people who move <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 4)</ref> because love stays and gets stronger until the end of your life and that nothing can change this.</s>
        <s>In this quatrain he uses two alliterations to compare love and time to underline the contrast of both because he uses for example the alliteration that love does not <quote>alter when it alteration finds</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>, so that the alteration of somebody or something does not influence the strength of the love.</s>
        <s>In contrast to the first quatrain the poet talks in the second quatrain about what love is.</s>
        <s>He starts with <quote>O no!</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> to outline his opinion clearly and to show that love is completely different to everything else in out life that fades and ends or changes by time.</s>
        <s>He describes love as <quote>an ever-fixed mark</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this metaphor he wants to explain that love is a guide for your life like a mark which shows you the right way.</s>
        <s>Love gives you stability in life <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He also uses personification to show this because he says that it <quote>looks on tempests</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Love cannot look on some thing but he wants to underline the similarities between love and the mark and that love <choice><orig>let</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> you see the way even in a storm.</s>
        <s>He goes on by saying again that love is as the star to ships <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> so he makes clear the love opens our eyes and shows us the right way even in dark times.</s>
        <s>He also mentions that its <quote>worth [is] unknown</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> with which he wants to say that love has no value but gives so much and helps many people.</s>
        <s>He underlines his thesis with the alliteration <quote>whose worth</quote> to outline the unknown value of love similarly to a guiding star.</s>
        <s>The poet uses in the whole quatrain many metaphors <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 5, l. 7,...)</ref> which all depends on one main metaphor.</s>
        <s>Love as a guiding star for ships.</s>
        <s>For him love guides you through your life and makes you even stronger when time changes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third quatrain starts with what love not is again.</s>
        <s>Because <quote>love's not time's fool</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This metaphor should show the love does not depend on time and that it is immortal, while everything changes and besides it is also a personification because love cannot be a fool.</s>
        <s>This should make clear that love does not go after time and it's not like all the other things in life because love is not influenced by time and change.</s>
        <s>In addition to that he uses an antithesis so that even if your loved one changes by time love does not change and that <quote>rosy lips and cheeks</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> are part of love but nevertheless love does not alters <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll 10f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>These <quote>rosy lips</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> should explain how beautiful love is but also that they can fade but this beauty of the outside nothing of your love changes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally the lyrical I says that <quote>love alters not with this brief hours and weeks</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> like nature or something else because love is special and different.</s>
        <s>While everything alters and changes is love an eternal process.</s>
        <s>This gets clear when the poet uses the antithesis that love does not <choice><orig>alters</orig><reg>alter</reg></choice> <quote>but bears it out even to the edge of doom</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This should show that love holds on until the day of God's <choice><orig>judgement</orig><reg>judgment</reg></choice> or the day of death which shows that it stays at least until you die, which describes again how strong love could be.</s>
        <s>The poet is of the opinion that in contrast to life or nature or something else love does not end until you die or even after your death until the day of <choice><orig>judgement</orig><reg>judgment</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The closing couplet deals with the topic that if this watch <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> <choice><orig>talks</orig><reg>talk</reg></choice> about is not true he <quote>never writ not no man ever loved</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 13, 14)</ref> because his love is based on what he thinks.</s>
        <s>In his opinion it has to be that love huides and that true love never changes no matter what happens.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also mentions that when no man ever loved <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 14)</ref> because he thinks that every man thinks about love like this and that there was no true love in life when his thoughts are proven wrong.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speaker's idea of love, so love as a guiding star and as immortal, gets strongly supported by language as explained before.</s>
        <s>The speaker often says <quote>love is not</quote> <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 2, l. 9, l. 11)</ref> to make clear that the picture of love what people have in their mind is wrong and also that love is not like other things we know because love does not alter which makes love very special.</s>
        <s>But also the structure of the sonnet supports it very well.</s>
        <s>The three quatrains, each of them have four lines, are changing in topic.</s>
        <s>The first quatrain should show the contrast of love to every changing and ending thing in life.</s>
        <s>In contrast to this the second quatrain talks about the speaker's idea of love and what love actually is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then he talks about what love is not again in the third quatrain to underline the power of love described in the second quatrain.</s>
        <s>The closing couplet sums up the sonnet and should show that the speaker believes in what he says and the true love is what he wants to show in his sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the sonnet deals with love as a landmark.</s>
        <s>The main topic is that love is immortal and does not alter.</s>
        <s>Love gives you stability in life and does not change which is all supported by language and also by structure of the poem.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
