<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g11_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In our today's generation, <choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice> will be teached in school.</s>
        <s>But most of the students get bored and don't know why it still will be teached.</s>
        <s>In the following I will discuss <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> relevance for young people today.</s>
        <s>Therefore I will mention pros and cons.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One benefit is that the themes, like love, hat, greed, jealousy and so <choice><orig>one</orig><reg>on</reg></choice>, are timeless.</s>
        <s>So the themes are today similar.</s>
        <s>One point against the teaching is, that the works are hard to understand, because it is very old and the language and structure have changed during the 400 years.</s>
        <s>It also doesn't help the students advance in life.</s>
        <s>On the one hand you can learn much about history, but on the other hand the works do not connect to today's controversial issues because they were written so long ago.</s>
        <s>And for the fact that the works from <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> are very old, reading <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> work will not teach the reader any conventional English.</s>
        <s>Furthermore <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is <choice><orig>on</orig><reg>one</reg></choice> of the famous person and has some of the best poetry and best plays in English but the plays of him works better on stage, because they an for example better express the feelings and the intention.</s>
        <s>I had mentioned that the works are hard to understand, but the language is less important thatn the content of the works.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I would say that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> relevance for young people today is not that much important, because they don't really understand the language and therefore they don't get the intention.</s>
        <s>The young people are also less <choice><orig>interrested</orig><reg>interested</reg></choice> and do not have fun on <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> works.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
