<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g35_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence starts with a medium-close up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa</ref> sitting happily next to each other while <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Mav</ref> wants to start praying.</s>
        <s>During the beginning of the scene everyone looks very happy, which we can tell by multiple close ups from every family member smiling or laughing.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> even says <quote>Thankful for my family</quote> at the prayer and everyone agrees with that.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>peacf.ll</orig><reg>peaceful</reg></choice> and calm mood from the scene is also represented through the fact that the viewers can hear silent and slow music in the background which reminds of yoga or some relaxing things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And even though there are a lot of cuts at the beginning it still doesn't seem hectic because the camera pands very slow to each family member over and over again.</s>
        <s>Moving <choice><orig>foreward</orig><reg>forward</reg></choice> in the scene we are able to recognize through a close-up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> face, which helps us focus on her expressions, that she is looking out of the window and her mood changes from happy to shocked in just one second.</s>
        <s>Out of the window we can see <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> standing in the middle from to other <choice><orig>man</orig><reg>men</reg></choice> at his car.</s>
        <s>His body language shows his serious and threatening attitude against <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Mavs</orig><reg>Mav's</reg></choice></ref> family because <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> snitched his drug dealing <choice><orig>buisness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice> the other day.</s>
        <s>The viewers are able to see him at a mid long shot from a person at the <choice><orig>restaurants</orig><reg>restaurant's</reg></choice> point of view at first.</s>
        <s>Because of this chosen camera shot and angle the director wanted to pointed cut that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> was standing there very dominant and you could even tell from far away that he is angry not just from <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> closer point of view.</s>
        <s>Also as soon as <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> recognizes <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> the music <choice><orig>changs</orig><reg>changes</reg></choice> into something more deep and dramatic so that the viewers can feel the dramaticness and mood changes in the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carter</ref> <choice><orig>Family</orig><reg>family</reg></choice> face.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> storms out <choice><orig>argessivly</orig><reg>aggressively</reg></choice> and angry the <choice><orig>viewers</orig><reg>viewer's</reg></choice> curiosity is <choice><orig>ewaked</orig><reg>awakened</reg></choice> and everyone wants to see what comes next.</s>
        <s>When he reaches <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> he feels provocated and beats him against his expensive car.</s>
        <s>He then gets in trouble with the other two <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King Lords</ref> and these scenes are shown to us with a mid shot to emphasize that they are only pushing each other and don't have a gun or another <choice><orig>wapon</orig><reg>weapon</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Through a light pan in the left direction the viewers can see and hear a police car which <choice><orig>turnes</orig><reg>turns</reg></choice> into their direction.</s>
        <s>Because of a presented long shot of the lane we are able to see that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and his two mates got away at time and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> didn't.</s>
        <s>So when the <choice><orig>policer</orig><reg>police</reg></choice> car stops the cops are presented to us with a mid shot so that we can more focus on their looks.</s>
        <s>One of them is black and the other one white, which makes it even more shocking.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The black police officer pushes <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> against the window of the restaurant.</s>
        <s>It is shown to the viewer also from the inside of the restaurant so they can put themselves in the shoes of if they <choice><orig>where</orig><reg>were</reg></choice> eating there and how horrible it would be.</s>
        <s>The highest point of the scene isn't reached yet but it comes when the black officer pushes <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> with his face on the ground.</s>
        <s>With the close-up to help us we can see how <choice><orig>unsuprised</orig><reg>unsurprised</reg></choice> <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Mavericks</orig><reg>Maverick's</reg></choice></ref> reaction is because he is sadly used to it but his three kids and his wife <choice><orig>where</orig><reg>were</reg></choice> all shocked and reached the point where they just couldn't just sit and don't help.</s>
        <s>This part of the scene also appears more hectic to us because of the many angles and perspectives.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> leaves the restaurant with presented in a rush presented in a mid-long shot with her mother following her to give the wallet.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> 2 <choice><orig>brother</orig><reg>brothers</reg></choice> also come outside.</s>
        <s>As the viewer can see through the windows, where <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is standing right before, we can see that there are a lot of people watching and saying but stuff to the police.</s>
        <s>And even though we can see that there are almost just black people at the <choice><orig>restaurante</orig><reg>restaurant</reg></choice> there a few white ones which are <choice><orig>argreeing</orig><reg>agreeing</reg></choice> with <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, who is currently filming the situation.</s>
        <s>With an over-shoulder shot we can see the shocked police man slowly letting <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> go because he doesn't want evidence of his behavior.</s>
        <s>When the officer gets <choice><orig>ups</orig><reg>up</reg></choice> the camera gets down to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>, which makes it appear at this was <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> phone and the viewer <choice><orig>feel</orig><reg>feels</reg></choice> more bonded to the situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As soon as the cops are gone because they were getting filmed by <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and all of the other people, we see a close up of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Sekani</ref> crying, because he never was in that kind of situation before and he was so overwhelmed with his dad laying on the ground an the police.</s>
        <s>I think this could be a <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">stav</gap> to the reference from <name type="misc">Tupac</name> which <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref> <choice><orig>explainend</orig><reg>explained</reg></choice> earlier in the movie: <quote>The hate you give little infants fucks everybody</quote>.</s>
        <s>The situation cooled down a bit and the music changed to how it was at the beginning, calm and <choice><orig>peacf.l</orig><reg>peaceful</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But I think all in all this scene wasn't <choice><orig>peacf.l</orig><reg>peaceful</reg></choice> which was clearly presented by the shots which shows that not everyone is racist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>and</orig><reg>And</reg></choice> especially the close ups with the worried faces.</s>
        <s>The whole situation also seemed kind of spooky because it was dark outside and at night always the worst things happen, like <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref> getting shot.</s>
        <s>It kind of gives the same vibe because the darkness and the police car light.</s>
        <s>The viewers just hope that no one gets shot again.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
