<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g33_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given sequence is very important because it shows the police brutality in the <name type="geo">USA</name> and the situation black people have to deal with.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene starts with an establishing shot to show an overview of the situation.</s>
        <s>One can see <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and her family sitting at a table in a restaurant.</s>
        <s>The camera walks from one person to the other.</s>
        <s>There are many close up shots from different family members to see their facial expressions.</s>
        <s>The conversation is dominated by over the shoulder shots because they are a typical way of presenting a conversation.</s>
        <s>It makes you feel almost as if you're the one who is spoken to and it creates an intimate atmosphere.</s>
        <s>The <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Carter's</orig><reg>Carters</reg></choice></ref> look happy as a family.</s>
        <s>This reinforce the happy sounds which are played at the beginning of the scene.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks outside the happy sounds stop playing.</s>
        <s>Instead there is a dramatic sound playing in the background which makes the sequence more thrilling.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> head turns in slow motion in the direction of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> which makes the sequence more dangerous and exciting.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> father, walks out of the restaurant towards <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>, the music gets louder and louder.</s>
        <s>This creates an exciting atmosphere.</s>
        <s>Also the high number of cuts makes the scene appear more hectic and it builds up suspense.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When the police arrives <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and the gang members are already gone.</s>
        <s>It seems like <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> is scared.</s>
        <s>When the black officer pulls him to the ground <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and the other family members run outside.</s>
        <s>This moment in this sequence is very dynamic and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="director">George Tillmann Jr.</ref> <choice><orig>put</orig><reg>puts</reg></choice> a lot of effort into the direction.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When all the people record the situation, the officer is shown from a high angle perspective which makes him look very small.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When the police officers realise that they get filmed they leave very fast.</s>
        <s>This shows that they're powerless.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence is very important because it is about the main topic of the movie: police violence and racism.</s>
        <s>Black people have to fight for equal rights.</s>
        <s>They need to speak out for the same chances.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
