<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g21_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mister Johnson,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am writing this letter to you because about thirty years ago I read your speec at the <name type="misc">World Leaders Summit Opening Ceremony</name> about the climate crisis in class.</s>
        <s>At that time I was very impressed about your optimism.</s>
        <s>But you also thought about the future and the next generations.</s>
        <s>You were afraid of failing because of the anger of unborn humans.</s>
        <s>You did not forget them and were sure that you had the neccesary <choice><orig>possibilitys</orig><reg>possibilities</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Now, I am mother of two children, but they are not kids anymore.</s>
        <s>One of them is not living with me anymore, but the other one still goes to school.</s>
        <s>When they were born there was chaos in the world.</s>
        <s>Everyone was afraid of war because of the political situation and climate change was still a huge problem.</s>
        <s>Now I can say that the aims of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> are not reality yet, but can be very soon.</s>
        <s>So I thank you for your hope you gave my generation with your speech.</s>
        <s>We have no long-term solution, as you predicted, but there are on-going agreements.</s>
        <s>The raising temperature has been controlled in some ways.</s>
        <s>But I do not konw how the future of my kids is going to be.</s>
        <s>I am afraid!</s>
        <s>But your speech always gives me hope, that we can find the wire and stop the destroying device.</s>
        <s>You were a bit <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> optimistic!</s>
        <s>Thank you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Your sincerely, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
