<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g22_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Boris Johnson,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last years were very hard for everybody on this planet.</s>
        <s>The droughts on the beginning and the tide at the ending.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I'm not <choice><orig>quiet</orig><reg>quite</reg></choice> sure why I am writing this letter to you.</s>
        <s>Maybe because I want to thank you.</s>
        <s>Yesterday as I told my little daughter a story about the time before the world started to go down, I remembered your speech at <name type="misc">COP26</name> that I read in my <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> class.</s>
        <s>I can't remember everything, but your statement.</s>
        <s>I think it's fantastic that next to all of the most <choice><orig>politicans</orig><reg>politicians</reg></choice> that have failed with their climate politic, there are or were some that saw the problem coming to us and tried to fight against it.</s>
        <s>This includes you.</s>
        <s>If we go back on the timeline we will find the point where the governments let us down, otherwise as you <choice><orig>warnt</orig><reg>warned</reg></choice>, where our technology was at his highest level and couldn't change anything and where the most NGOs has left us alone.</s>
        <s>Maybe everything could have went different and we weren't here where we are now.</s>
        <s>Maybe if more people followed your warnings.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope there will b esomeone who sees and analyzed problems like you did and help us in our future.</s>
        <s>Thank you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Your Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
