<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g21_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Henry,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you're doing well.</s>
        <s>You send me an interesting newspaper article about my school going sustainable.</s>
        <s>The article was published on <date>November of 2019</date> in a famous local newspaper.</s>
        <s>It is about a new special day at my school that is only about climate and climate protection.</s>
        <s>The students can visit over 40 different workshops in school, but also in the whole city of <name type="geo">Cologne</name>.</s>
        <s>All of the workshops deal with climate protection.</s>
        <s>It was the first time that this took place at my school.</s>
        <s>Students and teachers have cooperated to create great workshops.</s>
        <s>A teacher at my school says that many students participated on demonstrations of the <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> movement in the last months and that the interest in political themes is rising.</s>
        <s>The topic is more present than ever.</s>
        <s>Because of this they founded this special day with many different offers, so that the students aren's <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> interest again because they think that they can't do anything about climate change.</s>
        <s>But actually there are many ways to be more responsible and sustainable.</s>
        <s>There were many different ideas for a climate-friendly lifestyle.</s>
        <s>For example <choice><orig>Foodsharing</orig><reg>food sharing</reg></choice>, using less water by just showering, second-hand shopping with used clothes and so on.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the students thought about how to sell fairtrade products at our school.</s>
        <s>There was a fairtrade <choice><orig>cafe</orig><reg>café</reg></choice>, where you could buy vegan cake or fair produced <choice><orig>caffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This was initiated by two students who are convinced by the project and want to show how delicious vegan food can be.</s>
        <s>Furthermore two poetry slammers visited our school.</s>
        <s>One of them <choice><orig>teached</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> the students about their voice and <choice><orig>pronouncitation</orig><reg>pronunciation</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This could help them in discussions for example about the climate.</s>
        <s>All in all the article says that everyone participated well and that the students were very interested.</s>
        <s>So the idea worked great, so that there maybe will be a next time.</s>
        <s>I will inform you if the project will take place next year.</s>
        <s>If you are interested you could mabye visit me and see it with your own eyes.</s>
        <s>I hope I could help you, if you have any questions left don't be afraid to text me.</s>
        <s>Have a great day.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Greetings from Germany, your friend Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
