<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g25_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Robert,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I'm glad to hear that you're well and surprised about some of the stuff you wrote in your e-mail.</s>
        <s>I would've never guessed that climate change is such a disregarded subject in the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
        <s>Even less that you have never been able to participate in a <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> protest.</s>
        <s>But it's nice that you're still interested in that subject, although it's not been presented to you that well.</s>
        <s>The article you told me about that talks of the project <name type="misc">School B goes green</name> that was done at my school a few years back is really interesting to me too because I myself hadn't known about some of the things that were done as part of it.</s>
        <s>The project was a day replacing normal class in which the students still all had to participate.</s>
        <s>It was created because of the massive importance climate change has gotten over here in <name type="geo">Europe</name>.</s>
        <s>The <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> protests in my city were every week and many students of my school participated.</s>
        <s>In the <choice><orig>Article</orig><reg>article</reg></choice> the author quotes a teacher, my former <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> teacher, about how the idea came up.</s>
        <s>Some of the student representatives were common participants of the protests and interested in the subject and because of that proposed to do something at our school regarding climate change.</s>
        <s>The organizers, mostly teachers and those student representatives, thought that it was a good idea because it would help grow <choice><orig>students</orig><reg>students'</reg></choice> political and social interest and engagement.</s>
        <s>The over 40 workshops offered on this day were very versatile.</s>
        <s>Examples given in the article are fairtrade food and drinks offered in the cafeteria and the <choice><orig>schools</orig><reg>school's</reg></choice> small shop or even second-hand clothing and thoughts about changes in lifestyle like showering instead of taking a bath to save water.</s>
        <s>A special workshop mentioned by the author is that of two poetry slam artists invited to the school to teach the students how to express themselves properly to help them in further discussions about climate change and to advocate their position.</s>
        <s>Even I remember the workshop I took part in that day although it was in <date>2019</date> now a long time ago.</s>
        <s>We went to the zoo to look at a project they have to save gorillas.</s>
        <s>Because their environment is destroyed to find rare <choice><orig>ressources</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice> to build microchips for phones they started a campaign to collect old phones to recycle.</s>
        <s>It was really interesting and sad at the same time to hear about what is done to these poor animals while watching them play right <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of you.</s>
        <s>We later returned to the school and implemented this project there.</s>
        <s>We build a container for recycled phones to put in our school.</s>
        <s>It was really interesting to hear afterwards what type of projects your friends did and with it getting to know how many sides climate change and with it <quote>going green</quote> meaning protecting the environment and fighting pollution has.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I explained it well enough for you to udnerstand a bit what that day was about.</s>
        <s>In the end the article says that the students participated very well and that they plan to do it again so you might even hear about it again.</s>
        <s>I unfortunately won't be there anymore to experience it again but hope it becomes a <choice><orig>stable</orig><reg>staple</reg></choice> at this school.</s>
        <s>Maybe if <choice><orig>your</orig><reg>you're</reg></choice> interested you could present this project in your school to raise awareness about the subject and interest in change.</s>
        <s>Hope we talk again before the holidays and if everything goes well I'll visit next year.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best wishes, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
