<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g22_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The speech can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into four paragraphs.</s>
        <s>In the first paragraph <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> talks baout his topic of the speech, the climate crisis by comparing it to <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> film.</s>
        <s>The main characters in it are the <quote>doomsday device</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>, a fictive bomb as a <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> for the climate crisis and the agent <name type="person">James Bond</name>, who is a <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> for the global leaders.</s>
        <s>To adress his idea of the climate crisis he uses a lot of including language <quote>everybody</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> or speaking in third person <quote>we know</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His <choice><orig>metaphoras</orig><reg>metaphors</reg></choice> are <choice><orig>ment</orig><reg>meant</reg></choice> to point out his view too.</s>
        <s>It's also easier for the people that are listening to think of the problem, if you can connect it with pictures in your mind, like in a film or movie.</s>
        <s>Although <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> compares the climate change with a fictive movie, he titled it as a <quote>tragedy</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref> and underlines that it is a real problem and that we don't live in a movie.</s>
        <s>The results of an <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">danjoure</gap> like a bomb or a crisis are the same.</s>
        <s>If one of them really happened, it will end in a catastrophic.</s>
        <s>In the second part <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> talks about his personal experiences of summits or political meetings about the climate crisis.</s>
        <s>He takes the listeneres back in the years by making an allusion to <name type="geo">Copenhagen</name> and <name type="geo">Paris</name> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 10f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He <choice><orig>reflect</orig><reg>reflects</reg></choice> the achievements they already made, for example that they acknowledged that climate is a problem or the agreement about the limit of 1.5 degrees in <name type="geo">Paris</name> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 10-13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Next to the achievements they already have made he <choice><orig>critizises</orig><reg>criticizes</reg></choice> that the promises that they are made are not going to <choice><orig>happened</orig><reg>happen</reg></choice> if there will be no action by the governments of the global leaders <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 13f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is the task of the <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
        <s>In the third paragraph he points out that the action we have to take are absolutely possible.</s>
        <s>He says, that we have the technology to end this catastrophic <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He gives the audience hope by showing the option to move ot green energy <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>But to reach this goal, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> says that it is important to get away of coal and using funds to help other <choice><orig>contries</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice> financial with it.</s>
        <s>It's the task of the global leaders to work together and in cooperation with banks of organisations to make progress.</s>
        <s>No government will succeed if it works only by itself.</s>
        <s>Looking to his country, <name type="geo">Great Britain</name>, he wants to end their <choice><orig>depence</orig><reg>dependence</reg></choice> on coal and replace it by wind energy.</s>
        <s>In the fourth and last paragraph <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> talks about the effects of climate change and its crisis on the future.</s>
        <s>He points out that the next generation are the ones that are going to suffer under the effects of the climate crisis.</s>
        <s>It is the job of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> to take action.</s>
        <s>It's too late to fail because if they would fail <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref> it would be a turning point in the history of humanity.</s>
        <s><quote><name type="misc">COP26</name> will not, and cannot, be the end of the story of climate change</quote><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 42f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>And to reach this <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> <choice><orig>say</orig><reg>says</reg></choice> that they have everything they need.</s>
        <s>The money, corporations and NGOs <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref>, like <name type="misc">Greenpeace</name>.</s>
        <s>In his <foreign xml:lang="de">Fazit</foreign> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> talks directly to the listeners.</s>
        <s>He says that all of them may not be like <name type="person">James Bond</name>, but everyone of them have to begin to defuse the bomb, that means to take action against climate change <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 47-51)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The alliterations <quote>turn the tide</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 50)</ref> underlines his message.</s>
        <s>In the end he warns, that the fight will be hard, but gives hope by saying that we can do it <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 51)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
