<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g26_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Henrik,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>your</orig><reg>You're</reg></choice> what <name type="misc">School B goes green</name> was about no problem.</s>
        <s>I tell you because I were a student that take part at this very cool day.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="misc">School B goes green</name> was a day of school <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> we <choice><orig>learnd</orig><reg>learned</reg></choice> to be more sustainable in school or at home.</s>
        <s>At this day, the school <choice><orig>offerd</orig><reg>offered</reg></choice> 40 different workshops for every student.</s>
        <s>The students would pick one of them and so they get the day free to take part on one of these workshops.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It gave <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">kosinly</gap> every workshop with the topic sustainable.</s>
        <s>The idea came from students teachers and parents who worked together to plan this day and every single workshop.</s>
        <s>The idea was to create a day <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> the protection of climate and the school are under the same hat.</s>
        <s>So everybody knows that the school can be also sued to change something and protect the climate.</s>
        <s>The trigger for this day was that many students were missing because of the <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> demonstration and so the teacher try to change something in school.</s>
        <s>I hope you understand everything.</s>
        <s>The last thing I want to tell you is <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> workshops it gaves on this day for example one workshop was <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> second-hand market <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> the students can change <choice><orig>close</orig><reg>clothes</reg></choice>, a workshop <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> the students try to make the school <choice><orig>coffe</orig><reg>coffee</reg></choice> fair trade or a workshop about how to use water with more efficiency.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because the day worked very good and everyone is happy it should be there for a second time.</s>
        <s>I you want I can tell you when it is the next time then you can visit me and take part at this cool day.</s>
        <s>It you have other questions than ask me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See you soon,</s>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
