<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g24_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech for the opening ceremony of the climate conference <name type="misc">COP26</name>, prime minister <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> appeals directly to the assembled world leaders, stressing the urgency and the consequences that will follow if the conference fails at reaching an agreement on how to fight climate change.</s>
        <s>He puts pressure on them, by <choice><orig>empasizing</orig><reg>empathizing</reg></choice> the consequences for the future, the importance of the conference for the course and outcome of history and the fact, that the world's population is watching and relying on them.</s>
        <s>In order to achieve his effect on the assembled audience, he begins his speech by stressingn the immediate danger of climate cahnge and therefore the urgency to act against it.</s>
        <s>Thus, he compares the situation of the leaders to the fictional, well-known character <name type="person">James Bond</name> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 2-9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By doing so, he illustrates just hwo dangerous climate change is: that it will <quote>will end human life as we know it</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The raise of global temperature is compared to a <quote>doomsday device</quote> and the global leaders are metaphorically <choice><orig>straped</orig><reg>strapped</reg></choice> to this device, meanwhile a <quote>red digital clock</quote> is ticking.</s>
        <s>This shows how <choice><orig>life-threathening</orig><reg>life-threatening</reg></choice> and immedaite the menace of global warming is.</s>
        <s>The negatively connotated alliteration <quote>doomsday device</quote> represents the possible outcome of this scenario.</s>
        <s>It refers to an apocalyptic future, a <quote>doomsday</quote> that will come, if the conference fails.</s>
        <s>The negativly connotated word <quote>tragedy</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref> also adds to that effect.</s>
        <s>For <name type="person">James Bond</name> movies usually have a happy neding, there is also a future scenario in which the earth will be saved and the conference a success.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> continues in putting pressure on the assembled politicians, by mentioning past climate summits in the following paragraph <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 10-15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He states, that the promise made back then, <quote>will be nothing but blah, blah, blah</quote> if the <name type="misc">COP26</name> fails <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 12f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By resorting to a more informal language, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> uses humorism to again stress the importance of action against climate change.</s>
        <s>By doing so, he also appeals to the audience watching, that will be according to him full of <quote>anger</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> and <quote>impatience</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> if the conference fails.</s>
        <s>The familiar term <quote>get real</quote> also appeals to a younger, impatient audience <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In a further paragraph, he presents the means by which it is possible to stop global warming.</s>
        <s>By ennumerating the means that may stop climate change, he puts emphasis on the fact that <quote>We have the technology</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 30)</ref> to do something against climate change, but that there is a lack of will to implement this <quote>technology</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In order to pressure the politicians even more to implement this technology, to find the <quote>will</quote> to do so, he refers to <quote>the crowds of young people outside</quote>.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, he draws a parallel between the conclave and the assembled leaders at the conference <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 35)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By doing so, he emphasizes the age difference between the politicians and the <quote>young people</quote>, whose future is affected.</s>
        <s>The conclave and the pope usually tend to be very old and they play a very important role in for the <choice><orig>catholic</orig><reg>Catholic</reg></choice> church.</s>
        <s>By comparing the conclave and the members of the conference, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> also elevates their role as decision makers as well as their age.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next paragraph, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> puts the age difference, between the members of <name type="misc">COP26</name> and the younger generations, into context.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He states, that the <quote>yet unborn children will judge the members of <name type="misc">COP26</name> with bitterness and resentment</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 41)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It shows, that the people who are <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> affected by this crisis are yet not even born.</s>
        <s>The members of <name type="misc">COP26</name> will therefore be dead by then.</s>
        <s>Henceforth, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> illustrates the responsiblities taht the leaders hold.</s>
        <s>They will be responsible and judged for in the future.</s>
        <s>Even if they are dead by the year <quote>2060</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref>, their actions today will have <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> direct and heavy impact on the lives of future generations.</s>
        <s>The <name type="misc">COP26</name> conference is therefore a <quote>historic turning point</quote>.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>metaphore</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> stresses the importance of the <name type="misc">COP26</name> conference, so important that it can change the course of history and will go down in it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end of his speech, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> refers back to his analogy of <name type="person">James Bond</name>, by saying <quote>we may not feel like <name type="person">James Bond</name></quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 47)</ref> and <quote>defuse the bomb</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 49)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Thus he reminds the <name type="misc">COP26</name> members agin of their position as decision makers facing a great threat <add>bomb</add>.</s>
        <s>He ends his speech with the words <quote>But yes, we can do it</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 51)</ref>, spreading optimism and hope.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> tries to appeal foremost to his audicen, the assembled leaders in the room, in order to pressure them to take action against climate cahnge.</s>
        <s>He does so, using inclusive language, like <quote>we</quote>, putting pressure on them, while also assuring them that there is also reason for hope.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
