<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g08_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="hortatory exposition">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I heard that you have banned the book <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> from your school libraries due to several reasons.</s>
        <s>With this letter I am going to try to make you think about banning the book because I think that there are several reasons to let the students read the book not only in <name type="geo">US</name> but worldwide.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first the book is a great way to teach the students <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">rauid</gap> tolerance and it is way better way to teach it to them <choice><orig>throug</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> a novel than through a newspaper article or something else.</s>
        <s>In addition to that the novel depicts a very recent topic which needs to be discussed in some way.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the novel tells a story which has happened in a similar way very often and is a reflection of our society and our problems which makes it also a good reason to be <choice><orig>teached</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> to students.</s>
        <s>Equally important the story encourages young students to stand up and speak up for their rights or say something when they see that something is not right.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With all that in mind I really hope that you would reconsider your decision about banning the novel and I hope it helped you understand my point of view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Sincerely yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
