<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g05_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In chapter 24 narrative perspectives and techniques are used to present <name type="person">Starr's</name> state of mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> is the protagonist of the novel and tells the whole story out of her perspective.</s>
        <s>That is why the point of view is the first person protagonist narrator.</s>
        <s>The word <quote>I <add>I haven't been back since that night</add></quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> indicates it too.</s>
        <s>For the reader it is easy to relate to <name type="person">Starr</name>, because he knows exactly what is going on inside her head.</s>
        <s>The reader gets also emotionally involved.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <name type="person">Starr</name> arrives at the street where <name type="person">Khalil</name> got shot, <name type="person">Starr</name> gets flashbacks.</s>
        <s>Through the flashbacks <quote><name type="person">Khalil</name> drops it into the side of the door</quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>, <quote>he opens the door to ask if I'm okay</quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref> and <quote>then pow-pow</quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> the reader gets a closer look at what <name type="person">Starr</name> is thinking about.</s>
        <s>The reader also gets sympathetic, because she is going through the whole situation again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Interior monologue is often used in this novel, especially when <name type="person">Starr</name> has a conflict with herself.</s>
        <s>For example when she stands on the patrol car with the bullhorn, wants to speak out, but does not know what to say <add><quote>Shit, I have no idea what to say</quote><ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 44)</ref></add>.</s>
        <s>But she knows that she needs to speak up so she says to herself <quote><qs>You know what?</qs><qs>Fuck it</qs></quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 58)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This presents her state of mind very well, because the reader knows exactly which thoughts are going through her brain.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This whole situation is presented in scenic mode, which means that a situation is described in very detail.</s>
        <s>The direct speech <add><quote>A hairbrush is not a gun</quote><ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref></add>, which is also a narrative technique, indicates that it is written in very detail.</s>
        <s>But also phrases like <quote>ahead of the crowd a lady with twists stands on top of a police car, holding a bullhorn</quote> <ref target="a11gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> show that the reader gets to know every detail.</s>
        <s>It makes him feel like he is in the situation right now too and so he can relate to <name type="person">Starr's</name> thoughts more.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum it all up, once can say that through these narrative techniques the reader gets a closer look at <name type="person">Starr's</name> thoughts and her state of mind.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
