<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l09_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical_recount">blog</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Home - where are you?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Racism sadly is a topic that many people get confronted with.</s>
        <s>Because of its diversity, most the news related to discrimination come from the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
        <s>But how about also realizing what's happening in front of our own doors?</s>
        <s>Racist people are not bound to a nation, but to hate and prejudices we have to fight.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Scoring and bullying?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Many people of African heritage still face discrimination in many day-to-day situations.</s>
        <s>The soccer player <name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> opens up about how he has been discriminated.</s>
        <s>Even though he has been playing for the German national team and scoring goals for what he calls home, it was never enough to get accepted, as people were making monkey sounds from the tribune.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s><name type="geo">Germany</name> - a categorizes system?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>One thing many of you <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> people did not directly get confronted with, was the huge wave of refugees in <date>2015</date> in <name type="geo">Europe</name>.</s>
        <s>In his own magazine <name type="misc">Boa</name>, <name type="person">Boateng</name> talks about that specific time, when racists started to spread more and more and became more overt.</s>
        <s>The ex national player felt hpw people were objectified and categorizes as <q>the Germans</q> and <q>the immigrants</q>, and also as people who were not quite sure about their identity.</s>
        <s>But <name type="person">Boateng</name> clearly states that winning the world cup in <date>2014</date> showed once again how we, as a German society and even the whole world, are better together.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Values: Can racist people be parents?</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>By stating that <name type="person">Boateng</name> even faced racism as a child and teenager in such an extreme way of being spit on by not only children, but their parents too, shows the extent of what is currently going on.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>10-years old:</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>By the time most of us were playing with whoever we liked and thought to be the happiest children on earth, <name type="person">Jérôme</name> got in touch with how cruel the world can be.</s>
        <s>He realized that he looked different and that his outward appearance was made to be a problem by others.</s>
        <s>Asking his parents, <name type="person">Boateng</name> learned that some people were somehow disturbed by his skin colour.</s>
        <s>Hearing this as a 10-year-old didn't make any sense to him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But also now that <name type="person">Boateng</name> is an adult, it still doesn't make any sense.</s>
        <s>Especially Germans with African heritage do not feel accepted by some part of our society.</s>
        <s>It is our duty, to make <name type="geo">Germany</name> and the whole world feel home to everyone.</s>
        <s>That at least we owe to children and adults like <name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name>, who have been contributing to joy and peace for our home country.</s>
        <s>Be aware of what is happening in this exact moment and join us on our fight against the most dangerous weapon human kind has ever created: racism.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
