<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt displays scene <choice><orig>fourth</orig><reg>four</reg></choice> of the play <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 4</ref> written by <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="author">Ayad Akhtar</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this part <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and his nephew <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> got into a heated argument on how to act around American authorities.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir Kapoor's</ref> relationship to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe Hussein/Jensen</ref> changes quite a bit during this play.</s>
        <s>Thus it is important to look at their relationship in the beginning of the play.</s>
        <s>The first time <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> are associated together is in the first scene, where <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> wife <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily Kapoor</ref> pressure <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to show up for the trial of an Imam who was <choice><orig>apperently</orig><reg>apparently</reg></choice> wrongfully <choice><orig>accussed</orig><reg>acused</reg></choice> of terrorism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> asks his uncle for help even though he knows that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is not a part of the Muslim community anymore of supports any believes muslims share.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover he is <choice><orig>extremly</orig><reg>extremely</reg></choice> scared, maybe even terrified of people who are (un-) intentionally racist and patronizing towards him.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, who's a white American woman, supports <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and tries to convince <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to go to the trial.</s>
        <s>It's important to add that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> is an artist displaying Islamic patterns and shames <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> for <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word"/> his old religion.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref>, knowing all of this and still asking <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> for help, shows, that he looks up to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> but also thinks that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> can, while living his American life, still support his old community.</s>
        <s>In the end, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> goes to the trail of the Imam, which is going to be the downfall of his career.</s>
        <s>This is because a magazine ends up writing about the trial, portraying <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> like he was the attorney for <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Imam Fareed</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> boss reads the article and runs a background check on him, finding out he changed his name from a Muslim to a Hindu name and gets suspicious of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s>This leads to him not getting a certain promotion he wanted and later on even fired.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref>, who dresses typical American on the beginning of the play, integrated well into the American society as he respects American values but is still valuing his other identity.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> on the other hand, tries to hide away his other identity, suppressing his own emotions towards it and tries to be as American as possible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nevertheless it's clear that they're both afraid of being discriminated against because of their Muslim identity, this is also why they both changed their names to not be associated as Muslim right away.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Throughout the course of the play <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> admits at a dinner party with his work colleague, an African-American woman, and her husband <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Isaac</ref>, an art creator working with <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, that he felt a blush when <name type="misc">9/11</name> <choice><orig>happend</orig><reg>happened</reg></choice> and ends up spitting <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> in his face and beating his wife.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All of these situations are signs of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> second identity and his <choice><orig>opperessed</orig><reg>oppressed</reg></choice> emotions coming up.</s>
        <s>The last scene, which is also the one displayed have takes place around eight months after the dinner party.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> are separated and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> had a lot of time to think about how he acted exactly the way he always hated about the Islamic culture and ended up portraying the stereotypes which are usually used to patronize muslims.</s>
        <s>In this scene <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> asks his uncle <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> on how to act now that the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> interrogated him.</s>
        <s>Right in the beginning it's noticable how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is clearly mad at the American authorities and its government as he accuses them of going into the Muslim community and looking for people <choice><orig>who's</orig><reg>whose</reg></choice> immigration status might be out for renewal so that they can deport them more easily.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> on the other hand tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> that they might feel like he was antagonizing towards them as he laughed in their faces when they asked about his immigration status <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He calls a lawyer for advice <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 19)</ref> and tries to explain, that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> has to mindful and careful about what message he's sending the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> shows a completely different attitude towards American authorities as <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> as he makes it clear that he understands that there's always a chance of getting deported and that the American authorities, in this case the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>, make the rules, not him.</s>
        <s>He states that he's on the side of the American government and asks <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> to rethink his decision of going against them.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is clearly showing that he's more rebellious and even states that getting deported might not be so bad at all.</s>
        <s>He almost shows no respect to the American authorities and it's noticable now he doesn't think much of them <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 58)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the next paragraph <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> argument is getting more heated as <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> screams out that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> life isn't so good after all, that he lost his job because he was hiding his Muslim identity, making it seem like he was hiding something, lost his friends and his wife because he beat her face bloody and lost his American status.</s>
        <s>Moreover he tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> that he wants <quote>something from these people</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 44)</ref> he won't get.</s>
        <s>Here he is referring to the fact that Muslim people and the Muslim community is getting more and more judged and face daily discrimination more often.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tried to build himself a typical American life, even the marriage seems to be a symbol of marrying an American when your ethnicity is not accepted, and it all crumbling in the end because he never respected his background.</s>
        <s>He wanted to be seen as an American, just an American without migration background.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> states here that that was never possible as the American society has <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> many prejudice against the Islamic culture.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> adds that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> did the same when he changed his name to <name type="misc">Jensen</name> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 58)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> was sick of the American authorities making him trying to avoid being associated as a muslim.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> sees this totally different <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 60-62)</ref> but <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> cuts him off and tells him that his community thinks <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> hates himself <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 55)</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> agrees with them.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> explains how one can't just copy the Americans but needs to see himself as an American with a Muslim immigration background <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 69-72)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After saying that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> leaves.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This whole conversation shows that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> share totally different opinions on how to be and act in the American society and end developing hatred for each other.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum it up one can see that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> used to look up to his uncle in the first scene but ends up being <choice><orig>discusted</orig><reg>disgusted</reg></choice> by him, as <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, in <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref>, can't be honest with himself and just wants to please the American society, be seen as one of them, which is not possible.</s>
        <s>Turns out <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> were both right to be afraid of systematic and (un-)intentional racism, and of people who are patronizing them.</s>
        <s>The difference is that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> speaks up about it and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> hides his emotions away, trying to please the authorities.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
