<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l08_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Racism in <name type="geo">Germany</name></s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>How do African-Americans living in <name type="geo">Germany</name> experience racism?</s>
        <s>To be more precise, how does <name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> feel about racism in <name type="geo">Germany</name>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That is the question I want to discuss today.</s>
        <s>This is actually my first blog entry on here so I would just like to quickly introduce myself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>My name is <name type="person">Jane</name> and I am currently volunteering for an international cultural exchange.</s>
        <s>I am originally from <name type="geo">Germany</name> so it's quite exciting for me to be in the <name type="geo">USA</name> right now.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I recently found an article where <name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> talks about his experience playing soccer as an African-American in <name type="geo">Germany</name> which is quite fitting for this blog entry.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> states that there were multiple <choice><orig>insidencens</orig><reg>incidents</reg></choice> where he experienced racism in <name type="geo">Germany</name>, people used racial slurs against him, spit on him, made monkey noises when he was warming up for a game.</s>
        <s>Even when he was younger, maybe around ten, parents from the opposite team called him names, racial slurs, the n-word and so on, sometimes, he shares in the interview, he even cried.</s>
        <s>He explains that his parents never talked about racism and discrimination against African people or people with a different skin colour until someone called him the n-word.</s>
        <s>He explains that for him as a child, he really couldn't understand why someone would have a problem with his skin colour.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> also talks about the German society in general in an interview with <name type="person">Herbert Grönemeyer</name>, a German singer and songwriter.</s>
        <s>Here he says that the refugees crisis is actually a big topic in <name type="geo">Germany</name> right now, one he also talks a lot about with his family and friends.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Jérôme Boateng</name> adds that the country is struggling with itself and that always the same questions aren't answered, e.g. <quote>what happens with everyone coming here?</quote> and <quote>how will that change our life?</quote>.</s>
        <s>Moreover he adds that the society itself is more open and has more diversity.</s>
        <s>He states that the big win for <name type="geo">Germany</name> in the <foreign xml:lang="de"><choice><abbr>WM</abbr><expan>Weltmeisterschaft</expan></choice></foreign> <date>2014</date> <add>(European soccer contest)</add> wouldn't have been possible without the colourful and diverse team they had.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless he adds, that more and more people have prejudice against people of colour, people who weren't born here or people <choice><orig>who's</orig><reg>whose</reg></choice> parents weren't born here.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This article was published in <name type="person">Jérôme Boateng's</name> first magazine <name type="misc">Boa</name>, in case you want to look it up.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Personally I can totally agree with him.</s>
        <s>Our society in <name type="geo">Germany</name> is getting more and more diverse.</s>
        <s>But through that the hatred also grows.</s>
        <s>Especially as a public and famous person of colour, you don't have an easy life.</s>
        <s>This is why it's especially important to raise attention to this topic and not just sit down and watch it happening!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you all enjoyed this blog post, even if the topic is not joyful at all...</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you for reading, you're all welcome to leave a comment!</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
