<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l09_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>To get a better view of the opinions and line of thought of certain characters, it is important to take a deeper look into the course of the conversation, such a individual character evaluation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The very beginning of the excerpt shows <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> attitude towards his troubles with the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>As he laughed <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 4)</ref>, he doesn't really takes seriously, that he could get deported soon.</s>
        <s>Even though he is afraid of his mother <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 16)</ref> and comes to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> for help, he doesn't really listen to his advices and seems like he got it all under control <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 8, l. 10-11)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By questioning <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> all the time <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 23, l. 28, l. 30)</ref> he wants to seem superior and is probably still defiant because of what happened to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
        <s>He doesn't want <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to tell or teach him anything any longer, which also gets emphasized by <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> cutting off <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 30)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His defiance gets stressed by him simply saying that he is not on the same side as the authorities even though <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> strongly recommends him to be so <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 31-36)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Using an anaphora of <quote>maybe</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 40-41)</ref> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> doubts about living in the <name type="geo">US</name> become clear.</s>
        <s>He seems to feel unfitting and not comfortable.</s>
        <s>By talking about how both of their fathers <quote>wanted to make a better life for themselves and their families</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 42-43)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tries to go onto a more personal level and bond with <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s>However the opposite happens and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> bursts out (<quote>A better life?</quote>, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">l. 44</ref>).</s>
        <s>Full of anger, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> starts making accusations and shouts at his uncle <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 46, l. 48)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By talking about <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref> in a <quote>quiet, intense</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 50)</ref> way, he hits <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> in a sensitive spot.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Amirs</orig><reg>Amir's</reg></choice></ref> response <quote>I don't know</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 52)</ref>, also shows how he is ashamed for his unexplainable behaviour.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> realizes his situation in the conversation and for that wants to restore his pride by reminding <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> to be respectful <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 55)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It becomes clear that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> has had a personality change as he changed his name back <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 59)</ref> and now wears a kufi in public <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 60)</ref>, which is a Muslim skullcap.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> seems to no longer be afraid to show his Muslim background in public.</s>
        <s>For that, he becomes the opposite of <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> who tries to hide his identity and hates his cultural and religious background.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> talks about how he used to look up to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> but now cannot stand his pessimistic views any longer <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 64-66)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It becomes clear how much the problems they've faced pressured and traumatized <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> (<quote>You have no idea what it did to me!</quote>, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">l. 68</ref>).</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Amirs</orig><reg>Amir's</reg></choice></ref> behaviour has not only damaged himself and his marriage, but also his social surrounding.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By talking about the <quote>destiny</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 73)</ref> to <quote>conquer the world</quote> <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 70)</ref> one realizes that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> has not only had a change of mind, but now is convinced of more extreme and even radical things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This excerpt shows the evolution of the relationship between <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> throughout the play.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> used to look up to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and trust him <add>(<quote>even more than his own mother</quote>, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 16)</ref>)</add> but now finds himself disgusted with his uncle <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 63)</ref>, as he has been shaming his background and through that damaged everything around him.</s>
        <s>What is noticable is that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> talks way more than <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> does in this excerpt.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> seems to let <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> say everything he wants as he cannot say a word to defend himself and for that realizes his mistakes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It becomes quite obvious how <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> changed throughout the play.</s>
        <s>Being a not so relevant character in the beginning, he is a testament for the impact of discrimination on young people and how that can even get to radicalisation.</s>
        <s>Being like a mirror to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and enumerating all the things he has done wrong, he is leaving <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> in disgrace.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
