<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l04_t4</author>
        <name>blog</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical recount">blog</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello dear readers,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>the most of you are reading this because they are interested in different cultures and <choice><orig>countrys</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But when there are many cultures, there is always racism.</s>
        <s>People who do not want to understand and tolerate other cultures than their own.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Today <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> am looking at racism in <name type="geo">Germany</name>, against Germans with African heritage and for that <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> read an interview, with the <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> football star and retired national player <name type="person">Jerôme Boateng</name>.</s>
        <s>He talks about his experience with racism in the past and nowadays.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Back then, when he was a child, he already experienced a lot racism.</s>
        <s>He tells us, that when he was only ten years old, the parents from an enemy football team spit on him and his mates.</s>
        <s>At one football game, a father from an enemy player, came to his side and insulted him until he started to cry.</s>
        <s>I think this shows how heartless and brutal racism is, he was only a little boy and didn't even know why these mean people offended him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His parents didn't talked to him about his skin color and why some people have problems with it, until one time someone <choice><orig>sayed</orig><reg>said</reg></choice>: <quote><foreign xml:lang="de">Hey, mein kleiner Nigger</foreign></quote> to him, which means: <quote>Hey, my little nigger</quote>.</s>
        <s>When his parents then told him, that people exist, which have problems with skin color, he couldn't believe it.</s>
        <s>He said, that is makes no sense for <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> child, and <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> think, that is pretty true, because it didn't even <choice><orig>makes</orig><reg>make</reg></choice> sense for me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Today he still experiences racism, for example, when he is warming up at the side if the soccer field, some viewers make ape noises, even <choice><orig>tho</orig><reg>though</reg></choice> he achieved so much for and with the German team.</s>
        <s>This shows how hard racists reduce people at their skin color or heritage, they don't see the human or his skills, they just see the skin color and they have a problem with it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Jerôme</name> says that <quote><name type="geo">Germany</name> wrestles with itself</quote>.</s>
        <s>The refugee crisis in <name type="geo">Europe</name> is still much discussed in his circle of friends <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> colleagues.</s>
        <s>There always comes up the same question: <quote>What are we doing with all these people and what are the consequences?</quote>.</s>
        <s>For me, that wouldn't even be a question, it should be clear and <choice><orig>standart</orig><reg>standard</reg></choice>, that at the first point, you should help the refugees and give them human conditions to live in and then, at the second point, the question, how to proceed with them in the future should be discussed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote><name type="person">Boateng</name> notices, that many people put others in drawers</quote>.</s>
        <s>One drawer for Germans and one for refugees and even the Germans, which grew up in <name type="geo">Germany</name> and just have another skin color are put in an own drawer, even though so many people see every day, what advantages they have, because they are such a mixed country.</s>
        <s>For example, the win of the World Cup <date>2014</date>, wouldn't have been possible for <name type="geo">Germany</name>, without all the players with different heritage.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all we can see, that racism always was and still is a big problem and not just in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I thank you all for reading.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
