<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11l08_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211206</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary_recount">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given excerpt from <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 4</ref> written by <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="author">Ayad Akhtar</ref> a part of the fourth scene is displayed.</s>
        <s>Here <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and his nephew <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> have a discussing about a situation where <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> got involved with the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe Hussein</ref>, who changed his name to <name type="misc">Abe Jensen</name>, to not be directly recognised as a muslim, comes to his uncle <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir Kapoor</ref>, who also changed his name from <name type="misc">Abdullah</name>, to ask him for advice.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the beginning of the play we find out that <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is still a part of the Muslim religion and stands by it.</s>
        <s>In contrast to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> is proud to be a part of the Islamic culture and you can tell that he has integrated into the American society a lot better than <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this scene some things changed compared to the beginning.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> that he changed his name back to <name type="misc">Hussein</name> and he started wearing a Kufi again, whereas he was described as wearing typical American clothes in the first scene.</s>
        <s>Farther in the day <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> and his Muslim friend went to <name type="misc">Starbucks</name> and <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> friend started hitting on the barista.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> noticed right away that she wasn't into his friend but she ended up asking them about a terrorist organization.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> friend said that it was founded by the <name type="geo">US</name> and she ended up calling the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>There they were interrogated about Muslim terror groups.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> didn't want to tell his mom and went to his uncle for advice.</s>
        <s>He tells <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> that they brought up <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe's</ref> immigration status, which is up for renewal.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> explains to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> white American wife, that he started laughing when they said that.</s>
        <s>he says that the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> goes into the Islamic community and looks on purpose for people <choice><orig>who's</orig><reg>whose</reg></choice> immigration status is vulnerable.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> ends up calling a lawyer who he had contact with during the play, to ask him for advice.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> left a voicemail and said to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> that it's a good sign they let him go.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he explains to <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> that he should maybe reconsider on which side he wants to be, taking in the fact, that the <choice><abbr>FBI</abbr><expan>Federal Bureau of Investigation</expan></choice> makes the rules and could get him deported.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> makes clear, that he doesn't want to switch sides and might even want to go back to Pakistan the argument gets more heated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tries to convince his nephew that it's best to play low and act as American as possible, whereas <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> thinks that it's disgusting how he always turns on his people and his culture.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Abe</ref> ends up leaving, telling <ref target="a11lk1_1" type="character">Amir</ref> that he'll handle the situation by himself.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
