<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g17_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I'm going to analyze the most important film-stylistic devices, with regards to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and his behaviour as <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> boyfriend, just like his relationship with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The given sequence can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into four parts; <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is slowly walking towards <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, them talking about their relationship, <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dancing and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> going in another room with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene begins with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walking up to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>This sequence is presented in a medium shot, forcing the viewer to look <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>at</reg></choice> <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, confidently walking with his headphones.</s>
        <s>We experience that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is very popular, because everybody in school seems to know him and him being very confident.</s>
        <s>This feeling is made with the camera angle, which is slightly pointing up to him, giving us the feeling that he is indeed confident.</s>
        <s>Also, the camera is <surplus>is</surplus> showing him walking in slow motion.</s>
        <s>This is used when we see something special in movies.</s>
        <s>Therefore, <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> seems to be an important person.</s>
        <s>Another huge impact makes the music and the voice over.</s>
        <s>The music describes a person with beautiful eyes and the voiceoveris describing <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> thoughts about <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>Both, make <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> appear special and important to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While watching <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in slow motion, we can also notice <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> <choice><orig>secretely</orig><reg>secretly</reg></choice> watching him.</s>
        <s>This gives us the feeling that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is important to her and that she can't hide her feelings for him.</s>
        <s>The camera is also zooming in on <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, which is expressing the feeling of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> enjoying seeing and thinking about him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first part ends with a quick dolly shot, changing the focus from <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>It is interesting to see that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> stop smiling after having made eye contact.</s>
        <s>This is because their relationship is serious and not perfect at that time.</s>
        <s>The second part begins with a medium close up, so that we can see that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is turned with her back against <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and not smiling.</s>
        <s>We can also notice <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> behind her, putting his earphones on <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The music playing is rap which can be associated with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> actual home and her actual self.</s>
        <s>This gives us the feeling that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> very well, <choice><orig>becaus</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> it makes her smile.</s>
        <s>The conversation is presented in a close up and over the shoulder shot, forcing us to look at their emotions.</s>
        <s>Once again we can see the seriousness of their relationship at that time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third part is shown in a long shot.</s>
        <s>This is because we shall see <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dancing, him standing in the middle of the hallway and the people around him.</s>
        <s>Just like in the beginning of the scene, we get presented that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is confident and makes <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> smile, which also mirrors that they are meant to be together even if it is hard at that time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally, we can see the camera slowly zooming in on <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is made to show that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> wants to be with him and feels <choice><orig>embarassed</orig><reg>embarrassed</reg></choice> about him doing it.</s>
        <s>Finally we see them standing together in a room, with no people except them.</s>
        <s>The director maybe wants to express that even though their current situation is tough, they still belong together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, we get to know the personality of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, simply with good film-stylistic devices and experience that they both totally like one and another even if their relationship isn't perfect at that time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
