<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g20_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>First of all I have to say that the book <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> <choice><orig>aswell</orig><reg>as well</reg></choice> as the movie is something I really enjoyed watching/reading.</s>
        <s>You can see that the <choice><orig>books</orig><reg>book</reg></choice> is also from a black <choice><orig>women</orig><reg>woman</reg></choice> because their perspective is a little bit different than shown in the media and I really like that.</s>
        <s>This movie gave me a new perspective of life and a specially of people who get discriminated everyday.</s>
        <s>I think it's so sad to see what is happening in this world and that the media who should inform <choice><orig>tries</orig><reg>try</reg></choice> to hide most of the bad things.</s>
        <s>For teenagers it's already hard because you start a new <q>chapter</q> in your life but if you have to go through the same thing as <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> it's even harder.</s>
        <s>I think no kid or teenager should <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice> a friend this early especially because of a police officer.</s>
        <s>In my opinion you should be trusting the police and not be afraid of them.</s>
        <s>The film itself didn't change my life that much but it made me overthink some stuff.</s>
        <s>This helps me a lot to empathize with more people.</s>
        <s>I'm not saying I know exactly how they feel but this film helps me understand them more especially their feelings.</s>
        <s>Everyone has a story to tell and they should tell everyone.</s>
        <s>This film also made me question if there are people around me who act like <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Hailey</ref> without them or me knowing.</s>
        <s>I recommend watching this film if you haven't already because this shows you <add>(especially when you are white)</add> a whole new perspective of life.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
