<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g12_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The excerpt is important for the whole movie because it represents the relationship of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>We get to see the dynamics of the couple and how they work together.</s>
        <s>In the first part of the sequence we see <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> out of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> perspective.</s>
        <s>He's popular friends with everyone and it seems like <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> feels a bit small and insignificant next to her boyfriend.</s>
        <s>On his way to her he's shown in a medium shot.</s>
        <s>The camera is on the same level as his eyes.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is represented as the most important person in the hallway.</s>
        <s>This is underlined by the song <name type="misc">Ocean Eyes</name> by <name type="person">Billie Eilish</name> playing in the background.</s>
        <s>It's about a person watching and missing someone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is interesting to notice how there's a voice-over of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who comments on the situation.</s>
        <s>This makes the whole sequence seem like a diary entry.</s>
        <s>She's describing her boyfriend, her anger and the relationship.</s>
        <s>We see that she's in love with boyfriend and notices small details like him wearing the same <name type="misc">Jordans</name> like hers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is also in love with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>It seems like he's enjoying <q>fighting</q> for her to forgive him.</s>
        <s>He does a lot of things to show her his love and affection.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But, she also talks about wanting more intimacy.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> wants to meet <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> parents and accuses her of avoiding it.</s>
        <s>After <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> forgives him they both walk out of the camera frame.</s>
        <s>In the next shot we see them in a close up that underlines the intimacy and tension.</s>
        <s>Their faces are very near to each other like they're going to kiss in the next shot.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref><choice><orig>seemes</orig><reg>seems</reg></choice><choice><orig>releaved</orig><reg>relieved</reg></choice> and excited.</s>
        <s>However, he's presented very confident as we can see in a shot where he walks along the hallway towards the camera.</s>
        <s>It is interesting to see how <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is kind of two-faced.</s>
        <s>When talking to his friends he appears confident and funny.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> can see through the perfect wall <choice><orig>tho</orig><reg>though</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>She sees him the way he is.</s>
        <s>With <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> can be emotional and vulnerable.</s>
        <s>This is underlined with medium and long shots being used for <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> around his friends and (medium) close ups being used for <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> around <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is important to notice how the background music has an effect on the atmosphere.</s>
        <s>They're in a fight and missing each other, so we listen to a sad song.</s>
        <s>Later <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> tries to make <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> happy and cheer her up by showing her a dynamic, relaxing beat.</s>
        <s>There's a huge difference between these two songs.</s>
        <s>They always represent the atmosphere and how <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> are feeling.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Just like the songs, it seems like the two teenager complement each other.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented as a caring boyfriend who cheers her up but also has his own sadness and emotions which he shows her.</s>
        <s>Sometimes he's torn between being the popular guy and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> boyfriend at the same time which can lead to him hurting people by accident.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
