<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g17_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The movie had a huge impact on my life and perspective on racism.</s>
        <s>This is because the film really showed and expressed the problems that people like <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> have and that they need to speak up for themselves, because noone else will.</s>
        <s>It puts their life in perspective with our <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice> and how different it is.</s>
        <s>The given scene is a perfect example of that: While <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> can allow himself to do whatever he wants in school, <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> can't and has to hide herself, because she feels different from the others and not comfortable.</s>
        <s>This scene also shows that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> wouldn't be happy at that time if there wasn't <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> who ultimately made her smile.</s>
        <s>We get to know so many problems, we never could have imagined and this movie perfectly expressed them.</s>
        <s>For me, this movie completely changed my perspective on people like <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>Those people have gained my respect for still keeping up with all the issues around them.</s>
        <s>This movie showed, that even if everything and everyone is against you, you can still fight against it.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> was a perfect example for such a problem and the movie <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> has put that in perspective to people who may never have thought racism has such a huge impact on <choice><orig>peoples</orig><reg>people's</reg></choice> lives.</s>
        <s>This is why I think that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="author">Angie Thomas</ref> wrote an exceptional book on a topic which obviously needs to be talked about and cannot be accepted, so that every child can have a normal life.</s>
        <s>All in all, I really enjoyed watching the movie, because it covers the topic of racism in a teenage life very well and that you should stand up for yourself, even if everything is against you.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
