<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g11_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The main aspect of this scene is in first place to introduce <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to the audience because he is an important character.</s>
        <s>The other aspect is <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> goal to make it up with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> because of their conflict then which was <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> fault.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into three parts.</s>
        <s>The first part when <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walks through the hallway.</s>
        <s>The second part when they talk to each other.</s>
        <s>And the third and last part when <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> starts dancing and then runs or walks away with her.</s>
        <s>This scene plays after a conflict between <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> invited her over to his place and pulled out a condom as she arrived.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> didn't want to have intercourse and leaved <choice><orig>immidiatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> called her and wrote her messages but <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> didn't answer because she ignored him.</s>
        <s>Before this scene the audience <choice><orig>don't</orig><reg>doesn't</reg></choice> know about the reason of the conflict.</s>
        <s>How <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walks through the hallway shows that he is a friendly, popular and pretty cool student.</s>
        <s>As he walks towards her the audience can hear her thoughts.</s>
        <s>He wears shoes from the brand <name type="misc">Jordan</name> what is a weakness of <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> also likes his lips and smell.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Espacialy</orig><reg>Especially</reg></choice> the music he let her hear gets her she says.</s>
        <s>So it seems that <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows that he has done something wrong to <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>And to make the reconciliation easier he does everything <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> likes like the shoes.</s>
        <s>So he knows her very good and he even <choice><orig>emberes</orig><reg>embarrasses</reg></choice> himself just to make <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> laugh.</s>
        <s>It seems that he really knows and likes her.</s>
        <s>The question that the audience probably asks is why is she mad at him or why did they have a conflict.</s>
        <s>But because the reconciliation was pretty fast the audience probably <choice><orig>don't</orig><reg>doesn't</reg></choice> want to know the reason anymore.</s>
        <s>Because it was so fast it seems as if their conflict wasn't so important or big.</s>
        <s>All in all their relationship is shown pretty good.</s>
        <s>Fast reconciliation and a happy ending for this conflict in this scene.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is shown as a nice guy who is in a good relationship with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>Which not only seems to be because <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> true.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> behaviour as normal friend is shown a bit when says hello to some friend of him as they pass each other.</s>
        <s>So there is no real <choice><orig>comprasion</orig><reg>comparison</reg></choice> to his behaviour as her boyfriend.</s>
        <s>He behaves very nice, polite, kind and serious.</s>
        <s>He wants to make her laugh and is alright with talking about serious topics like their conflict.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> introducing is shown in a medium shot first which shows his upper half body because <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> necessary to see how he behaves with his friends.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and his actions are important.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looking at him is also shown in long shot.</s>
        <s>As the audience hears her thoughts his under half of the body is shown to show the shoes she is talking about.</s>
        <s>Then his head is shown in a medium close up too because she talks about his lips.</s>
        <s>Before their conversation starts there is music in the <choice><orig>backround</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> which could be about <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>The song says <quote>Can't stop starring at those blue ocean eyes</quote>.</s>
        <s>This could mean <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> eyes and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> opinion about the reconciliation because she wants him back.</s>
        <s>While they talk about the beat and not so important thing they are shown in medium shot and over the shoulder.</s>
        <s>So when <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> talks we can see <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> back and the other way <choice><orig>round</orig><reg>around</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While they talk about something more serious <choice><orig>likes</orig><reg>like</reg></choice> their conflict the camera <choice><orig>zoomes</orig><reg>zooms</reg></choice> in <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> we see both of them still with <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> over the shoulder shot but also with a close up that only shows their faces.</s>
        <s>It's done like this because it gets more emotional.</s>
        <s>Their conflict is about a very private topic.</s>
        <s>But then when they talk about the beat the camera zooms out and both are shown in a medium size again.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dances he is shown in a long shot because he moves a lot with his legs too.</s>
        <s>Also the passing people are important because they make fun of him but he ignores them.</s>
        <s>Then <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> laughs and is shown in a medium shot.</s>
        <s>The shot size is never <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> extreme long shot or something smaller than a close up.</s>
        <s>The shot sizes are between long shot and close up.</s>
        <s>Because they're in a hallway so you can't have an extreme long shot.</s>
        <s>And in school you can't talk about such private topics for long or make it deeper because people are passing by.</s>
        <s>So it can't get more emotional.</s>
        <s>That means no big close up or extreme close up.</s>
        <s>They are not good for their conversation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is shown in a very good light like I said before.</s>
        <s>His relationship with <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is also shown in a very good light.</s>
        <s>And <choice><orig>there</orig><reg>their</reg></choice> reconciliation was very fast.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Chris</ref> reached his goal and <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Starr</ref> too.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Its</orig><reg>It's</reg></choice> obviously that she wants him back too but she doesn't show it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
