<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g33_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="hortatory exposition">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <date>8th December 2021</date>
        <name type="person">Mr. Rump</name>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Mr. Rump,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am writing this letter to you, on the note that I heard from one of your students that <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name> got banned in your school and think that this is big mistake on your behalf.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Banning this book not only keeps the students of your school from learning about the important topics of police brutality, racism and other discrimination in society in the <name type="geo">USA</name>, but also makes students think that activism and standing up against discrimination is wrong.</s>
        <s>This also will strengthen racism in the society and especially their generation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The excuses for banning the book are not even logical.</s>
        <s>The <quote>vulgar and offensive language</quote> is partially <choice><abbr>AAVE</abbr><expan>African-American Vernacular English</expan></choice>, <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> dialect of the African-American community, and also normal street and teenage language.</s>
        <s>This is the racism depicted in the book shown through a real life example.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sexual references are nothing more than making out or kissing, which is completely normal for teenagers and also shown in tons of other books.</s>
        <s>It is also shown through these scenes what consent and personal boundaries are.</s>
        <s>An example is the scene where <name type="person">Starr</name> and her boyfriend are making out, but <name type="person">Starr</name> does not want to go further so they do not.</s>
        <s>Even though they have a conflict about it, they solve it through talking.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The depicted drug use mentioned is in all forms shown as bad and not wanted, but it shows the real experiences in those <choice><orig>communties</orig><reg>communities</reg></choice> and how they have to live.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At last all the <quote>negative light</quote> the police are shown in, just resemble real life experiences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All these things are shown in a way the reader can understand what black people go through and how systemic racism is a thing happening.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></name> character development is a great example for many, especially teenagers.</s>
        <s>Robbing them of that is stopping them from growing confident and being themselves and standing up for exactly that.</s>
        <s>Also is it extremely racist of banning a book of <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> black author describing her experiences as a black teen.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best regards, Jane Smith</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
