<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g30_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> situation and how her state of mind effects her actions is shown by the use of a specific point of view and various narrative techniques.</s>
        <s>The excerpt is written in a first person narrator.</s>
        <s>The story is told by the main character - <add>here <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref></add> - and used pronouns are <q>I, me, my</q>.</s>
        <s>The reader only knows what the protagonist knows as it is their subjective perspective.</s>
        <s>This point of view has a rather personal effect on the reader, as the emotions and thoughts of <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> are described.</s>
        <s>It can simply create a connection between reader and protagonist because the reader easy identifies with the character.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Still this point of view is very limited and subjective, throughout the fact that one only knows what <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> feels and what she says about other characters in the book.</s>
        <s>If she <choice><orig>portraits</orig><reg>portrays</reg></choice> them in a certain state, the reader has little chances of creating a picture <choice><orig>themself</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>According to that, one almost <choice><orig>automaticly</orig><reg>automatically</reg></choice> sympathises with <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, because one is nearer to her negative emotions and the bad things that happen to her.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first narrative technique is in lines five to seven.</s>
        <s>When they come to the protest, <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> remembers the night, because it is the same scenery.</s>
        <s><quote><qs>[...] and see him lying in the street.</qs><qs>The whole thing plays before my eyes [...].</qs><qs>He looks at me for the last time and</qs></quote><ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 6-7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The narrative technique used here is a flashback with a panoramic mode.</s>
        <s>The scene is not relived in the fullest, but told about.</s>
        <s>This makes it seem more passive, because the reader does not know exactly what she remembers, even if one knows what happened with <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> state of mind is shown here very distracted.</s>
        <s>She loses focus of the actual scene happening and zooms out: <quote>I stare too hard, the crowd disappears</quote> <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The cut after the <quote>and</quote> underlines how absence she was and how her thoughts are interrupted by <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Ms. Ofrah's</ref> <quote>A hairbrush is not a gun!</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A second flashback is in lines 19 and 20 to 21.</s>
        <s>As everybody starts shouting <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> gets a flashback to <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Khalils</orig><reg>Khalil's</reg></choice></ref> death.</s>
        <s>First, only how he put his hairbrush into the side door <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Then it is interrupted by a mutter of <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> how a hairbrush is not a gun <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It goes on with <quote><qs>He opens the door to ask if I'm okay.</qs><qs>Then pow-pow-</qs></quote> <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 21-22)</ref> as she <q>sees</q> how he is getting murdered once again.</s>
        <s>This flashback also has a cut, but this time it is <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> shouting and raising her voice all emotional.</s>
        <s>It is a turning point for <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>At first she only mutters, but as she <choice><orig>remember</orig><reg>remembers</reg></choice> and for the moment where she knows that she <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> be quiet anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, there are some interior monologues along the excerpt.</s>
        <s>For example when she talks in her head about how it is weird seeing her <choice><orig>attourney</orig><reg>attorney</reg></choice> on a car.</s>
        <s>Additionally, in line 44 when <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> stands on the car and is handed the bullhorn.</s>
        <s>She does not know what to say and thinks <quote>Shit, I have no idea what to say</quote> and also in line 48: <quote><qs>You know what?</qs><qs>Fuck it</qs></quote>.</s>
        <s>This has the effect that the reader can experience along with her thoughts and sees the process.</s>
        <s>Overall one can say that this excerpt shows <ref target="a11gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> development in the book.</s>
        <s>It summarizes it in one specific scene, how she was <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> afraid to speak but then could and spoke out.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
