<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g01_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented as a caring and adoring boyfriend.</s>
        <s>He supports her and knows her and wants to move forward in their relationship.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The excerpt <choice><orig>start</orig><reg>starts</reg></choice> with a medi-long-shot of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is the first time the viewer sees this character so the short size is used to introduce him.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> shakes hands and greets a lot of his schoolmates which tells us he is popular and has a lot of friends.</s>
        <s>The song that is playing in the <choice><orig>backgroung</orig><reg>background</reg></choice> is slow and melodic which is a hint that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> have a romantic <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice>, they are not just platonic friends.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This excerpt does not have a lot of cuts which creates a calm atmosphere.</s>
        <s>In the off we can hear <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> who functions as a narrator describe <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>Her description makes their relationship clear.</s>
        <s>She describes his lips as soft and only uses other positive attributes to describe his <choice><orig>phisical</orig><reg>physical</reg></choice> appearance.</s>
        <s>We also see a close up on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris's</ref> shoes.</s>
        <s>And, as <choice><orig>mentiond</orig><reg>mentioned</reg></choice> in the film before, shoes have a lot of meaning for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>They are also both wearing the same shoes which shows their strong connection.</s>
        <s>The director uses a lot of medium shots when we see <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face and her emotions are more visible because medium close ups and close ups are used to show <choice><orig>hers</orig><reg>her</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The director uses medium shots because <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> emotion is not really relevant.</s>
        <s>More relevant is his <choice><orig>appearence</orig><reg>appearance</reg></choice> and his behaviour.</s>
        <s>We haven't seen <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> before so getting to know him a bit can help us understand his actions later.</s>
        <s>The close ups on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> face are used to tell us more about their <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> spots <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> the camera pans towards her and the next shot we can see is a close up to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is standing behind her so only the viewers can see that she is already smiling.</s>
        <s>He puts headphones on her ears and makes her listen to his own mash-up which makes her smile even harder.</s>
        <s>Because we can see <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face we know that she is ready and willing to forgive him.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> made her listen to his music because she knows it would calm her down and make her laugh.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> does not want to forgive him <choice><orig>jet</orig><reg>yet</reg></choice>, she wants him to work for her <choice><orig>forgivness</orig><reg>forgiveness</reg></choice> which is proven when she takes the headphones off and turns to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> with an unhappy and grim facial <choice><orig>expresion</orig><reg>expression</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> explains why he did what he did and that he only did it because he wants to move forward in their <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> and doesn't know how to.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The director uses over the shoulder close ups to show that they are having a conversation and how they <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">fal</gap> and react to one another.</s>
        <s>The close ups on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chrises</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> face show his worry and helplessness.</s>
        <s>He fears that she will not forgive him which shows how much he cares about her.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> wasn't able to move their <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> forward and she blocked every other possible way to do that he thought that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> didn't want or <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">vwel</gap> it and she just wanted to have sex with him.</s>
        <s>He admits that is was his fault for thinking that way but he could not see another possible alternative.</s>
        <s>The close ups on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face show her annoyance and unhapping with the situation.</s>
        <s>But when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> tells her he misses her <surplus>her</surplus> features soften and she forgives <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> worry turns into happiness when he notices that.</s>
        <s>In both cases the close ups are used to show the change of their emotions.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> proves his devotion to their <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> again when he <choice><orig>start</orig><reg>starts</reg></choice> to dance to his mash-up which he is playing out loud.</s>
        <s>The medium shot of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is used to show his dancing and that he is dancing although other children who attend their school are surrounding them.</s>
        <s>The shot of him dancing is filmed in slow motion similar to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris's</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> entrance at the beginning of the excerpt where <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> was watching him from afar.</s>
        <s>By using slow motion the director gives us a chance to look at <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> from  <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> point of view.</s>
        <s>The slow motion makes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> seem like her is out of a dream which indicates her feelings for him, that she likes him a lot.</s>
        <s>The slow motion close up on  <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face also shows her happiness.</s>
        <s>It is like they are in a slow motion bubble and share this moment of happiness only with one another like no one else matters in this moment.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> wants to make her laugh.</s>
        <s>He does not care about the <choice><orig>emberessment</orig><reg>embarrassment</reg></choice> of dancing <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of the school.</s>
        <s>His intentions are pure and good.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion the spectatot <choice><orig>see</orig><reg>sees</reg></choice> that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented as a caring and loving boyfriend.</s>
        <s>He dances <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of the whole school just to make her laugh which proves his intentions are good.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
