<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a10g56_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk6</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a10gk6_1" type="title">Globalised Environmental Pollution - Causes and Effects</ref>, written by <ref target="a10gk6_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref>, published on <date>February 5 2014</date> in a blog on environment, informs us about the causes and effects of environmental pollution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a10gk6_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> describes the environmental pollution as an introduction of harmful pollutants into the environment.</s>
        <s>She wrote that these pollutants contaminate the environment and that they have a hazardous effect on the natural world and on the activities of living beings.</s>
        <s><quote>Environmental pollution can also have devastating effects on sea life, crops and human health</quote> so written in the article.</s>
        <s>The environmental pollution affects plants, animals and human life in a very destructive way.</s>
        <s>The gains we get from <choice><orig>sience</orig><reg>science</reg></choice>, technology and industrial progress there are so far at the cost of our health.</s>
        <s>The environmental pollution is caused by the fall-out from nuclear tests, industries, smoke left behind the automobiles and other vehicular traffic, the increasing use of synthetic detergents, nitrogen fertilizers and insecticides that contaminate both water and air.</s>
        <s>Because of the contamination our would is afflicted with a number of incurable diseases.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
