<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12g04_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Nowadays, it is critizized if <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still relevant in our lofe and society and especially for young people.</s>
        <s>Today, you can find many marks of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> in literature.</s>
        <s>But is Shakespearean literature actually that good for young <choice><orig>peaple</orig><reg>people</reg></choice> and do they really need this in their education?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion I think teaching Shakespearean literature should not be that relevant today because it is <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> hard to understand for young students.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly an important point is the language in Shakespearean literature.</s>
        <s>For young people it is so hard to understand.</s>
        <s>So for example, the tormented students have to translate on the one hand and read between the lines on the other hand.</s>
        <s>At best way, they understand the words but not the meaning.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Secondly, it is really archaic and old-fashioned.</s>
        <s>SO it is not that interesting for a young audience.</s>
        <s>Therefore it can get boring quickly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nevertheles, is it true that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is a part of English culture, and a history and language.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, it is an inspiration for young writers and performing poetry helps to increase <choice><orig>confidents</orig><reg>confidence</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Some people are saying that his plays help you to gain an insight into human feelings.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But the fact, that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> didn't write books, but he wrote plays makes it more hard to read them and to understand them at the same time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All the aspects that I mentioned for Shakespearean literature are not convincing enough for me and I am the opinion that the Shakespearean literature is not that relevant today or shouold not be that relevant in school.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
