<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12g17_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211210</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The question <quote>is <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> still relevance for young people today</quote>is an often discussed question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Young people all over the world have to read and analyse <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> plays or sonnets.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Often students are moaning about the old language, because it is <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> hard to understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A solution to this problem is, to read the plays or sonnets in modern <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> first, to understand the content.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another contra argument is, that students could read those plays or sonnets in their freetime or after school, if they are interested in it, becuase most of the students won't get the meaning and importance of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> plays or sonnets, if they aren't interested in it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other side there are a lot of themes which students have to learn in school in which they aren't interested.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is a very important part of the English culture and history.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His plays are countingto the general knowledge.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand another argument against the relevance of <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> for young people is, that norms have changed.</s>
        <s>The feminine role isn't mondern anymore and could arrange wrong images.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But on the other hand those unmodern norms are part of the history and it is important to learn about them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course students could read other plays or sonnets than Shakespearean, which are more modern and easier to understand, but then students wouldn't get this general knowledge about Shakespearean plays and sonnets and their importance for the culture and history.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has invented about 1700 qords and a lot of proverbs, which have a huge influence on our modern language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has a huge influence on other authors like for example <name type="person">Goethe</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By reading Shakespearean plays and sonnets young people and people in general can learn about those connections and understand them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course there are some negative <choice><orig>aspekts</orig><reg>aspects</reg></choice> about teaching Shakespeare, but in my opinion <ref target="c12gk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is still relevant for young people, because of the named arguments and his plays and sonnets should still get teached in schools.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
