<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>a12g26_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Sir John Worne,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I read your article <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref> published on the <date>27th January in 2015</date> in <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name>.</s>
        <s>I'm a British student and in my personal opinion learning foreign languages is <choice><orig>superflous</orig><reg>superfluous</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>You judge the decreasing number of students who learn foreign languages as something negative.</s>
        <s>For me this trend only represents the up-to-date development of English as a global language.</s>
        <s>Today way more non-native English speaker talk to <choice><orig>eachother</orig><reg>each other</reg></choice> in English than the native ones.</s>
        <s>The study you "that two-thirds of UK businesses need for language skills maybe old-to-date because your article was published in 2015.</s>
        <s>Also your <choice><orig>Expectation</orig><reg>expectation</reg></choice> that the numbers will grow doesn't seem reasonable to me, because I believe that through globalization the importance of one global language (English) Will increase and therefore foreign languages won't be that important anymore and the numbers of your study will <choice><orig>propibly</orig><reg>probably</reg></choice> decrease as time passes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>to stay up-to-date the school and education system won't need to make foreign languages a priority, but need to focus on English as a global language.</s>
        <s>Therefore out national view doesn't need to change, neither is the responsibility of our parents to shift the culture in our homes.</s>
        <s>To try to stop the developments that are happening would only take us back, to make progress we need to accept the change that is happening because of the globalisation.</s>
        <s>The cultures and languages all over the world will merge even more as time passes.</s>
        <s>All in all I believe strongly that the development that you judge is negative is just following the trend of globalization and English as a global language, which can be a big opportunity for all of us to exchange cultures and knowledge all over the world.</s>
        <s>To try and stop these developments through <choice><orig>foreing</orig><reg>foreign</reg></choice> children to learn foreign languages, would be a big step back.</s>
        <s>Therefore I think your line of argument is too one-sided and <choice><orig>old fashioned</orig><reg>old-fashioned</reg></choice> and the change that is happening is to be judged as something positive.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed><choice><orig>Sincirly</orig><reg>Sincerely</reg></choice>,</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
