<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>a12g33_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> said in his article <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: can't, won't, don't</ref> that <quote>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing</quote>.</s>
        <s>I'm going to <choice><orig>adress</orig><reg>address</reg></choice> that claim.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that foreign language learning is an essential part of globalization, a process that just speeds up exponentially in the 21st century.</s>
        <s>Considering how connected the world is, and that jobs often require you to travel and/or work aborad and for instance outsourcing, all of those make learning foreign languages a necessity that everyone should be doing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course there are and will always be people claiming that English is the dominant language all around the globe, and knowing it is sufficient, since almost everyone knows English, so why bother learning a new language?</s>
        <s>If you look closely, actual <choice><orig>English speaking</orig><reg>English-speaking</reg></choice> countries are less than 20 percent of the world population, meaning that despite it being the most widespread language, there is only a relatively small part of native speakers, definitely not enough to say that is sufficient knowing only English.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, there are already derived English variations, mindled with other languages, and this will probably continue to derive enven more, and grow in significance.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All I can say is, that I agree srongly with <ref target="a12gk3_1" type="author">Mr. Worne</ref>, sine I find that especially in this truly global world, learning foreign languages is a must.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
