<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12g27_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear friend,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I heard about your plans of going to Germany, which to my mind is a great idea.</s>
        <s>You asked me about Berlin and I found the perfect newspaper article.</s>
        <s>It's called <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="title">Berlin spricht Englisch</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Marina Kormbaki</ref> and was published in the <name type="misc">Hannoversche Allgemeine Zeitung</name> on the <date>15th July 2016</date>.</s>
        <s>As you can tell it is a German text so I will sum up all the information you need.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>the headline already gives you an answer, it says Berlin speaks English.</s>
        <s>Of course that isn't everything <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Marina Kormbaki</ref> has a lot of examples and evidence.</s>
        <s>First of all there are hundreds of thousand <choice><orig>english speaking</orig><reg>English-speaking</reg></choice> travelers and a lot of them stay.</s>
        <s>This leads to <choice><orig>similaritys</orig><reg>similarities</reg></choice> with <choice><orig>citys</orig><reg>cities</reg></choice> like London, Brooklyn and Sydney.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Kormbaki</ref> States that sometimes you don't hear a single <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> word while walking through parts of Berlin, like <name type="geo">Neukölln</name> and <name type="geo">Kreuzberg</name>.</s>
        <s>But it is not necessarily English as the <choice><orig>arabic</orig><reg>Arabic</reg></choice> language is pretty common as well.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless you can go wherever you want there will always be someone that speaks <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Especially the author points out the food that is mainly <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>besides Berlin being a city where you can easily communicate with others, there are more advantages.</s>
        <s>First of all Berlin has relatively low rents, when compared to other big cities and an overall cheap <choice><orig>live</orig><reg>life</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>So you could get a job, that you couldn't get back in Camden, such as <name type="person">Orta Baumgarten</name> who is Irish and now owns a book shop she couldn't afford.</s>
        <s>Furthermore <ref target="a12gk3_2" type="author">Kormbaki</ref> mentions another man called <name>David Walker</name>, who used to live in England.</s>
        <s>He works in a company with 21 different nations, so Berlin is also a city where you can meet new cultures.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>all in all Berlin is a affordable city to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice> in, where you can communicate with almost everybody everywhere and gives room to expand your horizon.</s>
        <s>If this doesn't convince you, <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> I think nothing will.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><abbr>PS</abbr><expan>postscript</expan></choice>: Maybe we could meet up if you decide to come to Germany.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
