<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12g21_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The 7th scene from the first act of <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> by <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is about <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> trying to convince <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> to kill the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First, <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> asked <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> why he left the chamber where the King is eating.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> is about to not continue in their plan killing him and is informing <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> over this.</s>
        <s>He arguments that the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice> and other people have shown him their respect lately and he does not want to disrespect them.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> disagrees and encounters, that he has to do it if he loves her and that he also want to become the king, but he has to do what is necessary to do.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> shows slight agreement and says if he kills him, there will be no one standing above him.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> continues and says that when he revealed his plan to kill the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice> to her, he was a real man.</s>
        <s>If he kills the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice>, he will be even more than a man.</s>
        <s>She also says that the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice> already has thrown away their values and she raises a child for <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> and all of it should not be for nothing.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> thinks about the event of failure, but <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> encounters that they do what has to be done and they will not fail anyways.</s>
        <s>She also tells him the details about the plan to get his guards drunk and kill the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice> while he is asleep.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> now changed his mind, agrees to kill the <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice> and describes his thoughts on it.</s>
        <s>Also, he suggests his wife to only give birth to male children.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
