<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g32_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>A statement that is often discussed is written by <name type="person">Norman J. Lund</name> and says <quote><s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> never grows old.</s><s>He continues to inspire each new generation</s></quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Many modern play or theatres are based on ideas of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>.</s>
        <s>In addition, facts about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> are a general knowledge.</s>
        <s>But for some students, the access to a <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> play could be very difficult, because the language is old and special, because he also uses words from other languages.</s>
        <s>One important point is, that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> enriched and influenced the English language.</s>
        <s>For students, it could interest, because the receive information of the origin of the English language.</s>
        <s>Some quotes of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name>, e.g. <quote>To be, or not to be</quote> are very famous and often used in the modern time.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> plays often use topics that are timeless and universal.</s>
        <s>They also describe experiences in life that everybody has, e.g. love, hate.</s>
        <s>But some facts of his plays are old-fashioned and unrealistic.</s>
        <s>But here, modern plays find other solutions, that have the same messages as the original play.</s>
        <s>Through <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays, people get a better understanding of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> time and the plays reflect the history and <choice><orig>cultur</orig><reg>culture</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But for people they don't want to study English, information about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> aren't necessary.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up, I am agree with <name type="person">Lund's</name> quote, because <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is very often used in the mordern times.</s>
        <s>His language is special, but also fascinating, so some people can become inspired by this language and want to know more about <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> himself and the century, he lived in.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
