<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12g26_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote><s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> never grows old.</s><s>He continues to inspire each new generation</s></quote> is a statement by <name type="misc">Norman J Lund</name>.</s>
        <s>This statement can often be discussed controversial, especially if it is discussed about the teaching of <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> at school.</s>
        <s>That is I would like to explain my own opinion and illustrate arguments for both sides.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course, <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> is more than 400 years away, but <choice><orig>noone</orig><reg>no one</reg></choice> can deny that his influence would not be still perceptible.</s>
        <s>New productions of his plays are well attended, new <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">fikus</gap> announced and his famous sayings can be found everywhere in modern media.</s>
        <s>His influence due to the importance of English is worldwide <choice><orig>recogniceable</orig><reg>recognizable</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That is also why in my opinion the teachment of <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> plays should not end.</s>
        <s>He is great in telling stories and creating vivid characters, so that he embodies the quality of English literature.</s>
        <s>His plays are often <choice><orig>reffered</orig><reg>referred</reg></choice> to by modern directors and also new productions of his play are able to display modern issues and problems, such like <choice><orig>digitization</orig><reg>digitalisation</reg></choice> or the tyranny of <name type="misc">Donald Trump</name>.</s>
        <s>That is also the next great benefit of <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> plays he may be old, but nevertheless he <choice><orig>adresses</orig><reg>addresses</reg></choice> timeless themes, like love, hate or discrimination, which are also important in today's societies and especially for students who must be educated to become a social-responsible part of today's societies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even if some say that students will be unable to deal with his language and hence get worse grades, there are several possibilities to help students understand what is going on.</s>
        <s>For example, I could imagine the use of modern media to show the students the real meaning, for example in a <choice><abbr>VR</abbr><expan>Virtual Reality</expan></choice> game in which they can embody the actors.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, they could also watch films and productions of the play and they could interpret it into a modern story, like in <name type="misc">Scotland, PA</name>, which <choice><orig>adresses</orig><reg>addresses</reg></choice> <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> by showing competing fast food restaurants.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion, the new generations even have more opportunities during dealing with <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> and if they were able to use it, nothing is against the teachment of <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>Hence, I hope that <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> will also help in the future to educate students to become social-responsible because I think that's his greatest service throughout the last 400 years.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
