<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c12g31_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>It's a big discussion if students should study <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> in school or not.</s>
        <s>In the following I will discuss what makes it interesting and what does it not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is one of the most popular <choice><orig>author</orig><reg>authors</reg></choice> so that he is a part of general knowledge and making influence of the today's audience <add>(like in films, poems, etc.)</add>.</s>
        <s>He also debates about current <choice><orig>theme</orig><reg>themes</reg></choice> like love, revenge, jealousy or hate.</s>
        <s>But in addition his plays represented an outdated world picture.</s>
        <s>It performs outdated attitudes and values like the debate of gender role, <choice><orig>loyality</orig><reg>loyalty</reg></choice>, religion or superstition.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand it presents current moral questions about good and bad or fairness and justice.</s>
        <s>The characters are authentic and have <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> understandable comprehensible modern adaptation in all literary genres.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But a disadvantage is that students prefer focussing on topics they identify easily with or prefer recent issues like the gender <choice><orig>deborate</orig><reg>debate</reg></choice>, fight against the racism or the climate change.</s>
        <s>Moreover <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> plays have inherent adaptability because of their three dimensional characters that can morph in myrical ways.</s>
        <s>They have the <choice><orig>openess</orig><reg>openness</reg></choice> that allows them to be endlessly reinterpreted customisations.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one side the texts have sense of meaning and <choice><orig>rythms</orig><reg>rhythms</reg></choice>, that it is truthfully and harmonically <choice><orig>dublicate</orig><reg>duplicate</reg></choice>, but on the other hand you have to know background knowledge to understand the plays.</s>
        <s>The students can understand the words, but not the content and his meaning.</s>
        <s>The emotions and feelings are not perceived.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I would say that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> interesting knowledge and he takes big part in our culture, but because of the outdated close text analysis it contradicts the original purpose of enjoying actors and their actions, it is <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> complex for the students.</s>
        <s>I would say it is <choice><orig>depentent</orig><reg>dependent</reg></choice> from the intelligence and qualifications of the students.</s>
        <s>In my opinion I would either tend against the study of <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> in school, because his texts are plays and the meanings and feelings are not perceived as good as in a theatre and this kind of language is outdated and above all for the students in Germany irrelevant.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
