<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12g19_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given test is an extract from <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> play <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> <add>Act 1, <choice><orig>Scene</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice> 7)</add>first performed in <name type="geo">London</name> in <date>1606</date>.</s>
        <s>The tragedy describes the bloody rise to power and the downfall of the warrior <name type="person">Macbeth</name>.</s>
        <s>In this, scene 7 of the first <choice><orig>Act</orig><reg>act</reg></choice>, <name type="person">Lady Macbeth</name> persuades and manipulates her husband into killign the present king of <name type="geo">Scotland</name>, <name type="person">Duncan</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the beginning of the scene, <name type="person">Macbeth</name> voices his worries and says that he does not want to murder <name type="person">Duncan</name>, because the king has shown him respect and he fears for his recently earned good reputation among the people.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Lady Macbeth</name> then accuses him of being a coward and letting his doubts stop him from doing something she deems necessary.</s>
        <s>She also links his inability to commit murder to his love for her and how he performs sexually.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Macbeth</name> wants her to stop talking and defends himself by saying that he's already doing everything a man should do.</s>
        <s>But <name type="person">Lady Macbeth</name> argues <choice><orig>agains</orig><reg>against</reg></choice> that because his conciousness stops him from committing murder.</s>
        <s>So she questions his masculinity and ability to do something so cruel.</s>
        <s>She continues to manipulate him by emphasizing her own willingness and ambition and insults him forn ot doing as he said he would.</s>
        <s>She describes her own ambition through her killing her own baby witha smile on her face if she needed to.</s>
        <s>After <name type="person">Macbeth</name> voices his worry of failing, his wife quickly argues that they wouldn't fail if he just found the courage.</s>
        <s>Then she continues to plan how they are going to murder <name type="person">King Duncan</name>.</s>
        <s>She wants to get the gaurds of his rooms drunk, so that they can easily <choice><orig>blamed</orig><reg>be blamed</reg></choice> for the murder.</s>
        <s>After that <name type="person">Macbeth</name> exclaims that the lady may only give birth to male children since her character resembles more that of a man.</s>
        <s>He then finally relents and is willing to commit the crime and to deceive the <choice><orig>word</orig><reg>world</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
