<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12g32_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211126</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The play <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> which is written by <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, is published on the <date>16th century</date> deals with information about a <choice><orig>men</orig><reg>man</reg></choice>, named <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref>, who defends his tribe form two other tribes forcing their way into <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth's</ref> kingdom.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>king</orig><reg>King</reg></choice> was very pleased from this action and invites <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> to his castle.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> also receives a prophecy from <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">three witches</ref> which reveal him that he will become king.</s>
        <s>In the following scene, <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> tries to convince her husband to kill <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Duncan</ref>, so that <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> earlier become king.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> and his wife are having lunch.</s>
        <s>She asks why <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> left the chamber and says that the chamber showed her respect lately.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> reminds her husband of the plan to kill <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Duncan</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the same moment, she also wants to encourage him, because of the fact that he defends the tribe from invading groups, which shows that <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> is actually brave.</s>
        <s>Over the course of the scene, <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> alludes to the masculinity of her husband to change his opinion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She also put her idea in a <choice><orig>concret</orig><reg>concrete</reg></choice> form, which she explains to <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> and displays that her plan is safe and nobody finds out who killed <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Duncan</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She also degrades <ref target="c12gk2_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> with the plan to strengthen him, so that he agrees to his wife's plan.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
