<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g56_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given text is a shortened speech called <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="title">Remarks of president Barack Obama at student roundtable</ref>, held by <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> at <date>April 7th, 2009</date>, when he was <choice><orig>President</orig><reg>president</reg></choice> of the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He held the speech in <name type="geo">Istanbul, Turkey</name> at the <name type="misc">Culture and Arts Center of Mimar Sinan Fine Arts University</name> in <name type="geo">Tophane</name>, where he hosted a discussion, but beforehand gave the short speech about the importance of student exchanges, crossing cultural boundaries and cosmopoligy to the students and professors.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speech can be divided into five paragraphs, where in the first one he declares that he wants to rebuild the relationship between the <name type="geo">USA</name> and Muslims all around the world <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 1-2)</ref> and adds, that he wants that relationship to be in mutual <choice><orig>intrest</orig><reg>interest</reg></choice> and mutual respect <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 2-3)</ref>, that he wants both sides to show interest and respect to each other again, so right in the beginning he takes a call for peace.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second paragraph, he says that he sees especially in the young people that they show interest in activism and <choice><orig>responsebility</orig><reg>responsibility</reg></choice>, all around the world, not just in the <name type="geo">United States</name>, and that he is really glad about that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this paragraph he is showing his audience <add>(which are mostly young people)</add> that he sees the efforts they put into their activism and that he <choice><orig>appreciate</orig><reg>appreciates</reg></choice> it very much.</s>
        <s>He praises them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third paragraph he declares, that he wants to <quote>find new ways to connect young Americans to young people all around the world</quote> <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 9-10)</ref> by supporting opportunities to do so because that had always a little <quote>critical part of how America engages in the world</quote> <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 11-12)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He simply tells his audience that they are welcome in the <name type="geo">USA</name> and he would be glad it at least some of them took these opportunities he talked about.</s>
        <s><ref target="c10gk4_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> talks in the fourth paragraph about the opportunities the exchanges between people from <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> parts of the world can be, and how that is important to show them that they are joined together by the pursuit of a life that is productive and purposeful <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref>, and that after that happens, when everybody sees that everyone is just human, that is where the program begins <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 16-17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this paragraph, <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses the pronoun <quote>we</quote> in the sentences to show, that he is human just like everyone else in the audience, that they are all the same, and that they can work on these issues together to solve them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fifth and last paragraph of the speech is <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> direct appeal to the audience, starting with <quote>So to all of you [...]</quote> <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref> and furthermore tells them, that they can choose to make the world a more justice and cosmopolitan place, that they can choose peace, and that <quote>in these endeavors</quote> <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref>, they will find support and a <quote>friend in the United States of America</quote> <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c10gk4_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref><choice><orig>want</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> the students to be even more active <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> before, to help the world become a better place.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because it is an appeal, he uses the pronouns <quote>you</quote> throughout the whole paragraph, so the audience feels more like they are directly talked to.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, the whole speech seems like an sometimes direct, sometimes indirect appeal at the students to become more open minded at active about issues like racism or things of that sort.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One can also tell that <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> wants them very badly to interact with <name type="geo">America</name> in things like student exchanges and things like that, but that is not really a bad thing so one could say that his speech indeed motivates the students in the audience to at least think about the opportunities <ref target="c10gk4_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> told them about, like student exchanges.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
