<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g54_t3</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="challenge">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I heard that you think, that student exchanges are a waste of time.</s>
        <s>And I can understand your opinion, but I want to tell you some arguments, why student exchanges may be not a <choice><orig>waiste</orig><reg>waste</reg></choice> of time, and can even be an opportunity for a better future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all, my opinion is that student exchanges are not a <choice><orig>waiste</orig><reg>waste</reg></choice> of time, and that they are great experience.</s>
        <s>I myself wouldn't consider to go abroad because I couldn't leave my family for that long, but if you go abroad great things can happen to you.</s>
        <s>The most important thing is that you make new experiences, by seeing another culture, hearing a new language and meeting new people.</s>
        <s>Making new experiences can be fun and maybe they help you in the future to find a better job, where they want people with experiences of another cultures.</s>
        <s>Also something very important is, that student exchanges can make you more <choice><orig>tollerant</orig><reg>tolerant</reg></choice> and accepting.</s>
        <s>If more people would learn about another culture and not just hating them, there would be more less racism in the world.</s>
        <s>And going abroad is a way to connect with each other and tolerate us we can change the future and make the world to a better place, not only for us but for the people that will come after us.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If we all connect, we would have such a great power that we could change the world.</s>
        <s>But you have to remember with great power comes great responsibility.</s>
        <s>And that is why we have to learn from each other, to have more tolerance in this world.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
