<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g58_t2</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>to: <email>john@gymnasium.herzogenrath.de</email>
		from: <email>somefriend@Britain.com</email>
		<s>sub: student exchanges are definitely worth</s>
		<date>16th of December 2021</date></p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have read your last <choice><orig>E-mail</orig><reg>e-mail</reg></choice> you have sent to me, about student exchanges I personally couldn't withstand so that I write you back and give you some arguments for an exchange.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So first of all you don't have to take a gap year so if you have already finished school and applied to a university you can try to get a semester abroad there this way you can study while exploring cultures and meeting new people and you don't have ro revise a whole year.</s>
        <s>So where is the wasted time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I personally would try to experience as much cultures as possibly so that when you apply for a job or a university you are way ahead of the others when it comes to intercultural understandings which in my opinion is a key ingredient in our connected world.</s>
        <s>So even when you do an exchange year in High School and have to revise the class I wouldn't say that you have wasted your time you just invested it in something different.</s>
        <s>By the way I think that such an exchange year is also a fun way to escape your current life and just see it in another perspective.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However I hope I've changed your view on exchange years a bit and that you write me back soon.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Cheers</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
