<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g56_t3</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="challenge">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey John</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you're doing good and well, but I think I need to talk to you about one specific topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Your statement earlier, that <quote>student exchanges are a waste of time</quote> gave me something to think about, and I am afraid I have to disagree with you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I do understand your point of view, because for some people, it really is, for some it is even a very bad decision because they don't understand anything in school so their grades drop, but that is by far not everyone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Many students who did exchanges are really happy now that they decided to do so, because it is a big opportunity.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At first, there is the language <choice><orig>aspekt</orig><reg>aspect</reg></choice>: As soon as you are living in another country, you need to adapt to the language <choice><orig>thats</orig><reg>that's</reg></choice> spoken there, and if not, you need to use at least English, because it is the world language.</s>
        <s>This will improve your language skills very fast, so at the end of it, many students speak fluently or nearly fluently a second/another language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That is a huge pro because it is not as hard as learning it on your own or at school with other people around you who speak your native language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then there is also the cultural <choice><orig>aspekt</orig><reg>aspect</reg></choice>: You visit another country, so therefore, there are many <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> holidays, <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> ways how the people interact with each other and so on.</s>
        <s>You really learn something about the culture, which helps you becoming more open minded and cosmopolitan.</s>
        <s>If more people would do exchanges, it would probably be a huge help on issues like racism.</s>
        <s>All in all <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> would like to say that I am a big fan of student exchanges, even if I have never been on one, because to me it seems like such a huge adventure, which I would not want to miss out, and also would not want you to miss out because it can be a lot of fun.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could help you a little bit more on that topic because you seemed a little uninformed to me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Bye, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
