<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g41_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical_recount">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Carlos,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have heard that you ignore the losers of globalisation and due to the fact that I read an article about it, I want to make you aware about the losers of globalisation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article shows the life of three people who visited an industry in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>Cambodscha</orig><reg>Cambodia</reg></choice></name>.</s>
        <s>They were shocked about the bad working conditions and the life there.</s>
        <s>Besides, they describe that the workers are sitting in almost the same position for hours and that they do the same procedure every day.</s>
        <s>The article shows how desolate a life at those industries can be and that the workers often have no choice and hope.</s>
        <s>Moreover they refer their lives to our, which underlines the shocking friction between human <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice> in our today's world.</s>
        <s>For example, the workers need to eat the same food every day and they get paid very poorly, considering that they even work much more than we do.</s>
        <s>Due to this shocking experience those three people had there in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>Cambodscha</orig><reg>Cambodia</reg></choice></name>, they decided to be more active to provide such catastrophical conditions in the future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope this opened your eyes my dear friend and that you might rethink your daily behaviour in order to help those losers of globalisation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Best wishes, John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
