<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g40_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The following analysis will analyse the author's intention by focusing on the use of stylistic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author writes about a current global issue and wants to inform about the effects and causes of globalised environmental pollution.</s>
        <s>She also wants to make, us, the readers aware about this issue.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author uses academical language in a serious tone.</s>
        <s>There are many facts by scientists that are listed in the article/blog to underline her arguments, like <quote>The biosphere has [...] oxygen, nitrogen, carbon dioxide, argon and water vapor</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 6-7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She also asks a question <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 18-19)</ref> to make the reader think about the worth of our actions.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, the author takes away the big effects <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 21-24)</ref> and also emphasizes that there are more causes to make the reader aware of being able to do <choice><abbr>sth</abbr><expan>something</expan></choice> against the pollution.</s>
        <s>Therefore, she quotes scientists <quote>we are living in an era of mass extinction, due to human made environmental pollution</quote> to underline the effects and also the causes.</s>
        <s>There is also an example the author uses to underline the effects pointing out that many people died because of pollution <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 31-32)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Moreover, she uses stylistic devices like a comparison with <name type="geo">Hiroshima</name> to make us aware about a possible end of our world to shock the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author also uses many <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices to reach the reader.</s>
        <s>By employing pronouns as <quote>we</quote> and <quote>our</quote> she underlines that everyone should be concerned including herself.</s>
        <s>Therefore she uses many <choice><orig>connotatives</orig><reg>connotative</reg></choice> words so that the reader looks from a negative perspective.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the author intends to make us aware and wants us to take action against this issue.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
