<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g48_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The following analysis aims to identify the language <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> uses in her blogpost to transmit her message.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly, the author explains what she means when she writes <quote>Environmental pollution</quote>.</s>
        <s><quote>Environmental pollution refers to the introduction of harmful pollutants into the environment</quote><ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By doing so, the reader is informed about what exactly is meant and can follow the blogpost better.</s>
        <s>Following that, she describes the planet earth and paints a perfect image into the reader's head: <quote>human life and other forms of existence have flourished on earth</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 7-8, ll. 4-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This results in the reader appreciating the earth and perhaps willing to protect it, if anything were to happen to it.</s>
        <s>By then turning everything to the negative side: <quote>surge in pollution</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>, <quote>man [...] began losing control</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>, <quote>victim of his own creations</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> the author not only frightens the reader, but also makes him/her aware of the appalling situation the earth they learned to love is facing.</s>
        <s>This is then strengthened by a more detailed description of the negative effects of pollution: <quote>devastating effects on sea life, on crops and human health</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>, <quote>affects all plants, animal and human life in a destructing way</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>, <quote>at the cost of our health</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref>, <quote>threatened with extinction</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>By introducing this wide span of effects, the author makes the reader feel threatened and feel the urge to do something against the problem discussed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The reference to the question <quote>whether all is well with our industrial growth and progress in the field of science and technology</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref> stimulates the reader to think about the question him-/herself and to doubt the positive effects of industrial growth and <choice><orig>scientif</orig><reg>scientific</reg></choice> or <choice><orig>technologic</orig><reg>technological</reg></choice> advance.</s>
        <s>As the author then reminds the reader of everyday causes of pollution, for instance <quote>traffic</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>, <quote>synthetic detergents</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>, <quote>nitrogen fertilizers</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref> or <quote>insecticides</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>, the reader realises the possibilities tha the/she has to limit her/his contribution to pollution, but also how he/she is affecting the environment.</s>
        <s>By warning the reader of the <quote>[contaminated] water we drink and [...] vegetables</quote> the reader becomes aware of how pollution is affecting everyone.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, the inclusive language makes the reader feel addressed and included in the happening.</s>
        <s>The example of the <quote>industrial environment tragedy [...] at Bhopal</quote> on <date>December 3, 1984</date> makes it clear how severe the effects of pollution, in this case a <quote>leakage</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 30)</ref>, can be.</s>
        <s>Finally, the author specifically stats the urgence of action: <quote>If we fail to restore the ecological balance right now, it will be too late tomorrow</quote> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref>, basically instructing the reader what is to be done.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Altogether, the author uses negative and inclusive language to make it clear how grave the current situation is and that the reader him- or herself can help to fix the problem.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
