<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g39_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The blog <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="title">Globalised Environmental Pollution - Causes and Effects</ref> by <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> was published in <date>5th <choice><orig>Febuary</orig><reg>February</reg></choice> 2014</date> and was found on the source <name type="misc">Blog on Environment</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She signalizes our dangerous position in the world with facts, she explains that the growth of urbans, our increasing industry and modernisation let the nature extend and us suffering.</s>
        <s>The author also sees the problem in the way we fail to create a balance between our environment and our industry.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author points out, that our planet is very important for us, and that everything on it is a <choice><orig>donnation</orig><reg>donation</reg></choice> for the life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For that she goes on the biological level and explains the conditions our survival is based on.</s>
        <s>For example, that air and water are the most common elements, which create life <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 4-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Heading to the role we play on the earth right now, the writes appeals on destructionable effects our achievements created.</s>
        <s>The industrialisation and fast growth of the urbans, let the nature extend <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 9-16)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition, the writer <choice><orig>adresses</orig><reg>addresses</reg></choice> the readers with the words <quote>it lets us wondering</quote> or <quote>we all live on planet earth</quote> which affects on the readers feel the importance to help finding a solution for helping our home.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Keep going to <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 17-19)</ref>, the author lets us questioning, if we really achieve new goals and better life, or just dig our own grave and destroy everything around us.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita</ref> announces about daily pollutions because of the transports, fabrics and free toxic materials.</s>
        <s>That <choice><orig>give</orig><reg>gives</reg></choice> us an illustration of a very serious situation we are <choice><orig>confrontet</orig><reg>confronted</reg></choice> with right now, in this decade <add>(or even century)</add> <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 20-24)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She brings us on a new knowledge, by confirming, that the pollution brings up many big diseasees like dirty food as water and suffering animals, plants and humans themselves <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 24-27)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita</ref> gives an example of a dangerous fabric in the <date>1980s</date>, which played at <name type="geo">Bhopal</name> as an environmental tragedy for more than 2000 people, who could not survive the effects of the toxic emission <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 28-32)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Moreover her prediction <quote>If we fail to restore the ecological balance right now, it would be too late tomorrow</quote> pushes us on high alert and gives us motivation and makes us aware of the big <choice><orig>menance</orig><reg>menace</reg></choice> we created.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
