<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a10g48_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The blogpost <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="title">Globalised Environmental Pollution - Causes and Effects</ref> written by <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> and published on the <date>5th of February 2014</date> on her blog, is about environmental pollution, why it exists and how it affects humans and nature.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author starts off by introducing pollution and the natural balance that has enabled life on earth.</s>
        <s><ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Mitra</ref> then moves on to explaining the origins of environmental pollution - urbanization and industrialization.</s>
        <s>Following that, <ref target="a10gk5_1" type="author">Mitra</ref> states that pollution has devastating effects on the flora, fauna and human health.</s>
        <s>By mentioning the question whether today's industrial growth and scientific progress is good, she explains that traffic, industries and nuclear power are also causes of pollution.</s>
        <s>As a result, our food, water and air are contaminated.</s>
        <s>Other effects that the author mentions include extinction, diseases and the leakage of poisonous gas at <name type="geo">Bhopal</name>, <date>1984</date> which resulted in over 2000 deaths.</s>
        <s>The author ends her blogpost by saying that the ecological balance urgently needs to be restored.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
