<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g40_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="discussion">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The British and American societies are very multicultural.</s>
        <s>The majority of American citizen have ancestors who immigrated once.</s>
        <s>The British society is much affected by their history of slave trade.</s>
        <s>In the following text I will discuss the question in what way the influences, which are caused by this multicultural society can be positive and negative.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand, a multicultural society can affects the life in this country in a positive way.</s>
        <s>There will probably be a big exchange between the cultures and hopefully they will even mix.</s>
        <s>On the other hand, there is the possibility that people are prejudged and <choice><orig>discrimminated</orig><reg>discriminated</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>There will always be people who think they are better.</s>
        <s>Furthermore there is a high risk for parallel societies.</s>
        <s>They already exist in the <name type="geo">US</name>, which is caused by their failed integration.</s>
        <s>These societies which exist parallel affect the life, <choice><orig>expecially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> of children and teenagers in a negative way.</s>
        <s>The impact on their sense of belonging is huge, since they are not fully American, but they do not see the homeland of their parents as home too.</s>
        <s>But there is another thing you have to see.</s>
        <s>This multicultural society can have a great impact, if you want to integrate and if you work hard for it.</s>
        <s>To finish my argumentation, I want to say that there are many risks, but the question is: are they high enough?</s>
        <s>The positive influences a multicultural society has are so present.</s>
        <s>Your family will be able to learn things about other cultures and your children will be raised as non racist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, I want to say that multicultural societies will <choice><orig>absolutly</orig><reg>absolutely</reg></choice> affect your life.</s>
        <s>In my opinion the positive influences are bigger <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> the negative ones.</s>
        <s>The cultural exchange can show you so much and you could add interesting things to your cultural identity.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
