<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g48_t2</author>
        <name>explain</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="consequential_explanation">explain</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>1.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>His <choice><orig>Grandparents</orig><reg>grandparents</reg></choice> probably lived in a time in which racism against black people in the <name type="geo">UK</name> was much more common.</s>
        <s>The state itself even discriminated black people, so overall his <choice><orig>Grandparents</orig><reg>grandparents</reg></choice> had to suffer under harder conditions than <name type="person">Reece</name> does.</s>
        <s>But still there is room for improvement in <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> <name type="geo">UK</name> and <name type="person">Reece</name> has to suffer under somehow bad conditions even <choice><orig>thoug</orig><reg>though</reg></choice> they are not as bad as those his grandparents lived in.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>2.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Because black people in the <name type="geo">UK</name> live in a country where slavery used to be normal, some of the ways of thinking about black people back then has still found his ways in to the society that exists now.</s>
        <s>So some black people are treated like slaves by others.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>3.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Slavery itself does not exist in the <name type="geo">United Kingdom</name> anymore but for some people this way of thinking about others is still there.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>4.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Black people who have probably suffered under the conditions but still managed to get <choice><orig>succesfull</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice>, now want to help others so they do not have to struggle with the same issues they had.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>5.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Black people used to be hated, even if they were <choice><orig>succesfull</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Most of the times they got hated especially when they became <choice><orig>succesfull</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Nowadays they get respected just like everybody else and are rolemodels for some children just like other <choice><orig>succesfull</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice> people often are.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>6.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Even <choice><orig>thoug</orig><reg>though</reg></choice> many black people have a hard time, trying to find their place in society, they are <choice><orig>hopefull</orig><reg>hopeful</reg></choice> and believe that it will be better for the next generation of black people.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
