<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g34_t2</author>
        <name>explain</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="consequential_explanation">explain</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>1.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>This <choice><orig>Sentence</orig><reg>sentence</reg></choice> means that he knows, that his grandparents had to go through worst and he is thankful for what he has, he still has his own <choice><orig>Problems</orig><reg>problems</reg></choice> that he has to deal with, for example racism or getting teased at school.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>2.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>What this means is that the black community has more pressure due to <choice><orig>theire</orig><reg>their</reg></choice> past.</s>
        <s>They have to fight for their name, for a chance and <choice><orig>alway</orig><reg>always</reg></choice> prove themselves.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>3.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>I think the meaning of that sentence is that slavery is gone but the people also known as racists still live and put pressure on black people in many situations.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>4.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Basically if black people who are somehow <choice><orig>succesful</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice> try to help young black people recognise their potential and selfworth.</s>
        <s>One example for this could be a footballer named <name type="person">Marcus Rashford</name>.</s>
        <s>He donated millions for people, who are hungry and are suffering.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>5.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The more you want to be like someone, the more you try and understand them <ref target="c10gk3_1" type="line">(l. 56)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This eliminates any barriers between people, because there is no reason to have them and if you do have them it's basically racism.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>6.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Black people or especially <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> black people are thankful that their lives were not that bad like the African Americans.</s>
        <s>They are not where they want to be, but they are happy, that they aren't where they used to be.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
