<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g39_t2</author>
        <name>explain</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
        <note genre="explaining" genre_family="consequential_explanation">explain</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>1.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Reece</name> goes through different things than his grandparents did in their time when they came to <name type="geo">England</name>.</s>
        <s>He feels like he needs to fight harder to get a chance out there and not end up like his grandparents.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>2.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Racism and slavery was mostly done at/against black people at the <date>mid-1960s</date> and other times.</s>
        <s>When people think about slavery, most of them instandtly think that only black people were included.</s>
        <s>That's why it impacts negatively upon the black communities.</s>
        <s>Looking back at those times, you can see how adults and teenagers in this generation still have the terrible thoughts about slavery in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>Britian</orig><reg>Britain</reg></choice></name> and how badly it impacts on them.</s>
        <s>Especially the countries with most those actions.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>3.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The slavery itself is no longer legal and already abolished, but most of the black people still get racist comments in some places/cities/countries and have family members who went through slavery.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>4.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The black leaders and artists are much older than most of the young black people in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>Britian</orig><reg>Britain</reg></choice></name>.</s>
        <s>So they know more about the background.</s>
        <s>That's why they work among the community and deal with the young persons to help them through their problems and feel worth it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>5.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Black people went through racist insults and abuse, but since all black people hold their strength and went through hard time together, most of them got <choice><orig>succesful</orig><reg>successful</reg></choice> and play sports.</s>
        <s>Or ended up being in the charts or producers.</s>
        <s>Most of the white kids think it is <q>cool</q> to be black now since they want to try and understand how it is to be black.</s>
        <s>Well, it is racist if you break down down yourself and try to be like someone who isn't you, someone who you want to be but don't know any problems they went through, because that isn't cool at all.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
    <head>
      <p>6.</p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Black people remain positive about that journey, of course the journey of the older generation was <choice><orig>tuff</orig><reg>tough</reg></choice>, but now the younger one can look back to it and take their own to find their place, make a change, think about their own future and how to make it a good one and most importantly to not end up like their ancestors.</s>
        <s>They are not exactly where they want to be, but not where they used to be.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
