<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g46_t2</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello,</salute>
        <s>&gt;my name is <name type="person">Faraj al-Byarshan</name>, I am 41 years old and I came to <name type="geo">New York</name> in year <date>2005</date>.</s>
        <s>My home country is the <name type="geo">Iraq</name> where I lived 25 years.</s>
        <s>During this time I got a wife.</s>
        <s>We have two sons.</s>
        <s>First they couldn't come with me to <name type="geo">New York</name> because we had not enough money.</s>
        <s>But two years later a friend of us took them with him.</s>
        <s>In these two years I was really sad angry about myself.</s>
        <s><quote>I shouldn't have gone to <name type="geo">New York</name> without my family</quote> I said to myself every day.</s>
        <s>But I had no choice to do anything else.</s>
        <s>In our country we had bad living conditions.</s>
        <s>My parents died there because they had no money to buy food for <choice><orig>themselfs</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>As I said before we hadn't much money as well.</s>
        <s>It was only enough to get me to <name type="geo">New York</name>.</s>
        <s>We thought that I can get a job there and earn some money so I can send something to my family.</s>
        <s>But it wasn't that easy.</s>
        <s>I asked restaurants, supermarkets and everything else.</s>
        <s>But no one wanted an immigrant who works for them.</s>
        <s>I couldn't communicate with my family from <date>2005</date> to <date>2007</date>.</s>
        <s>So I didn't know, if they are still alive or dead or maybe on the way to <name type="geo">New York</name> as well.</s>
        <s>I was hoping that they are alive so I tried to get a job for two weeks.</s>
        <s>After this time I finally got one at a cleaning company.</s>
        <s>Every month I earned 200$.</s>
        <s>I took 100 for myself and sent 100 to my family.</s>
        <s>I wasn't <choice><orig>shure</orig><reg>sure</reg></choice> if they get it but I believed in God.</s>
        <s>That's the only thing you can do in this situation.</s>
        <s>In <date>2007</date> when my family finally came to <name type="geo">New York</name> I was the happiest man on earth.</s>
        <s>My wife told me that they came in here with a little fishing boat.</s>
        <s>They drove over the whole Atlantic with a fishing boat!</s>
        <s>You can't imagine how scared you are at this time.</s>
        <s>But they are alive and they are with me.</s>
        <s>That's the only thing that counts.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
