<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b11g30_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Sir or Madam,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am writing to you in response to the interview of <name type="misc">Ayad Akhtar</name> in <name type="misc">Guernica Magazine</name>.</s>
        <s>We have recently read <name type="misc">Disgraced</name> in school and I have found it very interesting, <choice><orig>esspecially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> <name type="misc">Ayad Akhtar's</name> views of faith and identity, as he talked about in your interview.</s>
        <s>Even <choice><orig>tough</orig><reg>though</reg></choice> I don't know, what it is like <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> a minority, I still think I understand what <name type="misc">Ayad Akhtar</name> wants to express in that part of the interview.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I would have to disagree with him, as I think your identity marker is not given from outside, you can change it.</s>
        <s>I also think, that identity is not reliant on faith or even ethnicity.</s>
        <s>Your identity is what interest you, what you like or dislike and your opinions as well as other factors.</s>
        <s>It is not <choice><orig>neccesarilly</orig><reg>necessarily</reg></choice> dependent on your background, if you don't want to.</s>
        <s>Your identity is also not, what people think of you, when they first see you, but it is what people think of you, who have known you for a long time.</s>
        <s>This can also be seen in the character of <name type="misc">Amir</name> in <name type="misc">Disgraced</name>.</s>
        <s>He changes his identity away from islam and his upbringing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope this letter has informed you on a new view of identity.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
