<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11g17_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The excerpt at hand, dealing with the escalation of the dinner and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> sudden outbreak of violence, is very crucial for the drama and to get a better understanding of <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> character.</s>
        <s>In the same place it's a turning point.</s>
        <s>In the following I am going to do <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> detailled examination of the scene and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> emotional outbursts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all it is significant to mention the general change of behavior of all the characters in this excerpt.</s>
        <s>While they just discussed about their different opinions mainly about Islam, there is a conflict where they shout, spit and acting violently.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is very angry about her husband and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> lying at her: <quote>What the fuck is going on here?</quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 71, l. 21)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The vulgar words <choice><orig>reveals</orig><reg>reveal</reg></choice> her shock.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> gets hysterical when her husband walks in because she fears he could believe <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Her incredulous shouts, prove this fear <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, ll. 7-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>She manipulates <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> within telling him she was emotionally overwhelmed with the fact that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> got the job instead of <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, ll. 2-4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This makes <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> believe her and being even more angry about <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In general, one can say that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tries hard to get rid <choice><orig>off</orig><reg>of</reg></choice> Islam because of obsoleted punishments in the <choice><orig>quaran</orig><reg>Quran</reg></choice>, anti-semitism and mysogony he experienced in the <choice><orig>islamic</orig><reg>Islamic</reg></choice> <choice><orig>community</orig><reg>communnity</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Additionally, he made other bad experiences in his childhood.</s>
        <s>The first two scenes of the drama reveal the effort and struggles <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> has to fully get rid <choice><orig>off</orig><reg>of</reg></choice> the ingrained cultural values of Islam.</s>
        <s>He criticises her mother for teaching him to spit on Jews and the <choice><orig>quaran</orig><reg>Quran</reg></choice> saying wife-beating is an option.</s>
        <s>In this scene the impuls of the values comes back again, when he loses control.</s>
        <s>This happens twice: it happens once when he spits in <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 40)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Especially this behavior reveals <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> <choice><orig>surpressed</orig><reg>suppressed</reg></choice> <choice><orig>islamic</orig><reg>Islamic</reg></choice> values and refers to a memory of his childhood where his mother spat in his face after <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> telling her he had a crush on a <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> girl.</s>
        <s>This is up to this point <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> could stand his anger but the several circumstances coming together at one evening are like an emotional outburst.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These circumstances that triggered him were for example the injustices and islamophobia at his work because <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> got a job should be supposed to get.</s>
        <s>He believes the happening that happened as an act at islamophobia.</s>
        <s>The fact that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is African-American lets him call himself with the n-word <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This makes the reader realise that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> thinks he has more to suffer from islamophobia than <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> from racism against black people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The affair he becomes aware of leads <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to get completely out of control and hitting his wife <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 74, l. 6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His behavior is the complete opposite of the man he wants to be after critisizing the <choice><orig>quaran</orig><reg>Quran</reg></choice> for the point wife-beating.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In general one can see that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> both act discriminating.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> hurts perjuges at <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> as if he represents the <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice> community: <quote>There's a reason they call you people animals</quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>To sum up it can be said that the unconscious and surpressed prejuges or hate of <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> against the religions Islam and Jewishness comes up as a consult of integrated cultural values.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
