<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b11g27_t3</author>
        <name>formal_letter</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">formal_letter</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Sir or Madam,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am writing in response to the interview with <name type="misc">Ayad Akhtar</name>, recently published in the <name type="misc">Guernica Magazine</name>, because I found some interesting parallels between <name type="misc">Akhtar's</name> statements and the character <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> from his drama <name type="misc">Disgraced</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="misc">Amir</name> changed his whole identity, even is security number only to get rid of Islam, because he didn't want people seeing him as a <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>This disgust against Islam comes from him having childhood trauma caused by his mother who made him do unethical things because of Islam.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="misc">Amir</name> also sees religion as something that defines people, but in a segregating way.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">Amir</name> doesn't see religion as something that unites people, at least not Islam.</s>
        <s>Personally I don't think religion is the <quote>main identity marker</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course one could say that religion connects people all over the world, who can't even speak the same language, and that most cultures have deep connections with religion, for example <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> cultural belief are overlapping a lot with what the bible is saying.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand religion isn't the core of most people.</s>
        <s>It's part of them but it isn't them.</s>
        <s>While at first glance religion and ethnicity are the things that stand out the most, it's really the values and morals that are core of someone's identity trait and determine whether one wants to talk to someone or not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion I would say that faith is an important identity marker at times, but the way a person determines good and bad e.g. the values of someone, which can be heavily influenced by religion, make you want to stay with-/distance yourself from someone else, while their looks and/or religion way influence whether you want to get to know someone better.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
