<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11g28_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>At the beginning, it is important to know, that <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> already was upset, before he found out, that his friend gets his job and his wife cheated on him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly, <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> had an intense discussion about the Islam and his rules, where they both got <choice><orig>aggressiv</orig><reg>aggressive</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is drunk and just said he wants to make this evening special and wonderful and that they should stop talking about <choice><orig>islam</orig><reg>Islam</reg></choice> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 68, l. 33-36)</ref>.</s>
        <s>But when he comes back into the room he is inflamed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> was scared that his bosses <choice><orig>avoids</orig><reg>avoid</reg></choice> him and now he gets to know why.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Yet when <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> freaks out about <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> does not have the same reaction as her.</s>
        <s>He does not recognize or understand it.</s>
        <s>Even when <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> tries to explain it, he does not pay attention to it.</s>
        <s>He doesn not give <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> the fault, but <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He does not see what jsut happened, because he is so angry with <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref>.</s>
        <s>He acts like she would make the affair up <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 18-19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>With this words, his anger is shown very well, but it gets more intense after <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> does not pay attention to <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> accusations.</s>
        <s>At this point <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> explodes.</s>
        <s>He still does not react to <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Jory's</ref> words about <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, but he wants to make her feel really bad about her <q>taking</q> his job or his place in the company.</s>
        <s>He wants to make her feel like she does not deserve to have that job <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 27-28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>At one point he uses the N-word to really underline how unfair it is to ignore his hard work <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> offends <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> as an asshole he directly tells him back that he <add>(<ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref></add>) is the asshole.</s>
        <s>The author's intention is to show <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> fundamental anger and range.</s>
        <s>This range has got higher than the moment before, where he did not pay attention to the cheating.</s>
        <s>But after he exploded, he pays attention to everything.</s>
        <s>After he freaks out at one time, he can't be stopped.</s>
        <s>This can also be seen at p. 74, where he does not stop punching <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, and is stuck in his range.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> spits in <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face, the author wants to underline how deep all of his background and anger is hidden in him.</s>
        <s>Surely <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> was told by his mother to spit in people's faces or he has seen it because of her.</s>
        <s>But he told <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> and <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Abe</ref> that this opened his eyes about Muslims and their prejudices, but he did it again, in a face of a grown <choice><orig>jedish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> man.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This point is the outburst and change point of the play.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> makes the reader believe how much he hates Islam and the things his mother <choice><orig>thaught</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> him, but in this scene is able to see how much of the <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice> prejudices is still stuck in him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> words after the spit <choice><orig>underlines</orig><reg>underline</reg></choice> that <quote>There is a reason they call you people animals</quote> <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 1)</ref>, it is racist, but he clearly puts <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <choice><orig>muslims</orig><reg>Muslims</reg></choice> into one bag or drawer.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Indirectly he tells <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, that he is still a <choice><orig>muslim</orig><reg>Muslim</reg></choice>, because it is in him <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="line">(p. 66, l. 37: <quote>It is in the bones</quote>)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> action shows how aggressive he really is and of course the action where he hits <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> underlines that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To make a conclusion or to come to an end, the picture of <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> changes in this scene, because he does something he swore <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> was horrible for him again.</s>
        <s>He acts the same way his mother did and his anger is getting clearly here, and how the Islam is so much more a part of him the he thinks it is and probably more a part than he wants it to be.</s>
        <s>He does not regret it, to spit in <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Isaacs</orig><reg>Isaac's</reg></choice></ref> face, he only regrets that he hit <ref target="b11gk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
