<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l38_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical_recount">describe</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given excerpt is from <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref>'s play <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> which was written around <date>1596</date>.</s>
        <s>One of the main characters is the Jewish moneylender <name type="person">Shylock</name> who lends money to his enemy to take revenge on him and whose daughter has ran away.</s>
        <s>His situation in the given excerpt will be described in the following text.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Prior to this excerpt, <name type="person">Shylock's</name> daughter <name type="person">Jessica</name> has eloped with a Christian.</s>
        <s>Moreover, <name type="person">Shylock</name> has lent money to <name type="person">Antonio</name>, his enemy, under the bond that if he does not repay his debts on time, <name type="person">Shylock</name> will receive one pound of <name type="person">Antonio's</name> flesh.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the excerpt, <name type="person">Shylock</name> is talking to his friend <name type="person">Tubal</name> who is also Jewish.</s>
        <s>He questions <name type="person">Tubal</name> about his missing daughter but <name type="person">Tubal</name> also does not know about <name type="person">Jessica's</name> whereabouts.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> expresses his anger aobut his daughter eloping but his spirits rise when he is told that <name type="person">Antonio</name> has lost one of his ships.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Tubal</name> then tells him that <name type="person">Antonio</name> will go bankrupt due to the loss of the ship which pleases <name type="person">Shylock</name> even more because he realizes that <name type="person">Antonio</name> will break the bond and <name type="person">Shylock</name> will receive what he wanted.</s>
        <s>Meanwhile he also expresses his diappointment and anger for his daughter who has taken and spent a lot of his money and his belongings.</s>
        <s>Lastly, he orders <name type="person">Tubal</name> to get him an officer to arrest and charge <name type="person">Antonio</name> and hurriedly sends him away.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
