<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l40_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Beth,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>how</orig><reg>How</reg></choice> have you been?</s>
        <s>And how is your research going so far?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When you first told me about your presentation about unusual school projects I was a little worried that I would not be able to find anything weird in <name type="geo">Germany</name> since we always tend to follow our beloved ruler.</s>
        <s>But one morning last week I took a look at the <name type="misc">Tagezeitung</name> which my dad usually reads and found an article about chess projects in <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> primary schools.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article tells of a project called <name type="misc">chess makes you smart</name> which was founded in <name type="geo">Bremen</name> and turned 2400 primary school pupils into chess players by teaching them chess one hour a week.</s>
        <s>The teachers who are taking aprt in this project answered a survey which came to the conclusion that the majority of students are happy and enthusiastic about their chess classes and that some even started to play chess in their free time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The reason this project was started at all was because teachers hoped that it would improve the children's logical and strategic thinking, their concentration and their behaviour towards each other.</s>
        <s>Most of the questioned teachers answered that their expectations were met and that the project was successful.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Still there are children getting bored or frustrated easily which demands teachers to focus on the diverse characters of the children and to show them how to enjoy the game.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At one primary school in <name type="geo">Hamburg</name> chess even became a compulsory subject because of the positive outcomes and benefits for the students.</s>
        <s>After ten years of experience with chess classes the teacher speaks of positive effects on the children's achievements, communication with each other, social behaviour and concentration <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">bender</gap> learning to deal with the consequences of a decision, following the rules and dealing with a defeat <add>In <name type="geo">Bremen</name> the chess projects <choice><orig>ends</orig><reg>end</reg></choice> with a yearly competition for the students in the old part of the city</add> which were also noticed by other teachers who started a chess project at their school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now that I have read this article I am invested in your presentation's topic.</s>
        <s>Would you mind sending me your notes once you gave it?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In hope to hera back from you soon</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
