<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>a12l39_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> is nowadays still a very famous play and which is part of the <name type="misc">Abitur</name>.</s>
        <s>As soon as this play comes up there is always the question <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> it fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes or raises awareness for the problem of antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will discuss this question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand you can say that it fuel <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes because of the way Jewish characters are treated, but on the other hand you can say that it raises awareness for the problem because the way the Jewish people are treated.</s>
        <s>The behaviour of the Christian people back then way something horrible and they thought that Jewish people are not humans.</s>
        <s>This should <choice><orig>definitly</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> raise the awareness of the antisemitism problem we still have today.</s>
        <s>It shows that no one should be treated differently just because of their religion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand you can say that the play fuels the <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes because one of the <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> characters is in some parts of the play presented as a greedy, cruel and brutal person.</s>
        <s>You can also see him as the villain of the play.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In today's world there are still so many people that have <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> opinions and through this lay these people could think that they are right.</s>
        <s>Many stereotypes that <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> people have to deal with are presented to the audience in this play.</s>
        <s>The Jewish <choice><orig>Men</orig><reg>man</reg></choice> called <name type="person">Shylock</name> is presented as a preson who only cares about revenge and money.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other hand you can say that there are also many parts in this play where people can feel very sorry for the <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> character because of the way he is treated.</s>
        <s>The play is also very famous for the monologue from <name type="person">Shylock</name> where he compares himself to Christians.</s>
        <s>This is a strong point why this play raises awareness for the problem of antisemitism.</s>
        <s>Every normal human being who watches or reads this play should at some point realise that no one in this world should be <choice><orig>descriminated</orig><reg>discriminated</reg></choice> for their religion or other things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all one can say that this play <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes and raises wareness for the problem of antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion it only fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes for people who already have <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> opinions because I think that every normal being should feel sorry for <name type="person">Shylock</name> instead of seeing him as the villain.</s>
        <s>In conclusion I think it is more likely that this play raises awareness of the problem of antisemitism we unfortunately still have today than it fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
