<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12l40_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> himself probably never even met somebody Jewish throughout his life.</s>
        <s>Still he believes himself in a position to write a play in which a Jew is representing the villain who is hated by nearly every other character.</s>
        <s>Did this raise awareness for the problem of antisemitism in the Elizabethan era?</s>
        <s>Probably not, btu might do justice today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will discuss whether <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> <add>1596/97</add> by <name type="person">William Shakespeare</name>, a renowned playwright at this time and further on, fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes or raises awareness for the problem of antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion <name type="person">Shylock</name> is a problematic role in this <quote>comedy</quote>.</s>
        <s>He is often referred to as <quote>the</quote> Jew, sometimes even combined with insulting adjectives.</s>
        <s>Moreover, he <choice><orig>looses</orig><reg>loses</reg></choice> everything throughout the play and in the end he does not even get his money back, nor revenge towards <name type="person">Antonio</name> and even he has to convert to Christianity.</s>
        <s>At the end of the play he is standing there alone, without anybody else but the people in <name type="geo">Venice</name> <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">disrepting</gap> him and spitting on him.</s>
        <s>Still their play is considered a comedy even though comedies are known for their happy endings.</s>
        <s>So if this is supposed to be a happy ending, how ca we say that this play raises awareness for the problem of antisemitism?</s>
        <s>It seems to be doing the opposite.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the Elizabethan era adherents of a different religion than Christianity were persecuted.</s>
        <s>Therefore prejudices played a major role during this time.</s>
        <s>It is ahrd to argue that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> was trying to raise <choice><orig>awarness</orig><reg>awareness</reg></choice> even though he included <name type="person">Shylock's</name> famous speech about Jews not being different from other people.</s>
        <s>But we do not know how audiences reacted to this speech.</s>
        <s>Whether they took it serious or whether they were blind by their societal standards and fears.</s>
        <s>Therefore this play appears to have fueled <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice>stereotypes during <name type="person">Elizabeth's</name> reign.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nowadays we are able to look at this play from a different perspective.</s>
        <s>We are able to express our opinion freely and reflect on prejudices and stereotypes.</s>
        <s>We are able to see flaws in old literature, stereotypes that can be overcome.</s>
        <s>But in my opinion we do not have to censor literature for that.</s>
        <s>Forbidding a play will make it even more interesting and meaningful to people who misuse it.</s>
        <s>We should rather learn from the play and the historical facts that it conveys.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude I will say that <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> might have fueled antisemitism in the Elizabethan era but can be considered as a play that raises awareness for the problem of antisemitism nowadays.</s>
        <s>We can learn from history and we most definitely should.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
