<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12l38_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, I will discuss whether <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes or raises awareness for the problems of antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Throughout the play, <name type="person">Shylock</name> is always characterized by him being a <choice><orig>jew</orig><reg>Jew</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The other characters call him <quote>the Jew</quote>, combine insults with his religion or talk about <quote>his Jewish heart</quote>.</s>
        <s>This is <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice>and fuels such stereotypes because it engraves <name type="person">Shylock</name> being Jewish as something bad or, at least, something which sets him apart from everyone else.</s>
        <s>It does not raise awareness against antisemitism as it is not commented by any characters but is continuously present in the whole play.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, <name type="person">Shylock</name> has some <quote>typical</quote> Jewish stereotypes: he works in the financial business and is portrayed as very mean about money.</s>
        <s>This can be seen in the given excerpt as <name type="person">Shylock</name> does not mainly grieve his daughter's eloping but rather the financial loss he suffers in this.</s>
        <s>This does not raise awareness against antisemitism because <name type="person">Shylock</name> is just being portrayed that way.</s>
        <s>One has to be conscious about those stereotypes to recognize them and therefore this promotes <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes as they are unconsciously entered into the play.</s>
        <s>By not seeing them as stereotypes, the audience inherits this way of thinking.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, <name type="person">Shylock</name> takes the role of the villain in this play.</s>
        <s>Him being a Jew is always taken into account in the play when other characters talk badly about him which furthermore deepens the <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> view against Jews.</s>
        <s>As his religion does not define his bad actions in the play, it would not matter if <name type="person">Shylock</name> had another religion but he is being treated differently in the play.</s>
        <s>Once again, this promotes <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes as the villain is a Jew in this play and that is put into the foreground when talking about <name type="person">Shylock</name>.</s>
        <s>Nonetheless his actions which would, from the audience's perspective make him the villain have nothing to do with religion but only with money, revenge and hate.</s>
        <s>This cannot raise awareness against antisemitism as no character changes the perception about <name type="person">Shylock</name> and therefore he is only describes as the Jewish villain.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some argue that <name type="person">Shylock</name> is only that hateful and revenge-seeking as he is in this excerpt because he has experienced so much hate and antisemitism in his life.</s>
        <s>He wants to take revenge on <name type="person">Antonio</name> because he hates him for always having bullied him and <name type="person">Shylock</name> having suffered under <name type="person">Antonio's</name> but also the other characters' antisemitism his whole life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This raises awareness for antisemitism because it shows how hard <name type="person">Shylock</name> has suffered under his treatment and that he is rather a victim than a villain.</s>
        <s>It portrays the extent of the hate he has experienced and its effect on him.</s>
        <s>This cannot be an argument for promoting <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes because it shows <name type="person">Shylock</name> as a victim of antisemitism and a stereotype would be that he is bad because he is a Jew and therefore experiencing antisemitism but it is the other way around.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly, in Elizabethan times being Jewish was different than today.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shakespeare</name> had probably never seen a Jew his whole life as the religion had not spread far around the world and in deeply Christian <name type="geo">England</name> one would not find many Jews.</s>
        <s>Therefore, he wrote his play based off stereotypes he had heard, stories of other people and just the society's standards back then.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This indicates that the play promotes <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes as even the writer wrote it off mainly such sources.</s>
        <s>How could he raise awareness for the problem of antisemitism if he neither knew a Jew nor had ever seen society's <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> treatment of Jews?</s>
        <s>Not at all.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Weighing up, throughout the whole play <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> values and stereotypes are being pictured.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is being shown as <quote>the bad Jew</quote>, the villain, everyone hates him due to his religion and he is experiencing <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> hate.</s>
        <s>I don't think that the argument of <name type="person">Shylock</name> being a victim due to antisemitism is strong enough to invalidate the others because for that one needs to realize that he is a victim and this does not appear in the first reading but only analysis.</s>
        <s>The strongest argument, in my opinion, is that <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> presumably wrote this play off <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes - so how should the play not promote those stereotypes?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Concludingly, <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> in my opinion fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes because just reading it is not enough to understand the problem of antisemitism here, for raising awareness one needs to analyse tha play to see the problematic structures.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
