<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l37_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello Emma,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>how</orig><reg>How</reg></choice> are you?</s>
        <s>I hope you are doing fine and you have also found out interesting and unusual projects in school for your presentation.</s>
        <s>Since I got your message, I really wanted to know more about those projects.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have found a great article about playing chess in school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Chess is kind of <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> brain sport and after a while teachers and <choice><orig>sientists</orig><reg>scientists</reg></choice> <choice><orig>belive</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> that children get a great profit from playing chess in school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is great for your concentration, supports logical and strategic thinking and improves the social interactions with others.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Just by teaching chess one time in a week can help to get fit and ready to compete with others.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> the project is called <quote>Chess makes you smart</quote>.</s>
        <s>There must be something real about it then.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The kids like it so much that 23% say that they are playing chess now in their freetime too.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is just important that teachers adapt to the students and teach them the love and the fun about this play.</s>
        <s>Otherwise the good players get bored and the weak players lose their interest.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After more than 10 years of experience in this field teachers do find positive outcome of having chess as a subject in school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They improve their social behaviour with others and gain a lot more concentration, <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> are better in general, in school and with their communication.</s>
        <s>There is just one thing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Girls don't play worse than boys but they do not <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">gon</gap> to the finals.</s>
        <s>Maybe boys like the competition better than girls.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>What are your thoughts on this?</s>
        <s>Do you still have any questions?</s>
        <s>I hope I could help you with your presentation.</s>
        <s>If you like you can call me and <choice><orig>practaise</orig><reg>practice</reg></choice> your talk with me.</s>
        <s>I would be very interested what kind of unusual projects at school you have and if the kids just profit that much like they are doing from playing chess.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Love hearing from you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Bye, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
