<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l36_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Jack,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>what's</orig><reg>What's</reg></choice> up?</s>
        <s>How u doin?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It's very nice to hear from you again and I hope <choice><orig>your</orig><reg>you're</reg></choice> doing <choice><orig>all right</orig><reg>alright</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>I'm happy helping you with your presentation on unusual school projects worldwide.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I found a great newspaper article from a big German newspaper called the <name type="misc">TAZ</name> and it's about chess as a subject in school.</s>
        <s>It's also quite recent, it was published on <date>June 30th 2020</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It's pretty interesting: <choice><orig>They</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> started a project in the German city <name type="geo">Bremen</name> called <name type="misc">Schach macht schlau</name>, which means <quote>chess makes you smart</quote>.</s>
        <s>In the first year 1226 students from 56 elementary schools participated and now there are already 2400 students who participate.</s>
        <s>There even is a big tournament at the end of the year.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author of the article also mentions <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>two</reg></choice> schools as examples.</s>
        <s>The first one is the <name type="misc">Theodor-Mommsen school</name> <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> students from year 8 and 9 were allowed to choose between different subjects - one of them being <quote>strategical thinking</quote> <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> they mainly focus on chess.</s>
        <s>The class has 27 students, 18 boys and nine girls and is <choice><orig>teached</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> by a mister <name type="person">Smith</name>.</s>
        <s>He says that chess has a lot of positive effects for example that the younger ones can also beat the older ones and weaker kids can beat stronger kids.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second school that's mentioned is an <choice><orig>elementary-school</orig><reg>elementary school</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">Hamburg</name> <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> they teach chess from year one to four as a mandatory subject.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Eventhough</orig><reg>Even though</reg></choice> the students have less hours of arts, music, maths or <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> they are still good enough at these subjects and the parents don't mind it either.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Apparently the students really benefit from the chess classes.</s>
        <s>An expert called <name type="person">Gabriele Rietow</name> says that the communication between younger and older people, the concentration and other things have all improved.</s>
        <s>That also matches with what the teachers from the project in <name type="geo">Bremen</name> said.</s>
        <s>72% of them say that their classes enjoy the weekly chess lessons and 23% say that lots of kids also play chess apart from school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But also experts believe that chess is good for kids.</s>
        <s>Almost 50% of them say that the logical and strategical thinking and 37% say that concentration improves when playing chess.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think all in all chess is a really cool subject and it seems to only have positive aspects to it.</s>
        <s>I really hope I was able to help you with your project and <choice><orig>i'm</orig><reg>I'm</reg></choice> looking forward to hearing from you soon.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Love, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
