<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12l32_t1</author>
        <name>describe</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="biographical_recount">describe</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the excerpt of the play <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref>, written by <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="author"><choice><orig>William Shakespear</orig><reg>William Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref>, <name type="person">Shylock</name>, the antagonist of the story, finds himself in a <choice><orig>perculiar</orig><reg>peculiar</reg></choice> situation.</s>
        <s>Between the happiness of his enemy's downfall and the sadness of <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> his daughter and his money.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Prior to this excerpt we learn of a bond that a Christian named <name type="person">Antonio</name> made for his friend <name type="person">Bassanio</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> and <name type="person">Antonio</name> are enemies since <name type="person">Antonio</name> has treated <name type="person">Shylock</name> very poorly.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Antonio</name> was asked to lend 3000 ducats to <name type="person">Bassanio</name>, to <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> he asked to be allowed to cut one ponud of flesh out above <name type="person">Antonio's</name> heart if they don't pay the money back within three months.</s>
        <s>Also prior to this <choice><orig>exerpt</orig><reg>excerpt</reg></choice> <name type="person">Jessica</name>, <name type="person">Shylock's</name> daughter, ran away with a Christian and a lot of money.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> sent a good friend named <name type="person">Tubal</name> to look for his daughter.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this excerpt <name type="person">Tubal</name> has just returned from searching for <name type="person">Jessica</name> in <name type="geo">Genoa</name>.</s>
        <s>He tells the eagerly awaiting <name type="person">Shylock</name> that he was unable to find <name type="person">Jessica</name> and that she spent lots of money within one night.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> gets mad and talks about how he spends so much money on finding her, he says that she wishes she was dead, for then he would not have to search for her anymore.</s>
        <s>This makes him very pessimistic and sad.</s>
        <s>But then <name type="person">Tubal</name> tells <name type="person">Shylock</name> that he also heard that <name type="person">Antonio</name> won't be able to pay the money back and <name type="person">Shylock</name> is suddenly happy again, thanking good god that <name type="person">Antonio's</name> ship got cast away.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> gets carried away by his happiness and starts making plans on how to torture <name type="person">Antonio</name> when he's back, since he finally feels like he is able to get revenge.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Tubal</name> then switched topics back to <name type="person">Jessica</name>, exchanged a ring of her death mother for a monkey.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> feels down again.</s>
        <s>Afterwards <name type="person">Tubal</name> then restates taht <name type="person">Antonio</name> is bankrupt and <name type="person">Shylock's</name> mood lightens up again.</s>
        <s>He tells <name type="person">Tubal</name> to hire an officer for him so that he can execute the bond.</s>
        <s>So that he can finally have his revenge.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
