<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12l37_t3</author>
        <name>discuss</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">discuss</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Teachers often ask themselves the question if <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is still relevant or if he is just too old to teach.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even when there are good arguments for still teaching the <choice><orig>litrature</orig><reg>literature</reg></choice> of <name type="person">Shakespeare's</name> legacy, someone must say, that the language is just very difficult to discuss.</s>
        <s>Some questions about antisemitism and <choice><orig>rassism</orig><reg>racism</reg></choice> came up, while analysing <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> <choice><orig>nowerdays</orig><reg>nowadays</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The question I am now discussing on is about the fact taht this paly fuels <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes or does it more raise awareness for the problem of antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I personally think that this play has presumpous language and fuels through it <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Nowerdays</orig><reg>Nowadays</reg></choice> we analyse texts <choice><orig>diffrently</orig><reg>differently</reg></choice> than years before.</s>
        <s>The focus has changed and we now think omre human and pay special attention to language which can hurt people.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In times when <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> has written his plays, he might not thought about the <choice><orig>consequenzes</orig><reg>consequences</reg></choice> of his use of language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To that time the Jewish people were hated by everyone who thought they were different.</s>
        <s>Today equality is written big!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We need to pay special attention to such language because we only strengthen antisemitism while calling them the Jew.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, this language and those plays can be interpreted wrong and this is how wrong information and thoughts are watered and grown big.</s>
        <s>Students might get lost in the actual meaning of the play and stuck somewhere inbetween the old misunderstanding language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that we must help to work against <choice><orig>antisemetic</orig><reg>anti-semetic</reg></choice> stereotypes.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Lot's</orig><reg>Lots</reg></choice> of persons don't actually know how hostile they are to foreigners.</s>
        <s>those plays can help to make it much more worse.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We have to work against building stereotypes, because everyone has the right to be someone who they want to be without contesting their religion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other side teaching students <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="title">The Merchant of Venice</ref> can help to raise awareness for the problem of antisemitism.</s>
        <s>There is a room to ask questions about this topic, and how it found <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> beginning and why.</s>
        <s>Throughout the focus the students understand that Jewish people are humans too, just as everyone else and that this <choice><orig>stereotypic-thinking</orig><reg>stereotypic thinking</reg></choice> is very old and unpopular.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up I think that, when <name type="person">Shakespeare</name> is taught in school.</s>
        <s>The teacher must lay a focus on this play, because it is the only way the students get to know the history of antisemitism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It is also very important that in future we give the problem of antisemitism a lot more attention.</s>
        <s>It is good when a common awareness about this problem is in everyone's head.</s>
        <s>We need to fight <choice><orig>stereotypic-thinking</orig><reg>stereotypic thinking</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Therefore we have to start paying attention on our language and help others to build equality for everyone.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
