<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l34_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hi Joe!</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Of course I can help you with your presentation about unusual school projects worldwide.</s>
        <s>I came across an article that I think would be helpful.</s>
        <s>The article talks about chess as a subject at school, isn't that interesting?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Chess at school is actually getting quite popular.</s>
        <s>There's a project in <name type="geo">Bremen</name> called <quote>Chess makes you smart</quote> <add>I translated it for you</add> and almost 2500 kids took part in it this year!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Every week they had one hour of chess lessons in their primary shcools.</s>
        <s>But not only younger kids play chess at school: <choice><orig>At</orig><reg>at</reg></choice> one school 8th and 9th graders can play too <add>if they want to</add>.</s>
        <s>In almost all schools that offer chess classes, they're voluntary.</s>
        <s>But the article mentioned a primary school where it's a compulsory subject.</s>
        <s>I was really surprised by that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There seem to be so many benefits!</s>
        <s>It is supposed to promote logical and strategical thinking and lead to a better concentration and a better connection between the students.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The students learn to think about the consequences of a decision, to stick to the rules and to accept a defeat.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In some schools all grades play chess together, showing younger or weaker kids that they can win over older, stronger kids.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There are also positive consequences for the general level of achievement and the social behaviour of the kids.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Wow, so many positive results.</s>
        <s>Are you as surprised as I am?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Maybe I should start playing chess too!</s>
        <s>Keep me updated about the presentation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I'd love to hear from you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Love, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
