<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l37_t2</author>
        <name>characterize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">characterize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, <name type="person">Shylock</name> is going to be characterised.</s>
        <s>In doing so there will be a special attention to the use of the language and extra on the stylistic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is the antagonist to this play.</s>
        <s>He is the exact contrast to <name type="person">Antonio</name> and <name type="person">Bassanio</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is very religious and proud to be a Jew.</s>
        <s>Due to that he is very rich and common for lending money.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lending money is a sin in the Christian philosophy and they hate the Jews for it.</s>
        <s>It is forbidden to lend money for Christians, that is why <name type="person">Antonio</name> goes to <name type="person">Shylock</name>, in his last decision of fear, because he is going to be bankrupted <add>more or less out of money</add>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the past <name type="person">Antonio</name> has mocked and manipulated <name type="person">Shylock</name>, betrayed him for his money and joked around with him on <name type="person">Shylock's</name> costs.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This is why <name type="person">Shylock</name> hates him and wishes him just the worst <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He enjoys to hear that <name type="person">Antonio</name> is going to be bankrupt <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 20)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It seems that <name type="person">Shylock</name> is very cold-hearted and mean, but he actually tries to <choice><orig>defind</orig><reg>defend</reg></choice> and save himself from all the pain and sabotages he had to take in.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now he changed from a <choice><orig>naiv</orig><reg>naive</reg></choice> personality into a clever, strategic thinking man who wants to protect himself.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, the lines state that he really loves his daughter <name type="person">Jessica</name> and would do everything to get her back <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s><quote>Would she were hearsed at my foot and the ducats in her coffin</quote><ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 6f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He want her badly by his side to take care of her and know her well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that he would spend all his money and jewels on her <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 4f)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> even organized a friend who should look out for her <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All of that stresses his good intentions and his loev for his daughter.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is a caring, sensible and motivated person when it comes to his family.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Religion is very important to <name type="person">Shylock</name>, he is a proud Jew and is strong-headed in what he does <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 14, 29)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that his actions and behaviour about finding his daughter show that he is strong-willing to get what he wants.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 3, <quote>A diamond gone</quote> is a <choice><orig>similie</orig><reg>simile</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It stands for his daughter and how much she is worth for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His care is stresses through the anaphora before that.</s>
        <s>The repetition of the word <quote>there</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It underlines his pain of the loss.</s>
        <s>The monologue from line 3 to 10, is filled with a lot of conditional sentences.</s>
        <s>He uses a simple sentence structure with a lot of parallelism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It underlines the satisfaction <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> and his pain, because he is grieving and feels sorrow for <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> <name type="person">Jessica</name> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 9f)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition to that, it gets obvious that his family takes a huge amount of love in his life.</s>
        <s>Because the ring he gave to his wife, is very important to him.</s>
        <s><quote>I would not have given it for a wilderness of monkeys</quote><ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 25)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor stresses the significance of the ring and his love for his dead wife.</s>
        <s>He is a real family-lover and knows the worth of emotional things <choice><orig>eventhough</orig><reg>even though</reg></choice> they are materialistic.</s>
        <s>He is on this level very down-to-earth.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the other site, <name type="person">Shylock</name> is very revengeful and loves to have the power <quote>I can make what merchandise I will</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 28f)</ref> to decide about the destiny of others.</s>
        <s>He is gleeful <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The same sentence structure and the parallelism stresses the fact <name type="person">Shylock</name> is often repeating himself <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 5, 12, 16)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Everytime</orig><reg>Every time</reg></choice> when he does that he expresses his emotions and thoughts about something.</s>
        <s>Sometimes he is worried, then happy, cheerful or feels malicious pleasure.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is very present and always knows how to behave.</s>
        <s>This could be because of his long life <add>his high age</add> and his life experiences.</s>
        <s>He also loves his family and gives great care to his beloved daughter.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There is a huge character development of <name type="person">Shylock's</name> person.</s>
        <s>He started to be very <choice><orig>naiv</orig><reg>naive</reg></choice>, kind and unexperienced and throughout life he changed to be strategic, logical-thinking, cold, revengeful, power-hungry but also caring, loving and experienced how to handle with life situations.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
