<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12l38_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Natalia,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>in</orig><reg>In</reg></choice> your last e-mail you asked me if I was able to help you out with your  presentation about unusual school projects and I found something that might help you: I read an article about chess as a school subject.</s>
        <s>It was written by a German journalist called <ref target="a12lk3_2" type="author">Joachim Görres</ref> and published on the <date>30th June 2020</date> in the newspaper <name type="misc">TAZ</name> which is a trustworthy daily journal in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The idea of this chess project is taht students either have chess as an elective or even as a compulsory class.</s>
        <s>Once a week, they have chess class and their teachers who have undergone further trainings to teach chess hold these classes and the students play and learn strategies.</s>
        <s>At the end of the year, they can attend a tournament to show what they have learned.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The project is organised by <name type="geo">Germany's</name> national chess association.</s>
        <s>They claim that the chess class improves the students' general academic performance as well as their ability of logical and strategic thinking.</s>
        <s>Moreover, chess helps the students to a better concentration and the teachers also report better communication and behaviour in their classes.</s>
        <s>The project also teaches the participants competences like dealing with being defeated, weighung up consequences to one's actions and following rules.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think this project sounds great because the students will learn skills for life - I hope you think so too and find this information helpful for your presentation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If you have any other questions, don't bother to reach out and I'll gladly help you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Take care, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
