<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12l32_t2</author>
        <name>characterize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211004</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is a Jew who lives in <name type="geo">Venice</name>.</s>
        <s>He lends money to people but never for free.</s>
        <s>He has been treated badly all his life and has been holding on to a grudge for a really long time.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> loves his daughter very much, which one is able to see by the way he <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> asks <name type="person">Tubal</name> about her when they meet <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> and also by the way he repeats the word <quote>there</quote> in line 3 showing his discontent about not hearing good news about <name type="person">Jessica</name>.</s>
        <s>He also repeats his question in a <choice><orig>rethorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> way <quote>No news of them?</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> which shows how hard it is for <name type="person">Shylock</name> to understand that his daughter would leave him like that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But what is even more prominent is his love for his money.</s>
        <s>Because he <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> starts talking about how much money he is spending on this search, he constantly repeats <quote>two thousand ducats</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 3f)</ref> and finally gets so worked up that he wishes his daughter weredead so that he could have the money back <add>compare <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 5-7)</ref></add>.</s>
        <s>He claims that he experiences <quote>loss upon loss</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> and that he <quote>shall never see [his] gold again</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 18)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is a very depressed and <choice><orig>pesimistic</orig><reg>pessimistic</reg></choice> person which is especiall highlighted by the metaphor <quote>no in luck stirring but what lights on my shoulders, no sighs but of my breathing: no tears but of my shedding</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 9f)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Shylock</name> is also really <choice><orig>revengefull</orig><reg>revengeful</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Since he has been treated poorly because he is a Jew he holds a grudge against <name type="person">Antonio</name> but at fist he feels like he will never get revenge for anything, stating <quote>no satisfaction, no revenge</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 8-9)</ref> but he gets <choice><orig>awfuly</orig><reg>awfully</reg></choice> excited as soon as the tiniest hope of his revenge comes up.</s>
        <s>As soon as he hears of <name type="person">Antonio</name> having bad luck he <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> wants to know more, his <choice><orig>exitement</orig><reg>excitement</reg></choice> is underlined by the repetition of <quote>what</quote>, <quote>ill luck</quote>, <quote>I thank god</quote> and <quote>is't true</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(ll. 12+14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He thanks <name type="person">Tubal</name> for the good news and is happier <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> ever, seemingly forsetting the sadness he felt a few seconds ago about his daughter's <choice><orig>disapearance</orig><reg>disappearance</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He also repeats that he is glad and starts plotting his revenge <quote>I'll plague him, I'll torture him</quote> <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref>, he orders <name type="person">Tubal</name> to get an officer so that he can have <name type="person">Antonio's</name> heart if he forfeits <ref target="a12lk3_1" type="line">(l. 28)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His excitement about his revenge is also highlighted by the repetition of <quote>go</quote> in line 27 and 29.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <name type="person">Shylock</name> isn't presented in the best light.</s>
        <s>He is indirectly characterized by a generalised idea of a Jew who loves his money and is <choice><orig>revengefull</orig><reg>revengeful</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
