<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g01_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref> written by <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> and published in <name type="misc">The Sunday Times</name> on the <date>17th December 2016</date> is a text about language learning and its consequences for the integration of immigrant communities in <name type="geo">Great Britain</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the four paragraphs the author talks about her experiences and tries to convince the readers of her opinions.</s>
        <s>The text is written in informal English and in a serious tone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While in the first paragraph the governmental costs for translating services are mentioned, she explains the consequences of migrants not being integrated in the second one.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third paragraph where we get to know more about her education she uses an <choice><orig>Alliteration</orig><reg>alliteration</reg></choice>, repeating <quote>My parents</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 11-14)</ref>, emphasizing that those intentions and aspirations were drawn mainly from her parents and how much they wanted her to have a good education.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When talking about celebrating diversity in paragraph four, she uses a metaphor saying <quote>But you don't learn to stand on your own two feet if someone is holding you up</quote> <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 18-19)</ref>, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> helps the reader understanding what exactly she means by being able to picture it.</s>
        <s>Another thing that can be noticed is that <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> uses <quote>we</quote> and <quote>us</quote> multiple times, not only holding herself accountable for things she believes she can change, but also including the readers and appealing to them, making them feel responsible for the situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> wrote this article to convince and appeal to people, trying to get them to change something.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
