<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g11_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given text is very informative but also argumentative.</s>
        <s>The article is splitted in four paragraphs.</s>
        <s>The author uses formal language and he uses some complicated words at a few points.</s>
        <s>He doesn't make any jokes or something else he just tells us the facts and solutions that would be better than the way we try to solve the problem now.</s>
        <s>I think the author wants to give us deeper insights about the situation in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> and he wants to make it easier to learn a new language for other people, because he went through it and he knows how hard it is sometimes.</s>
        <s><ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref><choice><orig>adresses</orig><reg>addresses</reg></choice> the text to the readers of the <name type="misc">Sunday Times</name>.</s>
        <s>She tries to convince the reader of her opinion, confronting them with the problem and she tells them how a young male boy is treated in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name>.</s>
        <s>Many people out there are emotional and they will feel sorry for these boys, and then they have the same opinion as <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref>.</s>
        <s>In her text she doesn't use any metaphors, but she tells us a lot of our own story, probably to show the reader that it is very hard to learn a completely new language.</s>
        <s>I would say that <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia</ref> is an expert of this theme because she had to go through it by herself and so she knows how much work it takes to learn English.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Generally you can say that <ref target="c10gk1_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> tries ot convince the people of her opinion.</s>
        <s>She explains the situation in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> and she explains how the people try to solve the problem.</s>
        <s>She also tells us her own story, when she came to <name type="geo">Britain</name> and had to learn English.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
