<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g18_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the article <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="title">Is the usefulness of unions in the protection of workers rights coming to an end? The answer is yes</ref> the <choice><orig>Author</orig><reg>author</reg></choice> is using stylistic devices and specific kinds of language to express his opinion to his readers and convince them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He uses negative words and <choice><orig>frases</orig><reg>phrases</reg></choice> to express his clear opinion about unions and their consequences.</s>
        <s>In line 7 he uses the words <quote>[...] unions are [...] about power and greed</quote> to express that unions have changed and they <choice><orig>dont</orig><reg>don't</reg></choice> do their dedicated task anymore.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also uses metaphorical language to set a picture in the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>reader's</reg></choice> mind.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You can see this in line 11 <quote>they have become victims of their own success [...]</quote> and what he means by that is, that unions suffer from their own aim to increase the <choice><orig>workers</orig><reg>workers'</reg></choice> wages and that they now cannot sell their products that much because they have to be more expensive.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly, the author uses personifications to make it easier to imagine something and to put emphasis onto an object.</s>
        <s>For example ll. 16-17 <quote>Your job is protected by your union</quote> and with this he wants to explain why workers don't perform as well as before.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, Mr. <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Pollard</ref> uses his stylistic devices to express and explain his opinion and the downsides of unions.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
