<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g15_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Now I am going to analyse how the author <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> tries to persuade the reader of his opinion, with the help of stylistic <choice><orig>devises</orig><reg>devices</reg></choice> and communicative strategies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>articel</orig><reg>article</reg></choice> is about the usefulness of the unions.</s>
        <s><ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Brian</ref> is telling us his opinion in two <choice><orig>diffrent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> ways, in the first part of the text he is talking about, how good the unions are, with the help of long sentences, he is naming some good things that the unions <choice><orig>has</orig><reg>have</reg></choice> <surplus>has</surplus> been doing, he is naming a few like, shorter working days for the worker, better working conditions in the fabrics and about how they need higher wages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then in line 5 he is changing his opinion completely, he is saying, that his opinion has changed over the past few years, because the unions are no longer about the protection of worker rights, more about power and greed, they got selfish.</s>
        <s>A selfish desire for money <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5-10)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 7 he is giving us some more points, for his opinion, he is bringing up, that most of the fabrics are now regulated by legislation and laws, also our moral values.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>A</orig><reg>At</reg></choice> the <choice><orig>End</orig><reg>end</reg></choice> he is using something like a statement to make his opinion even more <choice><orig>powerfull</orig><reg>powerful</reg></choice> and to get the readers even more on his side.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You can say, that <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Brian</ref> used long sentences and many points, for his old and new opinion about the usefulness of unions.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
