<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g09_t4</author>
        <name>magazine</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>We all wear clothes.</s>
        <s>But do you know where they come from?</s>
        <s>Have you ever looked at the tag?</s>
        <s>Wll, they probably come from <name type="geo">China</name> or <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name>.</s>
        <s>But do you even know where that is?</s>
        <s>I'm now going to show you the bad conditions workers work in in these countries.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You're probably gonna be very surprised about how bad the situation is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> in the city <name type="geo">Dhaka</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There are 3000 to 4000 textile <choice><orig>factorys</orig><reg>factories</reg></choice> in this city which is a suprisingly high number.</s>
        <s>Due to these the river <name type="misc">Burigangen</name> is full of chemicals and people are living next to it, surrounded by trash.</s>
        <s>In the <choice><orig>factorys</orig><reg>factories</reg></choice> are many workers working 10-12 hours a day with a maximum of one day of per week.</s>
        <s>And their work is very monotone as they often just do one step of the production line.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <name type="geo">China</name> workers are even proud of the fast pace they produce in and how little pause they have as they don't know what work can also be like in for example <name type="geo">Europe</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So what can we do about it?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all just boycotting the goods from there isn't the right way as it would just take the <choice><orig>workers</orig><reg>workers'</reg></choice> jobs.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Instead we need to pressure brands and the politics to change.</s>
        <s>I think can all agree that this shouldn't even be allowed.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
