<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a10g12_t4</author>
        <name>magazine</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution_report">magazine</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Fashion Industry: How to improve and help!</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>You have probably heard or read about the fashion industry <choice><orig>issui</orig><reg>issue</reg></choice> in the world nowadays.</s>
        <s>A lot of guilt and a lot of questions how to help.</s>
        <s>So how can we improve?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I read the <ref target="a10gk2_2" type="title">Fast Fashion: Unser Kleiderkonsum ist Wahnsinn</ref> by <ref target="a10gk2_2" type="author">Jörd Oberwittler</ref> published on the <date>21st of December 2017</date> and an I am going to help you understand how to improve correctly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The exploit of employees is something we have know and supported for years.</s>
        <s>Most of the people just went along with it because of the lack of knowledge how to improve.</s>
        <s>Therefore the newspaper company <name type="misc">Spiegel</name> sent a journalist to <name type="geo"><choice><orig>bangladesh</orig><reg>Bangladesh</reg></choice></name> where most of the clothes are produced, to ask questions and find out more.</s>
        <s>She describes the danger of the climate which is created by the factories and their water <choice><orig>suage</orig><reg>usage</reg></choice>, which they through out in the river.</s>
        <s>She states it's dark black and a lot of plastic floating around.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So the bad conditions of the fashion production isn't just harming people but also our climate?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="misc">Spiegel</name> explains there are 3000 and up to 400 factories in a very small space.</s>
        <s>They all live in very bad conditions.</s>
        <s>They live between trash and a lot more trash.</s>
        <s>This doesn't just harm the workers but especially our world and climate.</s>
        <s>We are supporting this by buying the clothes made in those bad conditions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But how are we supposed to improve?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="misc">Spiegel</name> explains stop buying the clothes won't help because then all the there living workers will lose their jobs and probably have even worse conditions to live in.</s>
        <s>The journalist states the pressure is to be made by the companies.</s>
        <s>Not just by us but by the government too.</s>
        <s>We have to put pressure on them to create better working and living conditions for the workers.</s>
        <s>It cannot be right that people are sewing the same things ten to twelve hours a day.</s>
        <s>That has to change.</s>
        <s>Not just that has to change but workers have gotten used to this and start see it as <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> competition and <choice><orig>therefor</orig><reg>therefore</reg></choice> forgetting their breaks which <choice><orig>phiscally</orig><reg>physically</reg></choice> just overloads them.</s>
        <s>Their mentality will change over the changes made.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We have to start making a change and stop supporting the bad conditions for the workers.</s>
        <s>The best solutions stated is the company.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
