<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g09_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I'm going to comment on <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Brian Pollard's</ref> statement that <quote>[...] in the twenty-first century the situation has changed, workers are not being exploited by employers, now employers are being exploited by employees</quote> and why I very much disagree with him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While it may be true that this applies to some unions as they are a lot about workers rights I don't think you can generalize it as he does connecting it to the economic mess of the whole world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think the biggest problem is <choice><orig>capatalism</orig><reg>capitalism</reg></choice>, so how the capital is shared around the world, because many rich <choice><orig>companys</orig><reg>companies</reg></choice> take advantage of that situation as they abuse people in poor, foreign countries.</s>
        <s>So we still have the same situation of employers exploiting their workers by not caring about their health and paying them very little.</s>
        <s>The situation might have turned around in richer countries as people have a chance to have an impact but in countries like <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> many workers they need every little money and are not willing to risk their life for a fair job.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And that's <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> globalisation increases that problem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because as <ref target="a10gk2_1" type="author">Brian Pollard</ref> states, the prices of fair produced goods simply can't compete with the ones made in harsh conditions.</s>
        <s>People in for example <name type="geo">Germany</name>, like us, just don't want to spend a lot of money.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That's why I think we need to stop buying from brands producing in such conditions, like <name type="misc">Nike</name> and <name type="misc">Adidas</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By that you would pressure them into change.</s>
        <s>Some people would argue, that it destroys their living base but I think this kind of pressure is needed as they already work in slave like conditions and brands would have to react fast.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I think the main problem is still employers exploiting their workers, which is why we need to be more careful about what we buy in order to make change.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
