<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g28_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution report">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>A lot of pollution derives from human activity.</s>
        <s>As a result, it is we humans who will be able to stop pollution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="geo">Germany</name> is already a state which makes a lot for the climate change compared to other countries.</s>
        <s>But that is not enough!</s>
        <s>I <choice><orig>Personally</orig><reg>personally</reg></choice> think that the new regiment should stop every power <choice><orig>statione</orig><reg>station</reg></choice> which isn't climate friendly.</s>
        <s>If we switch to wind, sun, and water power stations, there will be less <choice><abbr>CO2</abbr><expan>carbon dioxide</expan></choice> in the air and the pollution is much better.</s>
        <s>Also <choice><orig>Flights</orig><reg>flights</reg></choice> should be more expensive and inland flights should be forbidden.</s>
        <s><name type="geo">Germany</name> must go on with <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> good example and rush other countries to make more against the climate change.</s>
        <s>European countries should focus more on their own market and not buy much fast fashion and use developing countries as slaves.</s>
        <s>But these laws will be hard to make and a lot of problems will be there to face.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>politicer</orig><reg>politician</reg></choice> shouldn't be afraid of big concerns and a lot of money and they have to stop the climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all you could summand that, if we all help a bit to stop the climate change and the regiment makes feasible laws, which are good for the pollution, and not <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> bad for the economy we could save <choice><orig>oure</orig><reg>our</reg></choice> planet.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
