<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g34_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution report">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will comment on the question what we humans can do to stop the environmental pollution.</s>
        <s>This is a very difficult question because I think that the perfect solution does not exist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Environmental pollution is the trash and gas we produce in the world.</s>
        <s>The effect on the planet while we humans destroying the planet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my opinion the perfect solution which is there all people can live like nothing <choice><orig>happend</orig><reg>happened</reg></choice> does not exist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think the only way to help our planet were laws, laws that were accept from the producers and do not damaging them so much.</s>
        <s>The laws have to be controllized by the police or the state.</s>
        <s>But you cannot say to the producers that they <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> produce their product <choice><orig>anymor</orig><reg>anymore</reg></choice> because of the laws.</s>
        <s>I think that laws which concentrate on the material there products are a good solutoin.</s>
        <s>Because for every material you can use a better material which not damaging the planet so much.</s>
        <s>For the producer is it important that the material is not expensive so he can get a very high profit.</s>
        <s>Another law you can make, is when a producer does not <choice><orig>exept</orig><reg>accept</reg></choice> the laws he <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> to pay very much money.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the ending I can say that the perfect solution is not existing but you can make it better with accepting laws.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
