<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a10g30_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the blog on <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>, written by <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> in the year <date>2014</date>, is about the <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> pollution as well as its causes and effects it has on us people and the earth.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author describes how the earth is the only planet, where animals, plants and human can live.</s>
        <s>Water and air keeps everything and everyone alive but the pollution of both of them is increasing every single day due to the growing urbanization and industrialization.</s>
        <s>In addition to that the exhaust fumes of cars, ships, planes and nitrogen fertilizers as well as synthetic detergents, makes everything worse.</s>
        <s>All of our food is contaminated and many different species of animals are in danger of their extinction.</s>
        <s>There have been many tragic incidents, where poisonous gases got leaked and killed thousands of people or contaminated whole cities.</s>
        <s>The environmental pollution has huge negative effects on our planet, <choice><orig>espeially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> the sea and on human health.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Scientist</orig><reg>Scientists</reg></choice> are worried that the industrial progress is getting out of hand and that an age of mass extinction is coming closer.</s>
        <s>All in all, it can be said, that if the environmental pollution is not going to less over the years, it is going to be very dangerous for the world.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
