<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g30_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The blogpost on <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>, written by <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> and published in <date>2014</date>, deals with the drastic increase of <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> pollution.</s>
        <s>The author states that if the pollution of the <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> gets out of hand the word is going to be in big danger.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will analyze the <choice><orig>authors</orig><reg>author's</reg></choice> intention by focusing of she makes us of language and stylistic devices.</s>
        <s>The author starts with a statement about <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> pollution, so the readers know what the blogpost is going to be about.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>languge</orig><reg>language</reg></choice> that is being used is formal, although the author is getting emotional at some points.</s>
        <s>The vocabulary is filled with complex words and phrases such as <quote>biosphere</quote> <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>, <quote>synthetic detergents</quote> <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>... She underlines the importance of her blog with strong adjectives which highlight the devastating effects of <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> pollution.</s>
        <s>In addition to that, she makes us of enumerations in line 6 <quote>no man, no animals, no plants</quote> and in line 7 <quote>oxygen, nitrogen, carbon dioxide, argon and water vapor</quote>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a10gk4_1" type="author">Mitra</ref> makes use of authority arguments <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 26-27)</ref>, <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="line">(l. 33)</ref> in order to show the readers that not only herself is worried about the <choice><orig>enviroments</orig><reg>environments</reg></choice> but also experts <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> scientists.</s>
        <s>Besides that she mentions tragic events from the past to create an emotional <choice><orig>connetion</orig><reg>connection</reg></choice> to the readers.</s>
        <s>For example the <name type="geo">Hiroshima</name> incident, which occured in <date>1945</date>.</s>
        <s>In line 34 she makes us of a simile to convince the readers that an accident like <name type="geo">Hiroshima</name>, could also happen to them at every time.</s>
        <s>The author wants to convince the readers to act now, to prevent the earth from mass extinction and to save our planet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Considering all these aspects, it can be said that <ref target="a10gk4_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> did a great job to spread awareness about <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> pollution and even if people just start thinking about what could be changed, it is the first stop for a better world and <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
