<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a10g31_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="inquiring" genre_family="problem-solution report">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will comment on possible ways of helping to solve the global problem of environmental pollution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In a world <choice><orig>were</orig><reg>where</reg></choice> personal ambition and wealth dominates the structure of society, our planet and our environment suffers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The immense growth of <choice><orig>industriell</orig><reg>industrial</reg></choice> progress has led to <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> environmental pollution, which has the potential to <choice><orig>distruct</orig><reg>destruct</reg></choice> our <q>comfortable</q> life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To restore the ecological balance, we humans need a change in mindset, before <choice><orig>activly</orig><reg>actively</reg></choice> making new rules which will help solve the problem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Each person should reflect on his personal connection to the topic and think about his responsibility regarding future generations.</s>
        <s>But not only the individual but also the government needs to reduce its <q><choice><orig>wastefull</orig><reg>wasteful</reg></choice></q> being.</s>
        <s>Plastic items should be <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> banned from the market and should be replaced by different, more <choice><orig>environmentfriendly</orig><reg>environmentally friendly</reg></choice> materials.</s>
        <s>There should also be new laws regarding the protection of rare species, which are one of the main losers of environmental pollution.</s>
        <s>But most importantly there needs to be a change in the <choice><orig>schoolsystem</orig><reg>school system</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The grown-ups of tommorow, need to learn, how to respectfully treat our planet and his <choice><orig>ressources</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>For that, a new subject should be introduced, which would teach better morals and the understanding of our biosphere.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
