<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>b12l02_t3</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="hortatory_exposition">speech</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his article <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="title">We are entering an era of pandemics - it will end only when we protect the rainforest</ref> one of <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak's</ref> possible solutions for stopping future pandemics is to not return to a system of unchecked consumption following the corona crisis.</s>
        <s>However how realistic is this?</s>
        <s>Will we really forego our consumptious lifestyle just to maybe prevent future pandemics?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While one could say that <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> happened because of our consumption and would be partly right, I think that for many people that concept is hard to grasp.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There is somply too much focus on consumption of goods in modern socety, that most people could live without it.</s>
        <s>The whole concept of capitalism os bared on the will of people to acquire things.</s>
        <s>The question is, how much would we need to change in our daily loves to make a difference on the environment?</s>
        <s>Many people are too lazy to even seperate garbage, so how much can you expect of them.</s>
        <s>Of course some or even most people would be able to change their lifestyle to help the environment, but the problem is, that everyone would have to do it.</s>
        <s>The changes would have to become the new norm in society, which is hard and takes a long time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It took in long time for example for society to accept regulations due to <name type="misc">Covid-19</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It would take much education by the government about the consequences of overconsumption.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion I think it is unlikely that mankind will not return to a system of unchecked consumption, because of stubbornness and the basic structure of capitalism, that promotes consumption.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
