<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b12l01_t3</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello everyone,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you for having me.</s>
        <s>I feel honored to speak on this conference, <name type="misc">The future of globalization</name>.</s>
        <s>Globalization is water enables me to talk in front of all of you right now.</s>
        <s>It gives us benefits that nobody would have even thought about 100 years ago.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If I were to buy something online right now it would probably be prepared for shipping while I am talking to you.</s>
        <s>Through the Internet we can talk with anyone at any time.</s>
        <s>Through globalized travel we can travel around the <choice><orig>word</orig><reg>world</reg></choice> without limits.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Globalization has brought us great things, being close with our loved ones even though we <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> see them personally, being able to travel after graduating and considering studying somewhere else, or just casually buying clothing online that you forgot you needed for a conference.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But are those things really all that <choice><orig>advantagous</orig><reg>advantageous</reg></choice>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For me, being able to communicate online stops being comfortable if you are forced to only do so.</s>
        <s>This is an experience we have all made with <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> which forest most of us to distance ourselves from other people and rely on online communication.</s>
        <s>But did we get to this point?</s>
        <s>I read an article about the arise, spread and prevention of pandemics.</s>
        <s>Now you are probably thinking <quote>what do pandemics have to do with globalization?</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Globalization supports pandemics in every aspect of their emergence.</s>
        <s>They arise faster since we have turned a lot of wildlife habitat into agriculture, which gets humans into contact with wildlife.</s>
        <s>Birds and <choice><orig>mamals</orig><reg>mammals</reg></choice> are the origin of most of the pandemics.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The pandemic travels around the world through our globalized travel and transport system <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">whits</gap> in your front yard.</s>
        <s>And so you are forced to sit inside and wait for the vaccine.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Vaccines are an advantage from globalization since scientists from all over the world can work together to create one.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless, the pandemic needs to be stopped before I can even start.</s>
        <s>To prevent pandemics from even happening we need to protect nature and our environment.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We not only need to stop over consumption, which leads to deforestation and exploitation of wildlife and <choice><orig>ressorces</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice>, but also need to punish companies that don't follow those rules.</s>
        <s>We need to fight against climate change which globalization has made it worse due to overconsumption, the transport and travel system and companies outsourcing every step of production.</s>
        <s>Not only wildlife causes pandemics but in the future melting glaciers which might carry diseases from thousand of years ago will.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Problems like pandemics and climate change came to life or were made worse due to globalization.</s>
        <s>Those problems can only be solved globally.</s>
        <s>If someone were to ask me what I imagine the future of globalization like, I would like to include all of the positive aspects mentioned previously.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Such as travel, communication, access to goods and the internet.</s>
        <s>However, everything should be consumed in moderation.</s>
        <s>Less travel and less consumption will help the environment and therefore us.</s>
        <s>If we want to stop viruses, floods, wild fires, natural disasters and the earth heating up we need to start working together globally.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We need to stop relying on ending <choice><orig>ressources</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice>, overproduction, over-consumption, non <choice><orig>regial</orig><reg>regional</reg></choice> productions that flying 30 min for a <choice><orig>buisness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All countries, every individual has to start protecting the environment to stop the negative aspects of globalization such as climate change and pandemics.</s>
        <s>We cannot always wait for problems to get really bad until we try to find a solution.</s>
        <s>Your decisions determine our future.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you for listening.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
