<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12l02_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hello Ben,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I recently read an article that deals with the topic of <name type="geo">Germany's</name> ability to isolate themselves from globalisation and since you wondered if that would be possible, let me summarize it for you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To see <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> <name type="geo">Germany</name> would be able to isolate you could <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">tirit</gap> look at their export and import numbers.</s>
        <s>In <date>2017</date> Germany exported goods worth 1279 billion euro.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Imported goods that would in turn not be imported are worth 1034 billion dollars.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So <name type="geo"><choice><orig>germany</orig><reg>Germany</reg></choice></name> would make about 245 billion euro less per year, which would be possible to be sustained.</s>
        <s>It would however not be possible to make the change over a short period of time, because there are a lot of professions, that simply don't exist in <name type="geo"><choice><orig>germany</orig><reg>Germany</reg></choice></name> at the moment, that would have to be reinstated.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore production would have to be moved back to <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A big reason why the complete isolation would not be possible is the lack of <choice><orig>ressources</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice> like fossil-fuels.</s>
        <s>They would still have to be imported.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So in theory, the isolation of <name type="geo">Germany</name> from globalization would be possible at least mortly.</s>
        <s>Although that probably is not desirable, because life would become much more <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">sbule</gap> for the <choice><orig>germans</orig><reg>Germans</reg></choice> without influences and products from the outside.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
