<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>b12l06_t3</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="hortatory exposition">speech</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Good evening ladies and gentlemen, fellow students and politicians</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you for the invitation to speak at this international student conference <quote>The future of globalization</quote>.</s>
        <s>It means a lot to me to be able to stand here and talk about a topic the effects each and everyone of us.</s>
        <s>Globalization is a topic where everyone can say something about it.</s>
        <s>We are all the result of globalization.</s>
        <s>Take a look at the situation now.</s>
        <s>It is an international conference where we come together from many <choice><orig>diffirent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> parts of the world and discuss the future of globalization.</s>
        <s>I, personally want to talk about the benefits of globalization.</s>
        <s>I came across a very <choice><orig>interessting</orig><reg>interesting</reg></choice> and somewhat disturbing article online by <ref target="b12lk1_1" type="author">Peter Daszak</ref>.</s>
        <s>The article deals with our current pandemic.</s>
        <s>While reading I realized that many people think <choice><orig>negativly</orig><reg>negatively</reg></choice> about globalization, <choice><orig>becaus</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> just like right now, we are in the middle of a global pandemic, which is partly the result of globalization.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I personally don't think that the pandemic is only caused by globalization as written in the online article I read.</s>
        <s>That is why, driven by the article, I am standing here to talk about the <choice><orig>positiv</orig><reg>positive</reg></choice> aspects of globalization.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now, first off I can agree that pandemics like our current <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> are able to spread <choice><orig>rapitly</orig><reg>rapidly</reg></choice> because of globalization.</s>
        <s>Airplane, cars, trains, boats.</s>
        <s>Through all of these inventions people traveled more than ever, so it is not a surprise that the virus originated in <name type="geo">China</name>, reached almost every corner of earth, and what felt like seconds.</s>
        <s>But pandemics have always existed.</s>
        <s>Viruses always existed.</s>
        <s>Like the <name type="misc">sars</name> virus from <date>2003</date>.</s>
        <s>Pandemics are always going to happen no matter white.</s>
        <s>So why should we not travel around the world and enjoy the different cultures and multicultural societies?</s>
        <s>I don't think the pandemics should stop us from globalizing.</s>
        <s>Through for example social media and generally digitization we can learn about different cultures, which is an enrichment.</s>
        <s>People are more openminded and curious about new cultures.</s>
        <s>Polycultures instead of monocultures develop.</s>
        <s>There is more acceptance and tolerance than ever before.</s>
        <s>If you think about yourself, what music do you listen to?</s>
        <s>What food do you eat?</s>
        <s>What do you wear?</s>
        <s>Or what languages do you speak?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Let us take me as an example.</s>
        <s>My parents are from <name type="geo">Turkey</name> but we live in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>I grew up with two very <choice><orig>diffirent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> cultures and learn from both of them.</s>
        <s>German people also <choice><orig>eats</orig><reg>eat</reg></choice> lots of different foods like Italian, Spanish or Vietnamese.</s>
        <s>There are plenty of <choice><orig>diffirent</orig><reg>different</reg></choice> cuisines that you can try out in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>It even helps people from these countries to integrate into society better because, what they are used to in their home country can be found here as well.</s>
        <s>If the world wasn't globalized I would not be able to enjoy my hobbies like traditional Korean martial arts.</s>
        <s>They teach <choice><orig>Taekwondo</orig><reg>tae kwon do</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">Germany</name>, which came all the way from <name type="geo">South Korea</name>.</s>
        <s>Amazing isn't it?</s>
        <s>My master is also Korean and I was lucky to learn a lot from him about Korean culture as well and it taught me many life lessons.</s>
        <s>I <choice><orig>definetly</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> think that the mixing of cultures and the opportunity to explore new ones is amazing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But of course <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> are different reactions to globalization when it comes to cultures globalizing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A lot of people might see it as a threat to their culture.</s>
        <s>They feel like their own culture is <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> alienated or taken away from them.</s>
        <s>A lot of people have difficulties identifying with a group of people and don't know where they belong.</s>
        <s>We have seen this in a very recent example.</s>
        <s>The <name type="misc">Brexit</name>.</s>
        <s>Allegedly the majority of <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> people felt like their culture is in <choice><orig>dangeour</orig><reg>danger</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Rising nationalism and xenophobia can be spotted all over the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So, is that the future of globalization?</s>
        <s>More racism, xenophobia and nationalism?</s>
        <s>Are more and more nations closing their borders like <name type="geo">Britain</name>, not only because of fear of <choice><orig>loosing</orig><reg>losing</reg></choice> the culture, but also because of the pandemic?</s>
        <s>That is a tricky question, because at the end there is not much we can do, when countries want to close their borders.</s>
        <s>There is a <choice><orig>noticable</orig><reg>noticeable</reg></choice> change in nationalism and xenophobia in this world and the pandemic gives countries just another reason to close the borders.</s>
        <s>In contrast to the article I read, <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> still think that globalization is something great and we should not bring it down and see it <choice><orig>negatively</orig><reg>negativly</reg></choice> just because of our current pandemic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I I have hope and I do not think that racism, xenophobia or nationalism will overshadow the good sides about globalization.</s>
        <s>We all as humans should stay open minded and not let the pandemic ruin the benefits of globalization.</s>
        <s>So dear fellow students and <choice><orig>politians</orig><reg>politicians</reg></choice> around, please take into account what just has been said and try to make the world more <choice><orig>tollerant</orig><reg>tolerant</reg></choice> and accepting through your power.</s>
        <s>It was an honor to give this <choice><orig>speach</orig><reg>speech</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Thanks a lot for listening.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
