<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a1</title>
        <author>b12l05_t3</author>
        <name>assess</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">assess</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The question of <choice><orig>weather</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> or not we will learn from the mistakes of our past, which led us to the situation we find ourselves in now, during <name type="misc">Covid-19</name>, is two-sided: On one hand, it seems obvious, that we will change our habits.</s>
        <s>We have experienced the conditions that <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> brought to us as a global cummunity.</s>
        <s>Apart from the fact that many of us have suffered losses, suffered from <name type="misc">Covid</name> ourselves or at least having experienced the risk of getting infected, the global communit has experienced how fast globalization can turn into a disadvantage for our lives.</s>
        <s>Considering the economic damage that came along with <name type="misc">Covid-19</name> and other pandemics of the past, it may seem reasonable to make a change to how we consume <choice><orig>recources</orig><reg>resources</reg></choice> today.</s>
        <s>As all of us are affected by a pandemic in a globalized world we would want to change our habits as fast as possible.</s>
        <s>Sadly, as we live as a global community, whatever actions we take has <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> impacts on the rest of the world.</s>
        <s>If a country, for example, does not keep to any agreements, considering climate change, the problem becomes a global issue.</s>
        <s>Therefore it is important that we act together, which is very hard considering the number of humans and individual opinions that exist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Personally I think that we will never reach a state in which ourr consumption will be checked.</s>
        <s>It is an issue that comes at cost of globalitation, specifically out free trafe markets.</s>
        <s>The rules we follow in out country might not appeal to the rules of other countries.</s>
        <s>Other countries might not have the same chances to enforce particular rules, due to political instability.</s>
        <s>Some countries and markets may not be as strict to check on which products are offered and even if they are, the danger of a human being carrying a disease from one place to another will remain.</s>
        <s>At last, even if there were rules, every member of the global community agreed on, illegal markets would remain, potentially causing even larger problems at a global scale than we have.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude, I think that unchecked consumption comes at cost of our globalized world and is hard to be in control of.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
