<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b12l16_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the given speech, held by <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Attenborough</ref> on the occasion of the opening of the <name type="misc">COP26</name>, he strongly advocates for the present world leaders to take measures in order to reduce the global CO2 emissions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He starts off by saying that decreasing this number should be the key aspect in the conference.</s>
        <s>Then, he goes on by arguing how climate change is of anthropogenic cause, meaning that, e.g. due to the burning of fossil fuels, humans created the catastrophe for themselves.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, the effects will be noticeable for everybody, although, today, the least guilty of causing global warming are the ones most affected.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir Attenborough</ref> continues by tressing how, for the sake of younger generations, change should and could be made, as it is known how to decrease emissions and restore nature.</s>
        <s>He also pronounces that there is still a way to go in order to save the planet and that this has to happen together with all nations motivated by hope, not fear.</s>
        <s>He finally says that emissions can be decreased by commitments made in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> and stresses how it is the deligates task to so and go beyond empty words and promises.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
