<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12l10_t4</author>
        <name>news</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="review">news</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <head>
      <p>
        <s>Is it time for hope, after <name type="misc">COP26</name>?</s>
        <s>The outcome from <name type="misc">COP26</name> with regards to German perspective</s>
      </p>
    </head>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In November of this year <date>2021</date>, the 26th conference, <name type="misc">COP26</name> about climate change took place in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name>.</s>
        <s>This is a yearly conference since <date>1994</date>, where governments of nearly every country of the world, 196 governments take part in.</s>
        <s>It is a conference based on climate change and how to deal with it.</s>
        <s>The governments discuss and decide on what to do, to prevent the earth of getting warmer.</s>
        <s>All of these countries are also part of the United Nations and therefore work together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="geo">Germany</name> also took part in the <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But how is the German perspective on the outcome of <name type="misc">COP26</name>?</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_2" type="speaker">Jochen Flasbarth</ref>, the state secretary at the Ministry for the Environment and Nature Protection has an answer to that question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>According to him, the <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <name type="geo">Glasgow</name> cleared a path to achieve the climate goal of 1.5 degrees Celsius, which was set in the <name type="geo">Paris</name> agreement.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However, it has to be clear that the <choice><abbr>UN</abbr><expan>United Nations</expan></choice> and the <name type="misc">COP</name> meetings are not governments.</s>
        <s>They only can call for action, but cannot set a law for the countries who participate.</s>
        <s>Therefore, the countries have to implement the decision that was made at the conference.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, <ref target="b12lk2_2" type="speaker">Mr. Flasbarth</ref> goes into detail about abandoning coal power.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Yes, the problem with <name type="geo">China</name> and <name type="geo">India</name> remains.</s>
        <s>They denied the complete abandonment of coal and rather want a gradual reduction.</s>
        <s>This is not the best thing, especially for countries like <name type="geo">Germany</name> who definitely would vote for a complete reduction of coal power.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The European Union (EU) brought up the topic at <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
        <s>The most surprising was that for the first time, it was accepted.</s>
        <s>Because for many countries, coal power is one of the most important income and at <name type="misc">COP26</name> they agreed to a <quote>phase down</quote>.</s>
        <s>This means that the time of coal will be over soon, which is great to hear.</s>
        <s>Moreover, climate experts predicted the global warming lower than before the <name type="geo">Paris</name> agreement.</s>
        <s>Before the <name type="geo">Paris</name> agreement in <date>2015</date>, they predicted a rise of five to six degrees.</s>
        <s>Before the conference <name type="misc">COP26</name> in <date>2021</date>, it has fallen to 2.7 degrees.</s>
        <s>According to <ref target="b12lk2_2" type="speaker">Flasbarth</ref> this is a huge process.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I agree with <ref target="b12lk2_2" type="speaker">Flasbarth</ref> that a step has been made in the right direction.</s>
        <s>And yes, in a German perspective the outcome is quite good.</s>
        <s>However, more concrete decisions must be made.</s>
        <s>I know that it is very hard to deal with climate change and the <choice><abbr>UN</abbr><expan>United Nations</expan></choice> cannot propose laws about abandoning coal power for example.</s>
        <s>But projects like <quote>A legal framework for impact</quote> by <name type="misc">Freshfields</name>, where they invest in companies to stop emitting are a great option.</s>
        <s>Because the problem is that every emission which is produced in the air, has to be reduced somewhere else: concept of balance.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, the outcome of <name type="misc">COP26</name> is a good way in the right direction.</s>
        <s>For <name type="geo">Germany</name> the outcome is quite good, however the reduction of coal power should be a complete reduction by <date>2030</date> according to German politics.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
