<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12l16_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211202</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir Attenborough</ref> wants to convince the audience of taking real action to decrease CO2 emissions and fight the climate emergency especially by deplying his line of arguement and the use of rhetorical devices like inclusive language to give them hope of a good outcome of climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all, when observing the line of argument it is remarkable, how <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough's</ref> speech can be divided into three distinctive parts with unique functions.</s>
        <s>In the first part <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 1-23)</ref>, tries to create a feeling of guilt and dear in his audience by deplying clear, short and unequivolcal expressions like <quote>We are already in trouble</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> and <quote>all of us will feel the impact</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Similiarly</orig><reg>Similarly</reg></choice>, the enumeration <quote>Our burning of fossil fuels, our destructions of nature, our approach to industry, construction and learning, are releasing carbon into the atmosphere at an unprecedented pace and scale</quote><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 14-16)</ref> intensifies the impression of an unimagineably great extent of environmental destruction caused by humans and highlights the mistakes that have already been made in the past.</s>
        <s>This, and the whole paragraph, justifies the need for change to show the politicians why acting is important.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 24-46)</ref>, shift in the overall feeling that is evoked, can be observed.</s>
        <s>As this part actually is shaped by words of hope and optimism.</s>
        <s>The shift is perfectly represented by the alliteration <quote>to turn this tragedy into a triumph</quote> which emphsizes how, parallel to the speech, a twist in the climate emergency is possible.</s>
        <s>This is further highlighted in the anaphora <quote><qs>We are after akm the greatest problem solvers to have ever existed on Earth.</qs><qs>We now understand this problem.</qs><qs>We know how to stop the number rising and put it in reverse.</qs><qs>We must recapture billions of tons of carbon from the air.</qs><qs>We must fix our sights on keeping one and a half degrees within reach.</qs><qs>[...] We will all share in the benefits</qs></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 28-34)</ref> where the <choice><orig>continious</orig><reg>continuous</reg></choice> use of <quote>we</quote> stresses how saving the earth in a task for all.</s>
        <s>There can also be notives a progress, as it developes from <quote>are</quote> to <quote>must</quote> and to <quote>will</quote> which, again, expresses hope for change and a positive perspective on the outcome of the climate crisis extent-wise.</s>
        <s>It addtionally makes use of a rational argumentation: We know about the problem and know how to fix it, so why not do everything that is necessary?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the same part, positive connoted words like <quote>balance</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 36)</ref>, <quote>journey</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref> and <quote>opportunity</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref> are clearly employed as a sign of hope.</s>
        <s>The last part represents a final appeal to the audience to act.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Attenborough</ref> does that by appealing to their moral conciousness:</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The expression <quote><qs>The people alive now, the generation to come will look at this conference and consider one thing.</qs><qs>Did that umber stop rising and start to drop, as a result of commiments made here?</qs></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 47-49)</ref> is supposed to make them aware of whom they are doing this from, younger generations, while <choice><orig>simultanously</orig><reg>simultaneously</reg></choice> representing a ference to the behinning of his speech which creates a clear framework.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the contrast <quote><qs>In my lifetime, I've witnessed a terrible decline.</qs><qs>In yours, you could and should witness a wonderful recovery</qs></quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 51/52)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir Attenborough</ref> directly addresses young people, whose future is at stake, to make them feel referred to individually, and creates a clear distinction between the past and the future while also giving a positive perspective.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, throughout the whole speech his use of inclusive language as in <quote>we</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 17, 28, 34, 30, ...)</ref> and <quote>our</quote> <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 5, 6, 24, ...)</ref> is striking.</s>
        <s>It is supposed to unify the audience and place himself and them on the same level to help identify with the common goal of reducing environmental destruction.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, <ref target="b12lk2_1" type="speaker">Sir David Attenborough's</ref> speech is convincible as he effectively tries to create a feeling of hope in the audience, especially though the line of argument, which is supposed to solve a motivation for action.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
