<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> tries to draw a convincing picture of dangerous, to let his audience take action in the future by using words like <quote>our</quote> or <quote>we</quote> to create a sense of community so everybody feels called to handle and by using stylistic devices to underlined the necessity of changing something.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speech can be divided in four parts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1-9)</ref> the speaker is welcoming everybody to <name type="misc">COP26</name> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> and introduce the topic by comparing it to a <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He compare is a fictional machine the doomsday device <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> the fast temperature rising caused by the climate change.</s>
        <s>Through this comparison he directly creates a picture how big this problem is and that it will destroy our world completely if we don't help like <name type="person">James Bond</name> did in the movie.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also uses inclusive pronouns like <quote>we</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> to address directly to the audience so that everybody feels to be called.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 10-21)</ref> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> mentions the last climate conferences and compares it to the climate conference <name type="misc">COP26</name>.</s>
        <s>He points out to that <name type="misc">COP26</name> should be a turning point in this topic and that it is time to handle by using again a direct address to the audience <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 14f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the next line the speaker uses in a enumeration <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> to underline all the topics where the population can make a change, so that the audience does not only feel addressed to handle but also what to do for solving the climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To encourage the people to take action <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris</ref> does not only <choice><orig>uses</orig><reg>use</reg></choice> inclusive pronouns he sends a task, a duty to the people, an <choice><orig>apeal</orig><reg>appeal</reg></choice> that <choice><orig>the</orig><reg>they</reg></choice> must help <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 18-21)</ref> to solve the problem which was caused 200 years ago.</s>
        <s>The next part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 22-37)</ref> the <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> Prime Minister explains that for making a big change we need more financial support which is possible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By using again pronouns like <quote>our</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 24)</ref> he creates that sense of community that people who are able to sponsor how to do it for everybody's life.</s>
        <s>To strengthen this comment he names an example how the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the dependence on coal <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 28f.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By underlining in the next line the word <quote>we</quote> through an anaphora <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 30)</ref> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> names to specifically that we the population is the only possibility to make a change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore he points out what will happen if we fail by using emotional expressions <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref> and by <choice><orig>repeatingly</orig><reg>repeatedly</reg></choice> naming the next generations <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref> to create a feeling of duty to help Internet the ones who are not helping feel bad for it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through another anaphora <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 45-47)</ref> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> <choice><orig>strengthen</orig><reg>strengthens</reg></choice> this comment by using now facts how we can help.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last part <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 48-52)</ref> the speaker creates a conclusion to the beginning by mentioning the <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie.</s>
        <s>He says that we may not feel or look like <name type="person">James Bond</name> but we have the same opportunities as him and that we can fight against climate change.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion uses <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris</ref> many emotions and repetitions to convince the audience to help fight against climate change.</s>
        <s>He uses the sense of <choice><orig>comunity</orig><reg>community</reg></choice> to touch the audience.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
