<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g05_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211217</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In his speech <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> tries to bring his audience to acting against climate change, while using the fear of letting future generations suffer as a motivation.</s>
        <s>He starts off by comparing the climate change to a scenario in a <name type="person">James Bond</name> movie <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Thus he is also indirectly comparing his audience to a well known hero-like character.</s>
        <s>He says how they can either act and be like the hero or fail and let future generations down.</s>
        <s>These two points are used to pressure and motivate the people to acting against climate change.</s>
        <s>He also explains what he <choice><orig>consideres</orig><reg>considers</reg></choice> as acting against climate change, saying that promises they made were <quote>nothing but blah, blah, blah, to coin a phrase</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This might be an allusion to a speech by climate activist <name type="person">Gretha Thunberg</name>, who also used the phrase <quote>blah, blah, blah</quote> in a similar context.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> goes on by naming the things they can change but are simply lacking the will to do so <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The lacking funds are an excuse and it is their responsibility to find them <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This makes his audience feel guilty for not taking action.</s>
        <s>For almost three following paragraphs he brings his audience to thinking about how the future generations are going to be affected.</s>
        <s>He stresses the importance of acting right now through a metaphor.</s>
        <s><quote>We mustn't fluff our lines or miss our cue</quote><ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This also implies that they are forced to act now, as it is their turn.</s>
        <s>During his speech, he uses a lot of inclusive language saying how <quote>the children who will judge us, are children not yet born</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 38)</ref> and that <quote>they will not forgive us</quote> <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>strenghens</orig><reg>strengthens</reg></choice> the guilt and pressure that the audience feels.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end of his speech he brings back the comparison to <name type="person">James Bond</name> he did earlier, saying that they have the chance to be like that hero and start acting against climate change <ref target="b12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 49f)</ref> right now.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
