<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g20_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The question is how it is important for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing to learn languages.</s>
        <s>I am the opinion that it is important to learn more languages and can join me to <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne's</ref> position.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If you learn new languages you get only positive things, advantages.</s>
        <s>The only bad thing or disadvantage to learn languages is, that it is hard work and needs a lot of your time and effort.</s>
        <s>But this is the only disadvantage.</s>
        <s>But if we look at the advantages, we have lots of things to say.</s>
        <s>People like employers have a better appearance of you and you can do more jobs.</s>
        <s>Today we live in a multicultural world, in which in all countries are tourists or people who does not speak the same languages like us.</s>
        <s>So first it has very much of importance for our communication with people in jobs, freetime or to help somebody for a way, they want to <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">couplete</gap>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>An other</orig><reg>Another</reg></choice> point is that you need foreign languages or better to say English almost in all jobs.</s>
        <s>As employee in the hotel, hospital, police, taxi, airport and always in the market.</s>
        <s>In our completely life we need a second language or more.</s>
        <s>The communication won very much of importance and helps us almost in all things we do.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So the learning of languages gives you a better appearance and helps to do your work better and develop new things in cooperation for your country.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all it has no bad effects to learn foreign languages.</s>
        <s>It brings you only positive things.</s>
        <s>You reach much of success, which helps you in your life.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
