<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a12g21_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear <name type="person">Emma</name>,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>in your last email you said, that you're thinking about spending a year in <name type="geo">Germany</name> after school.</s>
        <s>I was really happy to hear that!</s>
        <s>You also told me, that you heard that <name type="geo">Berlin</name> is the place to be.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As you know, I live in <name type="geo">Cologne</name>, so <choice><orig>eventhough</orig><reg>even though</reg></choice> I've been a few times in <name type="geo">Berlin</name>, I didn't really know how it is to <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice><choice><orig>their</orig><reg>there</reg></choice>, especially as an English-speaking person like you.</s>
        <s>So I did some research.</s>
        <s>By doing that, I came across the article <ref target="a12gk2_2" type="title">Berlin spricht Englisch</ref> by <ref target="a12gk2_2" type="author">Marina Kormbaki</ref>, published in the local newspaper <name type="misc">Hannoversche Allgemeine Zeitung</name>, on <date>15th July 2016</date>.</s>
        <s>I thought this article could be very interesting for your question, because the author describes that speaking English is really popular in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> and also explains some other positive aspects about living there.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk2_2" type="author">Kormbaki</ref> describes that <name type="geo">Berlin</name> gets more and more similar with big <choice><orig>metropoles</orig><reg>metropolises</reg></choice> like <name type="geo">London</name>, <name type="geo">Brooklyn</name>, <name type="geo">Sydney</name>, <name type="geo">LA</name>, etc., but in comparison to those cities, the <choice><orig>live</orig><reg>life</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> seems to be much cheaper in amny different parts of life.</s>
        <s>Not only the food, e.g. in cafés, is not as expensive as in the other cities, but also the rent is way lower.</s>
        <s>Furthermore you can find in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> a variety of art, culture and nightlife, which means that you'll never be bored!</s>
        <s>What's maybe also great for you, is, that many people in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> are speaking English, because there are coming diverse people from many different nations together.</s>
        <s>In <name type="geo">Berlin</name> there are even some places, where people don't speak German, rather English, e.g. some stores and some <choice><orig>Restaurants</orig><reg>restaurants</reg></choice> or <choice><orig>café's</orig><reg>cafés</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>So I think in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> you wouldn't have to worry that you can't communicate with others.</s>
        <s>There are even many English-speaking people in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> who were able to make their dreams come true, like starting their own business!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could help you with that information for your decision.</s>
        <s>Let me know when you decided whether you want to go to <name type="geo">Berlin</name> or not.</s>
        <s>I think, it would be really great!</s>
        <s>If you do it, I promise you to visit you in <name type="geo">Berlin</name> and mabye you'd even like to visit me in <name type="geo">Cologne</name> someday.</s>
        <s>Do you have any more questions about living in <name type="geo">Germany</name>?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I'm looking forward to hearing from you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Take care, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
