<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g20_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given article <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: 'can't, won't, don't'</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>, is from <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name> which is published in the <date>27th of January in 2015</date>.</s>
        <s>The text of <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> deals with the importance on speaking foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly the text starts with the view of the people in the <name type="geo">UK</name> that they are not erally interested on speaking foreign languages.</s>
        <s>The number of students which learn foreign languages in the university <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">nure</gap> be decline.</s>
        <s>But it is very important to can speak more than one language, because the people are looking for your language skills after you finished your <name type="misc">GSCE</name> and / or your <name type="misc">A-Levels</name>.</s>
        <s>In the following part the author lists some points why the people think not to learn more languages.</s>
        <s>Still it has importance like at the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="word">ntura tuermal</gap> marketing and exchange with people of other countries.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Some universities offer students the chance to study new languages.</s>
        <s>And it will be seem always more attractive for the employer to have language skills.</s>
        <s>The <name type="geo">UK</name> needs more young people, who have interest and talent in foreign languages.</s>
        <s>In conclusion the author says that not only the school is responsible for the young people, but always the parents need to help them on the way to have more experiences in foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up the author wants to explain us how important it is to have foreign language skills and how much positive effects for our lives it can <choice><orig>has</orig><reg>have</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text you can see on some points which view <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> has to learning foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
