<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a12g17_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="title">Language learning in the UK: 'can't, won't, don't'</ref>, written by <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> was published in the <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> newspaper <name type="misc">The Telegraph</name>.</s>
        <s>This article was published in <date>2015</date> and deals with the lack of foreign languages, <choice><orig>thaught</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> in <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> schools and the effect on the modern job world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The author starts the article with a very personal opinion on the theme.</s>
        <s>He points out, that there are much less students, who learn foreign languages <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> in the <date>1990s</date>.</s>
        <s>10000 students <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">rotter</gap> choose to note take on <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> exam in foreign languages.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he shows that these languages are needed in the <quote>real life</quote>.</s>
        <s>The learning of these languages is super important for the future of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>This is supported by a study of the <name type="misc">CBI / Pearson Education and Skills Survey</name> which points out, that two-thirds of the <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses are in need for <choice><orig>foreign-language</orig><reg>foreign language</reg></choice> skills.</s>
        <s>This fact often leads firms into picking a native speaker over <choice><orig>a english based-new</orig><reg>an English-based new</reg></choice>learner.</s>
        <s>The problem is that these foreign languages are not just needed in the job life.</s>
        <s>They are also needed in your personal life to communicate and understand with each other on your surroundings.</s>
        <s>All in all you are able to tell, that the schools and universities but most importantly the parents must help to educate the learning kids and students.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
