<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g25_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>To convince his readers, <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> uses different communicative strategies.</s>
        <s>In the following, <choice><orig>i'm</orig><reg>I'm</reg></choice> going to analyse these and explain his use of language in terms of arguments and structure.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Throughout the text several facts and statistics are employed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example, the decrease of people, studying foreign languages <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> or the dropped amount of taken exams <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>, relate to statistics, which give the article more validity and credibility.</s>
        <s>By showing numbers <add><quote>10,000 <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">fearer</gap> exams</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>, <quote>1990</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref></add> the reader gets the impression of a good investigation.</s>
        <s>On the other hand, <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> does not name any sources, which makes his statistics questionable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line twelve, an irony is used to refute possible counterarguments.</s>
        <s>In a hyperbolic manner, he <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">attrunes</gap> the <quote>perfectly intelligent people</quote> <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 19)</ref>, who believe that most people in global economic speaking <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>, thus having an example of someone who believes the counterposition.</s>
        <s>In this case, the irony indicates that this position is not <quote>perfectly intelligent</quote> but not reasonable, which supports his position.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly, <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">Worne</ref> uses his most powerful communicative strategy: <choice><orig>After</orig><reg>after</reg></choice> discussing the reasons for the <quote>steady decline</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> of foreign languages, he appeals to the readers and offers a practicable solution <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 32-35)</ref> <quote>So parents... without us</quote> <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 32-35)</ref> By adressing the parents, the people who have a chance to change these tendencies get <choice><orig>emotional</orig><reg>emotionally</reg></choice> involved, and are likely to change their own view.</s>
        <s>The metaphor of strings on a <quote>children's bow</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 34-35)</ref> emphasizes their responsibility.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The whole article pursues the intention of adressing the parents of the <name type="geo">UK</name> and influence them to educate their children in terms of cultural awareness / involvement.</s>
        <s>Hence the author uses the enumerated <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices to manipulate the reader.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also the structure does support this intention.</s>
        <s>An introduction adresses the problem <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1-12)</ref>, the <choice><orig>main-part</orig><reg>main part</reg></choice> enumerates arguments for supporting foreign speakers and lastly the appeal is used to demand action.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So the reader gets <choice><orig>subtle</orig><reg>subtly</reg></choice> pushed in the direction of <quote>action</quote>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
