<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g25_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In a globalised world, communication is one of the <choice><orig>key-elements</orig><reg>key elements</reg></choice> for collaborations.</s>
        <s>To stay in competition it is essential to speak a foreign language.</s>
        <s>The <name type="geo">UK</name> is in a special position.</s>
        <s>English is factual one of the most widespread languages worldwide hence allowing many <choice><orig>Brittains</orig><reg>British people</reg></choice> to work internaional without learning an additional language.</s>
        <s>Of course there are a lot of countries with different languages, but in terms of <choice><orig>globalization</orig><reg>globalization</reg></choice>, English is pre-dominant.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless it is quite important to have speakers for situations where noone is able to speak a certain language.</s>
        <s><name type="geo">China</name> for example <choice><orig>consist</orig><reg>consists</reg></choice> of one eighth of the world population.</s>
        <s>Many people there do not speak English, thus enforcing to have a translator.</s>
        <s>One argument <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> uses, is the demand for employees with skills in foreign languages.</s>
        <s>It is true, that people with these abilities are more <choice><orig>prefferable</orig><reg>preferable</reg></choice>, and thus helping the global standing of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nevertheless is it not an essential skill, if one already masters an international language.</s>
        <s>It is always better to speak more languages, but probably it is not a gamechanger in the <name type="geo">UK's</name> prosperity and global standing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She probably misses a few chances as jobs conerning languages get outsourced, but in the long run, the <name type="geo">UK</name> can participate via English.</s>
        <s>Additionally there is not always a direct communication between all countries.</s>
        <s>For example, it is not, necessary to contact a factory in Ghana, as a <choice><orig>logistic-company</orig><reg>logistics company</reg></choice> probably handles these <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">subtastes</gap>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
