<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g20_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>One important thing of his text is that the has wrote his text in a clearly language so that everyone can understand him without many problems by reading.</s>
        <s>At the <choice><orig>beginn</orig><reg>begin</reg></choice> he uses an anaphora <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="title">'can't, won't, don't'</ref>, to show the reader the attitude of the most people to learn a foreign language.</s>
        <s>He lists some points of people who are thinking they don't need to speak <choice><orig>an other</orig><reg>another</reg></choice> language and comments on that with <quote>cobblers</quote><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 12-15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This makes us clear that he is the <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> that we need to learn foreign languages and it has a convincing effect on the reader.</s>
        <s>In the following part of the text he tells about more advantages to learn foreign languages.</s>
        <s>It will be important for the future prosperity of the <name type="geo">UK</name> and global standing and also for their trade, cultural exports, diplomacy and national security <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 16-18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The list in this paragraph shows us again how <choice><orig>importance</orig><reg>important</reg></choice> it is to have foreign language skills.</s>
        <s>So you need <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">im</gap> lots of things, you have to do with people of other countries, foreign language experiences.</s>
        <s>He mentions this line 19 to 22  again.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> is the opinion that the number of universities offerign students the chance to study a language needs to increase <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 24-26)</ref>.</s>
        <s>And it will be always an advantage to have experiences in <choice><orig>an other</orig><reg>another</reg></choice> language because the most employers are looking for that <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 27f)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A point which <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref><choice><orig>critizes</orig><reg>criticizes</reg></choice> is that the number of people, who <choice><orig>studies</orig><reg>study</reg></choice> in the <name type="geo">UK</name> and learn foreign languages, need to increase a lot <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 30-31)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So all in all <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> is the opinion that young people or students need to learn foreign languages because of lots of positive effects like a better communication with people of other countries for <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">u</gap> better trading.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> uses a very good strategy to convincing the readers.</s>
        <s>Firstly he shows us the problem and how it is now.</s>
        <s>Then he tells us about the opinions of people who think, they don't need to study foreign languages.</s>
        <s>Following to that point he lists very important advantages of learning foreign languages and adds on that universities are giving students the chance to learn it and that the number of universities, which doing this, need to increase.</s>
        <s>Consequently he lists the positive effects of having foreign language skills and that the <name type="geo">UK</name> needs more of people like this.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up <ref target="a12gk2_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> uses lots of arguments and examples to give the reader a positive look to his opinion and he uses also daily language, which let the readers understand his text easier.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
