<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g70_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The citat <quote>The limits of my language are the limits of my world</quote> from <name type="person">Ludwig Wittgenstein</name> is today not anymore up to date.</s>
        <s>It is true that knowing a language is in a way more easier to communicate and there are less <choice><orig>missunderstandings</orig><reg>misunderstandings</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But you also can speak to a person whose language you do not know because of certain computer programs like <name type="misc">Google Translator</name> when there is any internet.</s>
        <s>But you should not rely on the technic and learn a foreign language, because when <name type="misc">Google</name> does not work you have a huge problem.</s>
        <s>When you are able to speak English you can ask maybe another person than being completely lost.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another argument for the citation and learning another language is that while learning the language you also learn a lot about the culture and you get an entry to a new world which is a new culture and you <choice><orig>does</orig><reg>do</reg></choice> not know without any help, but when you already know the culture you are not dependent on somebody else.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, you can say that the citation is semi-true, because on the one hand, when you do not have any technical help it is true like when <name type="person">Ludwig Wittgenstein</name> was alive, but today we often have technical help for solving our problems and it is not necessary anymore, but learning a language can be also fun and it trains your brain.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
