<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l24_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope you're doing fine.</s>
        <s>I <choice><orig>heared</orig><reg>heard</reg></choice> about you wanting to visit our school, probably because you read our school website about our received label <name type="misc">school without racism and school with courage</name>.</s>
        <s>I never really thought about it, until I recently read this article <name type="misc">Es gibt keine Schule ohne Rassismus</name> <add>in <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> <name type="misc">There's no school without racism</name></add> on the internet, which basically assumes the opposite of what the label seems to mean.</s>
        <s>In the article <choice><orig>roll</orig><reg>role</reg></choice> at schools, because places where different people of different cultures, sexualities etc. gather, racism and <choice><orig>discrimmination</orig><reg>discrimination</reg></choice> automatically are included.</s>
        <s>The reason for our racist behavior, which often isn't even on purpose, is that we early on get <choice><orig>thaught</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> about <choice><orig>stereotyps</orig><reg>stereotypes</reg></choice> by watching <name type="misc">Walt Disney</name> movies of children's books, where people of a specific ethnicity get portrayed negatively.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This has valid effects on how we treat others and is shown at schools as well.</s>
        <s>A study called <name type="misc">Max versus Murat</name> shows that dictates from <choice><orig>turcish</orig><reg>Turkish</reg></choice> students aren't graded as good as those from <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> students, even though they have the exact same amount of mistakes.</s>
        <s>Another example which is that racist <choice><orig>aknowlagde</orig><reg>acknowledge</reg></choice> isn't treated right, and therefore leads to racism in the everyday life, underlines <name type="person">Fereidooni's</name> statement about racism at school.</s>
        <s>Those schools that have the label still are affected by racism, but the difference they have towards other schools is that they actively do something to fight it.</s>
        <s>For example not denying its <add>(racism)</add> existance and talking about it.</s>
        <s>One of the reasons why this is so important is that most of the time people don't even realize that they are <choice><orig>discrimminating</orig><reg>discriminating</reg></choice> others, so talking about it could help being aware of it.</s>
        <s>Talking about my own experience, I realize how lucky I am to not have to deal with racism at school, and I hope you and others don't have to as well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
