<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11l19_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir Kapoor</ref> is the protagonist of the play <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 3</ref>.</s>
        <s>He is in his early fourties and lives in a spacious apartment in <name type="geo">New York's</name> upper east side with his wife <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>.</s>
        <s>He works as a corporate lawyer at a <choice><orig>jewish</orig><reg>Jewish</reg></choice> lawfirm.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is described to be and American-born male with south-asian origin who lives an affluent lifestyle.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Despite his violent appearance in scene three, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tries to control his anger.</s>
        <s>In order to avoid further development of the conflict, he asks <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> to <quote>get out</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This reveals that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> seeks to avoid <choice><orig>unneccessary</orig><reg>unnecessary</reg></choice> conflict and the use of violence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This conflict-avoidant attitude is underlined by <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> decency.</s>
        <s>The regret <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> shows after beating his wife is very apparent <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 74, l. 15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This proves that in spite of his ruthless act of violence, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> does not lack human decency.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The beating of his wife proves <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to be hypocritical.</s>
        <s>Even though <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> criticises the Quran for advocating the beating of one's wife earlier in the play, he does exactly that.</s>
        <s>This reveals that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is haunted by his strict Muslim upbringing and does not manage to refrain from the violence he seeks to avoid.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> identity is duplicious.</s>
        <s>Much like his hypocritical act, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> <quote>spits in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(l. 40)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This gesture refers to the story <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> tells earlier in the play, where his mother spat in his face because he exchanged notes with a Jewish girl, who would not be accepted in their Muslim household.</s>
        <s>These <choice><orig>hypocrysies</orig><reg>hypocrisies</reg></choice> and duplicities all show an inner-conflict of <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The primary source of anger, which <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> apparently shows in this scene, is the resentment he built up in the course of his life.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> is very resentful because usually well-meaning people discriminate him for his Muslim identity which he tries to obscure.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref>, who has a limited understanding of Islam, insults <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> as an <quote>animal</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 73, l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Therefore, even those who are superficially intrigued by Islam turn out to be Islamophobic and <choice><orig>confront</orig><reg>confronts</reg></choice> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> relationship with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> is characterised with trust.</s>
        <s>Even though <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is sure that she saw <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> kiss, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> believes <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily's</ref> excuse and sees <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory's</ref> act as an attempt to <quote>destroy</quote> <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 18)</ref> his marriage.</s>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> trusts <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> regardless of the situation or circumstances.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In contrast, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> relationship with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> is characterised with hate and disgust.</s>
        <s>The entire conflict revolves around <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> cheating on his wife and the polarised opinions <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> share on Islam.</s>
        <s>They both provocate the conflict to get physical <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="line">(p. 72, l. 32)</ref> even before <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> concedes that she is having an affair with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref>.</s>
        <s>Hence, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> relationship is toxic and hostile.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In summary, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> character is shaped by his strong resentment and duplicious identity, which form an inner-conflict that controls his emotions.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
