<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l18_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The poem <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Shakespeare Sonnet 60</ref>, written by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> is about time and nature, how everything changes in time and <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> impact on nature, art or living beings.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The 60th sonnet written by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> has the main topic of time in nature.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is writing about how everything changes over time or comes to an end, but also about how nature is still there even after so much time went by and still continues to exist.</s>
        <s>The rhyme form is like every other sonnet from <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, with 14 lines, there are three cross rhymes and one couplet at the end.</s>
        <s>It has an iambic pentameter with alternating rhyme.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first lines the speaker compares nature with time to show that nature is timeless, so even though it changes, it will never come to an end <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(v. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Later <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> explains that time always brings changes <add><quote>progress comes with time</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(v. 4)</ref></add>, by doing so he informs the reader about the meaning of <quote>time</quote>.</s>
        <s>The following lines <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> talks about the beginning of life, because he talks about how people make progress over time while getting older <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(v. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Next <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses a stylistic device, a metaphor to compare the life with the sun to explain that every time the sun goes lower, the sun <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> harder to see <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(v. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> wants to show that the more time goes by, the shorter the life <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses another metaphor in verse 11 where he uses <quote>nature's truth</quote> and the word <quote>feeds</quote> to show that time feeds on your life and eventually leads to death.</s>
        <s>This also emphasizes again that <choice><orig>Death</orig><reg>death</reg></choice> is part of the living <choice><orig>cyrcle</orig><reg>circle</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Life is uncertain and from the beginning you don't know what changes happen after time goes by, the only certain thing is <choice><orig>Death</orig><reg>death</reg></choice> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(v. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The next few lines start with the word <quote>time</quote>, to again enhance <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The final two lines are used to show that art preserves life, which means that this sonnet for example still <choice><orig>exist</orig><reg>exists</reg></choice> even after <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></ref> death and is still being read.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespeares</orig><reg>Shakespeare's</reg></choice></ref> sonnet shows that even after time his art still exists so what he wanted to describe with this sonnet has been proven to be true.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>All together</orig><reg>Altogether</reg></choice> does <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> describe topics which are still being talked about to this day.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
