<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l28_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> is a poem written by the <choice><orig>Englisch</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> poet and playwright <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> born  in <date>1564</date> and died <date>1616</date>.</s>
        <s>It ws most likely written in the <date>1590s</date>, but it was not published until <date>1609</date>, like most of his sonnets.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Like many of <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> sonnets, <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> is a love poem, discussing the passage of time.</s>
        <s>It is part of the <name type="person">Fair Youth</name> sequence, a series of poems that are believed to be <choice><orig>adressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> to unnamed young man.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>Shakespearan</orig><reg>Shakespearean</reg></choice> sonnet is made of three quatrains and a rhyming couplet ending the sonnet, concludes 14 lines each containing 10 or 11 syllables.</s>
        <s>It has an <name type="misc">ABAB CDCD EFEF GG</name> rhyme scheme and is composed in iambic pentameter.</s>
        <s>In the following I am going to analyse to giving sonnet on <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> content and form.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first quatrain, which usually sets the subject of the sonnet, the passage of time is mentioned <quote>so do our minutes hasten to ther end</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> which is compared to waves slowly reaching forward to hitting the shres.</s>
        <s>With a metaphor set in nature the lyrical voice displays how naturally it is for age to pass by.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second quatrain the lyrical voice begins with the birth of <name type="person">Jesus Christ</name> <quote>Nativity, once in the main of light</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> which is <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> intended pun, because <name type="person">Jesus</name> is seen as the <quote>light</quote> of the world or comparable to the glimpse of hope for humanity.</s>
        <s>So the sentence culd be translated to <quote>The light, once in the main of light</quote>, which has a sense of sarcasm because if one is <quote>the light</quote> you are not <quote>once</quote> in the main of light but always.</s>
        <s>The second line of the second quatrain says <quote>crawls to maturity</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref> whereby crawling could be seen as a metaphor for the processes of growing up, because baby's first start crawling in the early age of leaning and as they grow older they start to mature.</s>
        <s>In line 8 you can see the mention of time again <quote>And time that gave [...]</quote> which could prove that the sonnet discusses the passage of time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, in the third quatrain of the donnet it first seems like the lyrical voice is talking about nature but in the last line of the quatrain one could hint that he is actually alking about death, which can be indicated by <quote>[...] his scythe to mow</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The scythe is not only seen as a tool to cut grass but also as a symbol of death used by a black dressed silhouette called <foreign xml:lang="de">Sensenmann</foreign> in German.</s>
        <s>This quatrain has a twist to it because it suddenly talks about mortality.</s>
        <s>The final couplet attempts to conclude the sonnet.</s>
        <s>The lyrical voice says that he hopes that his <choice><orig>loves</orig><reg>love</reg></choice> stays in rememberance, also if he dies.</s>
        <s>With <quote>[...] despite his cruel hand</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> the lyrical I means <q>the death</q> which uses his hands or scythe to take <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Concluding, I would say that the sonnet discusses the topics of passage of age leading/shifting towards mortality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the beginning of the second quatrain, he mentions birth, with the birth of <name type="person">Jesus Christ</name> <quote>Nativity</quote> and at the end of the third quatrain he speaks about that.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>This</orig><reg>These</reg></choice> two quatrains could display the process of life.</s>
        <s>Moreover, the author of the sonnet makes use of a wordfield strongly based on nature e.g. <quote>waves</quote>, <quote>shore</quote> or <quote>naure's truth</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Striking stylistic devices <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses here are metaphors.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
