<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l30_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I am going to analyze <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This sonnet is about how the time keeps running and how cruelly and fastly our life's can end.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Just like the typical sonnet by <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> the <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> can be subdivided into three quatrains and one couplet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first quatrain is about how fast the time is running while a very usual event, like waves coming to the beach <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 1)</ref> happens.</s>
        <s>How the minutes hurry away <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 2)</ref> is described as toil <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 4)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second quatrain the author describes time's surprising talent <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 8)</ref> to make things become less important.</s>
        <s>As an example he mentions nativity, which was the <quote>main of light</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> once and <choice><orig>fought</orig><reg>faught</reg></choice> darkness <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 7)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third quatrain is about how time supports the youth's grow up <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>On the other side it is also mentioned how everything simply exists to become eliminated by time one day <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 12)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the couplet the author formulates his wish that his <choice><orig>textes</orig><reg>texts</reg></choice> won't be cut down by time <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 13)</ref> and that he does not <choice><orig>wan</orig><reg>want</reg></choice> to stop <quote>praising your worth</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> was written in the iambic pentameter with a cross rhyme in the three quatrains and a pair rhyme in the couplet.</s>
        <s>To underline his message the author uses a lot of stylistic devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first quatrain instantly starts with a comparison on a temporal base <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see ll. 1-2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This comparison between the running time and waves at the beach simply stresses how unstoppable and usual time goes by.</s>
        <s>He probably uses the waves as a comparison because watching them gives us the feeling that the time stands still for a <choice><orig>moments</orig><reg>moment</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he personificates the <quote>minutes [that] hasten</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This rhetorical device makes the reader think, that the minutes and with that the time in genral passes so fastly on purpose.</s>
        <s>That makes us seeing the time as the enemy.</s>
        <s>The expression <quote>minutes hasten to their end</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> is very tragically formulated.</s>
        <s>It gives the <choice><orig>ready</orig><reg>reader</reg></choice> an <choice><orig>unsecure</orig><reg>insecure</reg></choice> feeling because I think what happens after the end is a question which burdens a lot of people.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> keeps personification the minutes and writes, that they are <quote>changing places with that which goes before</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The process of time passing by is with that described as very <choice><orig>stressy</orig><reg>stressful</reg></choice> and busy.</s>
        <s>As everybody knows, <choice><orig>stressy</orig><reg>stressful</reg></choice> situations are not relaxed at all which an antithesis to the waves coming at the beach <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also I think that busy situations seem to us to be the shortest, as if time passes by faster.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The time passing by is also named <quote>toil</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> in the sonnet.</s>
        <s>A strong word like that effects the reader to have a negative opinion about the time in this case.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses the first quatrain to make the reader have a terrible opinion about time and to make them think that the time passes by to annoy us.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next quatrain the author mentions the <quote>Nativity [which was] once in the main of light</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The reader gets influenced and sees the Nativity as something really glory and important.</s>
        <s>Then there is another personification <quote>[Nativity] crawls to maturity</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The reader now has the image of fighting Nativity.</s>
        <s>This image gets confirmed by the verse <quote>Crooked eclipse 'gainst his glory fight</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then there is the metaphor, that time has a special gift <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(see l. 8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The thought about the time being alive is kept here but this time the author gives a talent to the time which does not let the reader have a bad image of the time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To <choice><orig>some</orig><reg>sum</reg></choice> it up, in this quatrain <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> gives an example how passing time can also trigger things that don't have to be negative.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third quatrain starts with a personification: <quote>Time doth transfix</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>, again to make sure that the reader sees the time as an living individual.</s>
        <s>Then we have a metaphor <quote>the flourish set on youth</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The growing up youth gets compared to things in nature that have to grow.</s>
        <s>That way he can relate to the first line in which also the nature is the comparison.</s>
        <s>furthermore he also describes the time's <quote>scythe</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref> which can fastly mean the end to all living plants.</s>
        <s>Another metaphor in line ten is <quote>parallels in beauty's brow</quote>.</s>
        <s>He probably wants to say that every single detail becomes beautiful.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Here the author <choice><orig>mentiones</orig><reg>mentions</reg></choice> clearly how the time makes the teenager become beautiful adults, which is clearly a positive aspect.</s>
        <s>Still it is also mentioned how quickly and cruelly time can end everything.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The final couplet the lyrical I appears with the first pronoun in the sonnet: <quote>My verse shall stand</quote>.</s>
        <s>His worry is mention, the time might also make people forget about the lyrical I's texts.</s>
        <s>We can guess that the lyrical I is <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, because he is an author who probably doesn't want his texts to become forgiven.</s>
        <s>By using the pronoun and show that the problem time is also about himself the author makes the reader feel with him and understand him.</s>
        <s>Also the pronoun <quote>thy</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> is mentioned.</s>
        <s>We don't know who exactly the author <choice><orig>adresses</orig><reg>addresses</reg></choice> here.</s>
        <s><quote>Praising thy worth, despite his cruel hands</quote><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 14)</ref> shows that the author won't let the time stop him and his writings.</s>
        <s>The last words of the expression leave an image of the time in the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>reader's</reg></choice> mind which is very terrible in which time passes on purpose to annoy us.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To conclude it, the author hopes that his writings won't be destroyed by time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
