<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l29_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211115</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>After doing the paraphrasing, I am now go on with my analysis of the sonnet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first quatrain of the sonnet the speaker points out, that they do not have much time left to spend together and they will eventually run out of time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk2_1" type="title">Sonnet 60</ref> opens up with a simile, which serves a double function <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 1-2)</ref>: It presents on the one hand the guiding idea of the poem, which is the time pressure and that time cannot be frozen, and on the other hand it predicts the upcoming misery.</s>
        <s>Line 2 <choice><orig>display</orig><reg>displays</reg></choice> a personification of the minutes hasting to the end to continue the theme of having no time left.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The comparison of uncontrolable water waves and ongoing minutes lays our the imagery of having no <choice><orig>controll</orig><reg>control</reg></choice> about the process of aging.</s>
        <s>The thesis laid out here to discuss, is that every minute of life and with your loved ones should be praised and given the value it deserves, since it always <choice><orig>travells</orig><reg>travels</reg></choice> to the end and can be over one day.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The word <quote>wave</quote> has a symbolical meaning, since it is used as a prediction of a tsunami in this context for a disaster <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This disaster is persuaded in the end of the quatrain, which underlines how close the upcoming misery is <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>While talking about the end and upcoming bad things in the first quatrain, the lyrical eye jumps in the second quatrain to the beginning of a lifetime <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To contrast the stages of life, the author uses a parallelism <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The lyrical view states that being a young adult is the highlight of the <choice><orig>life-span</orig><reg>lifespan</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He emphasizes this development with a climax.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The personification of birth <quote>crawling to maturity</quote> symbolically describes the process of a baby developing from crawling on the ground to eventually walking <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 6)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The metaphor of eclipses fighting against a glory fight, <choice><orig>represent</orig><reg>represents</reg></choice> the evil and forbidden things that will come across you in life <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The lyrical I want to import their knowledge to his lover by explaining that what you are fighting for is much more valuable than a something which will come across you, but does it only does harm to your fight <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Hear the author uses a <quote>crooked eclipses</quote> as a representation of the darkness that will eventually come in your way, but since it is <quote>crooked</quote> you can fight it off.</s>
        <s>The third quatrain is about the outer appearance of his lover.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The theme of time resumes in the lines 9 and 10, where are the author uses a enjambment or a run-on line to translate, that the passed time <choice><orig>function</orig><reg>functions</reg></choice> as red wine; the older person gets, the finer they age <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 9-10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The lyrical I metaphorically first talks about his lovers brows as the brows of beauty, emphasizing his love for them.</s>
        <s>To make this description more powerful he makes use of positive language like <quote>varieties</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref> or <quote>nature's truth</quote> <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the end of the quatrain is a turning point, when the speaker talks about a lawnmower, indirectly telling their partner that they should separate by shaving his <q>excess</q> brow hair <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This ironic language, as the truth behind these compliments was the opposite, emphasizes the speaker's sense of humor and despair.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The concluding rhyming couplet in the end forms a summary on the position the lyrical eye has to his lover.</s>
        <s>He uses an <choice><orig>Antithesis</orig><reg>antithesis</reg></choice> by saying he praises him because he is <choice><orig>devotet</orig><reg>devoted</reg></choice> to him even though the metaphor of his <quote>cruel hand</quote> indicates that his lover does nothing more to him than pain <ref target="c12lk2_1" type="line">(ll. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the whole the sonnet is based the <choice><orig>life-time</orig><reg>lifetime</reg></choice> from a <choice><orig>huming</orig><reg>human</reg></choice> being, where the importance of time is underliked.</s>
        <s>The author wants to display that time with your lover and in general on this planet is limited so we should enjoy every minute.</s>
        <s>I personally agree with the author because we often take time for granted, so it is important to pay attention and value it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
