<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g02_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In this scene the <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> reaching a development, because they are talking open and honest about their thoughts and worries about their relationship.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is not sure with introducing <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to her whole family in her <name type="geo">Garden Heights</name> part of her life, but knows that she can be herself with him.</s>
        <s>The character <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is here presented as the connection between <q>Williamson-Starr</q> and <q>Garden Heights-Starr</q>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will analyse the scene in detail to provide proof for this hypothesis.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene is introduced into the situation with a <choice><orig>Medium Long Shot</orig><reg>medium long shot</reg></choice>, which shows <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walking relaxed through the hallway to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, underlined by slow, relaxed <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">mer</gap>.</s>
        <s>In between there are close ups of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face to show her observing <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walking to her, in the background a voiceoverof <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> to show her thoughts about her knowing his smell and other details of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> presents his beat, <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> face is shown in a close up, to see, that she smiles and likes the beat, when her face is turning serious again as she turns around to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, because she confronts him with the problem she has and is showing him that she is mad.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene continues with switching between <choice><orig>Medium Close Up's</orig><reg>medium close ups</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>Close Up's</orig><reg>close ups</reg></choice>, to show the interactions and facial expressions of the characters during their talk.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The close <choice><orig>ups</orig><reg>up's</reg></choice> <choice><orig>allowes</orig><reg>allows</reg></choice> the viewer to emphasize with them understanding their feelings and reactions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For the following sequence, where <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> starts dancing with his loud music, the director <choice><orig>desides</orig><reg>decides</reg></choice> for a <choice><orig>Medium shot</orig><reg>medium shot</reg></choice>, to show the interaction of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> together with the surrounding, where other students are walking <choice><orig>trough</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> the hallway.</s>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> doesn't think it's embarrassing or strange ot show himself and together with <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> open and happy together around other people.</s>
        <s>The camera zooms in, <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> seeing <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dance, giving the expression <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> shares her <choice><orig>hapiness</orig><reg>happiness</reg></choice>, underlined by her voice-over, saying how she likes especially things like these about <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and that he makes her laugh everytime.</s>
        <s>The scene ends with them both going away laughing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides that, the director chose to have only a few cuts and not many switchings between the shot sizes, which makes the scene appear calm and fluently.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, the props used in the scene, together with underlining these with the slow music at the beginning and the fluently dialogue with the harmonic ending, the at first tense mood, turning into a lively, happy and relaxed atmosphere.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From what I've analysed, I can <choice><orig>proove</orig><reg>prove</reg></choice> my hypothesis, because the representation, in addition to the <choice><orig>stilistic</orig><reg>stylistic</reg></choice> devices means of the camera, are clearly showing the strong and clearly, but also honest and loving feelings and reaction of the characters, especially of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all, the given scene shows the strong and honest <choice><orig>realationship</orig><reg>relationship</reg></choice> between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>Especially that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, who accepts <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> in every way she is, and worries and cares about her, shows how he uses his lively and caring personality during a conflict is brought up in this scene.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
