<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g04_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the scene at hand you can see that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is an important person in <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The scene <choice><orig>start</orig><reg>starts</reg></choice> with a longshot of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walking through the hallways of their school to first show a whole image of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>You can see him greeting many people, smiling and laughing.</s>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is popular and therefore liked and maybe even admired by other students.</s>
        <s>The status of popularity is underlined by the sond <name type="misc">Ocean Eyes</name> by <name type="person">Billie Eilish</name> which is and was at that time a very popular song.</s>
        <s>He also <choice><orig>wear</orig><reg>wears</reg></choice> a <name type="misc">Nike</name> backpack.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">Nike</name> is a popular brand and is seen as cool by teenagers and so is <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>The lyrics also mirror what <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is doing.</s>
        <s>The song goes <quote>I've been watching you for some time</quote>, which <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is doing while <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is walking.</s>
        <s>While walking the camera focuses on the shoes of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is wearing the same shoes.</s>
        <s>You get to know this from her voice that talks from the off or voices the scene over.</s>
        <s>Shoes are important for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and so is <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, which the scene underlines.</s>
        <s>As soon as <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> sees <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> the camera swings from showing him to showing <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>Before that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> was walking in slow motion but not anymore.</s>
        <s>Both these aspects show that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is very attentive on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> thus caring for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>He focuses on her.</s>
        <s>When their eyes meet <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks away and into her locker which <choice><orig>shoes</orig><reg>shows</reg></choice> that she has some kind of problem with <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>The close up of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> faces when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> puts his headphones on her is used to shows <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> reaction to the music.</s>
        <s>A beat that he made <choice><orig>solemonly</orig><reg>solemny</reg></choice> to apologise to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> with.</s>
        <s>She starts to smile but catches herself and gives the headphones back because she breaks the character of the upset girlfriend that wants an explanation for her <choice><orig>boyfriends</orig><reg>boyfriend's</reg></choice> action.</s>
        <s>When they are both talking the camera switches between close ups of their faces to see their reactions but also to see who is speaking and their feelings and expressions whilst speaking, until it focuses on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris's</ref> phone to show that he is unplugging his headphones.</s>
        <s>He starts to dance to the beat and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> starts laughing.</s>
        <s>The camera starts to zoom into <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> face and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dancing.</s>
        <s>It zooms in from a medium shot of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> to a close up to her face to clearly show that she is laughing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This scene shows that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is not afriad of making a fool out of himself to make <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> happy.</s>
        <s>It also shows that he cares for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and their relationship.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conlusion you can say that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is portrayed as cool, popular, caring, happy person who is willing to fight for his relationship with <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>Their relationship is based on talking about their problems, finding solutions and caring for each other.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
