<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g06_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>This excerpt is the start of the stronger trust between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> relationship.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> comes into the <choice><orig>Hallway</orig><reg>hallway</reg></choice> the camera focuses on him and moves with him, while <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is at the lockers.</s>
        <s>It's a medium shot when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walks towards <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, and the shot is in slow motion.</s>
        <s>A dreamy song is played when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks at him, which means that he means a lot to her.</s>
        <s>She also scrutinizes him and says a lot about <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, which a normal person wouldn't know, unless they like him.</s>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> tells <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> that he misses her, you can tell that he means it because of his worried look to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, which is emphasized through the close up of his face.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is still upset and doesn't acknowledge it and <choice><orig>look</orig><reg>looks</reg></choice> away as if she were bored of his words.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> notices this, he knows that he has to do better to cheer <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> up and starts to dance to his song for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>You can see students in the background while <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> dances in the foreground in a medium shot.</s>
        <s>He doesn't hesitate to dance and isn't <choice><orig>embarassed</orig><reg>embarrassed</reg></choice> to show off <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>This means a lot for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> because she <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> reminded of why she likes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> so much, and starts to laugh.</s>
        <s>It shows, that she has mostly forgiven him for what he has done before.</s>
        <s>These things make a nice impression of their strong relationship.</s>
        <s>At the end of the scene <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> grabs his hand and pulls him away of the hallway, which is a sign of a strong bind between them.</s>
        <s>Even <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> said that he wants to get closer to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> himself.</s>
        <s>This presents his love for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The hypothesis of the relationship between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is proven mainly through the dance by <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>It shows that he trusts her and would do anything to cheer her up.</s>
        <s>You can tell that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> cares about <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> more than what people think of him and he will be there for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> when she needs him to calm her down.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
