<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b10g01_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The film <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> had an impact on me.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When I first watched the movie I was younger than I am now.</s>
        <s>As a teenager <choice><orig>u</orig><reg>you</reg></choice> have a lot of challenges e.g. keeping up with your schoolwork and your chores, finding friends and keeping them and figuring out who you are and who you <choice><orig>wanna</orig><reg>want to</reg></choice> be.</s>
        <s>Every teenager has different challenges but we all feel like we have is the most difficult.</s>
        <s>As a white <choice><orig>cathlic</orig><reg>catholic</reg></choice> girl living in <name type="geo">Germany</name> I never had to face oppression because of my skin colour or my religion.</s>
        <s>Watching this movie made me realise that in comparison to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> my life is <choice><orig>relativly</orig><reg>relatively</reg></choice> easy.</s>
        <s>I have never seen one of my <choice><orig>bestfriends</orig><reg>best friends</reg></choice> get murdered let alone two.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> already had to face a lot of different challenges but does not complain.</s>
        <s>The movie also showed me a perspective of what it is like to face the challenges a black teenage girl has to face on the daily.</s>
        <s>It made me more aware for struggles like racism because I got the chance to look at it from another perspective.</s>
        <s>The film also brings <choice><orig>awarness</orig><reg>awareness</reg></choice> to the topic of one sided friendschips.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because I watched the movie I got a better understanding of why one sided friendships are terrible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion the film did have an impact on me and watching it when I was younger shaped me for <choice><orig>live</orig><reg>life</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
