<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is presented in the scene as the <q>perfect</q> boyfriend.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> forgave him already but she wanted to wait for the right situation to end the conflict.</s>
        <s>In this text I prove or disprove my hypotheses by analysing the sequence with regard to stylistic-film-devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence begins with a medium close up on eye-level.</s>
        <s>This is used to show the viewer how <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> looks, what <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> <choice><orig>weares</orig><reg>wears</reg></choice>, and what he feels.</s>
        <s>In general it can be said that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is introduced in these shots.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> wears his school uniform with a white shirt, a blue jacket and a blue, striped tie.</s>
        <s>Also <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> wears a white shirt and a blue jacket over the shirt.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This is used to say that they are in a symmetric communication.</s>
        <s>Furthermore it can be said, that the first shot, which changed between a medium close up, for showing details, and a medium shot, for showing <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in general; these shots are filmed as a tracking shot, because <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walks towards <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As <choice><orig>allready</orig><reg>already</reg></choice> mentioned these shots are used to introduce <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>This can be underlined because the director used a slow motion to show <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in more detail.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This is connected with <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> voice from the off, who describes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> from <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> perspective.</s>
        <s><quote><s>He's wearing the same Space Jams Eleven like mine.</s><s>[...] His lips are soft.</s></quote><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> describes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> in her thoughts as a perfect boyfriend.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The slow motion and the melancholic/emotional music from the off ends, when the camera pans left to set the focus on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> from the perspective of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These shots are filmed with medium shots, medium close ups and a medium shot, which zooms into a medium close up.</s>
        <s>The director uses longer shots to create a silence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An important symbol are the headphones from <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> to demonstrate, that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> made a beat for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> as a symbol of <q>peace</q> and love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>I made that beat for you</quote>.</s>
        <s>Also <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> agreed by understanding that he messed up.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The long discussion between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is filmed as big close up to show <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> emotions in very detail.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The shots are filmed on eye-level as well and they change the perspective to show only one person in detail, when they talk.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sequence shows <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> inner conflict as well because <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> speaks as she would in <name type="misc">Garden Heights</name>; she <choice><orig>decide</orig><reg>decides</reg></choice> to be <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> version 1 instead of <name type="misc">Williamson</name>-<ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another symbol is <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> mobile phone, when he dances.</s>
        <s>It shows that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> also uses <choice><orig>embarassing</orig><reg>embarrassing</reg></choice> moments to get <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> in a happy mood.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion it can be said, that my <choice><orig>hypotheses</orig><reg>hypothesis</reg></choice> is proven.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> forgave <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> before they are talking.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is shown as a good boyfriend by using symbols and specific shot sizes.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
