<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the scene <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is tries to be presented as the cool guy in school that has many friends and who most of the girls like.</s>
        <s>He is also presented as very kind and lovely to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and a <choice><orig>pacient</orig><reg>patient</reg></choice> guy, who can also be funny.</s>
        <s>As <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> said in an other scene she isn't on the level of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, but they still are matching very good together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the movie are many film-stylistic devices used, that undeline this theory about the personality of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the very beginning of the given part of the movie, there is a scene in which <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is walking through the school floor.</s>
        <s>The whole scene is in <choice><orig>slowmotion</orig><reg>slow motion</reg></choice>, so that there is a better focus on the movement of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is walking in the middle of the school floor and also his arms are not laying beside his body, but are like 10 centimeters away from his body to create the effect that he looks bigger.</s>
        <s>In the same scene, <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is also shaking his hands with about 3-5 people and is greeting them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That creates the impression that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is well-known in the school and has many loyal friends on his side.</s>
        <s>The focus is not only on the way he is walking, but on his face, to give the watcher a first impression of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, who is seen by the watchers for the first time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next scene, where <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walks to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> locker, there are many important moments to get an impression about the relationship between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>The beats that he makes for <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and also his ability to make <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> laugh are very important in their relationship.</s>
        <s>At many points in the whole movie, there are scenes, where <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is unhappy and sad, where then <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is <choice><orig>comming</orig><reg>coming</reg></choice> and makes <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> happy again with his beats, but mostly his jokes and funny dancing.</s>
        <s>In this scene are the argument between <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, <choice><orig>ther</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> are used mostly eye-level shots to show that they are on the same level, which can also be applied on their relationship.</s>
        <s>The director also used over-the-shoulder and reverse-angle shots, to show the facial impression of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>, when they were talking.</s>
        <s>This should make the scene more <choice><orig>emocionel</orig><reg>emotional</reg></choice>, which is also underlined by the close ups used, when they were talking.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>When <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> places the headphones on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> head, he did it really careful, so that it makes the impression, that he cares about <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and is very lovely.</s>
        <s>The dancing of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> was also very important, because he wouldn't have danced in this scene, when <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> wouldn't be there so from that you can see, that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is willing to blame himself just to make <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> happy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A big thing in their relationship are also the shoes.</s>
        <s>In the beginning scene, where <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> was walking in <choice><orig>slowmotion</orig><reg>slow motion</reg></choice> through the floor of the school.</s>
        <s>In this scene was a close up on <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> shoes, which were <name type="misc">Jordans</name>.</s>
        <s>They share their love to <name type="misc">Jordans</name>, because <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref> also wears <name type="misc">Jordans</name> and also has many pairs of them at home.</s>
        <s>So this is a thing they share.</s>
        <s>One big thing that they don't share is their skin colour.</s>
        <s>This is a problem for some people in the school, for example the girls in the scene after this given <choice><orig>scen</orig><reg>scene</reg></choice>, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> are starring at <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, when they were kissing.</s>
        <s>The skin colour is also problematic in her family, but only with her father, her <choice><orig>Mother</orig><reg>mother</reg></choice> and her siblings have no problems with the skin color of <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So all in all one can say, that in this scene you can learn many things about <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and his relationship to his girlfriend <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>I could prove all the <choice><orig>tings</orig><reg>things</reg></choice> said in my hypothesis, so that <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is the cool guy in school, but is very lovely and kind to <ref target="b10gk1_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
