<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g72_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article has four paragraphs.</s>
        <s>The first one is informative and appealing, as the author uses <quote>we</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> to directly involve the readers, the second and the third paragraph are informative and the last one is appealing due to the same reason in paragraph one, and it is argumentative.</s>
        <s>Argument used in the last paragraph are: <quote>... you do not learn to stand on your own two feet if someone is holding you</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 18-19)</ref>, <quote>Indulging differences can be harmful if it prevents communities from integrating</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 19-20)</ref>, <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> should be compulsory for all citizens <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref>, public figures do not to speak up as they fear to be labelled as a racist but the not speaking up is even more harmful <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 22-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This specific text structure, results in the arguments being more memorable and effective.</s>
        <s>Additionally the detailed description of the problems in Bangladeshi community leads to the reader gaining sympathy for those who suffer.</s>
        <s>This does also support the effectiveness of the arguments.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, the author often uses pronouns such as <quote>we</quote> and <quote>our</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(e.g. l. 4, 18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>As a consequence, the reader is directly involved in the events which raises the attention.</s>
        <s>It also calls upon the readers to not against the problem as through the use of this, it is portrayed as it also is a problem for the reader.</s>
        <s>His personal experience which is mentioned in the third paragraph gives the article an authentic personal note which could possibly help immigrants identify with <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="author">Rahman</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the second paragraph the author uses an anaphora <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The words this affects are <quote>My parents</quote>.</s>
        <s>This marks the importance of the parents in this problems, as their displeasure to learn English or contrary to this their pleasure to learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> projects onto the kid.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>shorteness</orig><reg>shortness</reg></choice> also contributes to the effectiveness of the article due to the increased noticeably.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The in the second paragraph installed metaphor, describes the inability of immigrated Bangladeshis to achieve educational development <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It portrays the fatality of the circumstance through creating an image in the <choice><orig>readers</orig><reg>reader's</reg></choice> mind.</s>
        <s>The metaphor in the third paragraph compliments the other arguments <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 18-19)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The metaphor expresses that you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> learn, if someone else is doing your part thus making extreme celebration of diversity useless because it creates the possibility not to fully integrate.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
