<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g78_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>Text</orig><reg>text</reg></choice> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref>, written by <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> and published in <date>2016</date>, is about language learning and consequences for the integration of immigrant communities in <name type="geo"><choice><abbr>GB</abbr><expan>Great Britain</expan></choice></name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First he starts with the fact, that more than £100 <choice><abbr>m</abbr><expan>million</expan></choice> was spent in <date>2015</date> for interpreting and translating for British immigrants who don't speak <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That's a high amount of money, but this isn't the only problem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>If you know <name type="misc">Brick Lane</name> in the <name type="misc">East End</name> of <name type="geo">London</name>, the problem is for everyone visible.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The most is written in Bengali, that's a very huge problem, because no one is telling them to learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>, they have to integrate alone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <name type="misc">East End</name> of <name type="geo">London</name> is hopeless.</s>
        <s>The most guys can only choose between extremists in the mosque or the gangs on the street.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Next <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="author">Zia</ref> is telling us about his personal experience.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He arrived in <name type="geo">Britain</name> and spoke no <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>But he was lucky, because his family were determined not to be absorbed into <name type="misc">East End</name>, which was very rare because of their nationality.</s>
        <s>He and his parents started to learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At the end he talks about the <quote>Awareness-raising programmes</quote> and to be proud of the own nationality.</s>
        <s>We have to celebrate our diversity, curb the translation and interpreting services and help other to learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
