<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g70_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref> written by <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> and first published in <name type="misc">The Sunday Times</name> on <date>17th December 2016</date> deals with the problem that a lot of people coming from <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> into <name type="geo">Great Britain</name> does not learn the English language and that they stay close with other people from <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name> and does not integrate in the British culture.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The text is divided in four paragraphs.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first paragraph <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 1-4)</ref> is about that there is spend much money for people who <choice><orig>does</orig><reg>do</reg></choice> not speak English on translating important information for them, than helping them to learn English or to integrate.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Then, the next paragraph <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 5-10)</ref> deals with the <name type="misc">Brick Lane</name> in the <name type="misc">East End</name> of <name type="geo">London</name> with a high level of criminality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The following paragraph <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 11-17)</ref> tells us something about the author's life.</s>
        <s>He does not have to grow up in <name type="misc">Brick Lane</name>, when he arrived in <name type="geo">Britain</name>.</s>
        <s>He and his parents wanted to learn English and so they did.</s>
        <s>He goes to a normal school and had a normal life.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fourth and last paragraph is about that <choice><orig>everone</orig><reg>everyone</reg></choice> should get the chance to learn by curbing the translation and making English compulsory for all citizens.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
