<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g81_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The informative and non-fictional text <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref>, written by <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> from the <name type="misc">Sunday Times</name>, <date>17th December 2016</date> with 344 words is about learning language and its consequences for the integration of immigrant communities in <name type="geo"><choice><abbr>GB</abbr><expan>Great Britain</expan></choice></name>.</s>
        <s>The author has the opinion, that we should think about making English compulsory for all citizens.</s>
        <s>He also says that learning languages can broaden your horizons and give you better memory.</s>
        <s>Just because English is a foreign language we have to celebrate our diversity and getting us all to speak English so that we can communicate anywhere with people around the world.</s>
        <s>Besides these arguments for learning language there are also consequences for the integration of immigrant communities in <name type="geo"><choice><abbr>GB</abbr><expan>Great Britain</expan></choice></name>.</s>
        <s>First, the financial cost is bad enough and yearly a lot of money is spent on translating and interpreting for residents who <surplus>who</surplus> don't speak English or don't have English as their mother tongue.</s>
        <s>The immigrant communities get alone integrate and because of this every year Bangladeshis sit at the bottom of educational achievement and don't know how their lives will go on.</s>
        <s>So the crime and drug abuse rise fast in the <name type="misc">East End</name>.</s>
        <s>At the end the author <choice><orig>believe</orig><reg>believes</reg></choice> we should curb the translation and interpreting services, get involved for people who don't speak English and protect the educational achievement in <name type="geo">Bangladesh</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
