<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g75_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The author uses a few communicative <choice><orig>strategys</orig><reg>strategies</reg></choice> to convince us of his opinion.</s>
        <s>For example the structure, the text has four paragraphs in which he tells different things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first paragraph, he describes the problem of not speaking <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>After that, he gives an example of a place where they <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> speak <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> and shows how hard the life of the people there is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third paragraph, he tells the reader his own experiences with learning <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>With that, he wants the reader to be more interested in the text and in learning <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He also wants the reader to understand the problem more with having a real story he can understand.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first three paragraphs he wants to show the reader the problems and in the fourth paragraph he tells his idea of a solution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his text he also uses some stylistic devices to <choice><orig>strength</orig><reg>strengthen</reg></choice> his statements.</s>
        <s>From line 18 to 19 he says <quote>But you don't learn to stand on your own two feet if someone is holding you up</quote>.</s>
        <s>With that <choice><orig>metapher</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice>, he wants to say that you have to do some things by your own and in this case you should learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> so you won't need someone to translate for you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also uses the example of Bangladeshis <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 7-10)</ref> in which he shows how important it is to learn <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice> and he wants to give the reader the goal not to end like them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another communicative strategy he uses is the <choice><orig>repitition</orig><reg>repetition</reg></choice> of <quote>we</quote> and <quote>us</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(cf. l. 3, l. 4, l. 18, l. 20, l. 23)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With that he wants the reader to feel like he is concerned of the story.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up, the author wants as many people as possible to learn to speak <choice><orig>english</orig><reg>English</reg></choice>, so they can get employment and communicate with others.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
