<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c10g82_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The article <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="title">Hope of escape lost in translation</ref> is a text which was written by <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="author">Zia Haider Rahman</ref> and published by <name type="misc">The Sunday Times</name> on the <date>17th December 2016</date>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>It's</orig><reg>Its</reg></choice> target group is everyone who is interested and it was published with the intention to warn about the risks of not knowing your country's language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The text can be <choice><orig>devided</orig><reg>divided</reg></choice> into four paragraphs.</s>
        <s>In lines one to four, the author informs about the huge amount of money that is spent on translating and interpreting for immigrants who live in <name type="geo">Great Britain</name>.</s>
        <s>After that, he states that the people of <name type="geo">Britain</name> send confusing signals, convincing immigrants who don't speak English that they don't have to learn the language or integrate at all.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second paragraph <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 5-10)</ref>, the author shows examples of failed integration and <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> dangers.</s>
        <s>According to him, quarters in which solely immigrant communities live are more likely to have high criminality rates and a low educational standard.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, you can learn English quickly in the right environment and if you try hard enough.</s>
        <s>This is stated in the third paragraph <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(ll. 11-17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the last paragraph, the author concludes the article by speaking his mind on the topic <quote>celebrating diversity</quote>, which in his opinion reinforces the idea that integration is not necessary.</s>
        <s>His final statement is that learning English should be mandatory if you live in <name type="geo">Britain</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
