<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g82_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The text includes a few informative, but mostly argumentative elements.</s>
        <s>I would interpret the first two paragraphs as both informative and argumentative, since the author uses the given information to get his point across.</s>
        <s>An example for that technique is using figures like £100<choice><abbr>m</abbr><expan>million</expan></choice> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another way to convince the reader of his opinion is the usage of stylistic devices in the second paragraph.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Mataphors like <quote>sit at the bottom of educational achievement</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref> are meant to make the situation in parallel societies clear.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>You don't learn [...] if someone is holding you up</quote> is another example of metaphors in argumentative texts.</s>
        <s>This one specifically is used to once again show the significance of trying to integrate.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article is written in a very serious, perhaps even cold way, which is fitting for the serious message.</s>
        <s>This can also be a way to convince the readers of your opinion, showing them that the topic is important and that change needs to happen.</s>
        <s>In the last paragraph, the author states his most important argument, so it is the point the reader is more likely to remember.</s>
        <s>Another communicative strategy he uses is using the word <quote>us</quote> <ref target="c10gk5_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref>, which makes the reader feel included.</s>
        <s>Ending an article that way makes it easier to convince somebody of your opinion.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
