<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c11g15_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier's</ref> speech at the <name type="misc">European American Chamber of Commerce</name> in <name type="geo">New York</name> was held on the <date>10th July 2018</date> and is about the consequences of <name type="misc">Brexit</name> as well as the characteristics of a close relationship between the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> is an <name type="misc">EU</name> commissioner for the withdrawal negatiations of the <name type="geo">UK</name> in the course of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The consequences listed by <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> are mainly based on economic reasons and include the created friction, which will have an impact on the value chains of multiple economic sectors.</s>
        <s>He also states that the cost for the <name type="geo">UK</name> would be substantially higher than the <name type="misc">EU's</name>, but it would still be an unfavourable situation for both sides.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he warns <name type="geo">US</name> firms to analyse their supply chains and existing contracts in view of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For the characteristics of a close relationship between the two unions he describes one similar to that of the <name type="geo">USA</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name>, which was achieved by opening the <name type="misc">EU Single Market</name> for third countries like the <name type="geo">US</name> and the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>As another option he lists the inclusion of the right of establishment in future <name type="misc">Free Trade Agreements</name>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
