<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c11g07_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In order to convince his audience of his opinion, <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> makes use of several rhetorical strategies.</s>
        <s>In the text below, I will have a closer look on his choice of words, his line of arguments and the stylistic devices he employs.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first few lines <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> is introducing to the speech by telling the issue he is talking about and his position <quote>regret</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> the split of the <name type="geo">UK</name> from the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>So, firstly, he is announcing his topic in order to catch the audience's attention.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Secondly he goes on with the main part where he explains the consequences of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, especially for the <name type="geo">UK</name> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 4-10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Then he continues with talking about the troubles and difficulties the <name type="geo">UK</name> will face when aiming to sign a deal with the <name type="geo">US</name> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. 11-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Thus he explains after that the <name type="misc">EU</name> should have a <quote>close relationship with the UK [...] in financial services</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 15f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Lastly he refers to the <quote>regulation and supervision of third countries</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 21f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> explains that the <name type="misc">EU</name> single market <quote>works well</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 25)</ref> for the <name type="geo">US</name> and is wondering why it does not work for the <name type="geo">UK</name> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. l. 25f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the conclusion of his text, he puts visions for the future forward of the <name type="misc">EU</name> market remaining the most open in the world and of the <name type="misc">EU</name> remaining itself without change after <name type="misc">Brexit</name> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 27ff.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>With the intention of making is easier for the audience to follow his train of thoughts he is structuring his text with the use of words such as <quote>first</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>, <quote>secondly</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 21)</ref>, which enhances the understanding of the audience.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In order to make sure that the audience can follow him he employs several strategies, for ex.</s>
        <s>he asks a rhetorical question in l. 25-26 which makes the audience question why the <name type="misc">EU</name> market is not working for the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>The question is also helpful to manifest the audience's attention throughout the speech because of involving them.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he is putting emphasis on his question due to the anaphora <quote><qs>Why?</qs><qs>[...] Why?</qs></quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 25-26)</ref> which stresses his point.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The frequent use of the first <choice><orig>plurlar</orig><reg>plural</reg></choice> personal pronouns such as <quote>we</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>, <quote>we</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 15)</ref>, <quote>our</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> gives the listeners the impression that he does not regard himself as superior to them but rather as one of them.</s>
        <s>It also suggests that he is attempting to establish his personal relationship with the listeners.</s>
        <s>Moreover, it is creating an illusion of solidarity and mutual understanding which makes it appear unreasonable not to agree with him and that way helping him to impose his opinion on his audience.</s>
        <s>He is also drawing a sharp contrast between <quote>you [...] in the US</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 22)</ref> and <quote>we [...] in the EU</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 23)</ref> which again underlines those patterns of identification and solidarity.</s>
        <s>To put emphasis on the importance of the <name type="misc">EU</name> market, he makes use of an enumeration in lines 20-30: <quote>that is more open, comprehensive, and rules-based</quote>.</s>
        <s>The enumeration is also creating intensity, underlining the message of the speech.</s>
        <s>With the purpose of leaving no doubt he makes frequent use of the <choice><orig>adjectiv</orig><reg>adjective</reg></choice> <quote>clear</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 24, l. 27)</ref> and the adverb <quote>clearly</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> also employs another <choice><orig>adverbs</orig><reg>adverbs</reg></choice> that lead to better understanding and create a stronger impact and imagery, for instance <quote>deeply</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> and <quote>necessarily</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another much-used word is the verb <quote>will</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 27, l. 28, l. 32)</ref> when talking about the future.</s>
        <s>This employment makes <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> appears determined and convinced of what he is saying which gives the impression that he is trustworthy and in return he is more convincing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After the analysis of the speech of <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref>, I have come to the conclusion that he is using several devices with the intention of catching the audience's attention, manifesting it, and winning the trust of the audience in establishing a personal relationship with them.</s>
        <s>I think that he successfully appealed to the audience's heads and hearts.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
