<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g46_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>I really liked the film <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> because it concentrates on many important aspects of teenage life such as love, friendship, family, personality etc.</s>
        <s>In some situations you can emphasize with the <choice><orig>maincharacter</orig><reg>main character</reg></choice> <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> for example combining family life and friends.</s>
        <s>It also shows the character development of <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and you can see her journey from a girl who does not know who she is to a strong and brave <choice><orig>joung</orig><reg>young</reg></choice> woman.</s>
        <s>This showed me the importance of raising your voice when someone does you wrong.</s>
        <s>It also highlights the process of finding yourself and what is really important to you, for example that you have to realize if someone is not good for you.</s>
        <s>In the movie <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> needed to let <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Hailey</ref> go to develop her character.</s>
        <s>The importance of the family is also foreshadowed which I think is also something that most teenagers often forget.</s>
        <s>Of course this is the age where you get independent but a healthy and loving family is something that I think everybody still needs.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the film puctures the challenges of teenage life really good because of the difficulties that <ref target="b10gk4_1" type="character">Starr</ref> has to overcome.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
