<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b10g19_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="personal response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The novel <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> by <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="author">Angie Thomas</ref> had a very strong impact on my idea of everyday challenges of teenage life because I never heard a story like that before.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>storys</orig><reg>stories</reg></choice> that I usually hear are different because in <name type="geo">Germany</name> the injustice isn't that noticeable as in the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
        <s>It also helped me to open my eyes in case of everyday-racism which also happens a lot in <name type="geo">Germany</name> because I heard about the effects that it has on the victim.</s>
        <s>I say something when I hear that someone says something racist even if it is <q>only</q> a joke.</s>
        <s>Racism is <choice><orig>Racism</orig><reg>racism</reg></choice>!</s>
        <s>Through the story I also got a much better perspective how racism is tolerated in other countries and how bad the injustice between black and white people still is.</s>
        <s>It helped me to look through the eyes of a person who clearly is a victim of racism to really feel how racism is sadly a very dominant part of some people's <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The novel also shows that in some parts of the world even the <choice><orig>governement</orig><reg>government</reg></choice> <choice><orig>expecially</orig><reg>especially</reg></choice> the police uses prejudices to justify their actions.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk2_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> showed me that most of the people are raised with prejudices.</s>
        <s>Even <ref target="b10gk2_1" type="character">Uncle Carlo</ref> who is a black person in the book, says that it makes a difference when a police officer meets a white person or a black person.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think that this is totally wrong.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the novel had a very big impact on my with the topic racism and teenage challenges.</s>
        <s>I would suggest everybody to read this book so that maybe the eyes of other people can be opened to this topic.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
