<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3c</title>
        <author>a11l23_t3</author>
        <name>dialogue</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="personal_recount">dialogue</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
        <listPerson type="speaker">
          <person xml:id="A">
            <persName>Emily</persName>
          </person>
          <person xml:id="B">
            <persName>Maya</persName>
          </person>
        </listPerson>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <stage>Lights go on and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Maya</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> sit in small cafe, drinking coffee</stage>
      </p>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Again, I am so glad that you came.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Of course, but you seemed to be off over the last few days, is <choice><orig>ther</orig><reg>there</reg></choice> something that we need to talk about?</s>
      </u>
      <p>
        <stage><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily's</ref> eyes start to water and her voice gets shaky</stage>
      </p>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I told you about how <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> would come over for dinner, right?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Yes?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>They came over to tell me that I am in the show, which are great news, but the rest of the evening was a horror show.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, what happened?</s>
        <s>I have never seen you like that.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>So, from the beginning.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and I had an <choice><orig>affaire</orig><reg>affair</reg></choice> in <name type="geo">London</name>, which was a mistake, sure, but <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> was so distanced all the time and we fought every day.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Oh god, did <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> find out about that?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Yes, after <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> caught us kissing, I told him.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>How did he take it?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Really bad.</s>
      </u>
      <p>
        <stage><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> starts to cry</stage>
      </p>
      <u who="B">
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref>, everything will be fine, we will figure it out.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Thank you really, but that's not all.</s>
        <s>He beated me up, he punched me, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> punched me.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Oh shit, how are you?</s>
        <s>I never expected <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> to do something like that!</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I am fine, it wasn't that bad, I am just in shock and I don't know what to do.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Okay, first of all you need to calm down we will figure everything out.</s>
      </u>
      <p>
        <stage><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> slowly calms down</stage>
      </p>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Do you know if you want to press charges because if you do, sooner is better than later.</s>
        <s>Do you have any idea why he blew up on you?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I don't know yet, he sent me letters apologizing and explaining everything.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>What did he say?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>He said, that he is so sorry, but just couldn't help himself.</s>
        <s>He told me that everyday he felt unseen and not respected by me.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Wow, did you know that?</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>No, not at all, I am not racist.</s>
        <s>I love <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>.</s>
        <s>As an example he said that he felt so badly treated when I painted him.</s>
        <s>I never wanted to hurt him.</s>
        <s>I wanted to draw him like I see and how he really is, not how he looks from the outside.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>I know it is hard to understand, but that's exactly what he meant.</s>
        <s>You think that he is perceived a certain way, which is racist.</s>
        <s>And I know you didn't mean to hurt him, but you can't look into his feelings.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Oh wow, I never looked at it in that way.</s>
        <s>I always thought he would be happy, if I tell him that I don't see him like everyone else, but I just reminded him everyday of his ethnicity that he wanted to hide.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Yes, it's good that you understand that.</s>
        <s>Also, I know you love the Islamic culture, their art, but for <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> it's not just the art that is part of that.</s>
        <s>He knows how women are treated and has his own opinion on the Quran.</s>
        <s>If you don't accept his <choice><orig>believes</orig><reg>beliefs</reg></choice> you disrespect him.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I never thought about any of that, thank you so much <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Maya</ref>!</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>No problem, but still that he beated you up is not okay and you have to decide, if you want to press charges.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>Yeah, you're right.</s>
        <s>I will have to think about that.</s>
      </u>
      <p>
        <stage>lights out</stage>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
