<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l22_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>my name is Jane and I am in grade 11 at the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name>.</s>
        <s>In my English class we discussed your email to the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> and <choice><orig>where</orig><reg>were</reg></choice> given the assignment to do some research on the subject and to write an answer to you in which we set out our results.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I found your question very interesting and found a really interesting article from <name type="misc">Deutsches Schulportal</name> on <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> oder <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> not a school can exist where no incidents of racism occur.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Sadly the article in only available in German but nevertheless I will try to give you a mediatoin of <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> content.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The article already answers your question in the title.</s>
        <s>It states that there is no school without racism.</s>
        <s>According to the article inequality is inevitable in any social situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Racism is reality in the school life of for example <choice><abbr>P.O.C.</abbr><expan>people of colour</expan></choice>, or foreign looking kids in general.</s>
        <s>That racism can be expressed by teachers who grade the test of a foreign looking child worse than the test of a German child although the produced results are of the same quality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I can also be expressed by the other children who were taught racism by their <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>subconciously</orig><reg>subconsciously</reg></choice> apply that racism on e.g. <choice><abbr>P.O.C.</abbr><expan>people of colour</expan></choice> or foreigners.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <name type="misc">school without racism, school with courage</name> is not a label that schools receive who try to sensitize their students on the issue of racism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That sensitation is according to the article the only possible way to minimize racism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>That is because only by <choice><orig>subconcious</orig><reg>subconscious</reg></choice> racist structures can be extinct.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From my own experience at the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> I can say that that discussion of racism is <choice><orig>definetly</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> a reality.</s>
        <s>In almost every subject we have critically talked about racism and the profound consequences both individual and systematic racism can have.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Racist remarks are not viewed as a nuisance but as the profound issue that it is.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However the students at the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> are mostly born in <name type="geo">Germany</name> and almost everybody speaks German fluently.</s>
        <s>I would wish for some more diversity so that my <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> at school looks a little bit more like my <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> outside of school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could answer your question and am excited to see you here at the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> in the next term.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See you soon</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
