<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>a11l19_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary recount">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given extract from scene three of <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="author">Ayad Akhtar's</ref> play <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="title">Disgraced, Scene 3</ref> deals with the violent climax of a heated argument at a dinner party.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the beginning of the extract, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> return to the apartment after going out to buy a bottle of champagne.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is in utter shock because she sees her husband <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir's</ref> wife <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> kiss, as soon as she enters the door.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref>, still fuming because he was just told by <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> that she was promoted instead of him, enters soon after and catches up to what allegedly happened.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> deny having kissed and claim that they were hugging because <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> is upset about <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> not being promoted at his lawfirm.</s>
        <s>Consequently, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> confronts <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> for destroying his marriage, therefore implying that he believes that <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> is lying and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> and <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Emily</ref> did not kiss.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> reveals how much effort he put into his work at the law firm and implies that he did not get equal chances due to his belief and origin.</s>
        <s>When the conflict gets physical, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> spits in <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac's</ref> face, whereafter <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> insults <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> for his former Muslim belief.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> leaves.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> asks <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> to leave too, but before she does so, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Jory</ref> elaborates how <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> did not get promoted due to his duplicious identity.</s>
        <s>After the guests both leave, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> pressures his wife into admitting that she has slept with <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Isaac</ref> on a trip to <name type="geo">London</name>.</s>
        <s>Overwhelmed by his emotions and filled with resentment, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Amir</ref> proceeds to beat his wife in rapid succession.</s>
        <s>When he realises what he has done, he is filled with regret.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
