<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l26_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical_exposition">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Thank you for your email.</s>
        <s>We can't wait for you to come here and meet us.</s>
        <s>Your school the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> received the label: <name type="misc">school without racism, school with courage</name>.</s>
        <s>Well this sounds fantastic at first but that doesn't mean that there are unfortunately not racial incidences.</s>
        <s>That label that we have is from a network of schools.</s>
        <s>Three-tousand actually.</s>
        <s>And all schools who have this label are supporting the fight against racism.</s>
        <s>Many people think that there is not a single school that doesn't has racism in some point.</s>
        <s>There are only schools that fight against racism more than others.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now I will tell you my experiences with racism at our school.</s>
        <s>In the six or seven years I've been on the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name>, I've heard of eight or nine racist actions and confrontations.</s>
        <s>But in every single case there were students, that supported and helped the victim of the racial attack immediately.</s>
        <s>Maybe there were more cases with a worse ending, but that were just my experiences.</s>
        <s>To fight more against racism I find it important to talk about this topic more in school and school lessons.</s>
        <s>Many teachers actually act like it's not that important and that everybody would know that racism is a bad thing, but I don't think so.</s>
        <s>Children just <q>learn</q> racism.</s>
        <s>It's not like they are racist just for fun, but many childbooks and movies present people of colour or people with a different religion as something weird or bad.</s>
        <s>That's how children and young students learn it.</s>
        <s>They just don't know it better.</s>
        <s>We just have to talk more about it.</s>
        <s>That's the only way we can prevent it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could answer some of your questions.</s>
        <s>Feel free to ask more.</s>
      </p>
      <p>Greetings from <name type="geo">Cologne</name></p>
      <p>
        <signed>John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
