<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l12_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hi John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I informed myself about the topic racism at schools and wanted to help you with your questions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So, racism in schools is not a rare thing.</s>
        <s>Often it's unintentionally and teachers even <choice><orig>doesn't</orig><reg>don't</reg></choice> know that they discriminate students basen on their looks, their name or their ethnicity.</s>
        <s>But <choice><orig>thats</orig><reg>that's</reg></choice> also as harmful and bad as intentional racism because it has the same effect: People get discriminated and for example people of colour or with a non-German name get not as good grades as <choice><orig>german</orig><reg>German</reg></choice> people or people where you don't assume another heritage.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Thats</orig><reg>That's</reg></choice> very unfair and <choice><orig>definetly</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> has to be changed.</s>
        <s>The best thing to start with it is to be aware of racism and that it still exists, also in schools, because we get <choice><orig>thaught</orig><reg>taught</reg></choice> it in books or films.</s>
        <s>We have to talk about discrimination and learn to ask questions critically about for example books where black people are <choice><orig>discribed</orig><reg>described</reg></choice> as <q>bad</q> or something.</s>
        <s>That is not okay and we have to know about this issue to change something and don't make the same mistakes as people who are racist, even if they do it unintentionally.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think on our school students get informed about racism but it can still be improved.</s>
        <s>Not only in schools, but everywhere where different people come together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could help you.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Greetings, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
