<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l23_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>first of all I am very excited for you to come here!</s>
        <s>I think your question is really interesting and valid.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I found an article <name type="misc">Es gibt keine Schule ohne Rassismus</name>, which means as much as <name type="misc">There is no school without racism</name>.</s>
        <s>The article questions, just like you, if there can be a school, where racism is not existing.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of the answers is from <name type="person">Karim Fereidooni</name>, in his opinion it is unrealistic to have a place without any racism, when there are so many different people coming together and interacting with each other.</s>
        <s>Though, this is not <quote>our</quote> fault, says the article.</s>
        <s>Racism is not something you were born with, it is something you get taught over your childhood and bring into your adulthood.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>There has been a study called <name type="misc">Max versus Murat</name>, where teachers graded the exams, which had the same mistakes and <name type="misc">Murat</name> received a worse mark than <name type="misc">Max</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Again, supposedly it is not the <choice><orig>teachers</orig><reg>teachers'</reg></choice> fault, because they were also just taught this behavior.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So what can we do to improve?</s>
        <s>Pretty simple, we have to be aware of the ongoing racism in our every day life, including school.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, there also be a shift in children books and movies and racism must be included in school lessons.</s>
        <s>Speaking from my own experience at the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name>, I personally never had direct experiences with racism and non of my friends had.</s>
        <s>Of course I haven't had all the teachers, but the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> is really tolerant towards everyone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I would be more than happy if you decide to come here and I assure you, that you will be treated like everyone else.</s>
        <s>Happy to hear from you!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
