<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3c</title>
        <author>a11l24_t3</author>
        <name>dialogue</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="personal recount">dialogue</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
        <listPerson type="speaker">
          <person xml:id="A">
            <persName>Emily</persName>
          </person>
          <person xml:id="B">
            <persName>Maya</persName>
          </person>
        </listPerson>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <u who="A">
        <s>And then he just beated me up, like he didn't even knew me!</s>
        <s>I've never saw him that aggressive before, it really scared me.</s>
        <s>But I'm aware that it's also my fault.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>That doesn't give him the right to beat you up, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Em</ref>!</s>
        <s>You shouldn't have cheated on him - sure, but I told you from the beginning he has major anger issues, that you can't fix!</s>
        <s>Someone who is not in peace with themself can't be in peace with others, believe me.</s>
        <s>I know what I'm talking about.</s>
        <s>Sooner or later it would have ended either way.</s>
        <s>It's important now for you to be strong and get over it, even though it's a hard and long process you have to go <choice><orig>thru</orig><reg>through</reg></choice>.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I don't think I'm able to forget what happened.</s>
        <s>I mean I loved him or still do.</s>
        <s>I don't know, I never had such mixed feelings about something so obvious, oh my god!</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>I know honey, but you shouldn't even try to forget.</s>
        <s>Always keep in mind what he did to you and how much stronger you got because of that.</s>
        <s>Your job is to overcome the negative past aspects of the past and filter the good parts out of it.</s>
        <s>I'm there for you, and I'm sure you can do this.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>It's so strange, you know.</s>
        <s>I always kind of knew we weren't made for each other, because of our difference.</s>
        <s>I never felt like he understood me, even though he should.</s>
        <s>He is the one who <choice><orig>suppossed</orig><reg>supposed</reg></choice> to support Islamic traditions after all.</s>
        <s>But instead all he did was criticizing me in any way.</s>
        <s>I never felt like he was supporting me, the way a husband should support his wife.</s>
        <s>All I wanted was to show him how beautiful his origin culture and religion is, so he could accept himself, but I guess I did the opposite thing...</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s><choice><orig>Stopp</orig><reg>Stop</reg></choice> that!</s>
        <s>It was never <choice><orig>you</orig><reg>your</reg></choice> job to fix him!</s>
        <s>He has his own problems, nobody can fix.</s>
        <s>You are an amazing woman for trying so, but realizing you can't help him should show you how much you have tried and that it's not your fault he couldn't overcome his identity crisis.</s>
        <s>For now on you should focus on yourself.</s>
      </u>
      <u who="A">
        <s>I don't know what I would do without you, <ref target="a11lk2_1" type="character">Maya</ref>.</s>
        <s>I love you, thanks for the wise advice!</s>
      </u>
      <u who="B">
        <s>Of course.</s>
      </u>
      <p>
        <stage>hugs and kisses</stage>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
