<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>a11l25_t4</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211122</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11lk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>my name is Jane and I am a sixteen year old student of the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name> and I was asked to answer your question, whether a school without racism can really exist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I found an article about the label <name type="misc">School without racism/school with courage</name> on the internet and I think that it provides enough information to answer your question.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all it needs to be clear that it is impossible for a school to exist without racism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Racism and other discrimination are deeply rooted in our society and impossible to <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> eliminate.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But schools can still try to spread awareness about it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore, those schools also do not deny that racism <choice><orig>exist</orig><reg>exists</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They talk about it in class because the sooner children learn that racist <choice><orig>assumpions</orig><reg>assumptions</reg></choice> or behaviours is wrong, the more unlikely it is for them to develop those.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Still, there are a few teachers who have prejudices as well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I personally have not experienced any racism at all at the <name type="misc"><choice><abbr>School A</abbr><expan>School A</expan></choice></name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We talk about it in many different classes and I have not heard anyone of my classmates say something racist and if they did, I think it would have serious consequences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Overall, racism is always present, even at school and just because a school is <choice><orig>labled</orig><reg>labeled</reg></choice> <name type="misc">school without racism/school with courage</name> it is not <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> racism-free, but they are trying to be.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hoped this was <choice><orig>helpfull</orig><reg>helpful</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I am looking <choice><orig>foreward</orig><reg>forward</reg></choice> to meeting you in person!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
