<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>c12g48_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211123</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>At least it is an opportunity to comment on the fact that <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> work are believed to be still relevant today.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The story of <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> deals with the power of the influence from others and also the play <name type="misc"><choice><orig>Romio and Julliet</orig><reg>Romeo and Juliet</reg></choice></name> written by <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="author"><choice><orig>Shakespear</orig><reg>Shakespeare</reg></choice></ref> shows a conflict because of the influence of opinions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> works are still relevant themes today because the people around you often decide how you decide or act.</s>
        <s>If the witches would not have told <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref> about the prophecies of him becoming king he probably would not have killed so many people.</s>
        <s>He thought it is important to follow his <choice><orig>prophercie</orig><reg>prophecy</reg></choice> and do anything in his force to make it come true.</s>
        <s>He focused too much about what others told him than to think and adore the things he already has in life.</s>
        <s>It also is about not trusting people in everything they say.</s>
        <s>Of course there is always a way to make <choice><orig>prophercies</orig><reg>prophecies</reg></choice> true but trust on your own <choice><orig>intuiten</orig><reg>intuition</reg></choice> and do not let others influence on a bad way, just like <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Lady Macbeth</ref> did to <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="character">Macbeth</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also today many children are doing what their parents told them to do.</s>
        <s>They think it is the only right opportunity to strive after to the goal of their parents but actually there is more than one way to find <choice><orig>hapiness</orig><reg>happiness</reg></choice> either it is in your work or in family or love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The greeve behavior for power is also an important aspect <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare</ref> mentions in his plays.</s>
        <s>In <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="title">Macbeth</ref> and in <name type="misc"><choice><orig>Romeo and Julliet</orig><reg>Romeo and Juliet</reg></choice></name> people change because of money power or love.</s>
        <s>If we look on it today it has not really changed.</s>
        <s>The intentions of <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> plays are also very discussed themes in <choice><orig>todays</orig><reg>today's</reg></choice> world and people should still learn about them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To sum up I would say <ref target="c12gk3_1" type="person">Shakespeare's</ref> works are still relevant today, <choice><orig>allthough</orig><reg>although</reg></choice> the language is hard to understand and maybe the content is not <choice><orig>everyones</orig><reg>everyone's</reg></choice> favorite but all in all it deals with important statements which people should know and learn about.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
