<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g56_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is being analyzed by how he is presented and which stylistic devices are being used to present his relationship with his girlfriend <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the first shot <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> walks down the hallway in slow motion and greeting all his friends.</s>
        <s>The slow motion is being used to watch <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris'</ref> <choice><orig>apperiance</orig><reg>appearance</reg></choice> and behaviour.</s>
        <s>In this way, he is being watched by the audience through <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> eyes, because she watches him with dreamy eyes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the voiceover <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is talking about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> using nice words and describing him in a soft and dreamy voice.</s>
        <s>Because of the camera moving backwards it seems like <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is coming towards the camera or the audience.</s>
        <s>The director also presents him in a medium close up, because it is the first the audience gets to see <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> and like this they can make themselves a quick, but effective, impression of <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Besides the voiceover of <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>, soft and calm music plays in the background, which matches <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> raving about <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>While <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> puts his headphones on <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> head, the audience might think that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> knows what <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> likes and that he treats her well.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But when they both start talking about their conflict, the audience experiences the truth.</s>
        <s>Their conversation is presented in a close up, which makes it easier to understand or watch emotions, facial expressions and gestures.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The camera switches during the conversation to the one <choice><orig>whos</orig><reg>who's</reg></choice> talking, which again makes it easier to watch their emotions.</s>
        <s>For example, while <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> talks the camera switches to his face and the audience can see that he takes this conversation serious.</s>
        <s>During that, the camera switches only for a few seconds to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and the audience can see her face.</s>
        <s>Because <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looking away in that moment, it seems like she's not interested in <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> trying to say sorry.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> also tries to fix what he has done by playing the beat for <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and dancing to it in the hallway in front of the other students.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His dancing is presented in a medium close up to show his movements.</s>
        <s>He practically succeeded, because it makes <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> laugh and chuckle about it.</s>
        <s>This also shows that <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> really put effort in his acting to make <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> happy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> have a healthy relationship, although the argue some time.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> tries his best to fix all the problems he made to make his girlfriend feel better.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
