<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g54_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk5</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> seems to be a popular student at <name type="misc">Williamson</name>, because nearly everyone he walks past looks at him.</s>
        <s>He gives handshakes to everybody on his right.</s>
        <s>In the first part of the scene, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> is filmed from a medium shot perspective and a lower angle.</s>
        <s>This makes him look big and attractive.</s>
        <s>In the second important shot, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> is shown from a medium close up perspective on eye level.</s>
        <s>The camera slowly comes closer to her.</s>
        <s>Her attention is on <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris's</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> shoes <add>(<name type="misc">Jordans</name>)</add>, which are shown in the next shot from a medium close up perspective and a higher angle to turn the focus on them.</s>
        <s>The next important shot is the big close up when <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> turns her back to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is important to show how <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> mimics are at beginning and after <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> had put on his headphones on her head.</s>
        <s>With this shot size you can clearly see how <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> mimics change from serious to amused and back to serious.</s>
        <s>The next shot is a medium long shot, it shows how <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> gives <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> back his headphones.</s>
        <s>Then the conversation begins.</s>
        <s>The camera starts to switch from <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> to <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Chris's</orig><reg>Chris'</reg></choice></ref> face and back again.</s>
        <s>Both faces are shown in a close up, which should show their mimics and feelings during the conversation.</s>
        <s>After the conversation, <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> starts to dance in a medium shot again.</s>
        <s>With this shot the focus is on his hand movements synchronized to the music.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks at him from a close up perspective and you can clearly see her laughing face.</s>
        <s>You can see the difference between her seriously face some minutes ago.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all the shot sizes describe how <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Chris</ref> repairs the a bit broken relationship with <ref target="b10gk5_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
