<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g24_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The topic she's writing about is a very serious topic and it's already been there since many years and it still is.</s>
        <s>Everyone knows about it so she writes actually objective.</s>
        <s>She writes to the people out there to give them a better view in the topic, what it actually causes.</s>
        <s>Since a long time the topic <choice><orig>Enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> pollution is on the news and you can find it all over the internet.</s>
        <s>She starts with giving her opinion already in her introduction, so you already know, how the following text is <choice><orig>gonna</orig><reg>going to</reg></choice> be.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all she's writing very dramatic, which leads me to the first communicative technique.</s>
        <s>She uses <choice><orig>Appeals</orig><reg>appeals</reg></choice>, what shows that the topic is real serious for example in line 2 or 15.</s>
        <s>She is trying to involve the reader with inclusive pronouns, like <quote>we</quote> or <quote>us</quote>, with what she <choice><orig>try's</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to give the reader a better look into the topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She using evidence by bring up a few, but very strong arguments, like the industrial <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> tragedy occured at <name type="geo">Bhopal</name>, and the cause in <name type="geo">Hiroshima</name> in <date>1945</date>.</s>
        <s>In line 7 she uses an enumeration to increase all the causes.</s>
        <s>There are big repetitions in it, the main point that <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> pollution is a big trouble for the earth.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>What <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> can say is that, the most things she uses and is the most <quote>powerful</quote> point are the appeals and the <choice><orig>enumaration</orig><reg>enumeration</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It is the weight of the opinion.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
