<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a10g21_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211209</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In following I am going to analyse the text <ref target="a10gk3_1" type="title">Globalised Environmental Pollution - Causes and Effects</ref> to stylistic devices and communicative strategies.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first paragraph <ref target="a10gk3_1" type="author">Ankita Mitra</ref> <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to invite the readers to the topic and the main problem <quote>Environmental Pollution</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the second paragraph the author tells the <choice><orig>readars</orig><reg>readers</reg></choice> what the main reasons are why we are able to live on the earth - water and air.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>By directly using <quote>we</quote> in line four, the <choice><orig>readars</orig><reg>readers</reg></choice> get involved and start thinking more about the topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that she directly <q><choice><orig>shoks</orig><reg>shocks</reg></choice></q> us with the words <quote>the earth would be like the other planets - no man, no animals, no plants</quote> we feel a little bit <q>stressed</q> and feel even more <choice><orig>conected</orig><reg>connected</reg></choice> to the topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the third paragraph she tells us the first time that <quote>we are a problem</quote>.</s>
        <s>You can connect the fast urbanization and the fast grown industrialization with the problems of the <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fourth paragraph <choice><orig>get</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> directly started with the bad habitates of <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> pollution.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She directly speaks to the <choice><orig>readars</orig><reg>readers</reg></choice> through the often use of <quote>human</quote> or <quote>humans health</quote>.</s>
        <s>By the short enumeration in line 15 we get involved by directly getting told be risked.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She also uses the <choice><orig>pronounce</orig><reg>pronoun</reg></choice> <quote>our</quote> and us which involves us directly again.</s>
        <s>In line 19 we are getting indirectly told to be a problem of <choice><orig>enviromental</orig><reg>environmental</reg></choice> <choice><orig>polution</orig><reg>pollution</reg></choice> because of the <quote>achievements and industrial civilization</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We are not able to see that we are maybe just running into a <quote>blind alleys</quote> <ref target="a10gk3_1" type="line">(line 20)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the fifth paragraph she tells us that already some people are protesting against bad things we produce.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 26 she directly talks to our bad habits: <quote>using automobiles</quote> the <choice><orig>hug</orig><reg>huge</reg></choice> traffic and the <quote>use of synthetic detergents</quote>.</s>
        <s>In line 28 and 29 she underlines the problem by telling us how bad our <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> got.</s>
        <s><quote>We are drinking contaminated water</quote> and our vegetables are also full of <choice><orig>poission</orig><reg>poison</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Through <choice><orig>this</orig><reg>these</reg></choice> facts our world has a lot of diseases.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 30 she is involving us again directly by saying <quote>we are living in an era of mass extinction</quote>.</s>
        <s>The following words <quote>due to human made environmental pollution</quote> we are getting <choice><orig>shoked</orig><reg>shocked</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She makes us clear that we need to change something now if <quote>we want to live</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The sixth paragraph underlines the words of the fifth paragraph by telling us, that our world could be like the worst industrial <choice><orig>enviroment</orig><reg>environment</reg></choice> tragedy in the year <date>1984</date>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that she <choice><orig>incloudes</orig><reg>includes</reg></choice> the number of <choice><orig>death</orig><reg>dead</reg></choice> people in line 35 she makes us <choice><orig>realy</orig><reg>really</reg></choice> <choice><orig>belive</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> how bad is our earth in the moment and how worse it can get.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the last paragraph she scares us again <choice><orig>throug</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> the words <quote>that vrey soon our world would be uninhabitable like Hiroshima 1945</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last sentence <quote>If we fail to restore the ecological balance right now, it would be too late tomorrow</quote> we <choice><orig>completly</orig><reg>completely</reg></choice> understood how bad it is getting if we won't do anything.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
