<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c11g18_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211220</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Following I am going to analyze the dialogue between <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>, considering their dreams compared to the ones of the other family members.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>From the beginning it is very clear that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> do not listen to each other.</s>
        <s>Considering that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> <quote>ignores her</quote> wife <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> states that she already know what his husband was thinking about in the bathroom <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 2)</ref> it becomes clear that they are both tired of each other and their different interests.</s>
        <s>And so does <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> <choice><orig>explains</orig><reg>explain</reg></choice> in lines 11 to 14.</s>
        <s>You get to know that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> is <quote>tired of everything</quote>.</s>
        <s>About the family and the living conditions.</s>
        <s>He calls their home a <quote>beat-up hole</quote> which is a sign that he <choice><orig>als</orig><reg>also</reg></choice> do not like their way of life either.</s>
        <s>Though he has different dreams compared to his family members.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He wants to open a liquor store because he is annoyed of his work with the white people and wants to become <choice><orig>independant</orig><reg>independent</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Also <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Beneatha</ref> has got more future considering dreams.</s>
        <s>She wants to become a doctor and therefore needs the money for her education.</s>
        <s>But she also says that the money belongs to <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> and it is up to her what is done with it.</s>
        <s>Though that does not stop her fighting for her dream.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The rest of the family members want to invest in a house with better living conditions, so that they have more windows, their own rooms and a garden for <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So you can see that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter's</ref> dream is in great contrast to the other dreams and that is why he feels lonely, insecured and also betrayed especially from his mom and his wife, as she asks <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>: <quote>You couldn't be on my side that long, for nothing could you</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>And also he thinks that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> <choice><orig>listenes</orig><reg>listens</reg></choice> to <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> more than to him <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 18f.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In addition it seems that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> only focuses on his own dreams.</s>
        <s>He doesn't <choice><orig>considers</orig><reg>consider</reg></choice> the other family members in his actions since he needs all the ten thousand dollars for his investment in the liquor store <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 28)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he does not care about his wife a lot.</s>
        <s>He explains: <quote>A man needs for a woman to back him up...</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref> although <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> asks him to leave her alone.</s>
        <s>This shows that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> is not interested in his wife's interests but his own.</s>
        <s>But also from <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth's</ref> side there is no much acception as <quote>she doesn't look up</quote> at him when <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> speaks and <quote>doesn't answer</quote> to his questions <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 12)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all you can say that there is a conflict between them and their marriage of eleven years.</s>
        <s>They both do not listen to each other's problems or interests.</s>
        <s>That is the reason why they feel betrayed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You can add that there seems no solution in sight.</s>
        <s>In the beginning of the dialogue <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>, at least considers what <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> tells her but in the end she just says: <quote><qs>Walter, leave me alone!</qs><qs>Eat your eggs, the gonna be cold</qs></quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> seems annoyed about her behaviour and makes fun of her statement while exaggerating it with his <choice><orig>immaginated</orig><reg>imaginated</reg></choice> dialogue: <quote>Man say: I got to change my life, I'm choking to death, baby! And his woman say: [...] Your eggs is getting cold!</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(ll. 37-38)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another striking aspect is the fact that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> tells him after this exaggeration that it wasn't none of his money <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 39)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He replaces the word <quote>business</quote> which is normally used in this case, with the word <quote>money</quote> which clarifies how important money has become to <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> but also the other family members.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Money plays the central role through the whole play.</s>
        <s>And even if some family members like <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> or <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Beneatha</ref> do not consider it as that important they all talk about it a lot because it is essential for realizing their dreams.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Although <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> seems to just focus on his own dreams, he also cares about his family at least his son <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Travis</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the end he says <quote>very, very quietly</quote> that <quote>all [he] got to give [his son] is stories about how rich white people live</quote> <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(l. 42f.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through this sentence you can see that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> does care about his family and he does want better living conditions too, but he wants to realize it with an investment in a liquor store.</s>
        <s>But he also does not seem to listen to the advices of her family and his wife <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>, who <choice><orig>consider</orig><reg>considers</reg></choice> the liquor store as a bad idea <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 4, l. 26, l. 31)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Concluding you can say, that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> is not so sure about what he wants yet.</s>
        <s>He may seem at first sight because he plans and justifies his dream of having a liquor store but after analyzing this extract of the scene it is clear that <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter Lee</ref> is just in process of finding himself.</s>
        <s>He is questioning about his human being as he searches support from his wife and the other family members.</s>
        <s>The bathroom <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 1)</ref> and the mirror <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="line">(cf. l. 40)</ref> can be seen as a symbol of his search for identity.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
