<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c11g18_t1</author>
        <name>outline</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211220</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary recount">outline</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="title">A Raisin in the Sun</ref> from <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="author">Lorraine Hansberry</ref> is a play which takes place in <name type="geo">Chicago's</name> Southside during the time between <name type="misc">World War II</name> and the present.</s>
        <s>It is about a black family living in <name type="geo">America</name> in a little house with just one window and where they share a bathroom with their neighbours and as a five-headed family have to live in two droom with kitchen and living room.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Their dad or <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama's</ref> husband has died and the family is waiting for a check of 10000$ to arrive.</s>
        <s>They all have their individual dreams about what to do with the money and during the play there are a lot of conversations between the family members where becomes clear which dreams they have and how they want them to realize.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through that you find a lot of contrasts between the family <choice><orig>members</orig><reg>members'</reg></choice> dreams and so do you in the scene I will analyze in the following tasks.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The extract of the scene shows a conversation between <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter Lee</ref> and her wife <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> was coming out of the bathroom and wants to tell <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> about what he thought about, about what he wanted to do with the money from his dad, which is opening a liquor store together with his friends <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Willy</ref> and <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Bobo</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As you know from former conversations, <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> works as a chauffeur where he has to open white people the doors and drive them where they want to go.</s>
        <s>He is clear about that he does not like his job.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As he talks to his wife he realizes that she does not listen to him and explains that she is sick about their family and their living conditions.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He goes on with showing to <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> how much <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Mama</ref> listens to her, more as he does to him although she is just her mother-in-law.</s>
        <s>Even though <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> wants to be left alone, <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Walter</ref> justifies his dream.</s>
        <s>He says that it is reliable because he has figured it out with his friends and explains why he has to invest in this store.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally <ref target="c11gk3_1" type="character">Ruth</ref> gives up to prove his husband wrong about and just wants him to eat his eggs.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
