<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g29_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The director presents the action in three parts: At first the peaceful atmosphere in the restaurant, then the discussion of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and at least the interaction of the police with <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and with the customers of the restaurant.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>peacefull</orig><reg>peaceful</reg></choice> atmosphere in the restaurant is supported by the very slow and friendly music.</s>
        <s>In that part of the scene are nearly just close ups on the faces of the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carter</ref> family used so the viewer gets to see the impressions of the family members which are happy and not fearful or angry because they are laughing and are praying to god.</s>
        <s>Most of the close <choice><orig>up's</orig><reg>ups</reg></choice> are filmed by the perspective of a family so the viewer gets to see what the family member see when they're looking at each other.</s>
        <s>This effect is supported by over the shoulder shots and point of view shots.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The next part of the action is <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Mavericks</orig><reg>Maverick's</reg></choice></ref> discussion with <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s>It's introduced by switching the music from the peaceful sounds to a dramatic beat when <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> looks out of the window and spots <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s>She gets the attention of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> who <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> out to talk with <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> is at first shown in a medium shot of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr's</ref> point of view in a low angle so the viewer <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> the feeling that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> is more powerful than <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> still goes to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> and isn't afraid of him because camera focus on <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and just for a few seconds it's on <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s>The moment the discussion escalated the music stops for <choice><orig>sometime</orig><reg>some time</reg></choice> and it's just <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Kings</orig><reg>King's</reg></choice></ref> body crushing in his car to hear.</s>
        <s>The camera switches shortly to a police car after <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> attacked by one of the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> Lord to <choice><orig>introdue</orig><reg>introduce</reg></choice> the following sequence.</s>
        <s><ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Kings</orig><reg>King's</reg></choice></ref> car is leaving which you get to see in an establishing shot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The two officers are at first shown in a two shot from <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Mavericks</orig><reg>Maverick's</reg></choice></ref> point of view so it's shown because of which person the police has shown up.</s>
        <s>You can see the red-blue lights of the police car blink over the whole sequence which supports the shown hectic action.</s>
        <s>The moment <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> gets arrested is shown from a low angle and behind the two officer which supports the power of the two officers.</s>
        <s>At a very important part of the scene the beat stops and the viewer just can hear how the police pushes <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> to the window.</s>
        <s>The whole <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carter</ref> family goes to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> and give the officer <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Mavericks</orig><reg>Maverick's</reg></choice></ref> <choice><abbr>ID</abbr><expan>identification</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>A close up on <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Lisa's</ref> face shows how angry she is and that she really would like to attack the police.</s>
        <s>The officers always have a hand on their weapon which is shown by a close up on their hands to support the fear of the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carters</ref> and to show how powerful the officers are because they could just shoot <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> like <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">115</ref> shot <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To answer the main question how the director presents the action in the shown sequence, you can say that he supported always the feelings of the characters with close <choice><orig>up's</orig><reg>ups</reg></choice> on their faces but also the music <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> more dramatic over time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
