<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b10g26_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211221</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="105min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The given sequence has many purposes.</s>
        <s>In my opinion there are three main purposes.</s>
        <s>First is showing the <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carter</ref> family in different kinds of situations.</s>
        <s>The second is <choice><orig>showin</orig><reg>showing</reg></choice> <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> as an enemy.</s>
        <s>Lastly the third is presenting the police not as an ally but as a foe yet again.</s>
        <s>These three purposes make up most of the action in the sequence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To create a happy <choice><orig>Atmosphere</orig><reg>atmosphere</reg></choice> when the family was eating the director used many devices.</s>
        <s>First off is the music.</s>
        <s>The song that plays is a relaxing one.</s>
        <s>Furthermore the noises of people chattering in the background, <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> family eating and laughing creates a typical dining atmosphere.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They also prayed before eating which makes the viewer think that nothing bad can happen now.</s>
        <s>The camera made close up shots from everyone in front of them in the family and everyone smiled which adds to the good atmosphere.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The good atmosphere ended when the camera zoomed in on <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref> in focus standing outside the store in the dark with a few gang members.</s>
        <s>One can say that they are well built and strong, which makes the entrance even more dangerous.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The music changed to an intimidating one and the facial expression of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> <choice><orig>immedeatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice> changed to a serious one when they saw <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">King</ref>.</s>
        <s>These devices create a scary and intimidating atmosphere.</s>
        <s>The device which is the most important is that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref>, who was cheerful seconds ago, said in a serious voice and face to stay in the store.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The police moved to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> quickly and didn't let him explain.</s>
        <s>The camera also moved quick to <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Maverick</ref> to underline the action.</s>
        <s>The police man who took action against <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Carter</ref> first was a black police man.</s>
        <s>This shows the viewer that all of the police is corrupted in this movie.</s>
        <s>Their facial expressions went into a shocked state when they knew <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> was the witness.</s>
        <s>This shows the viewer that they are worry of <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> and <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Starr</ref> managed to overcome the situation where <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character">Khalil</ref> died without deaths this time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The director shows the viewer that <ref target="b10gk3_1" type="character"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></ref> family has a strong bond.</s>
        <s>They fight together and laugh together.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
