<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g20_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211006</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following it will be analyzed how <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> tries to convince his audience that <quote>dreams are worth fighting for</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 25f.)</ref> by examining rhetorical devices.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> tries to right in the beginning of his speech to catch the <choice><orig>listeners</orig><reg>listeners'</reg></choice> attention with the enumeration <quote>more separated by geography and ideology; race and religion; wealth and opportunity</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 5f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He says these words to underline the following paragraph, because there he says that when he <quote><choice><orig>traveled</orig><reg>travelled</reg></choice> around <name type="geo">Iowa</name> and the rest of the country</quote> he <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> not been struck by their differences but have been impressed by the values and hopes that they share <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 7ff.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> the effect that the listener now <choice><orig>see</orig><reg>sees</reg></choice> that many persons in <name type="geo">America</name> <choice><orig>wants</orig><reg>want</reg></choice> to live the American Dream and that it may not be like they thought before.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After that he uses an enumeration again: <quote>In big cities and small towns; among men and women; young and old, black, white, and brown</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 9f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> wants the listener to understand his point of view and wants to show how same they all are.</s>
        <s>He also underlines his words from the first paragraphs and <choice><orig>let</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> the listener build a graphic mental image, where everyone in <name type="geo">America</name> lives together in peace and harmony.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third important rhetorical device is the anaphora: <quote>These are dreams that drove my...</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13; l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The speaker uses these words to show the listener that there were also people before them who wanted the American Dream come true and that they now need to still work on it.</s>
        <s>This anaphora <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> the effect that the listener feels more connected to the speaker.</s>
        <s>Additionally you can say that <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> also uses this rhetorical device to underline his opinion that the <quote>dreams are worth fighting for</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 25f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Furthermore his last words <quote>And I knew dreams are worth fighting for</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 25f.)</ref> were build up by the called anaphora, so <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> connected the impact of the speech and <choice><orig>build</orig><reg>builds</reg></choice> a bridge to his last words.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Lastly <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="author">Obama</ref> uses the anaphora/repetition: <quote>no matter what color you are, no matter where you are from, no matter how much money you have</quote> <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 19f.)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He claims these words in context with his mother to show the listener that there is a <choice><orig>chane</orig><reg>chance</reg></choice> that everyone can achieve the American Dream just if they are willing to try.</s>
        <s>As listener you now maybe believe more in the <choice><orig>chane</orig><reg>chance</reg></choice> of achieving the American Dream and are more motivated to try to claim the barriers to success.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Taking all these analytical aspects into account, one <choice><orig>have</orig><reg>has</reg></choice> to aim that <ref target="a11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> <choice><orig>convince</orig><reg>convinces</reg></choice> the listener pretty well by using rhetorical devices.</s>
        <s>He connects and <choice><orig>structurs</orig><reg>structures</reg></choice> his speech good, so the listener could get a good graphic mental image of the American Dream and the listener is also more open to try to work harder on it.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
