<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g04_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Many <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> people speak only English.</s>
        <s>During the last years people start to overthink that.</s>
        <s>In connection to this topic <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> wrote an article, where he says that the <name type="geo">UK</name> has a problem.</s>
        <s>But is it a real problem that they speak only English?</s>
        <s>At least English is the world language.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> the author mentioned convincing arguments and examples.</s>
        <s>But I do not agree with him totally.</s>
        <s>Because of the globalisation English becomes more and more important.</s>
        <s>The huge majority learns English at school, at least in the industry countries.</s>
        <s>So English at school, at least in the industry countries.</s>
        <s>So English is the language that everybody has to speak and learn.</s>
        <s>It is the <choice><orig>word</orig><reg>world</reg></choice> language.</s>
        <s>And of course it is an advantage to be a native speaker.</s>
        <s>Furthermore it is also an advantage to speak more than just one language.</s>
        <s>In the industry people, who speak many languages are more in demand than other people.</s>
        <s>So it would be good for <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> human to speak more languages than just English.</s>
        <s>But they have also an advantage, because they are native speaker.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of the globalisation new fast-growing markets exist all over the world and it would be desirable to communicate with people, who live in growing markets and cannot speak English.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> describes also counter-arguments.</s>
        <s>For instance your phone can translate for you.</s>
        <s>He replies that you need roaming data for that.</s>
        <s>I think that this is a very bad and weak answer.</s>
        <s>Yes, you can translate with your phone.</s>
        <s>But do you want that?</s>
        <s>You say something into your phone and your opposite do that too.</s>
        <s>In my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> direct communication is better than indirect communication with your phone.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Now we come to the key sentence of <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref>.</s>
        <s>He thinks that language learning is vital for the<name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing.</s>
        <s>I cannot agree with him at every point.</s>
        <s>Language learning is important and has many advantages, that are mentioned before.</s>
        <s>But the risks are not that high.</s>
        <s>The <name type="geo">UK's</name> prosperity is not in danger.</s>
        <s>The <name type="geo">UK's</name> future is not in danger because of not learning languages.</s>
        <s>The Brexit is another topic.</s>
        <s>But for the global standing it would be desirable to learn foreign languages.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact, that the author does not name documentary evidence that the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future or prosperity is <choice><orig>endanger</orig><reg>endangered</reg></choice> is quite noticeable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Finally you can say that the author names striking and convincing arguments.</s>
        <s>Furthermore he uses cleverly examples.</s>
        <s>But on the key sentence he writes to dramatic in my <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless the article deals with a topic, that many people never heard before.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
