<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a12g03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> uses a big variation of communicative strategies and stylistic devices in his artucle to convince the reader.</s>
        <s>Even in the headline you can find a list, which is repeated in the first line <quote>can't, won't, don't</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The author uses this three words to quickly summarise his impression of the <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> view for learning foreign languages.</s>
        <s>These words right at the beginning of a article let the reader know what the text is about and which issue it's going to face.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We can see, that the author is not happy about this circumstance in line 12-15 at the latest.</s>
        <s>He says <quote>Everyone speaks English in the world of <choice><orig>buisness</orig><reg>business</reg></choice> (they don't)</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 12-13)</ref>, <quote>your iPhone will now translate road signs for you (but you may crash or choke on the roaming data charges)</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 13-14)</ref> and <quote>the next generation of wearable tech will enable intercultural telepathy anyway</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 14-15)</ref>.</s>
        <s>What we have here is a list of arguments that try to justify the decreasing number of students learning foreign languages.</s>
        <s>The author gives counter arguments for the first two.</s>
        <s>The last argument, which isn't <choice><orig>realy</orig><reg>really</reg></choice> a argument but more a ironic comment in the sense of these arguments, is just nonsense in the <choice><orig>authors</orig><reg>author's</reg></choice> eyes.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But like I said, after this list of arguments and counter arguments we know the <choice><orig>authors</orig><reg>author's</reg></choice> opinion on this topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In <choice><orig>generell</orig><reg>general</reg></choice> you can find a lot of statistics and use of numers in this article.</s>
        <s>For example <quote>more than 10.000 fewer language <name type="misc">A-level</name> exams than at the end of the <date>1990s</date></quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 9)</ref> or <quote>the most recent <name type="misc">CBI/Pearson Education and Skills Survey</name> showed almost two-thirds of <name type="geo">UK</name> <choice><orig>buisnesses</orig><reg>businesses</reg></choice> need foreign language skills</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 19-20)</ref> and much more.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>These statistics show the reader, that the issue of decreasing language knowledge is real an not exaggerated.</s>
        <s>At the end of his article in line 32, <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> speaks directly to the <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> parents.</s>
        <s>That brings his arguments to a more personal level and increases the chance, that the reader feels <choice><orig>adressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> and tries to change something.</s>
        <s>At the very end he uses a metaphor <quote>strings to out childrens bows</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(l. 34)</ref> to underline the importance of this topic a last time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
