<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g08_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>Another claim of <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> is that <q>language learning is whatever the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing</q>.</s>
        <s>First of all I don't agree with his examples given on problems English speakers without foreign language skills have abroad <ref target="a12gk1_1">(cf. ll. 13ff.)</ref> as they are very rare scenarios on are not of interest in the context of global economy.</s>
        <s>But apart from that I agree with <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> that language skills are <choice><orig>defenitely</orig><reg>definitely</reg></choice> needed in a globalised world for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> economy.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne</ref> proves that with the fact that <quote>almost two-thirds of <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses need foreign language skills</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1">(ll. 19f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Like it is important for countries around the world to learn English to enter the global market and adapt to Western developments it is for the British to have foreign language speaking abilities so they can gain knowledge about the rising markets in for example Brasil, India or China where adaptation to the local needs and proferations is needed.</s>
        <s>Because the <name type="geo">UK</name> can't just rely on the others to adapt to them in order for them to maintain a primary position in the global standing.</s>
        <s>And also prosperity can gained by the access to foreign markets.</s>
        <s>So considering <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">als</gap> points I would agree to <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> statement and see a great opportunity in foreign language skills for Brits that I believe that new progress by offerings of universities is a good development.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
