<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a12g10_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211130</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a12gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>After that I will comment on <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">Worne's</ref> claim that <q>language learning is vital for the <name type="geo">UK's</name> future prosperity and global standing</q>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>in my opinion this statement is absolutely true, because it is very important to learn languages.</s>
        <s>Without languages <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">tlue</gap> are no communication.</s>
        <s>Not only this, moreover it is very important for trades, prosperity, cultural exports, diplomacy and national security <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 17-18)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Our society grows up and it is difficult to have a good job and make a lot of money, because more people, less jobs.</s>
        <s>Today it is not enough to be a <quote>pure lawyer</quote> for example <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 28-29)</ref>.</s>
        <s>You have to be more, a lawyer with Chinese language skills for example.</s>
        <s>It is not enough to be great, or to be the best of your class, because on the world global market you are on a bad number of positions.</s>
        <s>The world markets <choice><orig>grows</orig><reg>grow</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>grows</orig><reg>grow</reg></choice> and the request will be bigger and bigger.</s>
        <s><ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref> also says <quote>almost two-thirds of <name type="geo">UK</name> businesses need foreign language skills</quote> <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="line">(ll. 19-20)</ref>.</s>
        <s>That's 75 percent and that is a lot.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>the international work together raise too and that's why international and foreign language skills are so important to be successful.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>if we don't have enough people who <choice><orig>has</orig><reg>have</reg></choice> foreign language skills, the global standing will decline.</s>
        <s>And nobody wants that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>not all have our luck and possibilities to get educated in our way.</s>
        <s>With smartphones and laptops you can learn from everywhere with internet.</s>
        <s>So if you can learn you have to catch this chance and have to learn as much you can.</s>
        <s>It is important for you and for all of us.</s>
        <s>So, all in all <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> completely agree with the statement of <ref target="a12gk1_1" type="author">John Worne</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
