<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g42_t2</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <head>
        <p>
          <s>Better hopes for the future?</s>
        </p>
      </head>
      <p>
        <s>Recently there were different immigrants in a panel discussion on <choice><abbr>TV</abbr><expan>television</expan></choice>, where they describe their immigration experiences in a speech.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Among them immigrants there is a 41 years old engineer named <name type="person">Faraj al-Byarshan</name> who immigrated to <name type="geo">New York</name> from <name type="geo">Iraq</name> in year <date>2005</date>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Faraj</name> has a wife and two sons who followed his road in year <date>2007</date>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Faraj al-Byarshan's</name> reasons for immigration refer to his were positive and negative immigration experiences and his hopes for the future.</s>
        <s>In the following I will comment on <name type="person">Faraj al-Byarshan's</name> reasons for immigration.</s>
        <s>First of all how does he <choice><orig>knows</orig><reg>know</reg></choice> that he'll get better hopes for his future in <name type="geo">New York</name> than in his home country which is <name type="geo">Iraq</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Faraj's</name> circumstances are so bad, that he risks it all.</s>
        <s>Probably his thoughts were, that since there is no war in <name type="geo">New York</name> everything would be better than <name type="geo">Iraq</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Since they came from <name type="geo">Iraq</name>, there weren't racism on them.</s>
        <s>Is racism so harmful for him?</s>
        <s>We know a lot of newspaper where people from other ethnic groups get shot, does he really <choice><orig>wants</orig><reg>want</reg></choice> to take this risk?</s>
        <s>The racism is probably way more harmfuller for him, <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> living in anxiety.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another reason for his immigration would be to get a better education for his children and better jobs for his wife and him.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Faraj</name> doesn't just <choice><orig>thinks</orig><reg>think</reg></choice> about him, his family is very important for him, he wants to give them and himself the <choice><orig>succes</orig><reg>success</reg></choice> they deserve.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
