<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3c</title>
        <author>c10g37_t3</author>
        <name>speech</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211216</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="2"</note>
        <note genre="NA" genre_family="NA">speech</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk3</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>My name is <name type="person">Faraj al-Byarshan</name> and I am 41 years old.</s>
        <s>I think <choice><orig>Migration</orig><reg>migration</reg></choice> is important and people should tell more about <choice><orig>there</orig><reg>their</reg></choice> <choice><orig>storys</orig><reg>stories</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>So I tell my story.</s>
        <s>I am an engineer who immigrated to <name type="geo">New York</name> from <name type="geo">Iraq</name> in <date>2005</date>.</s>
        <s>I was searched for better living consituation for me and my family.</s>
        <s>But before I immigrated I heard that it is very hard to be <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> immigrate and <choice><orig>beginn</orig><reg>begin</reg></choice> <choice><orig>everthing</orig><reg>everything</reg></choice> from the start because people look at you when you have <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> other skin colour than they have or when you in the city and speak with your kids on <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> other language than they do.</s>
        <s>And then they make prejudice.</s>
        <s>I didn't wanted that my both sons have a such situation.</s>
        <s>So I immigrate alone first and <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> when I had a home or a safe life there my both sons and my wife followed me in <date>2007</date>.</s>
        <s>I took 2 years to have a safe life but after 2 years other people say I am <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> immigrant and they are speaking about us.</s>
        <s>I must fight against all prejudice to have a normal life.</s>
        <s>I learned the language and my both sons learned the <choice><orig>languge</orig><reg>language</reg></choice> too.</s>
        <s>I have find a good job and I also maked three friends.</s>
        <s>I know three friends are not many friends but they are true friends which stand back of me and help me everywhere they can.</s>
        <s>I am very happy about that.</s>
        <s>I have a lucky life which is a lot better than in <name type="geo">Iraq</name> because in my little town was hunger ethnic so we can't ate many food sometimes I didn't ate anything, because I wanted that my wife and my both sons have enough, all that they want to have!</s>
        <s>So that is why we immigrated I wanted to give my family more.</s>
        <s>And it was a very good decision!</s>
        <s>At beginning it was a hard time for all of us but now it's so how I wanted.</s>
        <s>So stand for it that you an immigrant and what all you do and don't be shy.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
