<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>c12l01_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear William Shakespeare,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all, let me thank you for creating this beautiful and meaningful poem.</s>
        <s>I am honoured to receive such an ornate sonnet.</s>
        <s>I really enjoyed reading it and I cannot stop to do so.</s>
        <s>I can feel how laborious you worked on creating it and that you put your heart and blood into it.</s>
        <s>The sonnet shows how capable you are in understanding and rebuilding human emotions while expressing them with expertise!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I like that you wrote about themes, that are timeless such as love, disbelief, sadness and so on.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>At some point, I had to get deep into my inner self and think about some aspects of love, which I never questioned.</s>
        <s>That is because the speaker asked so many rhetorical questions.</s>
        <s>I felt connected to the speaker and identified myself with their character.</s>
        <s>That shows how good you know about the human psyche, better than any <choice><orig>writter</orig><reg>writer</reg></choice> before and after you.</s>
        <s>Also your special way of connecting different emotions is unbelievable and <choice><orig>quiet</orig><reg>quite</reg></choice> interesting.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And there are many reasons for your <choice><orig>rellevance</orig><reg>relevance</reg></choice> still today!</s>
        <s>No man ever accomplished that has made words got into the dictionary and are in use today.</s>
        <s>But also your phrases that people use in our every day language, or fascinating.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Even if we do not know much about your private life we know exactly what kind of person you are based on the way you wrote those many sonnets.</s>
        <s>Great work, I say!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
