<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l13_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote>Since brass, not stone, nor earth, nor boundless sea / But sad mortality o'er-sways their power</quote><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 1-2)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The first lines of the first quatrain describe that no element of nature can survive the <quote>sad mortality</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The enumeration emphasizes that indeed nothing in nature has the ability to do so; not even the <quote>boundless sea</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref> which is often used as a symbol of freedom and peace.</s>
        <s>The truth of death, the <quote>sad mortality</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 2)</ref> is going to destroy their power <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(ref. l. 2)</ref>, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> is stating that neither nature nor humans can overcome time.</s>
        <s>It is so powerful and invincible that mortal things cannot keep up with it and will eventually suffer defeat from its hands.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>How this rage shall beauty hold a plea, / Whose action is no stronger than a flower?</quote><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 3-4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The writer is probably <choice><orig>reffering</orig><reg>referring</reg></choice> to the heyday of nature and humans: the most precious and beautiful time of <choice><orig>ones</orig><reg>one's</reg></choice> life is their youth.</s>
        <s>But it will eventually experience an end because time causes beauty fade, people to age and life end.</s>
        <s>Therefore the beauty of youth and life is not able to withstan the <quote>rage</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 3)</ref> of time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The writer is also drawing a comparison between life and a flower <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(ref. l. 4)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Life and humans are as fragile and delicate as a flower, unable to fight the unbeatable power of time.</s>
        <s>Just like a flower we will fade when our time has come.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The second quatrain also puts emphasis on the transitoriness of youth and life.</s>
        <s><quote>O, how shall summer's honey breath hold out / Against the wrackful siege of batt'ring days</quote><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The peak, the crown of <choice><orig>ones</orig><reg>one's</reg></choice> life, the youth is described through the metaphor <quote>summer's honey breath</quote>.</s>
        <s>This comares youth to a sweet summer breeze which is often realized as one of the most pleasant experiences, but unlike time, is something limited that eventually fades away.</s>
        <s>Summer ends and winter awaits.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This beautiful experience is taken away from us and we cannot do anything about it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>When rocks impregnable are not so stout, / Nor gates of steel so strong, but time decays?</quote><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Time is <quote>impregnable</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 7)</ref>, strong and impossible to defeat.</s>
        <s>No strength and pwer of this world can withstand time which will bring our death as the end of its natural cause <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(ref. l. 8)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The rhetorical question <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(ref. l. 7-8)</ref> stresses this exact phenomenon: Nothing can slow down or beat time, it will eventually overcome us.</s>
      </p>
      <p><s>The last quatrain personifies time.</s><quote><s>Shall time's best jewel from time's chest lie hid?</s><s> / Or what strong hand can hold his swift foot back?</s></quote><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 10-11)</ref>. <s>This stresses, once again, that time gifts us with its <quote>best jewel</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref> being the youth but only for limited time.</s><s>We cannot <quote>hold his swift foot back</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 11)</ref>.</s><s>The writer is hyperaware of the fact which he puts emphasis on it by incorporating several rhetorical questions in a row <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(ref. l. 10-12)</ref>.</s></p>
      <p>
        <s>The last two lines of the last quatrain also form an <choice><orig>Anaphora</orig><reg>anaphora</reg></choice> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(ref. l. 11-12)</ref>, laying great stress on time's transitory gift to human kind.</s>
        <s>Time spoils us with the gift of our precious youth.</s>
        <s>It is so precious and sweet that we want to taste and keep it forever, which is impossible.</s>
        <s>Time brutally takes it away from us and there is no escape, no antidote to it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><quote>O, none, unless this miracle have might, / That in black in my love may still shine bright</quote><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>As usual the couoplet resolves the established theme in the previous quatrains.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> makes use of the word <quote>miracle</quote> as a symbol with which he underlines the impossibility of defeating and withstanding love.</s>
        <s>A miracle does not follow the laws of nature and therefore remains some thing of rare possibility.</s>
        <s>Assuming that no miracle it will take place, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> expresses that art is able to overcome time.</s>
        <s>While youth, life and nature will one day come to an end, words and poems will be passed on until eternity.</s>
        <s>The writer engraves his feelings and his verses so that they can treasure his most precious thoughts.</s>
        <s>Art is the only thing that proves to withstand time, refusing to age.</s>
        <s>The sonnet can be read in a melodic way through <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> use of language <choice><abbr>f.e. </abbr><expan>for example</expan></choice> anaphoras, alliterations and word plays.</s>
        <s>Examples can be found in the following lines: <quote>nor stone, nor earth, nor boundless sea</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 1)</ref>, <quote>steel so strong</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>, <quote>shall summer's honey breath hold out</quote> <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this sonnet <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> describes the everlasting power of time in comparison to the fragility and limits of the humankind and nature.</s>
        <s>Our youth is as precious and sweet as a summer breathe: we never want to let go but there's no chance <choice><orig>no</orig><reg>not</reg></choice> to.</s>
        <s>While time gifts us with that precious time, before we know it, it is also taken away from <choice><orig>was</orig><reg>us</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Button art and versus our time on this earth shall live on forever.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Considering <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> other sonnets it is clear that one of his main themes was the passage of time and mortality of the human kind.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is also one those sonnets in which he emphasizes the inferiority of mortality in comparison to time.</s>
        <s>This dilemma is often portrayed as a dead end by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>.</s>
        <s>Humans want to enjoy the privilege of youth and life until forever.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>longig</orig><reg>longing</reg></choice> clashes with the concept of time which is why <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> declares humans as defeated.</s>
        <s>Art is the only way to let us love on forever.</s>
        <s>Words, verses and poems are able to achieve what we will never be able to: withstand time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Scholars suport the idea that <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> first 126 sonnets were dedicated to a young man called <name type="person">The Fair Youth</name>.</s>
        <s>This sonnet was much likely <choice><orig>adressed</orig><reg>addressed</reg></choice> to that young man.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
