<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l12_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In following, I am going to analyze the sonnet by taking a closer look at the languge and stylistic devices used in order to convey the message and intention of the sonnet.</s>
        <s>In the first line, you can find an enumeration.</s>
        <s>The repetition of the things that seem to be undestroyable emphasizes that everything transitory.</s>
        <s>The form of the ennumeration could also imitate the sonnet of a clock, which has the intention to show the matter of time to the reaer.</s>
        <s>In the second line, you can see the personification <quote>[...] mortality o'er-sways their power [...]</quote>.</s>
        <s>This personification intensifies the <choice><orig>messag</orig><reg>message</reg></choice> of the first line and shows that even things that seem undestroyable lose their power <choice><orig>througt</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> mortality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the next line is again a personification.</s>
        <s>In connection to the <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> and comparing in the next line, it convinces the reader from the transitoriness of beauty.</s>
        <s>In line 5 and 6 are two personifications and a <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice>: <quote>[...] how shall summer's honey breath hold out / Against the wrackful siege of batt'ring days [...]</quote>.</s>
        <s>It has the intention to make it clear and imaginable for the reader that summer <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> beat the time.</s>
        <s>In line ten, the <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice> <quote>[...] time's best jewel [...]</quote> should convince the reader that nothing can resist the effects of the time.</s>
        <s>In the last line is also a <choice><orig>metaphora</orig><reg>metaphor</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It emphasizes that writing is important for <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, even when nothing can beat the time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the context of <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> catalogue of sonnets, the sonnet <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is similar to other sonnets.</s>
        <s>Every sonnet has 14 lines where the first 12 lines can be <choice><orig>seperated</orig><reg>separated</reg></choice> in three verses of four where <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> gets into a question.</s>
        <s>The last couplet which <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> uses as a resolution is similar to other sonnets.</s>
        <s>The metre and the rhyme of the sonnet are the same in other sonnets in <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> catalogue.</s>
        <s>Also the theme of the sonnet is fitting in his catalogue.</s>
        <s>The most themes are love, death, time and beauty.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
