<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>c12l11_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>My Dear Shakespeare,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You are the love of my life and my soul!</s>
        <s>I <choice><orig>recieved</orig><reg>received</reg></choice> your sonnet you wrote about me and I'm absolutely thrilled but also sad and worried.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I have to see that you wrote the poem in such a beautiful way.</s>
        <s>I know that time is not in our best interest but I am fully convinced that I would love towards each other is stronger than any boundless sea!</s>
        <s>Time is cruel and it is a curse but my darling, the sun as you wrote me will never die and cannot be destroyed.</s>
        <s>It is immortalized on paper and time will not change that.</s>
        <s>I felt your honest emotions <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> believed every word.</s>
        <s>I will always remember you, not only due to our relation but also due to your art of writing.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref>, you are an extraordinary and revolutionary poet, playwright and businessman.</s>
        <s>The way you can describe what others feel is a talent not everyone has.</s>
        <s>You really understand the human soul and your themes are timeless.</s>
        <s>The way you create idioms and words is unbelievable.</s>
        <s>The audience and readers can relate to every topic you mention in your work.</s>
        <s>Believe me, you help people understand love and hate and jealousy and greed... We are so influenced by your work!</s>
        <s>You are timeless.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is very meaningful to me and describes all of my thoughts.</s>
        <s>Thank you.</s>
        <s>And remember, our mortality does not <choice><orig>effect</orig><reg>affect</reg></choice> our love because our love will never die!</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>With love, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
