<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c12l16_t1</author>
        <name>present</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">present</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> is a poem written by <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">William Shakespeare</ref> and about the question, what real love can stop.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The poem has the typical Shakespearean structure with <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> 14 lines and four stances, of which three have four verses.</s>
        <s>These stances are called <choice><orig>quartrains</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The last two lines are the final couplet.</s>
        <s>The iambic parameter is the metre, with <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice> typical heartbeat rhythm.</s>
        <s>The three <choice><orig>quartrains</orig><reg>quatrains</reg></choice> have a cross rhyme at the end of each vese, while the final couplet has a pair-rhyme.</s>
        <s>Every line has ten syllables.</s>
        <s>This turns our well through using <choice><orig>enjambements</orig><reg>enjambments</reg></choice> in the first two and in the fifth and sixth lines.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first <choice><orig>quartrain</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> describes the power of love, which is indestructible, except from the death.</s>
        <s>But this power is only in mind and does not take action in the real life.</s>
        <s>The second <choice><orig>quartrain</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> comprises the problem, that the time to take actions is getting less, even if it is an inner fight.</s>
        <s>In the last two lines of the third <choice><orig>quartrain</orig><reg>quatrain</reg></choice> the lyrical I asked what the <choice><orig>adressee</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> even holds back and what he needs to make his mind come true.</s>
        <s>The answer in the final couplet is, that he writes about his love and hopes that it will come true.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>After describing the structure and summing up the content, I am going to analyze the sonnet by taking a closer look at the language, the using of Stella sacrifices and the intention of the structure in the following.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
