<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a2</title>
        <author>c12l04_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Shakespeare,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I received your sonnet and I'm happy to be the <choice><orig>addresse</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all I have to say that for me it was hard to understand your words and the meaning of them.</s>
        <s>I hope I understood your intention.</s>
        <s>When I haven't please say so.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think do you want to express with your sonnet how time is passing by and we miss the good things while concentrating on the negative.</s>
        <s>I agree that people miss out the most important while worrying about negative times.</s>
        <s>That is something which has not changed during the 400 years between us.</s>
        <s>It shows me that you have the talent to look into people's souls and to express people's feelings best.</s>
        <s>Your knowledge about human feedings is impressive.</s>
        <s>You catch you every feeling precisely.</s>
        <s>Even though your time is over you still influence us today.</s>
        <s>Not only the words and phrases who invented which we still use also the fact that everyone can interpret your sonnets and play for themselves.</s>
        <s>That shows how big your understanding of the human soul really is and how right you are.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I got your intention right and if not I hope you understand what I want to say and maybe you can even agree with me even if it is not what you wanted to say.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The world would miss something without your plays and sonnets,</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Yours, John</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
