<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c12l16_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211119</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c12lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>With the iambic parameter, Shakespeare wants to underline the theme love, because the iambic parameter has the <choice><orig>rhytm</orig><reg>rhythm</reg></choice> of the heartbeat.</s>
        <s>Also conspicuous is that on every question mark follows a <quote>O</quote> or <quote>Or</quote>.</s>
        <s>This supports the feeling of misunderstanding, why the <choice><orig>adressee</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> does not take action in the real life.</s>
        <s>The repeating of <quote>O</quote> in the whole sonnet and the repeating of <quote>Or</quote> at the beginning of line 11 and 12 are also anaphoras.</s>
        <s>Also <choice><orig>conspicicuous</orig><reg>conspicuous</reg></choice> is that <choice><orig>excepting</orig><reg>except</reg></choice> from the last verse no dots are used.</s>
        <s>There are only question marks at the end of each sentence, which underlines, how doubtful it is that the <choice><orig>adressee</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> does not speak his love out.</s>
        <s>Only in the final couplet is a full dot and not question mark, because the final couplet is the answer on the many questions.</s>
        <s>With the many questions <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> influences the reader to ask himself things and overthink the whole poem.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The repitition <quote>nor stone, nor earth, nor boundless sea [...]</quote> in the first line, shows how strong his love is.</s>
        <s><quote>Boundless sea</quote> is also a metaphor.</s>
        <s>The question <quote>How [...] whose action is no stronger than a flower?</quote>, underlines that the <choice><orig>adressee</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> doesn't take action, because flowers are not strong.</s>
        <s>This is a big paradox, but a symbol at the same time, because flowers are a symbol of love.</s>
        <s>The repitition of <quote>time's</quote> in the 10.</s>
        <s>line supports the problem of the running time, because time is not endless.</s>
        <s>With using this repetition, <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare</ref> makes clear that the <choice><orig>adressee</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> must take actions until it is too late.</s>
        <s>The answer on that is the <choice><orig>paradoxon</orig><reg>paradox</reg></choice> <quote>[...] that in black ink my love may still shine bright</quote> in the last verse, because black ink cannot shine bright.</s>
        <s>So the <choice><orig>adressee</orig><reg>addressee</reg></choice> can also maybe not take action on his love.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the context of <ref target="c12lk1_1" type="author">Shakespeare's</ref> catalogue of sonnets, the addressee of this sonnet is a young man, which has a problem with his strong love.</s>
        <s><ref target="c12lk1_1" type="title">Sonnet 65</ref> shows, that the young man in fact has the love inside him, but to make the love true, he must speak it out and take action.</s>
        <s>So the message of the sonnet is that people must take action and speak out their love.</s>
        <s>He underlines this with the factors of time and death.</s>
        <s>This creates the feeling to make decisions fast until it is too late.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
