<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l04_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>During the whole book narrative perspective switch around between the four main characters, <name type="person">Delaney</name>, <name type="person">Kyro</name>, <name type="person">Cándido</name> and <name type="person">Ámerica</name>.</s>
        <s>The given excerpt is out of <name type="person">Delaney's</name> perspective, which is why we learn a lot about his train of thought and in regard to that how he behaves.</s>
        <s>The reader learns that <name type="person">Delaney</name> is worked by a lot of prejudice against Mexicans.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The whole book is narrated in the 3rd person so we cannot exactly see in every detail what the persons think.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In this passage there is a lot of report of tohught used <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 60, 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This shows us waht comes across his mind, which in this passage has mostly to do with his thoughts about Mexicans.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For example <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref> where the first thing he recognizes about the man is that he is Mexican.</s>
        <s>In regard to that <name type="person">Delaney</name> is building his <choice><orig>oppinion</orig><reg>opinion</reg></choice> about him <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore a lot of direct speech is used aswell <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 27)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This also shows us the effects of <name type="person"><choice><orig>Delaneys</orig><reg>Delaney's</reg></choice></name> prejudice as he is very impatient in the way he talks and also really harsh <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 50)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He clearly does not respect him but also the Mexican does not respect him either <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 58)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Adding to that there is a clear symbolism in this whole excerpt.</s>
        <s>It stands for the general relationship between Americans and Mexicans.</s>
        <s>Americans often see all Mexicans as bad, because of prejudice and stereotypes.</s>
        <s>Delaney is an example that <choice><orig>stand</orig><reg>stands</reg></choice> for the typical American view of a Mexican.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But <name type="person">Delaney</name> doesn't only have prejudice, he also reflects on the way he acts and also knows that he sometimes is wrong and that he is marked by a lot of stereotypes of Mexicans <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 60f)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion we can say that out of the readers' perception.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> seems like a racist white guy, but at the same time as someone, who is fighting the urge to not let prejudice and stereotypes affect the way he behaves.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
