<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3c</title>
        <author>b11l13_t3</author>
        <name>story</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="entertaining" genre_family="narrative">story</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>And here he was, he thought, delivering flies for people who now want to build a wall around their community, as is a gate wasn't enough, to keep him out.</s>
        <s>Him, his people, Mexicans.</s>
        <s>And he was aware of that.</s>
        <s>So aware that to a point he didn't even care anymore.</s>
        <s>While walking through <name type="misc">Arroyo Blanco</name> he couldn't help admiring the houses, with their big gardens and big cars and what not.</s>
        <s>How ironic, <name type="misc">José</name> thought, he just couldn't seem to understand those gringos.</s>
        <s>Not only had they invaded the once-Spanish colonies here and <choice><orig>exploitated</orig><reg>exploited</reg></choice> them, no, even the name of the estate was Spanish.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">Arroyo Blanco</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">White Stream</name>.</s>
        <s>The name made sense though, still it somehow provoked him.</s>
        <s>It seemed like they were living where he was supposed to live.</s>
        <s>In their big ass gringo houses, also in Spanish style!</s>
        <s><q>Those pendejos</q>, he said under his breath, <q>they have everything already, more than we could even think of owning and they want more and more and more</q>.</s>
        <s>Walking endlessly he thought, those are really living the American Dream.</s>
        <s>But for him, it was dead.</s>
        <s>Never existed.</s>
        <s>There was no chance for him or his people.</s>
        <s>Never would.</s>
        <s>Even though he used to be a dreamer in the very beginning.</s>
        <s>It didn't last long.</s>
        <s>So he kept on shoving fliers into the <choice><orig>gringos</orig><reg>gringos'</reg></choice> houses when he saw one of them approaching him even though he thought he was alone here.</s>
        <s>What does this, wetback want, he thought, recognizing him <choice><orig>immediatly</orig><reg>immediately</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It was the gringo with the car, the one obsessed with hiking, now shouting at him.</s>
        <s><q>Hey, can I help you?</q> he said.</s>
        <s>Help me?</s>
        <s>He must be joking, <name type="misc">José</name> thought, being stunned by the approach.</s>
        <s>He didn't respond.</s>
        <s>He didn't have the nerves to do so.</s>
        <s>He was too irritated already, he was afraid of what he'd be capable of doing.</s>
        <s>But the gringo didn't seem to leave him alone.</s>
        <s>So <name type="misc">José</name> decided to put on his most provoking face possible.</s>
        <s>He knew that the gringo was too scared of him, he felt threatened and would flee when he saw that <name type="misc">José</name> didn't give a damn about him.</s>
        <s>He had nothing to <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice>, never would have anything to <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>Not here, in the land of opportunities, there was no place for him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><q>Help me</q>, he grinned, <q>sure, hombre, you can help me</q>.</s>
        <s>He just knew that the gringo was panicking.</s>
        <s>And he loved it.</s>
        <s>After all the miseries in his life it was a fun activity for him to harass and make fun of others.</s>
        <s>He enjoyed seeing his face like that.</s>
        <s>His expression was priceless.</s>
        <s><q>I want to know what you're doing here</q>, he asked, <q><qs>this is private property.</qs><qs>You don't belong here</qs></q>.</s>
        <s>And here we go again, <name type="misc">José</name> thought, the phrase that he'd heard millions, if not billions of times.</s>
        <s>So many times that it didn't even <choice><orig>effect</orig><reg>affect</reg></choice> him anymore.</s>
        <s>It was as if he'd build a shield over the years to protect himself from those words.</s>
        <s>He found it funny, that this was all the gringos could offer and thought it'd mean something to him, as if he was not trying to simply survive for many, many years.</s>
        <s>This was nothing compared to all the hardships he went through, and those assholes still thought they did something... <name type="misc">José</name> didn't even bother looking defeated.</s>
        <s>He didn't want to give him the power, the supremacy, so he gazed straight through him.</s>
        <s>Funny how the tables can turn so quickly, he thought, the superior white was feeling threatened by a small, powerless Mexican like him.</s>
        <s>Suddenly he felt a grip on his forearm, the man saying <q>I'm talking to you</q>.</s>
        <s>Not this pendejo having the guts to touch me, <name type="misc">José</name> thought and looked him fierecefully in the face, disrespecting him, before whipping his arm free.</s>
        <s>He showed him the <choice><orig>flies</orig><reg>fliers</reg></choice>, shouting him in the face <q>I got these flies</q>.</s>
        <s>He was fed up, so was the gringo, looking at him with a disgusted, condescending expression screaming at him to not give him that shit, not even knowing this was their own shit, their achievement, <name type="misc">José</name> thought.</s>
        <s>Then he threatened to call the police, said that he knew who he was and all that crap.</s>
        <s>He was trying to act all confident but <name type="misc">José</name> noticed too easily that he was in fact not.</s>
        <s>He was scared like a little girl, looking around for help, he thought, such a fool.</s>
        <s>One more time he hissed at him <q><qs>flies.</qs><qs>I deliver these flies</qs></q>.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">José</name> knew he didn't need to justify anything, he had nothing to <choice><orig>loose</orig><reg>lose</reg></choice> after all, but it was funny seeing the gringo all startled with a blank face after shoving a flyer in his hand.</s>
        <s>Without another second passing, <name type="misc">José</name> made his way up the street, not a last word, a last look or anything.</s>
        <s>He just left.</s>
        <s>And the gringo didn't follow him.</s>
        <s><name type="misc">José</name> was annoyed, even pissed, so he delivered the rest of the flyers and left the place where he didn't belong.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
