<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> is a man full of prejudice and anger against illegal immigrants, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> is shown through the use of reported thought and speech as well as descriptions by the narrator.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Through the <choice><orig>narraters</orig><reg>narrator's</reg></choice> use of reported thought the readers get a close up, of the prejudice <name type="person">Delaney</name> holds in him.</s>
        <s>Before <name type="person">Delaney</name> gets to see what is in the white cloth shoulder bag he builds up prejudices by beliving that the immigrant stole important personal belongings from the <name type="person"><choice><orig>Cherrystone's</orig><reg>Cherrystones</reg></choice></name>: <quote><name type="person">Delaney</name> demanded, eyeing the satchel and imagining the <name type="person">Cherrystones'</name> silverware in there, their VCR, <name type="person">Selda's</name> <choice><orig>jewlery</orig><reg>jewelry</reg></choice></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 37ff)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This underlines that <name type="person">Delaney</name> is an impulsive character, by handeling or prejudicing before he thinks.</s>
        <s>This prejudice comes from traumatic <choice><orig>experiencess</orig><reg>experiences</reg></choice> <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> happen throughout the novel, for example when <name type="person">Delaney's</name> car <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> stolen.</s>
        <s>The use of reported speech brings also evidence to <name type="person">Delaney</name> being a man, full of prejudice.</s>
        <s>By referring to the fact, that the immigrant is in his private property and that he doesn't belong there: <quote><qs>This is private property.</qs><qs>You don't belong here</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 39)</ref>, the narrator even underlines mroe the prejudice side from <name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Furthermore <name type="person">Delaney</name> is not only filled with prejudice, but also hate and anger towards the Mexicans.</s>
        <s>By using a scenic presentation and <choice><orig>detailled</orig><reg>detailed</reg></choice> description <quote><qs><name type="person">Todd Sweet</name> called at his back, but he wasn't lsitening, his mind gone numb with ambivalence.</qs><qs>He went up the block, barely registering the world spread out before him, glum, dogless, on his own</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 5ff)</ref>, the narrator points out the anger to the readers.</s>
        <s>This behaviour from <name type="person">Delaney</name> clearly indicates his anger and hate towards the immigrants, by overseeing the chance that could have prevented the situation when <name type="person">Todd Sweet</name> calls him, and just walking further while blending out the world around him.</s>
        <s>This could also be <choice><orig>describe</orig><reg>described</reg></choice> as him having an attentive and unfocused state of mind, while the whole anger takes him forward.</s>
        <s>Moreover <name type="person">Delaney</name> also expresses his anger by shouting at the Mexican: <quote><qs>Don't give me that shit!</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 50)</ref> and the use of <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> parallelism: <quote><qs>I'm calling the police.</qs><qs>I know what you're doing up here, I know who you are, you're not fooling anybody</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 51f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Throhugh this use of reported speech, the readers can see how <name type="person">Delaney</name> wants to appear dominant in opposite to the Mexican.</s>
        <s>On one side <name type="person">Delaney</name> shouts at the man and threatens him by mentioning the police.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand <name type="person">Delaney</name> <choice><orig>get's</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> also ready to fight the Mexican and to defend himself, if he has to: <quote><qs><name type="person">Delaney</name> was riding, the crest of the moment, trembling, angry, ready for anything</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 48)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another important aspect is that <name type="person">Delaney</name> also develops fear and panic thorughout the scene.</s>
        <s>In the beginning <name type="person">Delaney</name> starts to feel uncomfortable, after the Mexican answers his question: <quote><qs><name type="person">Delaney</name> was not.</qs><qs>He was uncomfortable.</qs><qs>He was aggravated.</qs></quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 31)</ref>.</s>
        <s>From this point on the panic grows more and more in <name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
        <s>For example, this is shown <choice><orig>throug</orig><reg>through</reg></choice> <name type="person">Delaney's</name> reaction, by quickening his stride, when he first speaks up to the man.</s>
        <s>Besides that <name type="person">Delaney</name> makes a <gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="word">sashly aaicn</gap>, when the Mexican does not answer his question.</s>
        <s>This action is narrated as a reported thought, <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> leads to, that the readers get to know that <name type="person">Delaney</name> doesn't think, before he takes actions and that he only <choice><orig>handels</orig><reg>handles</reg></choice> this way, because he fears the Mexican and <choice><orig>want's</orig><reg>wants</reg></choice> to appear more dominant, to mabye calm himself down: <quote><name type="person">Delaney</name> said, and before he could think, he had hold of the man's forearm, just above the wrist.</quote> After the man whipped his arm easily free, <name type="person">Delaney</name> craves on one hand the help and support from someone else: <quote><name type="person">Delaney</name> looked around him for support, for a car, a child on a bike, <name type="person">Todd Sweet</name>, anyone, but the street was deserted</quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 52f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This climax shows clearly to the reader, how helpless <name type="person">Delaney</name> feels and how much of panic and fear he is in hold of.</s>
        <s>But on the other hand <name type="person">Delaney</name> starts to suspect unrealistic things, for example that the Mexican has a knife and <choice><orig>developes</orig><reg>develops</reg></choice> a deathly fear.</s>
        <s>The use of reported thought here, <choice><orig>let's</orig><reg>lets</reg></choice> the readers feel what <name type="person">Delaney</name> is feeling in this situation: <quote>He's got a knife, <name type="person">Delaney</name> thought, a gun, and he went cold all over when the man reached into the satchel [...]</quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(ll. 55ff)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the end <name type="person">Delaney</name> has a turning <choice><orig>devalopmend</orig><reg>development</reg></choice>, when he finds out that the Mexican didn't lie.</s>
        <s>He <choice><orig>start's</orig><reg>starts</reg></choice> to requestion himself and his actions.</s>
        <s>The use of a <choice><orig>rethorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> question: <quote>[...] what was he becoming</quote> <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(l. 61)</ref>, leads to the readers getting a <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">incist</gap> in the now confused and devastated <name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In summary, through the use of a lot of different narrative techniques, the readers get a chance to have a close up on <name type="person"><choice><orig>Delaneys</orig><reg>Delaney's</reg></choice></name> over all mixed feelings, <choice><orig>referring</orig><reg>refering</reg></choice> to anger, hate, fear, devastation and prejudices.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
