<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g50_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The scene in chapter 24 of the novel <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> portrays <name type="person"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></name> final moment of speaking herself free of her anger and her <choice><orig>experiance</orig><reg>experience</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The scene starts with a <choice><orig>describtion</orig><reg>description</reg></choice> by the first perosn of the situation; <name type="person">Starr</name>, <name type="person">Seven</name>, <name type="person">DeVante</name> and <name type="person">Chris</name> meet a demonstration which is <choice><orig>leaded</orig><reg>lead</reg></choice> by <name type="misc">Just Us For Justice</name>.</s>
        <s>The demonstration is nearby the place where <name type="person">Khalil</name> died and at first <name type="person">Starr</name> feels a bit unconfident and gets a flashback of his death.</s>
        <s>This reminds the reader of what happened and shows how this experience still affects <name type="person">Starr</name>.</s>
        <s>This point of view also gives a very limited perspective, while <name type="person">Starr</name> has her flashback the recipient has no idea what is going on, which creates the effect that the flashback holds <name type="person">Starr</name> and that she is not even able to focus on anything else: <quote><s>I haven't been back here since that night.</s><s>Knowing this is where <name type="person">Khalil</name>... I stare too hard the crowd disappears, and I see him lying in the street [...]</s></quote> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 5-7)</ref>.</s>
        <s>After that <name type="person">Starr</name> comes back to reality because of the crowd.</s>
        <s><quote>A hairbrush is not a gun</quote><ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref>, she describes her feelings: <quote>The voice snaps me from my daze.</quote> That shows that she <choice><orig>do</orig><reg>does</reg></choice> not know how to deal with the flashbacks.</s>
        <s>She concentrates back on her real situation, <choice><orig>see</orig><reg>sees</reg></choice> <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> and realizes that her life is way more radical than she has expected.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Seven</name>, <name type="person">DeVante</name> and <name type="person">Chris</name> starts to join the crowd, first <name type="person">Starr</name> repeats quiet <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> she remembers the situation with <name type="person">Khalil</name> again; she <choice><orig>remember</orig><reg>remembers</reg></choice> what he said.</s>
        <s>This gives the reader the feeling of realization; <name type="person">Starr</name> has been through a lot and the reader can identify a lot with <name type="person"><choice><orig>Starrs</orig><reg>Starr's</reg></choice></name> anger.</s>
        <s>The anger comes <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> to a final: she screams as loud as she can and through the development of her first speaking quiet, <choice><orig>than</orig><reg>then</reg></choice> speaking so loud the <gap reason="illegible" quantity="2" unit="word">tightening lows</gap> a bit.</s>
        <s>This development from a watcher to a speaker <add>as part of the crowd</add> and later to a speaker in front of the crowd is highlighted by the flashbacks, it comes to a realization that she cannot stay quiet if she wants justice for <name type="person">Khalil</name> and peace for herself.</s>
        <s>While speaking to <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> she isvery sure taht she ahs to do something.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> tells her that she ahs to use her voice as a weapon.</s>
        <s>At this point <name type="person">Starr</name> realizes that she <choice><orig>do</orig><reg>does</reg></choice> not have to burn something down to change something; she starts to understand that her voice is even more effective.</s>
        <s>Here is also an appeal for the reader; everyone is in the position to speak for <choice><orig>them selves</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice> to change something.</s>
        <s>Before <name type="person">Starr</name> even starts to talk <choice><orig>infront</orig><reg>in front</reg></choice> of the crowd she has a moment of <choice><orig>unsurness</orig><reg>insecurity</reg></choice>; this shows the reader that to be brave to speak up is not easy.</s>
        <s>But by the moment when the crowd <choice><orig>encourage</orig><reg>encourages</reg></choice> her the novel shows that there is always a <choice><orig>save</orig><reg>safe</reg></choice> place to speak up even if this place is not easy to find.</s>
        <s>The line 57-58: <quote>Forget trigger happy - speaker happy is more my thing</quote> She notices that speaking herself free makes her happy.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The fact that no other person <add><name type="person">DeVante</name>, <name type="person">Seven</name>, <name type="person">Chris</name> or <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name></add> is mentioned at the moment when she speaks up shows that <name type="person">Starr</name> is the only witness and because of that it is her own fight for her own better ending.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>For her self-development in the novel this is very important: it does not matter that she has two worlds to live in or that she is not sure who she is.</s>
        <s>The only thing that <choice><orig>matter</orig><reg>matters</reg></choice> here is the fact taht she is brave enough to tell her truth by her own voice.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
