<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g51_t3</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear John,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This e-mail is about <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> schools should or shouldn't read the book <name type="misc">THUG</name>.</s>
        <s>First of, I think that is a stupid theme to discuss about.</s>
        <s>Of course you should read this book in school worldwide.</s>
        <s>The argument of the school board that the book shows the police in a negative light is just stupid.</s>
        <s>Of course the police is shown in a bad or negative light but I don't understand how the actions are showing the police in a negative light today.</s>
        <s>The police did something wrong in the book, that can anyone admit, but this actinos belong to the past and should not be seen as actions of the police today.</s>
        <s>I think the offensive language and sexual references should not be seen as a bad thing because it just shows that the book is real and if you ask me that should not be a problem.</s>
        <s>Because if you see it like this many other books should be banned from <choice><orig>american</orig><reg>American</reg></choice> school.</s>
        <s>Historical books like something that is about the NS-time in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>A historical book and <name type="misc">THUG</name> have in <choice><orig>comment</orig><reg>common</reg></choice> that you should learn out of the actions in the past and confront yourself with these problems.</s>
        <s>Racism is still a thing today, more like other things like the NS-time.</s>
        <s>Because of this it is just very important to learn from this book to solve future problems about racism.</s>
        <s>The argument that the book depicts drug abuse is true but also a proof that the book is real.</s>
        <s>How sad the truth can be, right?</s>
        <s>The other part of the argument that the book promotes drug abuse is just wrong.</s>
        <s>I think nobody after reading this book is like: <q>Oh, now after reading this book I wanna go to a party to take drugs like weed and risk to getting shot at</q>.</s>
        <s>Anyway use this arguments against the school board.</s>
        <s>I hope I could help you!</s>
        <s>See you soon.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
