<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g44_t3</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical_exposition">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Hey Jimmy,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Im</orig><reg>I'm</reg></choice> glad <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> can help you with this topic and hopefully you can get your points through and let the book nto be banned from the shcools.</s>
        <s>The book is about a young black girl named <name type="person">Starr Carter</name>.</s>
        <s>She attends a private school where mostly white people are that acome from good neighborhoods.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>that</orig><reg>That</reg></choice> isn't the case for <name type="person">Starr</name> she comes from a nieghborhood called <name type="geo">Garden Heights</name>.</s>
        <s>The name may sound ncie but there arem ostly poor people living and there is lots of crime happening.</s>
        <s>One day <name type="person">Starr</name> is on a party with her friend <name type="person">Kenya</name>, <name type="person">Starr</name> and <name type="person">Kenya</name> have different parents but share a brother <add><name type="person">Starr's</name> dad and <name type="person">Kenya's</name> mother</add>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>on</orig><reg>On</reg></choice> the party <name type="person">Starr</name> meets an old rfiend, <name type="person">Khalil</name>, both were very good friends but didn't see in a long time.</s>
        <s>As they talk they hear gun shots and run out of the building to <name type="person">Khalil's</name> car and drive away.</s>
        <s>They get stopped by a police officer who ends up killing <name type="person">Khalil</name>.</s>
        <s>That reminds <name type="person">Starr</name> of when the same thing happened to her and <name type="person">Khalil's</name> friend <name type="person">Natasha</name>.</s>
        <s>From there on she tries to get justice for <name type="person">Khalil</name>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Its</orig><reg>It's</reg></choice> a story about and against racism.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Its</orig><reg>It's</reg></choice> advocating supporting activists and shows how miserable some people's lives are and how easy one can feel betrayed or hopeless but if you speak up you can find new hope and help prevent people to ever get in your situation.</s>
        <s>Yes sometimes it contains offensive language or has sexual <choice><orig>refferences</orig><reg>references</reg></choice> but that makes it so you can relate better the people in the book aren't perfect, they're normal humans and live in a bad nieghborhood where bad things happen.</s>
        <s>It shows how racist some police officers are and that they don't get punished sometimes if they for example kill someone who's innocent.</s>
        <s>The books does not promote drug dealing or abuse it hardly scratches the topic.</s>
        <s>The book is supposed to encourage people to stand and speak up for the right thing because staying quiet doesn't change anything and makes you only feel guilty.</s>
        <s>I could go on but I don't want to spoil the book too much.</s>
        <s>I hope you can convince everyone and I hope this helped enough.</s>
        <s>If you know <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> the book was banned or not you can text me anytime.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Greetings from <name type="geo">Germany,</name> Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
