<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>a11g39_t3</author>
        <name>informal_e-mail</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="persuading" genre_family="analytical exposition">informal_e-mail</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Lilli,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>How are you doing?</s>
        <s>I haven't heard from you in a while.</s>
        <s>You know how I told you about the book I had to read in my English class?</s>
        <s>Yeah <name type="misc">The Hate U Give</name>.</s>
        <s>So, I did some research because I was wondering if racism is really a topical problem in the <name type="geo">USA</name>.</s>
        <s>Regarding to that I've found an article about African Americans in the <name type="geo">USA</name> and how they've been treated lately.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I would've just send you the link from it to read it yourself but unfortunately it's in German.</s>
        <s>According to that I will tell you the most important aspects of the article.</s>
        <s>The article starts by <choice><orig>meantioning</orig><reg>mentioning</reg></choice> that after the <choice><orig>18 year old</orig><reg>18-year-old</reg></choice> African American <name type="person">Michael Brown</name> got killed by a white police officer, the racial segregation is still very present.</s>
        <s>A statistic shows how black people are treated so much worse than white people.</s>
        <s>As an example <choice><orig>there</orig><reg>their</reg></choice> rate of getting <choice><orig>arrestet</orig><reg>arrested</reg></choice> is so much higher.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>articles</orig><reg>article's</reg></choice> author explains that this is caused by <q>stop-and-frisk</q> meaning that the police can stop and palpate suspects.</s>
        <s>Even 50 years after the <name type="misc">Civil Rights Act</name>, African Americans still have to suffer economy and social wise.</s>
        <s>Can you <choice><orig>belive</orig><reg>believe</reg></choice> that?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>And did you know that even when it comes to education white people have a higher chance to graduate plus if African Americans graduate they are most likely to be unemployed compared to white people.</s>
        <s>More than a quarter of the African American population lives in poverty.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I was really surprised after that article even though I've read the book and I have a lot of knowledge about <name type="misc">Black Lives Matter</name>.</s>
        <s>I still didn't <choice><orig>expected</orig><reg>expect</reg></choice> it to be that common and the really big differences.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>As you live in the <name type="geo">USA</name> I was wondering if you had any experience about this topic?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope to hear from you and to talk about this again as I find it a really important topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See you soon,</s>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
