<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g51_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following analysis I will show the stylistic devices and how the author uses them to spread a certain message.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the present text the story is told from the perspective of a <choice><orig>first person</orig><reg>first-person</reg></choice> narrator, in this case <name type="person">Starr</name>.</s>
        <s>The <choice><orig>first person</orig><reg>first-person</reg></choice> narrator comes in very good specially for telling this kind of story.</s>
        <s>Because of the first narrator <name type="person">Starr's</name> situation inside her can be told very good because you can get a more detailed view of her feelings and her impressions.</s>
        <s>You can also identify yourself more, when she is telling the story.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The flashbacks that were used in this text, told by a <choice><orig>first person</orig><reg>first-person</reg></choice> narrator, are being used to show <name type="person">Starr's</name> PTSD and that she is still very sensitive with the confrontation of the situation.</s>
        <s>Every time <name type="person">Starr</name> is getting one of her flashbacks she is going into a daze.</s>
        <s>That shows, that <name type="person">Starr</name> relives the situation inside her again.</s>
        <s>To show this sensitivity the <choice><orig>first person</orig><reg>first-person</reg></choice> narrator is suitable.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Starr's</name> state of mind is in general presented very unstable.</s>
        <s>That is hown in line 45-55 <quote>My -</quote> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 45)</ref> <quote>Don't be scared... speak</quote> <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 46)</ref>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> needs help to solve her problems inside and get the <name type="person">Starr</name> who fights for <name type="person">Khalil</name>.</s>
        <s>That is the <name type="person">Starr</name> she truly wants to be.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Starr's</name> voice is shown as a weapon <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 33+40)</ref>.</s>
        <s>You can interpret her voice as a weapon of justice.</s>
        <s>With this weapon <name type="person">Starr</name> fights against the weapons of discrimination, the real weapons of the police.</s>
        <s>It also shows how great <name type="person">Starr's</name> voice is because it is the voice of the witness who saw the <q>real</q> face of the police.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion you can say that the <choice><orig>first person</orig><reg>first-person</reg></choice> narrator is very important to show <name type="person">Starr's</name> feelings, her anger and her way of thinking.</s>
        <s>The stylistic devices that were used are being usd to show <name type="person">Starr's</name> superiority in front of the police and her side on the peaceful side of protesting.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
