<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>a11g42_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>a</publisher>
        <date>20211208</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>a11gk4</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The <choice><orig>bookscene</orig><reg>book scene</reg></choice> of the novel <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="title">The Hate U Give</ref> on page 328-332 in <choice><orig>Chapter</orig><reg>chapter</reg></choice> 24, written by <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="author">Angie Thomas</ref>, is the scene, where the protagonist <name type="person">Starr</name> and her brother and friends get at the place, where her childhood best friend was <choice><orig>shoot</orig><reg>shot</reg></choice> by a cop named <name type="person">nine-fifteen</name>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> is a 16-year-old teenager, who lives with her family in <name type="geo">Garden Heights</name>, which is a ghetto, where black people <choice><orig>lives</orig><reg>live</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The novel is about her <choice><orig>two-sides-life</orig><reg>two-sided life</reg></choice>, which consists of the ghetto black girl and the polite girl, who goes on a <q>white</q> school.</s>
        <s>One day, she goes to secretly to a party in <name type="geo">Garden Heights</name> and sees her childhood best friend, <name type="person">Khalil</name>.</s>
        <s>They leave the party, because of weapon <choice><orig>shoots</orig><reg>shots</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>A cop car stops <name type="person"><choice><orig>Khalils</orig><reg>Khalil's</reg></choice></name>, without a reason.</s>
        <s>When <name type="person">Khalil</name> <choice><orig>get</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> out of the car, the police officer presses him on the car and said him to not move, but he bend down into the car to get a hairbrush and the officer shoots him, because he thinks he <choice><orig>get</orig><reg>gets</reg></choice> a gun.</s>
        <s>In the follow of the novel, <name type="person">Starr</name> tries to fight for <name type="person">Khalil</name>, who was killed wrongly.</s>
        <s>In this scene, what is given, she protests with a crowd of black people, for <name type="person">Khalil</name> and sees her attorney <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>.</s>
        <s>With the motivation of <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>, she <choice><orig>manage</orig><reg>manages</reg></choice> to <choice><orig>speek</orig><reg>speak</reg></choice> for <name type="person">Khalil</name>, on the top of a cop car with a bullhorn.</s>
        <s>The scene is written in the narrative perspective and it kinda consists of just <choice><orig>speeking</orig><reg>speaking</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>It was written in a perspective of <name type="person">Starr's</name> mind, how she thinks in this situation.</s>
        <s>In line 5-9 is the thought of <name type="person">Starr</name> written, how she imagines the repeat of <name type="person">Khalil's</name> death.</s>
        <s>Again in line 18-22 was the mind her mind of imagine <name type="person">Khalil</name> written, this shows, how much she is traumatized about the death, she sees him everywhere and this makes the situation worse than it is, but also it gives <name type="person">Starr</name> the power to fight for her best friend, who was shoot because of his skin color.</s>
        <s>On line 29 is shown, that <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name>, don't want, that anything bad happens to <name type="person">Starr</name>, but she knows that <name type="person">Starr</name> wouldn't hear at her.</s>
        <s>But on the following lines <name type="person">Ms. Ofrah</name> shows her, her <choice><orig>strongless</orig><reg>strength</reg></choice> with the sentence <quote>Your voice is your biggest weapon</quote>.</s>
        <s>Also an example, that <name type="person">Starr's</name> thought is written in this scene is line 44, where she uses words like <quote>shit</quote>.</s>
        <s>From line 49-61 is her point of view <choice><orig>discribed</orig><reg>described</reg></choice>, which consists of, that <name type="person">Khalil</name> was <choice><orig>shooted</orig><reg>shot</reg></choice>, because the cop thinks he's bad, because of his skin color, also that everyone talks about how he died, but no one sees the fact, that he lived <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(ll. 59-61)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also on line 60-61 he repeats 3 times, that <name type="person">Khalil</name> <choice><orig>was lived</orig><reg>lived</reg></choice>, this also shows her point of view and how it hurt her, that no one sees, that he was killed wrongly.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Starr</name> is here presented, like a girl who fights, <choice><orig>althought</orig><reg>although</reg></choice> she has pain and is just a 16-years-old teenager.</s>
        <s>It also shows, that she won't give up, until white people <choice><orig>sees</orig><reg>see</reg></choice> that black people aren't bad and until this <choice><orig>racistic</orig><reg>racist</reg></choice> comments and all ends <ref target="a11gk4_1" type="line">(l. 56)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
