<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t4</title>
        <author>b12g24_t4</author>
        <name>e-mail_informal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive report">e-mail_informal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Louis,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>thank</orig><reg>Thank</reg></choice> you for your last e-mail, in which you were telling me about the newspaper article <ref target="b12gk2_2" type="title">Mehr Bio nicht nur am Freitag</ref>, published in <date>November 2019</date> in the <name type="misc">Kölner Stadt Anzeiger</name>.</s>
        <s>I've read the article and want to tell you what it is about.</s>
        <s>The highschool <name type="misc">KLS</name> organized an event called <quote>KLS goes green</quote>.</s>
        <s>It took place in one day, with over 40 projects, that students could participate in, in the school and in <choice><orig>it's</orig><reg>its</reg></choice>area.</s>
        <s>It was the first time, this even had took place.</s>
        <s>It was organized by students and teachers.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because of an increase in interest in political and social problems, associated with the <name type="misc">Fridays for Future</name> movement on sides of the students, <name type="misc">KLS goes green</name> was founded <add>set in place</add>.</s>
        <s>All of the projects had to do with climate change and sustainability.</s>
        <s>The students had many ideas how to increase sustainability in our day-to-day lives, i.e. foodsharing, thrifting or economizing water and selling organic food and snacks in the school.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the school's fairtrade café, students sold organic fair and vegan products.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Two poetry slammers also visited teh school and one of them conducted a project for the students in which they could learn to use their voice to convey a certain atmosphere and content.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>According to <name type="person">Peter Clemm</name>, who participated in organizing the event, claims to be very content about the outcome of the event and looking forward to it possibly taking place next year.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I hope I could help you understand the article.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>See you soon,</s>
        <signed>Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
