<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b12g19_t3</author>
        <name>letter_formal</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">letter_formal</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <salute>Dear Adeline,</salute>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I wanted to tell you about a thought of mine.</s>
        <s>I actually found an old speech of <name type="person">Boris Johnson</name> in <date>2021</date>, do you remember the speech?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because I actually did.</s>
        <s>I remember that when the speech was in the TV that I watched it and one specific line stuck with me.</s>
        <s>He says taht the unborn children would be even more angry at the leaders of <date>2021</date> if they would fail to stop climate change.</s>
        <s>Then he says that they would have had the technology, the ideas , the corporations and the NGOs.</s>
        <s>What do you think about this?</s>
        <s>I mean, I do admire his spirit and <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">compasion</gap>, but we all <choice><orig>now</orig><reg>know</reg></choice> what happened.</s>
        <s>And I mean ... he was right.</s>
        <s>We are mad.</s>
        <s>Our children are mad.</s>
        <s>I remember when I told <name type="person">Josie</name> <add>my daughter</add> about how we had snow in winter, she could not imagine it.</s>
        <s>And then she threw a <choice><orig>tandrum</orig><reg>tantrum</reg></choice> because she wanted to see it, she even wanted to build a snowman.</s>
        <s>We build a snowman out of clay afterwards to make it up to her that we ruined the planet.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I think if she gets older she will not be satisfied with a clay snowman anymore, when she realizes the consequences.</s>
        <s>We <choice><orig>life</orig><reg>live</reg></choice> in the <foreign xml:lang="de">Norden</foreign> of <name type="geo"><choice><orig>germany</orig><reg>Germany</reg></choice></name> <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>and</reg></choice> the lowest temperature this year was 30°C.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Half the <choice><orig>worlds</orig><reg>world's</reg></choice> population died, because of the temperature, the new viruses set free from the melted ice in the polar caps and then the tornados, the fires and droughts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>She will be infuriated.</s>
        <s>Like me.</s>
        <s>So yes, we will be mad.</s>
        <s>We are mad, <name type="person">Johnson</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But actually, I am not sure if we really had the ideas, technology etc. like <name type="person">Johnson</name> claimed.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>We had ideas yes, I remember when people tried to use solar energy and wind energy instead of <choice><orig>cole</orig><reg>coal</reg></choice>, but the multiorganisations did not <choice><orig>went</orig><reg>go</reg></choice> along.</s>
        <s>Like the governments.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>They made promises but did nothing.</s>
        <s>On the other hand, I am not sure if the technology of <date>2021</date> was enough to prevent this.</s>
        <s>We relied too much on fossil fuels and unsustainable methods.</s>
        <s>The people could not have lived back then how we do now.</s>
        <s>We live in bunkers in the earth, earn energy only with the sunpower and use every bit of food and goods not we gives us.</s>
        <s>The people did not have the right mindsets, they could not reuse a T-Shirt for multiple years, they did not learn how.</s>
        <s>So many irrelevant things were important, like having a <quote>perfect</quote> body, being fashionable and so on.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It's actually hilarious.</s>
        <s>Why would it matter to look fashionable, when the world is dying?</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The answer is easy, they did not see it.</s>
        <s>We understand now, all of us even <name type="person">Josie</name> does and she is only four years old.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The selfishness and profit were <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> important, the capitalism screwed all of them over.</s>
        <s>Even me, to be honest.</s>
        <s>Do you remember how you behaved back then?</s>
        <s>Your thoughts?</s>
        <s>I'd love to talk about them, it'd be funny I think.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But back to <name type="person">Johnson</name>, I think he <choice><orig>hold</orig><reg>held</reg></choice> a fairly decent speech, but no matter how good his speech was he failed.</s>
        <s>I would say that he was right, we had the ideas, we may even have had the <choice><orig>appropriat</orig><reg>appropriate</reg></choice> technology, but we did not have the right mindset.</s>
        <s>The unsustainable lifestyle and selfishness sat <choice><orig>to</orig><reg>too</reg></choice> deep.</s>
        <s>It is very sad, that that is what killed half of our population and the world.</s>
        <s>Especially the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But maybe, just maybe have our children the right mindset and maybe they will make it right.</s>
        <s>Maybe they can do what we, what they could not.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>I do not know.</s>
        <s>What do you think?</s>
        <s>I'd love to hear your thoughts!</s>
        <s>And I am sorry for the depressing letter, but this was on my mind for some time and I needed to share my thoughts.</s>
        <s>Greet <name type="person">Will</name> and your little ones.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <signed>Love, Jane</signed>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
