<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b12g20_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>12</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="225min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b12gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the speech <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Boris Johnson</ref> compares the role of <name type="misc">COP26</name> with <name type="person">James Bond</name> and the climate change with a ticking bomb or the <quote>doomsday device</quote>, which is able to destroy the whole world <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 2f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>These are metaphors, which are used to make his point easier for his listeners to understand.</s>
        <s>They also may be like <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> homage to <name type="geo">Great Britain</name>, because <name type="person">James Bond</name> is a <choice><orig>british</orig><reg>British</reg></choice> work and the conference takes place in <name type="geo">Great Britain</name>.</s>
        <s>He also uses certain metaphors to explain the situation of the climate crisis with for example <quote><gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">edored wire</gap></quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> which stands for the solution to stop climate change or the <quote>detonation</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref> which stands for the moment when it's too late to stop the rise up of the temperature of the earth.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> creates a feeling of community by using the pronoun <quote>we</quote> through the whole speech <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 5,8,9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In the second paragraph <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> starts with the anaphora <quote>I was there [...]</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 10f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It's according to conferences from the past and connect that directly to his listeners by telling they visited them together <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 10)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> says these conferences weren't more than <quote>blah, blah, blah</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This is used to make fun about them in oder to show that the <name type="misc">COP26</name> is the <quote>deciding conference</quote>.</s>
        <s>He also says that clearly in line 14.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The third paragraph starts with an ellipse and an anaphora.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Trough</orig><reg>Through</reg></choice> the ellipse <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> wants to reduce the sentence to his point.</s>
        <s>Also he <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">numents</gap> important words of climate change like <quote>coal, cars, cash and trees</quote> <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 16)</ref>, which underlines the large scale of the topic.</s>
        <s>The alliteration supports that.</s>
        <s>The metaphor <quote>doomsday device</quote> is used a second time <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He wants to explain that it's important to ahndle right now by saying climate and environment was ignored for about the last 200 years <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 18f)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the fifth paragraph he shows that they have all the conditions to start fighting the climate crisis by using an enumeration and anaphora of the things they need but already have <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 30)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also he directly talks to the audience with the sentence <quote>we all talk about what we're going to do in <date>2050</date> or <date>2060</date></quote>.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> wants to underline that everybody is affected by climate change.</s>
        <s>He even talks about children and that they will suffer and judge them if they don't start the fight against climate change, which is a very personal way to talk to the audience.</s>
        <s><ref target="b12gk2_1" type="speaker">Johnson</ref> uses repetitions and anaphoras to underline that.</s>
        <s>He knows that <name type="misc">COP26</name> will not be the <quote>final attack</quote> against climate change and he makes that clear through the sentence <quote>COP26 will not, and cannot, be the end of the story [...]</quote>.</s>
        <s>In line 45 he repeats that all the necessary conditions are reachable or even reached <ref target="b12gk2_1" type="line">(l. 45)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
