<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g18_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As mentioned in the summary is the extract of the speech about how important school exchanges are when you want to break down certain walls between people from all over the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The extract is structured in four different paragraphs.</s>
        <s>The first one says why he is there, in the second one he talks about how young <choice><orig>americans</orig><reg>Americans</reg></choice> already <choice><orig>connects</orig><reg>connect</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>The third one shows why exchanges are important and the fourth is a request/invitation, so the extract is divided into different parts of one topic.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses when he speaks in lines 14-17 about progress the pronoun <quote>we</quote>, with this he wants to include the listeners and also to raise attention.</s>
        <s>In lines 18 to 22 he uses the pronoun <quote>you</quote>, which has <choice><orig>an</orig><reg>a</reg></choice> similar effect, <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> wants to <choice><orig>emphatize</orig><reg>emphasize</reg></choice> on how important it is for every person to build bridges instead of building new walls.</s>
        <s>This also raises the attention of the listener, you are spoken to directly.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses a certain metaphor a few times in his speech <quote>walls</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13)</ref> or <quote>build new bridges instead of building new walls</quote>.</s>
        <s>With this stylistic advice he wants to make this more clear, because if you stand before a wall you <choice><orig>can not</orig><reg>cannot</reg></choice> get to another person or even hear another person behind that wall.</s>
        <s>While if you would say as an example barrier it is not as clear, because a barrier is a lot of time easier to break those than a wall, also a wall is a clearer picture.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In lines 18-20 you can find <choice><orig>anophora</orig><reg>anaphora</reg></choice> as well as parallelism, all the sentences begin with <quote>You can</quote>.</s>
        <s>This <choice><orig>emphatices</orig><reg>emphasizes</reg></choice> that is for everyone but especially for <quote>you</quote> possible to do this.</s>
        <s>It marks how important it is with the use of the pronoun <quote>you</quote>.</s>
        <s>It also raises the attention of the listener and motivates <choice><orig>yo</orig><reg>you</reg></choice> to do everything that he tells you to.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> uses certain stylistic devices as an example metaphor or anaphora and pronouns like <quote>you</quote> or <quote>we</quote> to speak to the listener directly.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
