<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c10g21_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>As stated in the summary, the speech by <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> is about the positive consequences by doing a student exchange.</s>
        <s>Now I will analyse the structure and choice of words the president <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> uses to convince especially young people of his opinion that a simple exchange can break down walls between the world.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Right from the start, you can see <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama's</ref> conviction towards the student exchange.</s>
        <s>You directly see his positive view about the topic and because of that, the reader or listener also have a positive view about it.</s>
        <s>The sentence <quote>In America, I'm proud to see a new spirit of activism and responsibility take root</quote> <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(l. 4)</ref> gives a good feeling that it works what he says and because of his positive radiation you <choice><orig>wold</orig><reg>would</reg></choice> like to read on.</s>
        <s>With his speech <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Barack Obama</ref> will cheer especially young people up to do a student exchange.</s>
        <s>It seems that he will encourage young people to come together with other countries and share experiences <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 13-14)</ref> for a better interaction in the <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> world.</s>
        <s>Because he talks about his own experiences he also makes young people courage to do a student exchange and meet therefore new people and the language <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 5-10)</ref>.</s>
        <s>You can see in the speech how important it is to <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> that as much as can travel around the world to learn much about the other parts of the world and interact with them for a better communication in the <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> world <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
        <s>His positive conviction and the appeal at the end of the extract about the topic in the <choice><orig>hole</orig><reg>whole</reg></choice> speech gives the listener and reader a good feeling about was he says and let you thinking about doing a student exchange <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 18-22)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all you can say that he <choice><orig>convince</orig><reg>convinces</reg></choice> the reader in a really positive way.</s>
        <s>Because of his positive radiation directly from the beginning of the speech, you would like to read on.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
