<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c10g18_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211215</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>10</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="90min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="4"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c10gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote>Simple exchanges can break down walls between us</quote><choice><orig>thats</orig><reg>that's</reg></choice> a line of his speech.</s>
        <s>It means that when you talk to someone from another country and exchange information you break down certain barriers that exist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Those include as an example stereotypes, which still influence how we see people.</s>
        <s>This can show that our <choice><orig>exspections</orig><reg>expections</reg></choice> of people are different <choice><orig>then</orig><reg>than</reg></choice> they really are.</s>
        <s>As an example a lot of people say that Germans are really upright and boring, but if you do things with a lot of Germans you can see that this is a lot of the time not true.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><choice><orig>Its</orig><reg>It's</reg></choice> normal that they are always people who <choice><orig>fits</orig><reg>fit</reg></choice> stereotypes, but not everyone is like that.</s>
        <s>This can defeat racism in a way, because those divisions that we have and misconceptions can be destroyed by simple exchange.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But I don't think that every simple exchange can break barriers down, because some people are going to hold grudges against cultures or minorities.</s>
        <s>This can be because of how they were raised, bad experience or other things.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So in general <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> agree with <ref target="c10gk2_1" type="speaker">Obama</ref> that exchanges can tear down walls between cultures or countries, but not every exchange is going to have the same effect.</s>
        <s>But exchange is going to help with destroying barriers, but <choice><orig>its</orig><reg>it's</reg></choice> going to take a long time.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
