<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c11g12_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> says in his speech <quote>Brexit is clearly a lose-lose situation for both</quote> and in the following I will comment on that.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So in my opinion he says the not exactly right.</s>
        <s>I think not the same like him.</s>
        <s>There are pros for the <name type="geo">UK</name> for remaining and also pros for leave.</s>
        <s>If <name type="geo">Britain</name> would stay they could have much greater influence.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A union also better equipped <name type="geo">Britain</name> to tackle threats to security, including terrorism and crossborder crime.</s>
        <s>And it is also free trade within the <name type="misc">EU</name> reduced red tape and enabled companies to grow.</s>
        <s>But there are also pros for leaving.</s>
        <s>The <name type="geo">UK</name> would have improved global trade <choice><orig>aggreements</orig><reg>agreements</reg></choice> and more selective immigration could have a positive effect on the British job market.</s>
        <s>And the <name type="misc">EU</name> subjected <name type="geo">Britain</name> to slow an inflexible bureaucratic red tipe making it more prohibitive for smaller companies to do business.</s>
        <s>So you can see there are pros for leaving and also pros for remaining so the <name type="geo">UK</name> <choice><orig>lose</orig><reg>loses</reg></choice> something but they also win something and the <name type="misc">EU</name> is winning nothing in my opinion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So all in all I would say it is not wrong what <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> says but it is also not exactly right because both sides lose something but the <name type="geo">UK</name> also <choice><orig>win</orig><reg>wins</reg></choice> something good for them.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
