<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c11g08_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text <choice><orig>i</orig><reg>I</reg></choice> will point out the consequences of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, as well as the characteristics of a close relationship between the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name> as indicated by <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> in his speech excerpt at the <name type="misc">European American Chamber of Commerce</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The consequences of the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> are very big.</s>
        <s>He means, that it is a <quote>lose-lose situation for both</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 4-10)</ref> what shows that this is just bad.</s>
        <s>The <name type="misc">Brexit</name> will cost much and they will be substantially higher <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 3, l. 9)</ref>.</s>
        <s>It will be very difficult to trade <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This will have an impact on value chains, particular manufacturing and logistics as well as the <choice><orig>argicultural</orig><reg>agricultural</reg></choice> and food sector <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 6-8)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also said, that they should prepare for the worst case scenario of a <quote>no deal</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following he talks about a close relationship between the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>He said, that this is their common interest.</s>
        <s>There are many ways to achieve this first the <name type="misc">EU</name> <name type="misc">Single Market</name> is open to third countries, which include the <name type="geo">UK</name>, and second, long history of relying on the regulation, which is called equivalence <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 15-23)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Then he pointed out, that the <name type="misc">EU</name> is the most open jurisdiction in the world <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 24)</ref> and asks why this would not work for the <name type="geo">UK</name> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 25-26)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The last thing he tells, is that the <name type="misc">EU</name> will not change because the <name type="geo">UK</name> is leaving.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So there are many bad consequences of the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> for the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name> but with a close relationship between them it will be not that bad.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
