<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c11g07_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="describing" genre_family="descriptive_report">point_out</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref>, <name type="misc">EU</name> commissioner for the <choice><orig>withdrawl</orig><reg>withdrawal</reg></choice> negotiations of the <name type="geo">UK</name> in the course of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, delivered his speech at the <name type="misc">European American Chamber of Commerce</name> in <name type="geo">New York</name>, the <date>10th of July in 2018</date>.</s>
        <s>In his speech he addresses the topic of the consequences of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, the characteristics of the relationship between the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name> as the most open market in the world.</s>
        <s>He held his speech after having thanked for the opportunity to speak about this topic with the purpose of convincing of his criticism of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the <choice><orig>Text</orig><reg>text</reg></choice> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> announces his regret for the <name type="geo">UK</name> leaving the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>In regards to the relationship of the both he claims that <name type="misc">Brexit</name> will evoke a disagreement on non-existing trade <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. l. 5)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He also thinks that <name type="misc">Brexit</name> will <choice><orig>effect</orig><reg>affect</reg></choice> both the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>However, he is out of the opinion that the consequences for the <name type="geo">UK</name> would be higher <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(cf. l. 8f.)</ref>.</s>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> counts results of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, for instance the <quote>impact on value chains, which are currently closely integrated </quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 6f.)</ref> in the <name type="misc">EU</name> states.</s>
        <s>Especially the manufactoring, logistics, agricultural and food sectors will be effected.</s>
        <s>He goes on by offering a further argument for his claim.</s>
        <s>In the lines 11-14 he is talking about the difficulties the <name type="geo">UK</name> will face when trying to sign another trade deals for ex.</s>
        <s>with the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
        <s>He even assumes the <name type="geo">US</name> would refuse the deal.</s>
        <s>Thus he suggests having also in financial services in close relationship to the <name type="geo">UK</name>, which is a mutual interest.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To his mind, the future <name type="misc">Free Trade Agreement</name> with the <name type="geo">UK</name> should consider the right of establishment with applying <name type="misc">EU</name> rules.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Towards the end of his text he mentions that the <name type="misc">EU</name> market is the most open market in the world, which is also welcoming the <name type="geo">UK</name> and still will not change even the <name type="geo">UK</name> is leaving.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In conclusion, one could say that <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> has the opinion that <name type="misc">Brexit</name> will have a negative effect on the <name type="misc">EU</name> but mostly or the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
        <s>Nevertheless the <name type="misc">EU</name> will not change.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
