<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>c11g05_t1</author>
        <name>point_out</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The excerpt of the speech at the <name type="misc">European American Chamber of Commerce</name> spoken by <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> in <name type="geo">New York</name> at the <date>10 July in 2018</date> about the consequences of the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> and how the <name type="misc">European Union</name> wants to build a financial relationship with the <name type="geo">United Kingdom</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text I am first going to point out the consequences of <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, as well as the <choice><orig>caracteristics</orig><reg>characteristics</reg></choice> of a close relationship between the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>Secondly I am want to analyse the text by looking at his line of arguments, his choice of words and the stylistic devices he uses.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The first <choice><orig>concequence</orig><reg>consequence</reg></choice> that he names is caused by the decision from the <name type="geo">UK</name> ot leave the <name type="misc">European Single Market</name> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 4-5)</ref>.</s>
        <s>He says that this is going to have a big influence on the value chains and the trading <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 5-6)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also it is going to have a really big impact in the particular manufacturing, logistics, agricultural and food sectors <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 7-8)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Also he thinks that the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> is a <quote>lose-lose</quote> situation for both sides because the costs will be very high <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 8-10)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>An other consequence is for the <choice><orig>buisinesses</orig><reg>businesses</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s>He says that they should analyse their exposure to the other side and be ready to adapt their logistical channels, supply chains and existing contracts <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 11-13)</ref>.</s>
        <s>There could also be a <quote>no deal</quote> <choice><orig>wich</orig><reg>which</reg></choice> would be worse <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 13-14)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In his opinion the <name type="misc">EU</name> and the <name type="geo">UK</name> have a close relationship in a fincancial way <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 15, 16)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Therefore the <name type="misc">EU</name> might have to open the <name type="misc">Single Market</name> to third <choice><orig>countrys</orig><reg>countries</reg></choice> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 16-17)</ref>.</s>
        <s>This financial relationship and the market should be based on the <name type="misc">Free Trade Agreement</name>, where the <name type="geo">UK</name> should follow the <name type="misc">EU</name> rules <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 20-21)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
