<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c11g08_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The speech excerpt given from <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref>, the <name type="misc">EU</name> commissioner, at the <name type="misc">European American Chamber of Commerce</name> and on the <date>10th of July in 2018</date> in <name type="geo">New York</name> and published on the website <link>ec.europa.eu</link>, is about the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> and what consequences it will have with it and to make it a little bit better.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>His <choice><orig>argumentiv</orig><reg>argumentative</reg></choice> structure, is that he first talks about the problem, which is obviously the <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, then he lists a lot of things why this is a problem after that he points out why a close relationship between <name type="geo">UK</name> and <name type="misc">EU</name> will make things better at the last thing he said things about the <name type="misc">EU</name> and how good their system is.</s>
        <s>He is very serious because he did not really talk about his feelings, just in the first line, that he <choice><orig>regret</orig><reg>regrets</reg></choice> the <choice><orig>decicion</orig><reg>decision</reg></choice> of the <name type="geo">UK</name>, and he uses a lot of facts.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In line 6 to 7 he uses <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> anaphora <quote>impact...impact</quote> to establish a connection between the sentences and to show how much the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> will impact.</s>
        <s>He also did this in line 17, 18 and 22 to establish a connection between his arguments for the relationship.</s>
        <s>In the speech are also a lot of <choice><orig>anumerations</orig><reg>enumerations</reg></choice>, where he <choice><orig>list</orig><reg>lists</reg></choice> things that will be consequences of the <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, to underline how much and big they are and how bad, for example in the second paragraph.</s>
        <s>But he also did this with good things to underline that there is a way to make everything better <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 15-26)</ref> or to show how good the <name type="misc">European Union</name> is and what they achieved <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(ll. 27-32)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In line 13 to 14 he uses a hyperbole to <choice><orig>emphasizes</orig><reg>emphasize</reg></choice> how bad it will end even for the <name type="geo">US</name> with the words <quote>worst case scenario</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> uses inclusive pronouns, like <quote>we</quote> <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(f.e. l. 15, 21)</ref> <choice><orig>whe</orig><reg>when</reg></choice> he talks about the <name type="misc">EU</name>, but that <choice><orig>underline</orig><reg>underlines</reg></choice> that they all want to do that and not just him he also connects him with all people in the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Whe</orig><reg>When</reg></choice> he speaks about the US or <name type="geo">UK</name> he uses the personal pronouns they and you to distract him and the <name type="misc">EU</name> from them.</s>
        <s>All in all he makes a connection with the audience, when he said we will help you because he <choice><orig>include</orig><reg>includes</reg></choice> them in his speech.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>In the first paragraph he just <choice><orig>use</orig><reg>uses</reg></choice> the personal pronoun <quote>I and my</quote> because he tells them his opinion about the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> and to distract his opinion with everyone else opinion.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all he talks about the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> by using arguments against it and <choice><orig>taks</orig><reg>talks</reg></choice> about ways to help each other.</s>
        <s>He did this very serious and formular.</s>
        <s>His intuition is very clear, he wants a relationship with the <name type="geo">UK</name>, and he emphasizes this really good with his <choice><orig>Arguments</orig><reg>arguments</reg></choice> and <choice><orig>Argumentive</orig><reg>argumentative</reg></choice> structure.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
