<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>c11g03_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="interpretation">analyze</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The speech given on <date>10 July 2018</date> in <name type="geo">New York</name> of the <name type="misc">European American Chamber Commerce</name>, by <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> is addressed to the listeners of this <name type="misc">Chamber of Commerce</name> and other political interrested people.</s>
        <s>It thematizes the negative aspects of <name type="misc">Brexit</name> and how the <name type="misc">EU</name> reacts to them.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> starts the excerpt of the <choice><orig>speach</orig><reg>speech</reg></choice> by naming his opinion the <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, he is clearly against it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He underlines that the <name type="misc">Brexit</name> will have a few negative aspects, like upcoming trade frictions, which has a strong impact on many important sectors.</s>
        <s>He <choice><orig>sais</orig><reg>says</reg></choice> summarized that <name type="misc">Brexit</name> is bad for both, the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But he also <choice><orig>sais</orig><reg>says</reg></choice> it's still important to have close <quote>relationship</quote> with the <name type="geo">UK</name> and names ways to achieve this goal.</s>
        <s>He names that trading is still possible, but there also might return tariffs to it.</s>
        <s>He says that when the <name type="geo">UK</name> wants to access the <name type="misc">EU</name> market they must agree with the equivalence system.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He stresses that the <name type="misc">EU</name> <choice><orig>wont</orig><reg>won't</reg></choice> change only because the <name type="geo">UK</name> left, and the now need to conform to the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The speaker <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to explain the negative aspects of <name type="misc">Brexit</name> but <choice><orig>maby</orig><reg>maybe</reg></choice> also <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to manipulate the audience, you can notice that on the fact that doesn't <choice><orig>relie</orig><reg>rely</reg></choice> on <choice><orig>proffecional</orig><reg>professional</reg></choice> <choice><orig>cources</orig><reg>sources</reg></choice>, at least he didn't mention his sources, that makes him look not really serious.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Most of the time he speaks pretty objective, but sometimes he changes to his personal opinion, and asks <choice><orig>rethorical</orig><reg>rhetorical</reg></choice> questions, like <quote>Why would this [...] not work for the UK?</quote>, in this case he <choice><orig>actiuly</orig><reg>actually</reg></choice> asks the audience to question it <choice><orig>themselfs</orig><reg>themselves</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Barnier</ref> starts with a unrelied argument against the <name type="misc">Brexit</name>, the next arguments are better grounded and stronger.</s>
        <s>Then he goes on with points the <name type="misc">EU</name> can do to make it less bad and ends with saying how they should act in the following time.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He uses a few stylistic devices to underline his points, like enumerations, <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="line">(l. 8)</ref> which make it look really drastic.</s>
        <s>Also the parallelism in line 17 to 22, <quote>third countries</quote> <choice><orig>trys</orig><reg>tries</reg></choice> to show how he sees the <name type="geo">UK</name> now.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
