<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>c11g07_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>c</publisher>
        <date>20211222</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>c11gk2</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><quote>Brexit is clearly a lose-lose situation for both</quote> is the claim of <ref target="c11gk2_1" type="speaker">Michel Barnier</ref> in his speech when talking about the <choice><orig>withdrawl</orig><reg>withdrawal</reg></choice> of the <name type="geo">UK</name> from the <name type="misc">European Union</name>.</s>
        <s>In the text below, I would like to comment on that statement and explain why he may be mistaken with his assumption.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Firstly, it is a well-known fact that the <name type="geo">UK</name> was one of the most important states of the <name type="misc">EU</name>.</s>
        <s>Its drop out the <name type="misc">EU</name> will certainly change the relationship between the both.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>First of all, critics of the <name type="misc">EU</name> in the <name type="geo">UK</name> were claiming that the <name type="misc">EU</name> had taken too much power from the <name type="geo">UK</name> government with regulations that were costly for the economy of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>However, outside the <name type="misc">EU</name> market and its shared regulations the <name type="geo">UK</name> would be able to establish a new relationship with the <name type="misc">EU</name> without being bound to its laws.</s>
        <s>And the <name type="geo">UK</name> could decide over itself.</s>
        <s>Furthermore, there are aspects and decisions that were made within the <name type="misc">EU</name> which Britains had great effect effect on and which could be different without the votes of the Britains, for ex.</s>
        <s>There would be probably more red tape within the <name type="misc">EU</name> and higher contributions from the remaining members without opposition of the <name type="geo">UK</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>It may be true that there is at the moment some difficulties both have to deal with for <choice><abbr>ex</abbr><expan>example</expan></choice>.</s>
        <s>the worker shortages in the <name type="geo">UK</name> and as a result the probably higher unemployment rate in the <name type="misc">EU</name>, however the <name type="geo">UK</name> would be able to sign new trade deals with other growing economies for ex.</s>
        <s>with <name type="geo">China</name> and <name type="geo">India</name>.</s>
        <s>Additionally <name type="geo">Britain</name> has no big influence on the <name type="misc">EU</name>, so from outside the <name type="misc">EU</name> it could retake seats on international institutions.</s>
        <s>It also could set new rules to encourage innovation and have the right to decide over itself as the citizens decided with the referendum.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Another significant point is that the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name> have shared values and narrow ties that would help them to hold together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>So, yes even though the <name type="geo">UK</name> and the <name type="misc">EU</name> would have a different kind of relationship and would face some troubles at the beginning, I think that the two powers are able to handle the situation and draw new ways and visions for the future.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
