<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b11l12_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211211</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following I will discuss on why it's difficult for Whites and Hispanics to live together and how the situation can be improved.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One of the main aspects that cause hate towards Mexicans is the fear, especially collective fear and prejudices that make people blind for facts and becomes an obstical when trying to sympathize with them.</s>
        <s>Since fear is an emotional reason people stop thinking rationally.</s>
        <s>Stereotypes make it even harder to understand their situation and since most of the things reported about Mexicans is their huge number and crimes it doesn't help to get a positive view on them.</s>
        <s>Although <name type="geo">California</name> is located directly at the border to <name type="geo">Mexico</name> and therefore many immigrants enter the <name type="geo">US</name> through this state, I doubt that most people don't come in touch with them except for labour exchanges.</s>
        <s>This distance also creates fear, but in this case the fear of the unknown.</s>
        <s>Would they see Mexicans and interact with them more chances that they fear them would be less.</s>
        <s>This brings me to another aspect, which is language.</s>
        <s>Since most Mexicans, who immigrate illegally, don't speak <choice><orig>american english</orig><reg>American English</reg></choice> or only poorly it's hard for them to express themself which therefore leads to misunderstandings like in the given excerpt because they can't explain themselves and the situations they live in, which would again help people get a view into their <choice><orig>lifes</orig><reg>lives</reg></choice> and make it easier to understand.</s>
        <s>Another issue is that the word illegal as well <name type="geo">Mexico</name> are negatively connotated and connected to corruption, gangs and just bad things.</s>
        <s>That shapes an image into <choice><orig>peoples</orig><reg>people's</reg></choice> heads that associates Mexicans with all these negative aspects.</s>
        <s>I would also argue that illegal Mexicans aren't seen as humans like everyone else with feelings and <choice><orig>worrys</orig><reg>worries</reg></choice> ad the desire to just live at a safe place with enough money to feed their <choice><orig>familys</orig><reg>families</reg></choice> but rather annoying people on the streets.</s>
        <s>This is proved by the poor <choice><orig>hygene</orig><reg>hygiene</reg></choice>, they can't change though.</s>
        <s>But if they had proper clothes this wouldn't make people think of them differently than others and maybe also treat them fairly.</s>
        <s>On the other hand wearing a gun raises the chances of people using them and scaring Hispanics <choice><orig>of</orig><reg>off</reg></choice> the moment they see them.</s>
        <s>Gated <choice><orig>communitys</orig><reg>communities</reg></choice> only worsen relationships between those two groups.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A solution to that problem would be to actually give illegal immigrants access to the promises of the American Dream so they can have decent living conditions.</s>
        <s>Education and interaction play an important role if as I stressed the distance between them want to be solved.</s>
        <s>Especially kids of these two groups should get in contact through school for example because they and their <choice><orig>believes</orig><reg>beliefs</reg></choice> will <choice><orig>chape</orig><reg>shape</reg></choice> the future generations.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
