<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b11l05_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211211</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following, I will discuss the subject why it is difficult for Whites and Hispanics to live together in <name type="geo">California</name> and will give a suggestion how the situation could be improved.</s>
        <s>In order to do that we need to have a look at the situation in <name type="geo">California</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="geo">California</name> is a state <choice><orig>whith</orig><reg>with</reg></choice> a lot of immigrants.</s>
        <s>A lot of legal immigrants who work there.</s>
        <s>In addition o that, people who are born there but their family <add>the generation before them</add> has other roots.</s>
        <s>A lot of them are <choice><orig>european</orig><reg>European</reg></choice>.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Jack Jardine</name> in the novel portrays an example of that.</s>
        <s>Moreover, there are immigrants who once immigrated illegally and became citizens over time after going through a long process.</s>
        <s>This process of gaining citizenship can take five years or longer.</s>
        <s>Can you imagine that?</s>
        <s>In addition to this, the tests you have to take are really hard and contain topics and questions Americans could not even answer themselves.</s>
        <s>So, the process is hard.</s>
        <s>That is why the percentage of illegal immigrants in <name type="geo">California</name> is rather high.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>A lot of these illegal immigrants are Hispanic because <name type="geo">California</name> is located right next to <name type="geo">Latin America</name>, at the border to <name type="geo">Mexico</name>.</s>
        <s>It's rather easy immigrating to <name type="geo">California</name> that way.</s>
        <s>That is how <name type="person">Cándid</name> and <name type="person">Ámerica</name> came to the <name type="geo">US</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>You should think that with the high rate of immigrants in the state you would be used to it and it wouldn't be a problem at all.</s>
        <s>Sadly though, apparently it is not that easy for a lot of people there.</s>
        <s>A lot of Americans are full of prejudices in this aspect.</s>
        <s>They claim that Hispanics are criminals and often treat them this way.</s>
        <s>The gate discussion in the novel is a clear example for that.</s>
        <s>They want to shut themselves of.</s>
        <s>Avoid Mexicans and the things that supposably come with them.</s>
        <s>Of course, most Americans don't admit it that openly.</s>
        <s>They act out of indirect racism.</s>
        <s>Because of that attitude, which is totally ironic by the way because <name type="geo">California</name> used to belong to <name type="geo">Latin America</name>.</s>
        <s>However, this attitude, makes it really hard for Hispanics, especially illegal immigrants to live with them peacefully.</s>
        <s>I am sure they want to and wish for that but the reality looks different.</s>
        <s>Sadly.</s>
        <s>They want to be included, they want to do their part by working for example.</s>
        <s>Although even that doesn't work that easily.</s>
        <s>Employers will probably alwys prefer a legal, American worker over <choice><orig>a</orig><reg>an</reg></choice> immigrant with no paper, no matter how desperate they are.</s>
        <s>Which is also understandable.</s>
        <s>Illegal work is also forbidden in <name type="geo">Germany</name>.</s>
        <s>To conclude, in order to improve this situation, the process of being able to work legally has to get easier.</s>
        <s>Moreover, Americans who are not tolerant yet need to change their attitude and should try to be more over and not let themselves be <choice><orig>leaded</orig><reg>lead</reg></choice> by prejudices, even though it can be hard for everyone to act completely without prejudices.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
