<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3c</title>
        <author>b11l11_t3</author>
        <name>story</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211211</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="entertaining" genre_family="narrative">story</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p><s>It was afternoon and he worked the last 4 hours in this rich white neighbourhood setting up these flies.</s><s>The sum was shining and burnt on his back.</s><s>He thought about his friend with whom he immigrated and if he <choice><orig>als</orig><reg>also</reg></choice> found work at the labour exchange in the inner city.</s><s>They would have to work a few more weeks to have enough money for an apartment to not sleep in the sleeping bags out in the woods.</s><s>He heard a man yelling on the other side of the streets.</s><s>Was he shouting for him?</s><s>Had he done something wrong?</s><s>He came over the street and repeated his question.</s><s><quote>I said can I help you</quote> barked the man <choice><orig>agressely</orig><reg>aggressively</reg></choice> in his face and in that moment he recognized his red hair.</s><s>In the woods he was acting very strange and didn't even said hello back.</s><s>He was unsure what the gringo wanted from him and replied grinning ironically: <quote>sure, hombre, you can help me</quote> but it didn't turn out to calm the situation.</s><s>He was <choice><orig>aggressivly</orig><reg>aggressively</reg></choice> looking like I have done something to him but he couldn't detect what it was.</s><quote><s>This is private property.</s><s>You don't belong here</s></quote>. <s>And he knew exactly what this white <choice><orig>mans</orig><reg>man's</reg></choice> problem was: He thought he was a criminal a dirty Mexican thief.</s><s>The rich people here are all the same he thought.</s><s>All of them were racist, unempathic people, wanting him to die.</s><s>He felt his fury coming up.</s><s>The white man was red of anger and pulled him out of his thoughts: <quote>I'm talking to you</quote>.</s><s>He holded his wrist with his sweaty hands like he was a criminal or an arsonist.</s><s>He was so furious but he had to <choice><orig>supress</orig><reg>suppress</reg></choice> his anger <choice><orig>becaus</orig><reg>because</reg></choice> no matter what the gringo did he would always be the dangerous Mexican.</s><s>He shooked his wrist free from his hold and tried to explain with his broken English what he was doing, but the gringo didn't believe him and it looked like he was setting up for a fight.</s><s>Now with a stronger undertone he said the in his head prepared sentence another time: <quote>Flies, I deliver these flies</quote>.</s><s>Now he seemed a bit ashamed and walked with no words away.</s><s>The red <choice><orig>hairded</orig><reg>haired</reg></choice> gringo got in his big house but he felt the rest of the day like he was observing him.</s></p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
