<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3a</title>
        <author>b11l01_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211211</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="responding" genre_family="critical_response">comment</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s><name type="geo">California</name> is a melting pot where white people and Hispanic cultures mix together.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Nonetheless, there is a lot of tension between those ethnic groups which is rooted in mainly racism.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="geo">California</name> is right at the morrder to many South American countries where most undocumented immigrants come from.</s>
        <s>Although the <name type="geo">USA</name> relies on those people for a functioning economy, for example in agriculture or construction, many white people are against illegal immigration, even if they profit from it.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Like in the book, many white Americans seek out illegal immigrants to do house work for them at the labour <choice><orig>exange</orig><reg>exchange</reg></choice>, since it is cheap and they don't have to pay taxes.</s>
        <s>Many white people are not aware of the complicated system of getting citizenship in <name type="geo">America</name>, so they usually just dismiss the struggles of undocumented immigrants.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But they are ways to improve the situation.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>One way would be to educate white people about the reasons for illegal immigration and the harsh struggles that those face who are undocumented.</s>
        <s>Or making the process of getting citizenship or applying for assylum easier.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>To summarize, racism and uneducation of mainly white people are the reason why the climate between them and Hispanics <choice><orig>are</orig><reg>is</reg></choice> not so good, but learning about illegal immigration could help better the situation.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
