<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t1</title>
        <author>b11l01_t1</author>
        <name>summarize</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211211</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="180min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
        <note genre="recounting" genre_family="literary_recount">summarize</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>b11lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>The novel <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="title">The Tortilla Curtain</ref>, written by <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="author">T. C. Boyle</ref> and published in <date>1995</date>, deals with the harsh reality of undocumented immigrants, who are seeking a better live in the <name type="geo">United States</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The passage at hand is an excerpt from <choice><orig>Part Two</orig><reg>part two</reg></choice>, <choice><orig>Chapter</orig><reg>chapter</reg></choice> 6 of the novel.</s>
        <s>It <choice><orig>depictes</orig><reg>depicts</reg></choice> the growing paranoia of <name type="person">Delaney Mossbacher</name>, which is fueled by his prejudice against Mexicans.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
        <s>one of the protagonists of the story, is talking to one of his neighbours, <name type="person">Todd Sweet</name>, about the ongoing discussion <choice><orig>wether</orig><reg>whether</reg></choice> <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco</name>, the wealthy area they live in, should become a gated community.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The majority of the inhabitants of the area voted for the erection of the gate, while <name type="person">Delaney</name>, in that part, is still against it, because he sees it as undemocratic and exlusionary and he wants to convince his wife <name type="person">Kyra</name> and his good friend <name type="person">Jack Jardine</name> from his point of view.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>But during the conversation with <name type="person">Todd Sweet</name>, he suddenly spots <name type="person">José Navidad</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>He is an undocumented immigrant from <name type="geo">Mexico</name> and also involved in criminal activities.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> has seen and heard of multiple occasions, for example on the day his car was stolen or when his wife tells him that <name type="person">José</name> was <choice><orig>rouming</orig><reg>roaming</reg></choice> around their house.</s>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> confronts him on the lawn of one of his other <choice><orig>neighbour</orig><reg>neighbours</reg></choice>, <name type="person">Jack Cherrystone</name>, who is out of town.</s>
        <s>He tells <name type="person">José</name> to leave, who does not comply, which makes <name type="person">Delaney</name> feel humiliated by <name type="person">José's</name> indifferent reaction.</s>
        <s>This is where <name type="person">Delaney</name> grabs him by the arm, but <name type="person">José</name> quickly reacts and spits at him.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s><name type="person">Delaney</name> becomes more and more agitated, because he assumes he will havea to fight <name type="person">José</name> till death.</s>
        <s>But <name type="person">José</name> pulls out flyers he claims to distribute throughout the neighbourhood, which are informing the <choice><orig>residants</orig><reg>residents</reg></choice> of <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco</name> about further discurse of the gated community topic.</s>
        <s>After that <name type="person">José</name> leaves and <name type="person">Delaney</name> feels ashamed of his irrational behaviour.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
