<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t2</title>
        <author>b11l09_t2</author>
        <name>analyze</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211201</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="120"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>lk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>This chapter portrays <name type="person">Delaney's</name> character development in regard of his attitude towards Mexican immigrants and shows a turning point of <name type="person">Delaney's</name> bigotry.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The gap between what <name type="person">Delaney</name> thinks and how he presetns himself was in previous chapters very big and he often claims to be a <q>liberal humanist</q>.</s>
        <s>In this chapter however he starts to openly show his racist part of him and instinctivly acts because of his prejudices <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 39)</ref>.</s>
        <s>The use of direct speech in this case emphazises his change to <choice><orig>beeing</orig><reg>being</reg></choice> openly and directly racist.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Because the story is told by an omniscient narrator the reader also dives <choice><orig>in to</orig><reg>into</reg></choice> the thoughts of <name type="person">Delaney</name>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>The narrator often uses reported thought which lets the reader be aprt of <name type="person">Delaney's</name> thoughts but still creating a distance because it is very clear that it is not the own opinion of the narrator <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(e.g. cf. ll. 55-59)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>This clear separation and the created distance allow the reader to be part of the story but still being able to form their own opinion.</s>
        <s>For example when <name type="person">Delaney</name> is surprised about the reaction of the man to his calls because he thinks that the man is committing crime and therefore expects him to behave more shocked <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 20f)</ref>.</s>
        <s>In this case the reader is able to follow the outturn of the situation because they know <name type="person">Delaney's</name> thoughts but are also capable of noticing the differences between his expectations and the reality.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Moreover, in situations where the narrator tries to show how and for what reason the conversation escalates he uses interior monologues of <name type="person">Delaney</name> and his way of building up a climax by enumerating all the reasons for his outrage <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. ll. 49f)</ref>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Interesting in this chapter is his overwhelmed mind in the beginning and in the end of the chapter.</s>
        <s>Both, beginning and ending, deal with the decision of whether or not building a wall around <name type="geo">Arroyo Blanco</name> is in his interest <ref target="b11lk1_1" type="line">(cf. l. 6 and 65-69)</ref>.</s>
        <s>Through this technique, the incident with the Mexican seems to be inserted in his very ambivalent way of trying to make a decision.</s>
        <s>It is once again a very uncomfortable experience with a Mexican.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>Taking everything into account, the incident almost feels like it is <gap reason="illegible" quantity="1" unit="word">utaged</gap> to help <name type="person">Delaney</name> make a decision and for him to realize his changing behaviour.</s>
        <s>Both sides for and against the wall, try to influence him in this chapter and the situation with the man makes the decision even more urgent.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
