<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" version="4.3.0">
  <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
      <titleStmt>
        <title>t3</title>
        <author>b11g09_t3</author>
        <name>comment</name>
      </titleStmt>
      <publicationStmt>
        <publisher>b</publisher>
        <date>20211207</date>
      </publicationStmt>
      <seriesStmt>
        <title>11</title>
      </seriesStmt>
      <notesStmt>
        <note>time="135min"</note>
        <note>#tasks="3"</note>
      </notesStmt>
      <sourceStmt>
        <p>gk1</p>
      </sourceStmt>
    </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
    <body>
      <p>
        <s>In the following text I will comment the thesis <quote>CPS should have taken Pearl away from Margot and the trailer park, put her into a foster home and help her to get a good education and prepare for a better and independent way of life</quote>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>On the one hand it's a good solution for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> because then she has better life conditions, how a healthy or a hygienic life, but on the other hand this will leave <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> from her mother and that can be sad for both.</s>
        <s>Another aspect is that when the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> have taken <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away from the trailer park <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> can have a life which is not dangerous for her but maybe she's happy in the trailer park and doesn't want to leave it.</s>
        <s>Also it can open a better future for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> and a rich future when she works hard.</s>
        <s>On the other side it can be a sad life and future and maybe a life with depression, also for <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref>, because they don't live together anymore.</s>
        <s>So maybe they feel alone.</s>
        <s><choice><orig>Furthemore</orig><reg>Furthermore</reg></choice><ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> can <choice><orig>meets</orig><reg>meet</reg></choice> new friends when the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> takes <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away but also she leaves her best friend <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">April May</ref>.</s>
        <s>The American Dream is also important to say because it says that everyone can achieve everything when he works hard and the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> gives <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> the chance, but we see that the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> and foster homes not only have good aspects because when we see <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Helen</ref>, it is clear that the <choice><abbr>CPS</abbr><expan>Child Protective Services</expan></choice> is not often good and can be bad for a <choice><orig>children</orig><reg>child</reg></choice>.</s>
      </p>
      <p>
        <s>All in all I would say they should have taken <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> away because so she can have a better life, but I think it's hard for a <choice><orig>children</orig><reg>child</reg></choice> and maybe they can give <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Pearl</ref> a better future with <ref target="b11gk1_1" type="character">Margot</ref> together.</s>
      </p>
    </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
